Chapter 1

Mushrooms... So Many Mushrooms

Jake had to question if it all was just one cruel joke that everyone but himself was in on. Had Villy put them up to his? Was he the one who had tipped off Draskil to choose this dungeon? Maybe influenced Irin? There had to be more to this than pure randomness. Because what Jake saw was just a hellscape.

The expansive cavern before Jake contained a large forest, but it had massive mushrooms rather than trees. The underbrush was just moss and mushrooms. Mushroom spores covered the sky and floated in the air, and there were even mushrooms growing on the mushrooms.

And if that wasn’t enough, then the first movement Jake saw was of a large mushroom with mushroom arms and mushroom legs, holding a mushroom shield and wielding a mushroom stalk as a club. The figure was about three meters tall and on the bulkier side, but was overall clearly a low-tier creature, even if its level was decent.

[Mushroom Man Warrior – lvl 171]

"I hate this place," Jake said, the first person to speak after entering the dungeon.

"Smells like shit," Draskil snorted, clearly not enjoying the mushrooms either.

Irin looked a bit confused, while Reika understood Jake’s hatred. Not because she carried it herself, but because Jake had ranted plenty of times to her about the evil shrooms.

Bastilla was even more confused than Irin and, in her infinite ignorance, asked, "Why? Aren’t mushrooms great for poisons?"

"Great for poisoning people who don’t know better, too," Draskil muttered before looking at Jake. "We kill everything?"

"Wait!" Irin cut in. "Please do not destroy the corpses too badly, as we may need them for materials or to get their life cores. Do we have anyone here with scavenging or dismantling abilities, by the way?"

Bastilla raised her hand. Jake was a bit surprised but didn’t show it. Irin looked at Jake momentarily with approval before nodding. "Very well, then. You take care of dismantling all the corpses."

"I will begin to collect materials and search for them, then," Reika said, but Jake decided to cut in as he looked at Draskil.

"Will killing any of these mushrooms even give you any experience worth mentioning?"

"No, but I would enjoy it," Draskil answered bluntly.

"Totally fair. I was just thinking that we should have Reika and Bastilla kill those here on the earlier floors while we collect stuff and pass the test. Besides, we have four whole weeks total, and we both know we won’t need that time—and if we do need the time, it is due to the far more time-consuming alchemy aspect and not due to killing things slowly, so better you help me out.”

Draskil clearly didn’t like the idea but grunted in approval anyway. "Fine… but if any of those damn mushrooms get in my way, I kill them."

"Again, totally fair." Jake nodded with a smile before turning to Bastilla and Reika. "Time for you two to put on your hunting boots and get killing."

"Alright," Reika agreed without arguing.

"I… I’m not really the fighting type of gal?" Bastilla said, seeming a bit shy for the first time since they’d met. She was obviously not a fan.

"Too bad, but sometimes you gotta fight to survive.” Encouragingly, Jake added, “You are a beastfolk. You are innately a fighter. Just tap into some of that primal instinct and go rip those damn shrooms to pieces.”

It wasn’t like it would be dangerous either way. Jake had a very good feel for the mushroom warrior, and it was clear it was damn weak, just as one would expect from a mushroom man. Mushrooms all sucked, after all.

"Okay…" Bastilla agreed after a comforting look from Reika.

"I shall help guard them while they hunt," Irin added.

"No," Jake said, shutting the sentiment down. "Unless some hidden boss or a horde of those shroomy fucks pops out of the ground, those are their fights, and no one interferes."

Bastilla looked like she wanted to protest, but Reika spoke up first. "I must agree. It is no proper fight if we have someone constantly guarding us. I have not fought for a while, and it is about time I get in some proper practice. Without a true element of danger, it wouldn’t be as worthwhile."

Jake nodded in approval, seeing some of that Noboru blood leak through. Irin looked a bit concerned, but Jake wasn’t. One had to remember that while Reika was not considered a peak fighter on Earth, she was merely considered a single tier behind. And the peak fighters of Earth were out of the ordinary, to say the least.

They all watched as Reika pulled out a white scabbard from which she drew a sword. Jake felt the immense cold emanate from it as her mana stirred and infused the blade further. "I am ready."

Her aura had changed and was now both colder and sharper than before. Irin looked surprised, while Draskil now seemed far more approving.

Bastilla was the most surprised, just staring until she collected herself. "Fine… Let’s go."

They all watched as Reika took the lead and approached the mushroom man. Cold white air revolved around her as she stepped forward and charged. It looked like a simple charge, but Jake saw how the concept of ice enveloped her feet in icy mist, making her footwork faster and far more unpredictable.

The Mushroom Man Warrior turned to the human twenty or so levels below himself… itself… whatever. The mushroom swung his club, displaying a respectable amount of Strength and speed. Reika didn’t even flinch as she dodged the attack and swept her blade upwards, leaving a cold trail. The mushroom man took a deep cut to his mushy flesh and made an odd roaring sound as he just kept swinging the club haphazardly.

Reika took a bit to really get in the zone, and Jake saw noticeable improvements in her movements with every exchange. Having seen her fight before, Jake knew she was just getting into the swing of it. The mushroom man was nothing more than a training dummy for her to refine her fighting instincts after a long time of just doing alchemy and living in safety.

It took her only five minutes until Jake saw she was done with her opponent. She took a single step back from her opponent and fanned the sword in a circular pattern that left afterimages behind. These afterimages froze in the air and turned into blades of ice that Reika sent barraging towards the mushroom man. It was impaled by dozens of them before Reika sheathed her blade again, and the moment she did, all the frozen blades exploded, blowing the body of the shroomy fuck apart into seven frozen chunks.

"That felt refreshing." Reika smiled as she walked back to them, not a single trace of dirt on her clothes.

"You know how to fight," Draskil said, speaking to Reika for the first time. “You are skilled.”

"I try my best," Reika said, bowing, "but I still have a long way to go before I would call myself skilled."

"Don’t compare yourself to the old man," Jake joked.

"Who is this old man, if I may ask?" Irin said curiously.

Jake gave Reika a look, signaling that if she wanted it to be shared, it was up to her.

She nodded and chose to answer. "My great-grandfather and a true swordsman," Reika said with a smile, clearly proud.

"Is he strong?" Draskil asked again.

"Yes," Reika answered. "He taught me just a little bit of swordsmanship, and it has served me more than well."

Draskil looked like he wanted to ask more, but Jake cut in. "Anyway, how about we actually do the dungeon now? As you can see, Reika knows how to handle herself, so let’s leave the two roomies and go find out how to pass this floor and get to the more exciting parts of this accursed place. Hopefully somewhere with no mushrooms."

Irin nodded in agreement, even if she did throw a few more curious glances at Reika. "Let us. We should look for the passageway to the next floor. The requirements to pass must be there."

They better be, Jake thought. So far, all he had seen in the dungeon was mushrooms, and he wanted to pass this floor fast. The system message when he entered the dungeon wasn’t very useful either.

You have entered the dungeon: Nine Floors of the Indigo Caverns.

Objective: Pass at least four floors of the Indigo Caverns within the 28-day limit.

The only new information here was that you only needed to pass four floors to complete the dungeon, meaning everything after that was optional for better rewards. The time limit of four weeks was likely there to ensure that people couldn’t just enter, find out what they needed to do, and then leave the dungeon to make detailed plans or spend insane amounts of time testing and experimenting until a solution was found. Sure, one could leave the dungeon, but Jake knew that time kept passing inside even after one left. At least it did so for a period of time, making it unfeasible. There was also one more thing… Jake couldn’t find any exit. Not that he planned on leaving, but he had kind of gotten used to there being an exit from where they entered, while in this dungeon, there was just a cave wall.

Leaving Reika and Bastilla behind, Jake, Irin, and Draskil flew further into the dungeon floor. The first floor wasn’t actually as big as Jake had initially thought, but only a few dozen or so square kilometers at most, with two kilometers to the mushroom-covered ceiling.

With that in mind, it didn’t take them long to find the passage to the next floor. It was a gate like the one they had entered the dungeon through, and in front of the door was a large cauldron with a lid on it. Furthermore, on the wall beside the gate, an inscription could be found.

An inscription with pretty easy instructions.

Create three different kinds of poisons of at least inferior rarity from the materials found on this floor and place them all in the cauldron. In order to open the lid of the cauldron, at least one hundred Mushroom Man Warriors must be slain.

Progress: Mushroom Man Warriors killed: 3/100. Poisons placed in the cauldron: 0/3.

As expected, the first floor was easy-peasy. They just had to kill a hundred mushroom men, and with Reika and Bastilla having already killed three, it would get done pretty quickly by itself. So all Jake had to do was to make the three poisons.

"Well, this is easy enough," Jake said. “Just get some different ingredients, and I will toss them together and make a few different poisons.”

None of them had expected much difficulty to begin with, and all set out again. Draskil and Jake both had Sense of the Malefic Viper, and Irin also had her own skills to search for valuable items. Amidst the many normal mushrooms spread throughout the forest were special ones that counted as items, and Jake also quickly noticed how peculiar the fungi were.

The spores in the air all around them at all times weren’t just for ambiance and released from the mushrooms; they were a unique feature of the dungeon, and something all the ingredients there relied on. Nothing could be taken out of the dungeon without wilting, and Jake noticed how these spores even seemed to "enter" his spatial storage whenever he put a mushroom in it.

Jake also became aware of this from eating a lot of mushrooms. He hated mushrooms, but he still recognized that eating them was a good idea due to their uniqueness. Every single mushroom inside the dungeon could not be found on the outside, having been made specifically for the dungeon.

Pulling out some old tricks, Jake made mushroom soup and went around eating as he collected stuff. In the distance, he heard fighting, and at times a dark green pulse of power went through the floor when Draskil killed a Mushroom Man Warrior that got in his way.

What was a little disappointing was that all the mushrooms were common rarity at most, but it had to get better as they progressed through the floors, right? He damn well hoped so, as finding nearly only inferior-rarity stuff sucked.

After an hour of eating and searching, Jake headed back to the passageway and plopped his ass down to do some alchemy. He had already gotten some ideas, and quite frankly, it was an easy job anyway.

If this had been before Jake had ever gone to the Order, it would have taken him a lot longer to confidently say he could successfully create three poisons that easily, but his general knowledge in the art of poisons had experienced notable growth in recent times. Taking out a few mushrooms and some of the moss, Jake tossed it all into the cauldron along with some purified water and a few drops of his blood to act as a catalyst.

Ten so minutes later, Irin returned to check on Jake, who was sitting there and letting the cauldron simmer. She clearly didn’t want to disturb him, but that was a needless worry.

"Found good things?" Jake asked.

"Not really," Irin answered after getting the go-ahead to talk. "This is the first floor. There aren’t really ingredients I think anyone would consider good."

"Fair," Jake said.

"Are you confident in making the three poisons by yourself?"

"Well," Jake said as he dispelled his Alchemical Flame, “got one already."

He opened the cauldron and nodded as he took out a few bottles. Once everything was in them, he inspected the final product.

[Weak Necrotic Mushroom Poison (Inferior)] – A poison created from the unique mushrooms of the Nine Floors of the Indigo Caverns dungeon with necrotic properties, infecting and killing off biological material in the affected area. Wounds caused by Necrotic Poison are somewhat difficult to heal. The poison takes effect upon any contact with biological material.

Jake instantly knew that even if it had added a bunch of things about the dungeon, this was really just normal Necrotic Poison. He also knew he could bring it outside without a problem and use it like normal.

"That was fast," Irin exclaimed.

"Of course," Jake said, laughing a bit as he began his second concoction.

Looking at the engraving, he saw that the hundred Mushroom Man Warriors were already dead, and the dungeon cauldron was open. To test, Jake tossed a bottle in the cauldron and saw the progress tick from 0/3 to 1/3.

"Well, then, second poison." Jake smiled as he threw in the ingredients. "In the meantime, can you do me a favor?

"What is it?" Irin asked curiously.

"Can you roast the mushrooms or something to eat? The taste is driving me nuts," Jake said spitefully.

Irin surprisingly smiled as she took out a small canister, of sorts, along with a large bowl. She then deposited all her collected mushrooms in the bowl and opened the container as an orange liquid covered the mushrooms. She tossed the mix a bit before nodding.

"Try one now," she offered, and Jake promptly responded by extending a string of mana.

He swooped up a mushroom and put it in his mouth, and his eyes opened wide. How could he have forgotten the secret to making horrible salads edible?

Tasty dressing.

Chapter 2

Truly Evil Dungeon Design

It didn’t get better. Jake had hoped that the second floor would be less mushroomy, but it wasn’t to be. In fact, there were even more mushrooms, and some of them were even aggressive and attacked them. Mushroom Man Mages had also been added to the list of enemies, usually wandering with their warrior kin.

The second floor ended up proceeding much like the first. Jake hadn’t even needed any materials gathered by others from the first floor, and he and Draskil had ended up just having a mushroom feast prepared by Irin, who shared that she had a skill related to cooking. Why would a succubus have a skill related to cooking, one might ask? Jake didn’t truly know, but he did know that he and Draskil both liked her better after she began making their mushroom meals far tastier. Perhaps she had only become a cook to integrate herself with others—not only through social interactions, but through their stomachs. A truly insidious strategy that Jake was totally fine with.

Anyway, the second floor was also rather dull. All it required was for the party to kill at least two hundred mushroom men and craft at least three different resource-restoring potions using the materials found in the dungeon. Jake once more did all the crafting while Reika got some combat done with an already-tired-looking Bastilla joining in.

Draskil was just wandering about eating stuff, and Jake did see him at one point juggle three Mushroom Man Warriors in boredom. No, not juggle in the figurative sense, but the literal one. He tossed them up in the air before catching them again.

On a side note, Jake and the others also finally found the exit to the dungeon. Inside every passageway leading to the next floor was an exit that could be used, but it was only available in the passageway. If anyone entered the next floor, the exit would cease to function, and one couldn’t go back to earlier floors once one had been successfully passed.

The third floor was once again more of the same, but at least there was something more than mushrooms present. Several flowers and plants had begun to grow together with the mushrooms, and one part even had a small lake with water plants inside. The challenge on the third floor was to craft a poison using the lake water. The poison itself had to retain all the toxic effects of the lake water but without any of the restorative properties. In essence, it was a test of purification rather than true crafting. There was one small snag, though: the water had to also increase in potency enough to be recognized as a common-rarity poison.

By default, the water was of inferior rarity, and if the restorative effects were removed, it was questionable if it would even qualify as an item. This floor was the first time Reika proved her skills; she quickly figured out a way to distill the water, and Jake then realized that if he just added some mushrooms also present on the floor, he would be able to make it.

On this floor, Bastilla also had to stop joining in on the combat, or at least only fight with Reika. Reika herself was also struggling as the mushroom men got stronger, and the mages and warriors now also had something called defenders, which carried two mushroom shields.

Ah, not that there was any cause for concern as to whether they could pass the floor or even subsequent ones. Draskil still ripped every single opponent apart with ease, and Jake himself had only killed a few who got in his way, all of them requiring just a few moves with his two katars.

From the fourth floor, the dynamic became more how they’d initially planned to do the dungeon. Draskil was in charge of the killing, with Bastilla primarily dismantling the corpses using skills Jake had never seen before. Usually, any creature killed only dropped its core or one other item, but Bastilla could dismantle a corpse and gain far more. Using her skills, most parts of the creature would turn into items of some variety, but her greatest ability was redirecting the Records of a slain creature. Rather than having all the energy stored in the orb, it would instead enter another or several other parts of the body. Sure, crafters could already infuse cores into materials from a monster, but Bastilla didn’t just infuse the core into something—she infused the whole damn corpse. It was a bit weird seeing an entire mushroom man be reduced to a small piece of white mushroom flesh teeming with energy, but who was Jake to argue with system rules?

Reika and Jake also began to team up from the fourth floor and did all the alchemy. The challenges got quite a bit more complicated, and it was clear that the fourth one had a spike, likely due to being the last required floor one had to pass to complete the dungeon.

Oh, yeah! The fourth floor also had a boss: Mushroom Man Commander. It was a bigger than a usual mushroom man, surrounded by many other mushroom men. Jake needed a piece from the boss to pass the floor, so he had Draskil be nice and not destroy the mushroom too much so Bastilla could still use her skills properly on it.

Needless to say, nothing seen so far could even touch Jake or Draskil. The Mushroom Man Commander had only been level 185 and wasn’t even that strong of a D-grade. Jake could likely have killed it with one well-placed Arcane Powershot, and one hundred percent have killed it with an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. Draskil also only needed a few moments to kill it with his claws.

Jake had yet to really see how Draskil fought, even after going through the floors with him. Seeing the dragonkin kill mushroom men by swiping his claws casually didn’t give much insight, but at least let Jake know Draskil was a melee fighter. Granted, Draskil didn’t know Jake’s fighting style either, as he had yet to pull out his bow.

Even if the fourth floor was a tad more difficult alchemy-wise than those prior, it still only took Jake and Reika a few hours to find out how to properly combine the Lifecore from the boss monster with the other ingredients. This floor was harder primarily due to only having one real shot at succeeding with the Lifecore, but at least they could practice the craft with lesser Lifecores from the other mushrooms before the real attempt. On the note of crafting, Jake was the one doing all of the actual alchemy, with Reika taking more of an advisory role. She did still do some crafts, but only exploratory ones to figure out stuff for Jake to reference.

Only a bit over twenty-four hours after entering the dungeon, they stepped foot in the passageway to the fifth floor, having officially "completed" the place. They all stopped as a system message appeared before them.

You have successfully passed four floors and have officially completed the dungeon.

However, if the quest ends here or not is up to you. Five more floors await you as you delve deeper into the Indigo Caverns, with challenge and opportunity growing hand in hand. Perhaps you may even see what dwells at the bottom of the caverns and obtain the true reward…

Do you wish to continue delving into the Indigo Caverns?

"I must admit… we got here faster than expected," Irin said, shaking her head in slight disbelief. "I had estimated it would take us around two days, maybe closer to three."

Jake had to agree with her assessment… Shit had been easier than expected. Granted, it would have taken him a bit longer if he was alone, but Jake could have definitely passed the place solo in between two and three days easily.

"Well, we do have two absolute monsters here," Bastilla muttered.

"Yeah, Reika and Irin are damn beasts at what they do!" Jake agreed, failing to hold himself back from making a joke. The two of them had been incredibly helpful, but it was obvious that the two main contributors had been Jake and Draskil. However, one should not discount the absolutely essential job Irin had.

She made mushrooms actually edible. The succubus had complained at one point about being reduced to a cook, but she’d nevertheless kept making mushroom feasts. Okay, calling it cooking was maybe a bit much, as all she did was season the mushrooms. Ah, but it was special seasoning. Not only did it make the mushrooms taste better—it had synergy with Palate of the Malefic Viper.

It made the knowledge obtained more… digestible and allowed Jake and Draskil to absorb it faster. It was a small and near-negligible effect, and the true worth was in making the mushrooms edible, but it was something. Not that the two of them would have cared if all her seasoning did was make mushrooms taste somewhat good, as that was sure as hell a requirement… because the goddamn mushroom nightmare continued floor after floor, only getting worse.

On the note of eating copious amounts of mushrooms, Jake learned that while Draskil was not an alchemist, he still kind of was? He didn’t concoct poisons the usual way, but instead told Jake how he made it inside his body. He had what could almost be called an organ where he cultivated poisons using Palate, crafting toxins for him to use on his claws and fangs, or even to refine his blood.

Draskil thus needed to also eat a lot of poisons to expand both the scope and depth of his poison. Jake could only imagine the nightmare if he was the only one eating all that Irin prepared, so he was glad to have someone to share the pain with.

"Are we going to keep up the pace?" Reika asked, ignoring Jake’s "praise."

"Yes," Draskil stated.

Jake shrugged. "The big bad dragonkin has spoken. I want to reach this final C-grade boss too."

"Will we actually fight it?" Bastilla asked with a bit of worry.

Draskil and Jake both looked at her and answered in concert. "Yes." "Yeah."

They had both killed C-grades before—well, Jake had killed one—so not trying to at least fight it would be silly. Irin had even mentioned how it was weak, so it would be a shame not to.

Having decided to continue, they entered the fifth floor after all agreeing to continue. The system prompt was not really a vote, more just an opportunity to leave, and Irin explained that if anyone did choose to exit, they could get their rewards then and there and be out. The rest of the party could still continue.

This floor was more of the same, even if the difficulty had spiked. Jake decided to finally join in on the action and helped kill some foes, as they now had to slay five hundred mushroom men to proceed and craft a weird type of poison Jake had never come across before. A poison that seemed to erode water somehow. Not absorb it, but just make it disappear. It was weird, but Reika came in clutch again and helped find a solution, making the fifth floor take only around ten hours total.

Sixth floor? Same shit, more mushrooms. Took them twenty-two hours, as the alchemy challenge was actually quite hard.

The seventh floor was next, but this one was at least different… in a bad way. It was a fucking water level with mer-mushroom men, which looked exactly as abominable as one can imagine. This floor was by far the hardest, and everyone hated it, even those who didn’t carry the justified hatred of mushrooms Draskil and Jake did.

Irin complained because her magic felt weaker and her wings were getting soggy, Reika because she hated how her ice magic sucked in water, Bastilla because she had fur and wasn’t made for swimming, and Jake because he was a sane human being who knew water levels sucked.

Draskil, though… Draskil didn’t really hate the water. No, he was more just uncomfortable. Jake wondered why, but it got worse as time passed, and after about half an hour, Jake finally realized… he was terrified. Jake felt legitimate fear from the mighty dragonkin as he swam in the underground cavern full of water. There had to be a story there, but Jake didn’t want to pry. There was a time and a place for everything, and an underground cavern where the likely-stronger-than-him dragonkin was already on edge was definitely not that time and place.

They still passed the dungeon, but it took a grueling two days and three hours. The poison they had to craft was also just a goddamn nightmare to make. They had to make a bloody fire-affinity poison using only water- and earth-affinity mushrooms found in the water. This was all while getting chased by horrifying mushroom men with squiggly tails and octopus-like tentacle arms trying to kill them.

Passing the gate to the eighth floor, they all took a small breather in the passageway. They dried off and decided to make camp for the first time there to recover. They had just been running on potions and not really expending any resources due to how easy it had been on all the prior floors, but the seventh water level had been hell.

Irin took out a massive party tent of sorts that barely fit in the rather large passageway and pulled out furniture to allow them to sit down and relax.

"I fucking hate water levels," Jake muttered as he sat on a couch in the large tent.

He got a few approving nods as Irin inquisitively asked, "Oh, you got a term for these kinds of challenges?"

"Yeah, that term is called shitty design. At least I tend to view them as proof the creator of the game ran out of good ideas and just decided to make something shitty to pad the time. I guess the creator of this dungeon wanted to spice things up and added a water level, but ended up just making this dungeon go from a mushroom-filled hellhole to a soggy and wet mushroom-filled hellhole.” Jake said it all half-jokingly. Not even half-jokingly… maybe quarter-jokingly.

Irin stared for a moment before regaining her composure and smiling. "I am sure the previous floor was well-thought-out. Knowing how to adapt to a new environment is an important trait that the dungeon creator wanted to teach us."

"Sure. Doesn’t mean it didn’t suck," Jake countered, getting a reluctant nod in return.

"I will need to go meditate for a while," Reika added in with a sigh after their useless quipping about water levels. "Just wake me up once everyone is ready. I should be able to manage either way."

"Same… for the meditation part, not the manage-either-way part," Bastilla also said, a bit downtrodden.

Irin nodded. "I shall rest too. Please do not hesitate to wake me."

Jake nodded at them before finally turning his attention to Draskil, who had taken a seat on the ground, just staring out into space. He had been largely mute for a long while. In fact, he had barely spoken during the floor at all and only now seemed to relax, making Jake decide this was the time and place.

Putting up a quick barrier so only the two of them could hear, he asked the dragonkin, "You okay, mate?"

The dragonkin looked at him instantly, his eyes filled with bloodlust. "What?"

Jake didn’t feel intimidated as he shook his head. "If you want to talk, just talk. If you don’t… then don’t. Just wanted to let you know that if you want to, we are both here, and I am at least decent at listening."

Draskil didn’t say anything, instead turning his gaze away and staring into the wall of the tent. About a minute passed before he spoke, "Water brings death.”

Jake soon learned an excellent reason for aquaphobia.

Chapter 3

Heroes of the Ninth Floor

"Underground… water is not like up above," Draskil began, speaking far more than usual. "We sought long and far for it. Digging. We needed water to live… but the water was also a bringer of death. The skilled ones tried to be careful, but they failed. Sometimes. If they made a mistake…"

Draskil stared into the air again as he sighed and spoke in a serious tone, "They fucked up. Made a hole into a large reservoir of groundwater, flooding everything. It spread through our caverns and into our homes. So many drowned… I was the only one left. Family dead. Alone. Stuck for days with the water rising… Had to swim."

Jake saw the now so-powerful dragonkin shiver as he stopped talking. He had known that Draskil had been a mole-type creature before the system and what Villy had described as half-human-like. Something with intellect between that of a human and a chimpanzee. Smarter than any normal animal, for sure, and smart enough to form societies and have full sapience.

"Happened often… but we needed to dig. Water fine, but being in it is not." Draskil finally shook his head as he stared down. A few more moments passed before he looked at Jake. "Fear makes me weak?"

"Being afraid of something and being weak have nothing to do with one another," Jake said with a shrug. "What matters is what you do when afraid. You swam alongside us, you fought, you killed. Even if you were afraid, you didn’t show weakness. So no, that doesn’t make you weak, but quite the opposite."

Draskil was clearly skeptical as he sneered, "I was weaker because of fear."

Does he want me to scold him or what? Jake asked himself, but he still didn’t fully agree.

"We were all weaker. You have already shown that even in the face of fear, you don’t back down, and even if you are afraid of it now, you can overcome that fear." Jake was trying to be convincing, hoping for Draskil to accept the answer and feel relieved, but it didn’t go that way.

"What do you fear?" Draskil instead asked.

Jake opened his mouth and was about to answer… but stopped. What was he afraid of? If he was thinking back… he’d felt a bit scared of Oras when he saw him in the void? No, that wasn’t really him being scared, but more an instinctual fear. But there was…

His silence seemed to annoy Draskil. "Don’t know?"

Jake took a moment longer before shaking his head. "I don’t. Not really."

That was… a lie. Jake just didn’t want to say it, as he realized he did have one fear. It was a weird thought, but Jake was legitimately scared of one thing: losing control. Not in the sense of momentarily being unable to do something or being forced into doing things, but truly losing control of himself. He remembered one time that had truly scared him.

It was the time he thought Miranda had tried to take over his Pylon. The anger and bloodlust he had felt at that moment. Those emotions that now felt so foreign. He had not been in control then, but acted on pure impulse and emotion. Jake feared those kinds of emotions. And there was one other recent time where that had happened.

During his meeting with Ell’Hakan within the Seat of the Exalted Prima, Jake had lost his wits and trusted someone for no goddamn reason. He had been furious afterward but knew deep down it was due to fear. He was afraid of the kind of power that could make him lose—even just momentarily—control of his own emotions… because he knew that even without any outside sources interfering, his own emotions were scary.

It was honestly a stupid fear. Fearing your own strong emotions. Or maybe it was a normal fear that many people had. Perhaps it wasn’t truly the emotions themselves he feared either, but what he would do while feeling those emotions.

"Or you do… and don’t want to share," Draskil said, accurately reading Jake. For some reason, this seemed to make the dragonkin feel better, as he regained his old toothy smile. "All things to overcome."

Jake wryly smiled as he nodded, not sure if his fear was something one could truly overcome. Especially not with his Bloodline. Perhaps it was closer to something you just came to accept and live with. Something to manage.

The two of them didn’t speak much more, instead relaxing and meditating. Hours passed as they all got back into optimal condition, just needing a potion or two to top themselves up. The break was ultimately more to replenish mental energy than anything else, giving them a mental reset before the eighth floor.

Entering the eighth floor, it instantly became clear this was more of the same as those before the seventh, making Jake think that his theory of the water level being a failed attempt to diversify was correct. The only real difference on the eighth floor was how everything had just gotten massive in scale. Even the mushroom men had changed.

[Mushroom Man Giant Warrior - 183]

It towered more than fifteen meters into the air but otherwise looked the same. They all felt like they were miniatures of themselves. It was a pretty fun and novel experience.

Not that it had any effect on the outcome. Draskil still tore the big bastards apart with ease, and Jake blew them up with Arcane Powershots as he killed in droves together with the Malefic Dragonkin. Reika and Irin also joined in, but Bastilla could well and truly no longer participate meaningfully in combat. Reika barely could, but at least her ice magic helped slow down foes for Irin to sometimes finish them off. The problem was that Irin didn’t really have many offensive skills or abilities.

Her race offered her skills mainly related to subterfuge and illusion magic, as well as other things one would expect of a succubus. Skills that were obviously not usable inside the dungeon, unless Irin wanted to get really freaky with a giant mushroom. And that was a mental image Jake really didn’t need.

Making their way through the cavern, they soon reached the next gate and saw the challenge to pass the eighth floor. Once they read it, Jake nearly wanted to laugh.

Create a Hemotoxin, Necrotic Poison, or neurotoxin of at least uncommon rarity from the materials found on this floor and place it in the cauldron. In order to open the lid of the cauldron, at least eight hundred mushroom men must be slain.

Progress: Mushroom men killed: 78/800. Poison placed in the cauldron: 0/1.

"Quite a spike in difficulty," Irin said after reading it. And she was technically correct. While the seventh floor had also required them to make an uncommon-rarity poison, the materials provided had been far better, as there had even been a few rare-rarity mushrooms they could use. On this floor, based on their initial observations, the best one could get was of uncommon rarity, and mushrooms with any of the required properties would take a good while to find.

However…

"Well, this will be easy," Jake said, smirking as he pulled out two types of mushrooms he had already picked up earlier. "I will need more of these two mushrooms. Also, I need some of that red stalk you picked up earlier, Reika, and to get the cores of those big stabby-arm mushroom men."

They all looked at Jake, who just shrugged. "What? Not my fault the dungeon decided to suddenly get easy. I wanted to gather all this stuff to eat anyway, as I am always looking to improve my Hemotoxins and Necrotic Poison."

Draskil nodded in approval, showing himself a true man of culture. "Good poisons."

With those words, he left to collect what Jake had asked for, and Reika handed him the stalks before going to find more. Jake ate some of the materials he had gathered to absorb some knowledge through Palate, then got to work while the rest of his group killed things. Occasionally they would return with materials as Jake slowly refined the process. He made a common-rarity Hemotoxin in the very first concoction, and less than four and a half hours after entering the eighth floor, he got it.

Jake grinned as Draskil returned with some more materials, only to see Jake toss the poison bottle towards the cauldron. It landed on the lid with a clank as Jake shook his head in an overly dramatic way.

"Man, you guys are sooo slow," Jake failed to hold himself back from saying. He looked at the cauldron, feeling very good about himself.

Progress: Mushroom men killed: 771/800. Poison placed in the cauldron: 0/1.

"Only because we bring you stuff," Draskil scoffed.

"What’s that? Us doing our assigned jobs, with me excelling?" Jake kept laughing as he got up.

Draskil looked slightly annoyed but didn’t complain more. In fact, he looked happy even with all his grumbling, as the floor had gone far faster than expected.

Jake joined the dragonkin as they headed out and got killing. There were around a thousand giant mushroom men on the floor total, and they ended up slaying most while collecting materials. Even if they could have passed the floor within less than five hours, they ended up staying for ten or so more simply to take full advantage of the place. Each floor held mushrooms Jake had never seen or heard of before, just as the dungeon had been described, and it would be foolish not to eat as many as they could for Palate.

Bastilla and Irin were the only ones really working for the last sevenish hours, as Irin was making their food and even mixing some salads using the mushrooms. Bastilla frankly had too many corpses to dismantle and ended up only bothering with those who had Lifecores within. If they had to wait for her to dismantle nearly a thousand corpses—well, realistically nine hundred, as Draskil had taken his frustrations from the water level out on a few—they would have been there for well over a day. Probably longer. This time also allowed Draskil to get back in top condition, as he had expended quite a bit of energy. There had been a lot of them, after all.

"One floor left," Irin said, smiling. They had ended their break and now stood before the passageway to the ninth floor.

"And that C-grade optional boss floor," Jake added.

"Technically, every floor after the fourth is optional," Reika correctly said.

"I feel like I should be paying to be here," Bastilla said self-deprecatingly.

Draskil just grunted as they opened the gate and went through the passageway. Jake dearly hoped the designer hadn’t decided to make the ninth floor a water level, and was relieved when he saw it was just more mushrooms without the water. It was a bit of a mix between the giant stuff on the eighth floor and all the prior mushroom floors with regular-sized foes. Regular-sized being the three-meter-tall mushroom men.

One thing that was different was the sheer number of foes. Just standing at the entrance to the floor, Jake saw thousands of them. Mushroom Man Healers, Mushroom Man Warriors, Mushroom Man Defenders, and Mushroom Man Mages. All kinds of mushroom men. And in the middle of them, standing on a large mushroom, was the boss of the ninth floor.

[Mushroom Man General – lvl 199]

With the General were naturally its commanders, which were just copy-pasted versions of the boss on the fourth floor with a few more levels on top. Four of them.

[Mushroom Man Commander – lvl 195]

"The level of enemy diversity in this dungeon is just utter shit-tier," Jake said, stating facts. Recycling older bosses as semi-regular enemies. Really?

"I must admit, it does seem rather uninspired," Reika agreed.

"I am sure there is a reason it is like this," Irin said, trying to defend the dungeon designer again even if she had to know, deep in her heart, that the dungeon designer had kind of sucked.

"Anyway, let’s get to the gate on the other side and figure out what the objective is this time around," Jake said.

They all agreed and followed, avoiding the central part of the floor to not engage the boss. Not because they thought it was a threat, but because they wanted to avoid killing the boss only to figure out they needed to do something special to reach the next floor.

Only a few mushroom men were killed on the way to the cauldron placed in front of the gate. Another set of instructions was naturally also there, and this time there really was a spike in difficulty.

Create a poison using the Lifecore of the Mushroom Man General and from the materials found on this floor, and then place it in the cauldron. This poison must be at least of uncommon rarity and must primarily contain life-affinity energy. In order to open the lid of the cauldron, at least two thousand mushroom men must be slain.

Progress: Mushroom men killed: 41/2000. Poison placed in the cauldron: 0/1.

"Only one real attempt… a complex affinity to have while still making it a poison…" Jake muttered as he read it.

"Uncommon rarity, too," Reika added with some worry. "We will need to make the life-affinity energy highly volatile—that is for sure. If not, it won’t be recognized as a poison."

"The problem is that the General’s core will likely lean far more towards a very stable and controlled life affinity, considering its Records as a general," Jake pointed out. "We will also need some cores from healers, but that energy is obviously of the healing kind."

It would’ve been fine if Jake were able to add some of his own materials, but he couldn’t. The only thing he seemed allowed to add was his blood, as it was semi-qualified as dungeon material due to parts of it stemming from the dungeon, courtesy of eating a lot of mushrooms.

"Before we decide anything, we need to get a proper understanding of what we have available," Reika said, shaking her head.

"You can do it?" Draskil asked.

"Well, I think so, yeah, but I need to have the core of the General first," Jake said. "Also, the cores of the commanders are likely just lesser versions of the General’s, so we can use them for practice crafts."

"So, the first objective is to collect what this floor has available to get a scope of what we need?" Irin asked clarifyingly.

"And eat a mountain of mushrooms to figure out which ones are best," Jake sighed.

"We go?" Draskil asked.

Jake summoned his wings and looked at Reika and Irin. "You two take the perimeter and hunt the stragglers?"

The two of them nodded as Bastilla added, "Then I will stand and cheerlead uselessly on the side, waiting for them to kill stuff I can dismantle."

He gave her a pity thumbs-up as he and Draskil got to work. Jake and the dragonkin took to the air and flew towards the army of mushroom men. Every floor had grown in size as they progressed, and this one was no different. The large Mushroom Man General sat upon its mushroom uncaringly, unaware of the two monsters on their way to slaughter it.

Nay. Not monsters. Monsters did not act to set the world right by killing abominable existences that should have never existed. These were truly evil beings that deserved only death to make up for the sin of being alive. There was another name for those like Jake and Draskil, who selflessly became arbiters of justice:

Heroes.

Chapter 4

Mushroom Massacre & Friend Visit

It was war. On one side was a general with his four commanders and an army of soldiers willing to fight and die for their leaders. An organized group that worked together and used synergy to become more than what they were individually. There were thousands of them, every single one towards the end of D-grade.

On the other side were two people. A hunter with a bow and a dragonkin who seemed to finally have found an opportunity to let loose. These two were naturally the heroes of this fight. The brave men who would stand against the evil mushrooms.

It was also a display of something else… the disparity of power, even in the same grade and level bracket. Jake was at a lower level than most of his opponents, and Draskil was still lower than a few of them. One would think their numbers would matter, that their synergy would allow them to fight. It didn’t.

Maybe if they’d had actual tactics and not just sometimes tried to take hits for one another, it would’ve mattered. Maybe if they’d had ritual magic or complex formations. Had healers working together to form large barriers. However, as it was, they had none of these things, which made what transpired next only describable by one word:

Massacre.

Two words?

Justified massacre.

Explosions of arcane power lit up the cavern as Jake bombarded his opponents. A dense mist of poison hung thick in the air as Draskil and Jake both pumped it out of their wings. Jake killed primarily using explosive arrows that tore mushroom men apart with ease and followed up with occasional kill shots with stable arrows, while Draskil had a far simpler style.

He was more the rip-and-tear sort of fighter. His entire body was a weapon that none of their opponents could even scratch. His scales offered defenses to nearly all magic, his attacks unstoppable to the mushrooms as he tore their limbs off and ripped up their flesh, leaving rotting wounds behind.

Draskil also showed fighting methods Jake could never even attempt. His tail was like a fifth limb that whipped around and sometimes even impaled his foes. If not, he used it for movement, yanking himself back or pushing himself, even using while he was mid-air as a counterweight to allow him to rapidly reposition.

The dragonkin did not show any magic besides some to strengthen himself. Jake did notice how he also had the Pride skill like Jake, but his version was clearly far more focused on the mental attack aspect and making a domain of intimidation without any of the mana-control amplifying aspects.

Jake was actually pretty certain Draskil had all the of the Malefic Viper skills. He had believed it for a good while, but after the dungeon, it was more obvious. He clearly had Palate, based on all he ate, and Sagacity to properly store the knowledge. Jake did think Sagacity was still at a relatively low rarity, and Draskil did say that he had some bad skills he was working on. Besides that, he clearly had the wings, claws, and scales skills. These were likely unavoidable racial skills for any Malefic Dragonkin.

Sense of the Malefic Viper was also obvious based on how well he found mushrooms. That just left Blood and Touch. Jake was most unsure about Touch, honestly. Draskil also had Blood, based on how he had used some of it as a weapon once, but Jake had yet to see the dragonkin use the familiar glow of Touch of the Malefic Viper. It was possible he had it and just never used it, but it was also possible he didn’t have it or had changed it to a form very different from what Jake used. Like a purely non-combat version or something.

Now, Jake could’ve just asked him, but where was the fun in that? He would rather just try and figure it out himself while slaughtering an army of mushroom men. The human and dragonkin had already killed hundreds before meeting up as Jake turned to Draskil.

"You want the big boss?" Jake asked. "Just remember we need all the Lifecores intact."

Draskil grunted in confirmation before asking, "We need the small ones?"

Jake shrugged. "Some, but not all."

Draskil then grinned. "You wanna see my breath?"

"I guess?" Jake asked. He wasn’t sure what Draskil meant initially, but he soon understood.

The dragonkin took a breath, and for a moment, Jake felt all the mana in the environment stop before getting dragged in like Draskil’s mouth was a vacuum. Intense mana gathered at a level far above anything Jake had ever seen in D-grade.

Then he released it. A green beam was emitted from his mouth that swept across the cavern below. It was only a few meters in diameter when it hit the ground and made a grand sweep from one end of the cavern to the other. Not a single mark was left on the ground where it hit… but everything between the dragonkin and the ground was gone.

A line had been made through the entire dungeon. For a few dozen kilometers, a rotting black line that emanated death and decay had been formed. Everything the breath had touched had decayed to nothingness in an instant. It did not matter if it was a plant or mushroom man over level 180—they had all just ceased to be.

Jake stared at the sight that was both impressive and unimpressive at the same time. It was not an impressive-looking attack. There was no grand explosion, no massive scar left by the breath… just an eerie nothingness. It had simply killed everything it hit, and even more scary was how Jake did not feel a single wisp of mana from where it had hit. It was just… desolation. Jake didn’t know for sure, but he had a feeling no mushroom would grow on that black line for a very long time.

All in all, the breath had killed only about ninety mushroom men that had been hit. Mind you, it didn’t matter where they were hit. As long as a single part of their body had touched the breath, their entire bodies had turned to black sludge in an instant.

One thing was also clear… If Draskil ever used that attack on Jake, he would have to dodge it using his precognition. The beam moved faster than any attack Jake could make, and if he didn’t move before it was released, he would have no way to evade. And if he didn’t dodge in time? Well, Jake was just happy he still had Moment of the Primal Hunter, because that would sure as hell activate.

"Impressive?" Draskil asked with a satisfied grin.

"Definitely wouldn’t wanna be hit by it," Jake agreed. "Ah, but don’t use it on essential foes… It didn’t leave even a single Lifecore behind. Or anything, really."

"Bah," Draskil said, jokingly dismissing his words. "I kill the General. No breath."

Jake motioned for him to go ahead as he instead targeted the commanders. He saw that Reika and Irin were doing fine on their own, too, killing a few here and there themselves. Compared to Jake and Draskil, they barely made a dent, but they were never meant to anyway. This dungeon was made for members of the Order, not just those who were supremely talented. Jake and Draskil were way above the expected power level of anyone expected to do the dungeon, even on the ninth floor, and only the C-grade could potentially offer them a good fight. Shit, this was a dungeon where the alchemy portion was the real challenge, so maybe it was silly for them to expect a good fight to begin with.

But before alchemy, it was always good to get some killing done. Always got Jake in the mood to do some concocting, ya know?

Meira was incredibly nervous as she waited. Master had given her permission, that was true, but she still felt unsure about actually doing it. In the end, she’d agreed to it after she and her friends had completed a lesson together and begun working on an assignment where some of her master’s books could be useful.

The Grand Elder had also made it clear he didn’t care if she invited people over and had told her that he would just not be there if she did. Meira was still perplexed why someone like the Grand Elder even bothered spending time on her, and it made her even more confused when she considered that her master had clearly been the one to make him accept such an arrangement.

She just tried to not think about it too much and instead did her best in everything. Her master clearly had plans, and Meira would do her best to follow his will and try and make them a success. If inviting her friends over was something he had explicitly given her permission to do, and if even the Grand Elder had voiced his lack of concern about doing this, perhaps it was just their way of telling Meira to do it? She wasn’t good at subtle hints and trying to interpret commands, but maybe it was possible he didn’t just allow her to bring people, but wanted her to?

That is why, when she was asked to bring some books, she then spoke up and said she had been allowed to bring them to the library. Meira felt proud of herself for that and was happy that the three of them had agreed to come. The only one a bit reluctant was Izil, but Nella and Utmal had both agreed that it was about time she invited them over. Maybe it was? Meira didn’t know… She had never invited friends over for anything before.

Or had friends at all, really.

About five minutes later, a gate opened, and out stepped Izil. The elf instantly saw Meira and smiled.

"Thank you for the invitation," she said courteously as she took out a small basket with flowers in it. "A token of my appreciation to you and the lord of the mansion. Native flowers of the Altmar Empire, all with their roots intact for potential planting."

Meira was surprised at seeing the gift, but she quickly understood. It wasn’t that odd to bring something for her master, considering he was far above the four of them in status as a black token. Ah, Meira had told them her master had a black token, as he had allowed her to do so.

"Thank you," Meira said, bowing as she accepted it. "I am sure my lord will appreciate it."

"Is he present?" Izil asked with a raised eyebrow.

"Sadly not. My lord had other engagements." Meira would not have dared to invite them if her master was there… She barely dared to when he was not.

Izil just nodded and followed Meira as they entered the mansion to place the basket of flowers. Just as they entered the house, and after she had stored the basket properly, Meira saw that the gate outside activated again, with Nella and Utmal stepping through.

Meira hurriedly ran outside to greet them and got a disapproving look from Nella as she approached. "I hope you treat your owner better than guests," she scoffed once Meira got close. "Or maybe you just consider it acceptable to not greet guests?"

"I apologize!" Meira said with a bow. She really didn’t want to be a bad host, especially not if it would reflect badly on her master.

"She was just inviting me inside," Izil said as she walked out of the mansion, glaring daggers at Nella. "And if you two had been here on the agreed-upon time, there would be no issue."

"Relax, I was just joking around," Nella said dismissively, Meira now feeling even more awkward as she had apologized. She still wasn’t good at jokes or that sarcasm thing… or was it called irony? She really didn’t quite know the difference.

"Nice place your master’s got," Utmal then spoke, throwing Meira out of her thoughts. "You didn’t lie about him being a black token, it seems. Where is he?"

"He is busy elsewhere," Meira once more explained apologetically.

"Oh? That is unfortunate," Nella said with a smile. "I would have loved to meet him. Now, if he is not here, let’s just get going. Where is the library?"

"Right this way," Meira said, motioning towards the large mansion. The three of them followed. Meira wanted to keep the mood good, but Izil and Nella had been less and less friendly recently, and Meira really hoped they could get along better.

As they walked through the mansion, Izil asked, "Are there no other servants or occupants?"

"There is—" Meira began, but she quickly cut herself off. The Grand Elder had been staying there most of the time, but he wasn’t there now and wasn’t truly living there. Also, she shouldn’t share he was there at all. "There is currently only me here. My lord doesn’t have any other servants or slaves residing within the Order of the Malefic Viper, as far as I am aware."

Meira saw Utmal and Nella both frown a bit as Izil just nodded. "I see."

Then, suddenly, Meira felt a mental probing from Izil. She was confused and accepted it as a telepathic connection was formed. "Meira… I didn’t want to ask before, but are you a slave of the owner of this mansion?"

Now Meira was even more confused. "Yes?" she answered instantly, using the connection. Didn’t they already know that by now?

Izil frowned even more than before. "If possible, can I meet the owner of your contract?"

"I can maybe ask…" Meira answered, more than a little unsure. She didn’t want to bother her master needlessly with matters that were clearly her own to deal with.

"That is all I can ask," Izil responded as she smiled again. Just as they entered the library, she spoke out loud, "What an incredible library. Could you point me towards the tomes you spoke of?"

Meira responded positively, but she was still not sure what Izil had actually wanted… but what she did know was that Utmal and Nella were both looking at her quite a bit differently than before. It should be fine, though. They were friends, right?

A great wrong had been set right. The abominable mushrooms were now dead, slain by the two heroes as their bounty had been harvested. Jake and Draskil had disengaged after a good period of fighting to collect materials from the areas they had cleared of mushroom men and then taken a small break.

By now, Jake was sitting at the exit of the ninth floor together with Reika, trying to figure out a solution. Both of them had their crafting equipment out, Jake using his cauldron and Reika having a far more advanced setup with several flasks, bottles, filters, and whatnot… still surrounding a cauldron, though.

It had been over two days since they entered the floor, and Jake and Reika had been busy as hell. Jake was eating and experimenting at all times with the different materials on the floor, but making the required poison wasn’t as straightforward as one could hope.

Draskil was off hunting alone again, and the alchemists worked while Bastilla dismantled corpses, having Irin protect her.

During this time, Jake decided to experimentally enter Serene Soul Meditation to check in on a certain someone.

"Could you do me a favor and spend less time sitting hunched over a cauldron and more time watching that dragonkin fight?" sim-Jake asked the moment Jake popped into his Soulspace.

"What?" Jake asked, confused as he oriented himself. He saw that sim-Jake had resealed the Eternal Hunger chimera using some kind of shadow barrier, standing impatiently and waiting for Jake to enter.

"I just want you to reflect on what you gave up on," sim-Jake said, shrugging. "I would have one hundred percent chosen to become a Malefic Dragonkin. And no, giving up on alchemy would not be a loss."

"Oh, are you getting jealous you can’t be a scaly boy? I thought you wanted to learn from his fighting style or something." Jake smirked.

"Heh," sim-Jake scoffed. "Not much to learn there. His style is simple and effective but far below what I am aiming for."

"But you are jealous of the claws," Jake still pointed out.

"Fuck yeah, you bet I am! Those things are insane.” Sim-Jake grinned. "Now I will excuse myself and allow you to do your alchemy… but just one quick question. If you want the life-affinity energy to be more volatile, isn’t it enough to just mix in a bit of our arcane affinity? Just the destructive aspect. If not the affinity, then at least the concept you know?"

Jake shook his head. "Thank you for pointing out your utter lack of knowledge when it comes to alchemy. Won’t work. We need it volatile but still with a direction to cause harm using the life-affinity energy. Life affinity does not deal damage by destroying… It is more like it grows stuff wrong."

Sim-Jake nodded. "Yeah, I have no idea what the fuck I am talking about. I am gonna play some more with the chimera. Now that thing is a good example of a bundle of energy turned very antagonistic and full of life, even when getting smacked around!"

"See you arou—" Jake stopped, having gotten an idea. An idea he had not even considered before now, and it was an incredibly novel one.

Curses were all about emotions… powerful emotions… so what if they could add some of that to the mix? Make a curse poison? One making use of an emotion Jake had plenty of:

Hatred for mushrooms.

Chapter 5

United in Hatred

Jake didn’t really know all that much about curses. But he did know a bit. He’d had the Root of Eternal Resentment in his Palate for a long-ass time, and it had housed a shitload of curse energy. Now, as for infusing that concept into a poison? Well, that was something entirely different.

He shared his idea with Reika and got a very skeptical response initially. She did point out some rather glaring issues. Curses tended to be born from strong emotions, yes, but they were also extremely hard to control, as they were essentially emotions so strong they had tangible effects on the world. To contain a curse within a poison should not be easy, especially while avoiding it overpowering the life-affinity aspect of the finished product. So that would be a bit of a challenge, but at least he was a bit better at another aspect of the task.

Jake had some experience with something that was kind of a life-affinity poison. Well, one real experience—all the way back in the Challenge Dungeon where he had created his Unstable Amalgamation of Malefic Vitau. He now knew in retrospect that it was pretty much just a Vitality-increasing elixir on crack and made unstable as fuck, but he also knew that this wasn’t possible to do with the materials he currently had available.

Firstly, the amalgamation had not been made from life-affinity energy but more a vital affinity. They were closely related but not exactly the same, and changing it into a Vitality-increasing energy type would likely result in it no longer counting as truly life-affinity.

Secondly, the only reason it had worked back then was due to Malefic Viper’s Poison triggering and upgrading the poison to above what it would usually be. It had been a direct impartment of Records by the Viper himself and not something Jake could replicate even if he wanted to.

Jake thus spent a good while considering how to make it, and Reika also came with plenty of input. One thing quickly became clear: if he wanted to use his curse energy, they would have to find a way to infuse it without overpowering and dominating any other part of the concoction. Transmutation was quickly ruled out, as its transformative effect likely wouldn’t work well with the curse energy.

There was the possibility of infusing a catalyst, but there tended to be rather stringent requirements before one could infuse an object with curse energy. One requirement tended to be time and connection to the curse. Infusing a mushroom with a curse related to hating mushrooms sounded like a good way to just make it implode. The same was true for doing it to a Lifecore.

Yet this did not deter Jake or Reika as they began working on another way: ritualism. And for this, Jake had a skill that he hadn’t really used much but would no doubt prove useful.

[Soul Ritualism of the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist (Ancient)] – As a master of your own path, the power of your Soulspace and authority of self is unquestionable. Grants knowledge of, and allows the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist to perform rituals pertaining to, the soul. Soul Rituals must be performed both within the Soulspace and the real world. As a forger of your own path, Records infused during any soul ritual will hold more weight. Effects of the ritual are based on the nature of the ritual performed as well as the materials used during the ritual. All rituals will scale with Willpower in addition to other stat bonuses applied according to the nature of the ritual performed.

While this skill primarily revolved around souls, it also gave some general knowledge about rituals. Curses were also deeply related to the soul anyway, as they were born from it. Most curses came into being when someone died, as they were the remnant emotions in one of the layers of the soul that managed to collect and take a form with intent. Most often, it was due to a lot of people dying with similar grievances and thus empowering each other. However, the part of the soul that would turn into a curse upon death could also be focused on and extracted to forcefully make a curse. An oversimplification, sure, but this was effectively it.

This is what Casper did. He focused, extracted, and infused his own emotions into vessels that he then used as weapons. That he could also mix it with mana was the kind of technique that Jake was still very unsure about. Anyway, none of this was that important, as Jake didn’t plan on making a truly cursed item but just a poison with a bit of curse energy mixed in to give it direction.

It didn’t take him long to figure out how he wanted to infuse the energy. He was limited to materials from the dungeon, but as he’d discovered earlier, he could also use his blood. He could naturally also use his own mana and energy, as that was just a part of the crafting process, and one could argue Jake was technically part of the dungeon since he was within it, so his plan should work.

With enough focus and a ritual to further amplify the effects, Jake believed he could essentially make his blood into a cursed liquid that would mix with an otherwise non-damaging life-affinity item. Life affinity was by itself not damaging unless made volatile or, as Jake hoped to do, self-destructive.

Because yes… when Jake considered earlier how infusing a curse would just make the life-affinity item self-implode, Jake saw that as an opportunity.

What he wanted to do was to make the life affinity latch onto the vital energy of the mushroom man, making it self-implode in self-hatred upon entering the body out of pure disgust, turning it into poison. Would this work? Maybe. Was Jake going to try, hoping to see a mushroom man consume itself and effectively commit suicide? Fuck yeah, he was.

Reika was supportive of his idea, and the two of them began experimenting in this direction. He had decided to begin by just making a highly dense life-affinity liquid using the mushroom juices of slain foes and further infusing that with Lifecores. He also had to remind himself that the final concoction would require the Lifecore of the General, which actually worked out perfectly with his plans. He wanted it to be a controlled self-implosion, after all.

It was one of the most ambitious things Jake had ever done, but he felt confident, and he really wanted to do it.

Hours passed as iteration after iteration was made. Soon they settled on a stable version of highly focused life energy in the form of a flask. Reika was the one who crafted it using her skills and managed to create several common-rarity flasks for Jake to experiment with. She added that when it came to the real thing, she should be able to make an uncommon flask using the best materials they had.

Jake, on the other hand, focused entirely on the poison aspect of the creation. He planned on making a ritual where he would infuse his own blood into the Lifecore using a ritual. However, as he attempted to do this several times, he repeatedly failed to actually create a curse. He didn’t understand why, so he kept trying until a realization struck him. One he never thought possible.

My hatred isn’t strong enough…

How it was even possible, Jake didn’t know. He did hate mushrooms; of that, there was no doubt. But… he had to admit his hatred was not as strong as the level he had seen from others. It wasn’t like mushrooms had killed his family, cut off his Path, or removed his freedom. They had just made Jake mad and annoyed, and there was that one time where it had tied him to a toilet for far too long.

Casper had an extreme natural affinity to curses and had initially channeled his anger toward those who killed his now-ghost-girlfriend Lyra. That was some real anger, and Jake knew that while Casper was a very introverted person, he was also the sort of person go to all in when he felt something.

Jake could not claim his hatred of mushrooms was at that level. Feeling a bit distressed at the thought of failing, Jake remembered: he was not alone in his hatred.

"I need Draskil," Jake spoke. "I need his hate."

Reika raised an eyebrow. "Wouldn’t it be best if we all joined in and contributed to the ritual?"

"On a scale of one to ten, how much do you hate mushrooms?" Jake asked.

"Well, I guess it depends on the type of—"

"Already disqualified by not instantly saying eleven," Jake said, shooting her down.

"Now you are just being unreasonable," Reika argued with a sigh. "It is utterly illogical to hold such a level of hatred towards fungi."

"Hate is illogical by nature. And it is in my nature to hate mushrooms. Always has been. From the time I was a kid, and my mom tried to make me eat those shitty white button mushrooms or whatever the fuck they are called, I have despised them. They bring nothing good to the world, and their only use is when they are destroyed and their juices are squeezed out to kill things. Because even in death, mushrooms bring only suffering.” As Jake spoke, he got a bit flared up and felt like he was already a step closer to successfully creating the curse.

"Okay…" Reika said, shaking her head as she went off to contact Draskil while Jake made modifications to the ritual.

He needed to bring Draskil into the fold and not just make his hate part of the curse. Curses were naturally inclined to combine similar negative emotions, so it wasn’t a difficult adaptation.

A few minutes later, Draskil appeared together with Reika.

Jake looked at him and asked, "On a scale of one to ten, how much do you hate mushrooms?"

"Not worth giving number, not deserving of the thought energy to consider," Draskil sneered.

Jake looked at Reika, who reluctantly resigned herself and went back to making a flask good enough to use in the final concoction, or at least in one of their four available test concoctions using the Lifecores of Mushroom Man Commanders.

"Draskil, our plan is to—"

"I don’t care," Draskil said, cutting him off.

"Fair.” Shortening his speech down to only what the dragonkin needed to do, he explained, “I need you to pour all your hate into your Blood of the Malefic Viper, put it in my cauldron, and then join me in my hatred of mushrooms for the ritual.”

"Make curse?" Draskil asked, clearly a little interested even if he said he wasn’t. Jake understood. It was about hating mushrooms, after all.

"Yep." Jake nodded.

Draskil nodded back, fully understanding without needing any more explanation. Jake began the ritual without further ado, mixing his blood with Draskil’s along with the Lifecore of a dead mushroom man—and by now, Jake was beginning to realize that he was pretty much doing a blood ritual with what was effectively the heart of a monster.

It was a bit morbid… but nothing was off the table when it came to slaying mushrooms.

Jake instantly felt the difference, as he realized that Draskil’s hatred for mushrooms seemed to rival or even surpass his own. That, and Jake also ran into the issue of Draskil’s blood being far more potent than Jake’s. And it wasn’t just due to the level disparity—clearly, Draskil had Blood of the Malefic Viper at a higher rarity than himself.

It was a challenge to overcome, but one Jake gladly took on. Draskil was incredibly patient, far more than Jake would have expected, and assisted Jake with rituals throughout the next two days as he improved more and more. At the end of the second day of making rituals with Draskil, he made a Lifecore.

[Cursed Mushroom Man Mage Lifecore (Common)] – The cursed core of a Mushroom Man Mage. This Lifecore contains a large amount of life-affinity energy that has now been contaminated with a curse of immense hatred towards its own kind. The core is slowly degrading due to its inherent nature caused by the curse, making it seek to consume and destroy itself.

It wasn’t much, but it was honest work. Sure, it would self-detonate within an hour or two, as far as Jake could tell, but it was good enough. They didn’t even need the finished concoction to last very long—just long enough to pass the floor.

Draskil also seemed pretty happy with the finished creation and decided to stay and help. During the last two days, he’d gone off once in a while to hunt some more mushroom men, but he always returned quickly and got really engrossed in the process.

Only about a day and a half later, Jake got frisky and tried to use one of the Commander Lifecores. The first attempt failed, but feeling that he was close, he tried again, only to succeed the second time around.

[Cursed Mushroom Man Commander Lifecore (Uncommon)] – The cursed core of a Mushroom Man Commander. This Lifecore contains an immense amount of life-affinity energy that has now been contaminated with a curse of immense hatred towards its own kind. The core is slowly degrading due to its inherent nature caused by the curse, making it seek to consume and destroy itself.

With that, he and Reika began the final part of the process: fusing the Lifecore and flask. One would think this would be hard, but it was actually incredibly straightforward. Jake just had to place the Lifecore in the liquid of the flask and slowly diffuse it into the concoction while controlling the process.

He did also have to keep infusing some of the curse energy during the entire thing, needing Draskil present at all times. About a day after the first Commander Lifecore was made, they also made their first uncommon-rarity concoction using it. If this had been the General’s, it would have been enough then and there… but Jake was pushing for more.

Refining the process more and more, it finally culminated nearly a full day later. Using a large ritual and with Reika and Draskil both assisting in the process, they gave birth to liquid justice.

[Desired Fate of the Mushroom Men (Rare)] – On the border between a flask and a poison cursed by intense hatred, a bane of the mushroom men has been created, as this very liquid desires nothing but their demise. Contains an intense amount of life-affinity energy that will act to help those who seek to slay mushroom men. If consumed while actively killing mushroom men, this concoction will temporarily increase health regeneration as the life affinity helps you on your quest. If injected or consumed by any mushroom man, the effect will be the opposite, turning natural regeneration into active degeneration and flooding the body with intense amounts of hostile life energy as long as the will of the curse remains or until the concoctions runs out of energy. The concoction is currently stable but, with time, may slowly begin degrading due to its inherent nature caused by the curse, making it seek to consume and destroy itself.

With great satisfaction, he looked at Draskil and Reika. Reika just seemed relieved and Draskil was happy upon seeing the completed product. Inspecting the item itself, Jake was more than satisfied. He was happy to see it was even somewhat stable, even if it did carry a warning that it was temporary.

Was this kind of poison actually useful in practice, one might ask? No… no, not really. It had taken far too much effort to create, it was unstable, and Jake could quickly see that one would have to infect the foe with pretty much a full bottle’s worth to get a proper effect, contrary to normal poisons where just a little would be highly effective. This was more the kind of poison you had to fool a mushroom man into drinking, which Jake had a hard time seeing.

This didn’t make Jake any less satisfied with what they had made, though. It was objective proof of his and Draskil’s hatred of mushrooms and a rare-rarity item.

Now for the moment of truth. Would the concoction they had made qualify as poison and allow them to pass the floor?

With much anticipation, Jake placed the concoction in the cauldron in front of the final gate as he stared intently at the progress bar on the wall beside it.

Progress: Mushroom men killed: 2000/2000. Poison placed in the cauldron: 1/1.

After the obligatory round of high-fives and waves of relief, their entire group took a well-deserved rest.

Well, besides Bastilla, who kept dismantling, and Irin, who kept making food for Draskil and Jake. But before eating, Jake decided it was high time to get a bit of meditation done and check something he had neglected over the last few days: his notifications.

Chapter 6

Reflecting On Stats & Supreme Final Boss

Jake sat down and relaxed while recuperating before moving on to the final optional boss. He felt pretty damn good about himself and, while he was sitting there, reflected on the progress he had made recently. Level-wise, he had gained one level in his profession during the period of nearly a month before they entered the dungeon, but after entering, Jake had now already gained four whole levels… which was actually an insane speed.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 171 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 174 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

What made it all even more insane was that Jake had not only been doing alchemy but also fighting. Though, to be fair, the fighting hadn’t been difficult. Even so, it had netted him two levels.

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 170 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 171 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

The combination of easy fights and the monotonous type of enemies made every foe barely give any experience, but he had killed enough to still get some levels. It did help that Jake usually had to actually go looking and find enemies, while in the dungeon, there were ten mushroom men around every corner.

With these levels also came a few race levels.

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 170 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 171 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 172 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Now… finally, with levels came Free Points. Jake wanted to just throw it all in Perception—he really did—but a voice at the back of his head that totally wasn’t sim-Jake screaming within his Soulspace made him reconsider.

With great reluctance, Jake did something that disgusted him: He invested 280 Free Points into Strength. Instantly, he felt a hot glow go through his body as his muscles seemed to almost bulge for a moment before settling down. He had exited meditation at this point and now sat opening and closing his fist.

His total Strength had increased by more than ten percent just by investing those points. It was an actual tangible difference, but Jake also knew that a ten percent increase in Strength did not mean he now hit ten percent harder. The system and reality just didn’t work like that, and the only time where Strength was the only real factor was when in a tug of war or when trying to push someone.

Not that it wasn’t massively helpful to him, especially his melee skills. Sim-Jake had made it clear Jake needed more Strength, but also that Agility was still by far the most important stat. Something like a sixty-forty split was best, according to him. Jake chose to trust his other self in that department.

Looking over his stats as a whole, they were relatively balanced, and he was beginning to get close to the optimal Strength-Agility split.

Stats

Strength: 4146

Agility: 6761

Endurance: 3626

Vitality: 4828

Toughness: 3521

Wisdom: 6207

Intelligence: 5067

Perception: 10720

Willpower: 5252

Free Points: 0

Toughness and Endurance were both really falling behind, but Jake wasn’t that worried, as both stats were still considered high for his level.

The highest amount of stat points one could possibly gain per D-grade level—counting race, profession, and class—was around 250 total. 100 from class, 70 from race, and 80 from profession. This was all, of course, only in the case of a human. In reality, it would always be lower, and even in the top tier, one was considered close to the apex at 220 stat points per D-grade level.

Below D-grade, it was a third for E-grade, so around 75 stat points total per level was the top, and then it was even lower at F-grade below that. All in all, if someone gained around 60 per level in the first hundred levels—or 6000 total stats at the point of evolution to D-grade—it would already be considered close to the theoretical maximum for pure stat gains while leveling.

Jake had had over 10,000 total stat points the day he’d evolved to D-grade—even without counting his equipment.

In reality, it wasn’t as simple as just a pure equation due to all the other factors like titles, equipment, and elixirs, especially not counting percentage bonuses, which Jake had plenty of. The "of the Malefic Viper" skills also added extra stat points, making it even more skewed.

Even then, if one stayed with the simplified math, then someone powerful at Jake’s level, 172, would end up with 6000 stat points for the first hundred levels and 220 for the next seventy-three, for a total of 22,000 stat points. Dividing that out in nine parts, then around 2500 in a single stat would be considered average. With Jake having a thousand more than that in even his lowest stat, it honestly wasn’t bad, especially considering this example was of someone with a powerful Path. Again, oversimplified, but it was still clear Jake was far above the expected durability of the average D-tier at his level, despite never investing much into Toughness.

Ah, on a final note, Jake also just realized that he had surpassed 50,000 total stat points counting everything. Having a nearly sixty percent overall stat increase amplifier really was nice. To summarize, Jake was just good in pretty much all aspects, and in Perception, he was in the realm of being a little bonkers with how much he had.

Abandoning any more thoughts about annoying math that Jake honestly couldn’t be bothered with, he returned to meditation. The dungeon group meditated and recuperated for the better part of a day before it was time to take on the final challenge.

"We passed this a bit faster than expected," Irin said. "I expected us to take at least a little longer, and our speed is especially impressive considering the potentially needless overcomplication of the ninth level."

"Hey, we passed it, and it allowed us to bond over shared hatred." Jake grinned at Draskil.

"I must also admit it was a very interesting method,” Reika added. “I would never have come up with using a curse. Instead, I think I would have mixed some of the death-affinity mushrooms into the concoction along with the life-affinity energy and then just had it be stabilized and dormant using the Lifecore. Using a catalyst or just having the balance between the energies be very reactive, we could then do so it was activated upon entering another living foe, making the life and death affinity clash. It should have counted as a rather effective poison. But I guess there are some pitfalls I missed since Jake rejected the idea."

"Nah, it would have totally worked—I just really wanted to go with my idea," Jake said, waving it off. "With my method, Draskil also got involved!"

Reika stared at Jake for a moment before just shaking her head in slight disbelief. "Honestly? I think I learned more from your method too, so screw it."

Draskil and Bastilla just stood silently in the background and didn’t seem to have anything to add, even if Jake could see Draskil had enjoyed Jake’s method. After Jake and Reika’s brief talk, Irin took the lead again.

"Anyway, time to tackle the final floor. Now, let me warn you, this is a full-fledged C-grade we are dealing with.” She put a hand on the gate, and a notification appeared before all of them once more.

You have successfully passed the ninth floor and gone above and beyond expectations!

Now only one more challenge remains. A single floor is sealed away at the bottom of the dungeon, only available to those who have proven themselves exceptional. But be warned, for the final floor houses an entity far deadlier than anything you have faced so far.

Do you wish to explore the final floor of the Indigo Caverns?

"I… should probably just leave," Bastilla finally said. "I will just get in the way, and from what you said earlier, the final floor is pretty much just a single fight. Not much I can help with there, and I am unsure if I can even use my dismantling skills on a C-grade."

"I concur, in that I doubt I would be of much use." Reika shook her head. "I couldn’t do anything to the General before, and a C-grade is bound to be a lot more powerful. I think it better I sit this one out."

Irin also ended up nodding. "While I am confident I can stay hidden if the foe is distracted, I must admit I also don’t see myself making any meaningful contributions. I am not a fighter, as you have probably noticed."

Jake exchanged a look with Draskil before he smiled lightly. "Well… I wouldn’t mind either way. If you want to come along to watch and maybe get some better rewards, I am all for it."

Draskil grunted in approval. While he wasn’t the most talkative, Jake had a feeling he could actually be a bit of a softie and had genuinely taken a liking to their three other party members.

"I can try to hide us using illusions," Irin wondered out loud, not even trying to be subtle that she wanted to enter the final floor with them. Reika also clearly wanted to go, and Bastilla fell to the peer pressure with a huge, animated sigh.

"Fiiine!” Bastilla moaned in resignation. “Let’s go and possibly die due because the two of them forget we exist and accidentally blow us up or something without even noticing.”

"Wouldn’t happen—my Perception is too high to not notice," Jake rightly defended himself.

"I am not even going to argue that," Bastilla said, sighing again. "Let’s just go, alright? I already feel like I am some young mistress getting escorted through this dungeon, so I may as well stay shameless and finish it."

With that, they all agreed to continue the dungeon and began going through the passageway. It was a bit longer than before, and while Bastilla did throw a second glance at the exit in the middle of the passage as they passed it, she stayed with the group.

Exiting the passageway, they came to yet another large floor… but this one was also very different from any prior. A blue hue dominated the entire place, and while it was filled with mushrooms, they weren’t the usual diverse kind. There were only glowing blue mushrooms spread throughout, and in the middle of the floor was an absolutely massive mushroom towering more than a kilometer into the air.

It gave off an intense sheen, and the cap was clearly illuminated as Jake saw something that looked like a throne on top of it. A small throne that barely registered as a small bulge on the mushroom cap. It looked like a throne for a child, which made sense when Jake saw what was sitting on it. It was a small mushroom man with a cap vaguely shaped like a crown.

You gotta be fucking kidding me.

[Mushroom Man King – lvl ???]

Defeat the supreme leader of the mushroom men: the Mushroom Man King.

Jake just stared in disbelief at the "final boss."

It was just a small mushroom man no more than a meter tall, holding a wooden scepter with a glowing mushroom growing out the tip. On a scale of one to ten, it was a solid zero when it came to representation and intimidation.

"I…" Irin muttered as she stood there. "An unexpected opponent for sure, and—"

"Irin," Jake interrupted, "just admit it already."

She looked reluctant but finally sighed. "Okay… okay, I admit, the design of this dungeon could be better, and maybe some questionable decisions were made during its creation."

"It’s shit," Draskil muttered.

Reika and Bastilla also didn’t hide their contempt. Jake decided to take charge and spoke, "Nevertheless, it is still a C-grade. With that in mind, we must go all out from the very beginning and utterly destroy this abomination. So stay back."

Draskil understood as he moved forward. Jake joined him by pulling out his bow and instantly beginning to make an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter in his quiver. Irin and the others stayed at the gate many kilometers away from the throne of the Mushroom Man King, setting up a barrier to make them invisible and hide their presence.

"It is a mage of some kind," Jake quickly said as he felt the mana from the mushroom man in the distance. "And this entire place is that little bastard’s domain."

"Hm," Draskil grunted. "Not strong."

"No." Jake shook his head. "No, it is not."

Draskil grinned as his wings unfolded and his body began burning with power. Jake responded in kind as Arcane Awakening activated, and they both took flight towards the Mushroom Man King, who only now became aware of their existence.

The entire cavern began humming with mana as the little mushroom got off his throne and lifted the scepter. Every single mushroom present seemed to resonate with the scepter, and even the large mushroom beneath the little king responded.

Bolts of mana condensed by the thousands as the king attacked. Scales covered Jake’s body as Draskil just flew unbothered towards the boss. Beneath the king, the flesh of the mushroom cap began changing and seemed to almost liquify and come alive as it moved to defend.

Jake had already stopped in mid-air and nocked an arrow to shoot. He avoided a few mana bolts before releasing it towards the Mushroom Man King, but he found his attack blocked by the tendrils of mushroom. However, even if he was blocked, he did his job: making an opening.

With the tendrils out of the way, Draskil disappeared and reappeared right in front of the Mushroom Man King. He swept his claw upwards and sent the little creature flying through the air with a few new claw marks on its shroomy body. Yet Draskil still frowned, as the mushroom king healed before he even hit the cavern wall.

Jake did notice a very slight dimming of some of the mushrooms on the ground far below, and he understood. He should have known it was another case of kind of shitty design. Every time they dealt damage to the Mushroom Man King, it would absorb energy from the many mushrooms spread throughout the cavern to recover, making it effectively one tanky motherfucker.

"Gotta destroy the mushroom!" Jake yelled to Draskil, getting a roar of recognition in response. He didn’t really do as Jake expected, instead just charging the Mushroom Man King again and smashing it down towards the ground.

The little abomination was ready after the second strike and summoned blue barriers to defend himself, but Draskil just tore straight through them and grabbed the Mushroom Man King. He proceeded to tear the final boss in two and threw the pieces away.

Only for both of them to regrow a little crowned mushroom man holding a scepter.

Fuck me, do I hate this place, Jake cursed. He proceeded to bombard the area with explosive arcane arrows but found the effect underwhelming. As he thought about other ways to fight, he got an idea, then reached into his inventory and took out three bottles.

On the ninth floor, the batch of poison had been put into four bottles total: One for the cauldron to pass the level and three for Jake. Looking at them, Jake decided to see how good they actually were. He wrapped all three in arcane bolts and sent them into the massive blue mushroom before proceeding to explode the bolts and spread the poison.

The poison instantly took hold, and Jake saw parts of the mushroom begin to wither and die. The Mushroom Man Kings—both of them—lifted their small scepters, and the mushroom began to immediately regenerate and rapidly eliminate the poison.

Draskil turned towards him and threw him a glance, as they both knew what had to be done. Jake acknowledged Draskil going for the two Mushroom Man Kings as he beelined it towards the large blue mushroom. During the dungeon, Jake had used most of his alchemy skills, but one skill he hadn’t used yet was absolutely perfect for this situation:

Touch of the Malefic Viper.

Chapter 7

A Rude Interruption

Everyone knew by now that mushrooms sucked. No, they didn’t just suck; they went above sucking. Their level of suck was so high they were endless vacuums of suffering. One of the reasons mushrooms sucked so much was because of how they worked.

Jake had encountered it before and knew that fungi were sneaky fucks. They liked to hide in things and make it look like there was totally an entire cavern full of mushrooms… when it was actually just a single goddamn fungus. This final boss floor was the same, Jake quickly came to realize. He tracked his poison in the large mushroom as it spread throughout the entire system of the fungus, the curse energy dividing and conquering among what had to be millions of mushrooms.

This made the entire fungus have an absolutely massive body covering well over a dozen square kilometers. And all of this was somehow linked to the Mushroom Man King. No, this wasn’t a case where the huge fungus was actually the body of the little guy, but far more likely one where the small Mushroom Man had stumbled upon an incredibly powerful natural treasure and then grown it to the huge fungus Jake and Draskil were now seeking to destroy.

Based on what Jake could see, it was possible to just repeatedly kill the Mushroom Man King until the massive fungus ran out of energy, but it was far faster to kill both at once. It would probably take Draskil in excess of two hours, given the current speed with which he was expending the energy of the mushrooms, and Jake wasn’t even sure if the dragonkin would last that long if he had his boosting skill active. This approach of destroying the fungus also fitted way better with the theme of the dungeon, as it wasn’t as much a fight against an individual so much as a task to poison an entire ecosystem.

Jake used One Step to get to the stem of the massive mushroom as he was surrounded by the glowing blue fucks. Spores were released from all of them, trying to poison Jake, but all it did was make him more aware of the nature of the fungus.

Kneeling down, Jake blew away some soil as he took hold of the massive root system beneath the ground. The largest roots were around the massive mushroom, and Jake would use that as his point of entrance.

Above him, explosions repeatedly sounded out as the Mushroom Man King tried to get Draskil away from him, but the dragonkin shrugged it all off as he continued his assault. One party released dozens of different spells every second, while the other simply ripped and tore with his claws and tail. Draskil dominated it handily, giving the mushroom man no opportunity to address Jake.

Jake had grasped hold of the massive mushroom and closed his eyes for a moment. Touch of the Malefic Viper activated, and with his high Perception, he quickly came to understand the massive network of roots. The cursed concoction had nearly run out of power while Jake got in position, but some of it still remained. He decided to take advantage of this.

Poison was pumped in as Jake sought to strengthen the cursed poison. At the same time, he delivered some more common fungicide to deal massive damage to the entire root system. He didn’t need to use any of the aspects of subtlety from the soul poison he’d used on the last big blue mushroom he killed, instead just going all in.

A barrage of spells was then released down towards him, but Draskil moved to intercept as he teleported with a flap of his wings. Jake would have been fine either way, but his dragonkin buddy had clearly decided that the little king was not even getting a sliver of a chance.

Focusing on his task, Jake kept poisoning the monstrosity of a fungus. He believed he was doing a good job until he suddenly felt something… A push. Usually, when one used Touch of the Malefic Viper, it was an infusion. But to make an infusion, a connection had to be formed, and through this connection, the fungus now attacked.

Dense energy flooded through the fungus’ roots and into Jake. He considered letting go, but he knew that the fungus was now awake and would rapidly destroy the poison he had used if he gave up now. Even more importantly, Jake didn’t want to lose out and give up when his dragonkin buddy was watching and doing a splendid job himself.

Gritting his teeth, Jake felt the energy invade his body and begin to ravage him from within. The fungus contained far more energy than Jake did… Far, far more energy. It was like a massive battery of pure power, and Jake’s only saving grace was that it couldn’t discharge much of it rapidly. The closest comparison Jake had to the fungus was the curse energy in Eternal Hunger, but that was a pretty bad comparison, considering the curse energy had not been actively antagonistic towards Jake and was also on an entirely different level in both quality and quantity. This fungus did contain a lot of energy, sure, but if what was within Eternal Hunger went rampant, Jake knew entire planets could be consumed by its hunger.

Jake and the mushroom continued their battle of push and pull as both tried to combat the energy they were injected with. Jake felt that the energy flooding him was surprisingly pure, not having any affinity. It was still trying to kill him, but he was now sure it was all controlled by the Mushroom Man King.

Draskil and Jake were fighting the same foe in the battle of attrition as Jake pushed in more and more energy. He allowed the mushroom to attack him in kind, believing in his body’s ability to take it. Considering the lack of affinity in the mushroom, Jake also began to pump in some dark mana. The nature of dark mana was to consume other types of mana and propagate itself, and Jake happily helped it do that to consume more of the mushroom’s energy storage. He controlled the poison through Touch and tried to attack the most essential parts of the massive fungus to kill it faster.

It was a game of cat and mouse. The fungus tried to eliminate the toxic energy Jake poured in, while Jake wanted to keep pumping. In the meantime, he also needed to keep avoiding the elimination of what he had already put in. If the massive fungus could lock down what toxic energy he was injecting, it would be able to instantly flood it with mana and destroy it.

Hence Jake controlled it. He condensed the toxic energy as he focused. A vivid image of a giant network of paths appeared in his mind, and he instinctively knew it was a representation of the Soulshape of the fungus. It almost felt as if Jake was a small yellow circle with a mouth running around a maze being chased by ghosts as he slowly consumed more and more of his foe.

Realizing the fight was not going its way, the Mushroom Man King began trying to change its tactic. It saw Jake as the primary threat, and the now four versions of the little king began waving their wands and making tendrils of shroom emerge to attack Jake.

Jake, still holding onto the roots of the massive fungus, kept his eyes closed as he focused. The tendrils flying for him suddenly began withering and turned into black dust that promptly scattered. More came, but they all met the same fate as Jake smirked unknowingly.

Every time the fungus moved, its Soulshape shifted slightly to represent it. All Jake did was split off some energy towards these moving parts, essentially sending toxic payloads into the tendrils to instantly destroy them. With the lacking ability of the Mushroom Man King to properly focus on taking down Jake while fighting Draskil, it had a tough time combatting this.

Jake kept up his part of the battle as he manipulated the toxic energy within the fungus like never before. At the same time, he also managed to do something else he usually didn’t: amplifying the existing toxin he had injected into—or, more accurately, thrown on top of—the giant mushroom.

He felt like he had more control than ever before and was touching upon an opportunity. Rather than infusing toxins into the creature itself… what if he injected it directly into the toxin he had already placed there? Sure, it had to go through the fungus, but currently, it was more like Jake connected a facet of toxins to the fungus and just let it drain into the maze-like Soulshape of the fungus before finally taking control of it. What if he instead shot it directly towards the toxic energy already in there? So rather than connecting a facet, he shot a water beam straight towards his target.

Combined with Sense of the Malefic Viper, mayb—

*You have slain [Mushroom Man King – lvl 201] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 172 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 173 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Jake’s train of thought was interrupted by the entire Soulshape suddenly withering and breaking. His mind took a second to process what had happened as he looked up and saw Draskil with his mouth still open, a large black line cutting the massive mushroom in two along with a few black, rotting parts of the many Mushroom Man Kings falling to the ground.

He still stared as the dragonkin teleported down.

"It died," Draskil said, a bit disappointed.

Jake felt the crumbling roots of the fungus in his hands as he sighed. "Fuck me… Be right back."

Do you wish to experience the Legacy of the Malefic Viper? Uses remaining: 3

With that, Jake flashed out of existence for a moment as he went on a journey to experience the Path of the Malefic Viper—or at least a little snippet of it.

"Alright, we are closing in on the den," a male elf wearing golden armor said as he lifted his hand, signaling those behind him to stop.

Four men and six women followed him closely, all wearing different equipment and wielding powerful weapons. Jake, who was observing this, instantly knew all of them were C-grade… Mid-tier C-grade, he guessed.

Out of this group, many would perhaps put most of their attention on their elven leader, but Jake focused on someone else: a human-looking male with long black hair, wearing a relatively simple robe. He didn’t appear particularly threatening, and from how he was in the back and his equipment, he was clearly a caster of some kind.

However, the reason he stood out to Jake was his familiar eyes and aura. This was the weakest iteration he had ever seen of him, but it was clearly the Malefic Viper fully disguised as a human.

"Strolas, do you have the flasks ready?" the elven leader asked as he turned to the one who would one day be known as the Malefic Viper.

"Yes, sir," the Malefic Viper—going by Strolas—answered in a meek tone. "Just remember not to take too much damage, or the flasks may lose their effect."

"I trust you," the elf said with a smile. With that, the Viper handed out flasks to everyone in his group. They headed closer to the den, and once they were near enough, another caster of the group cast some magic before nodding.

"It’s in there."

The elven leader nodded. "Let’s go."

Everyone drank their flasks. A few were a bit hesitant, but Strolas consumed his own instantly, making everyone else follow suit. Jake barely noticed a glint in the eyes of the Viper as the hunt began.

A massive beast firing out intense lasers of pure light magic emerged from the den and attacked. Jake watched on as the battle raged with what he quickly identified as a late-tier C-grade. It was a real struggle and a damn close fight, from the looks of it, but the party of eleven persevered. Everyone took damage and was hit back, and Jake had to admit that any person shown in this vision would be able to kill him.

After nearly two grueling hours—which had felt more like a minute, due to the entire fight getting fast-forwarded through—the giant beast lay dead, with not a single one in the group falling. The elf in his golden armor now had a bare chest, as his coverings had been broken, and one of the mages was missing an arm. The one healer in their group was spent, and everyone looked exhausted. All of them had done their utmost and pushed themselves… Everyone but one person.

Jake had noticed how the Viper had gone easy. He had avoided nearly all hits and only allowed some attacks to reach him, making it look like he had taken significant damage with his singed cloak and scarred upper body, but in reality, he was in near-top condition.

"Good job," the elven leader said as they all celebrated. He praised all the members with a genuine smile and also turned to the Viper. "Strolas, you have gone above and beyond once more. Those flasks surpassed my expectations. You truly are the best alchemist in the Empire, and I will make sure to mention your performance to my father."

The Viper seemed thankful as he went closer to the elf. "Thank you, sir, but if I may have one request…"

"What is it?" the elf asked, still happy as he got close to the Viper.

"Would you all kindly die?"

Pride of the Malefic Viper—or what would be known as Pride—descended as a domain appeared. The entire group of celebrating party members became alert as the Viper’s head flew forward and bit into the neck of the elf. At the same time, he lifted his hand into the air. It began glowing a dark green color… and Jake’s Perception of time slowed as he felt it.

Within every single person in the group, a toxin stirred—touched not by his hand, but his domain. It was the flask they had all consumed before. Jake did not know what it was made of, but clearly, it had been an incredibly potent toxin in disguise.

The Viper ripped out the neck of the elf before he was blasted back by a flaming sword from the stumbling group leader. He looked at the Viper with shock as black scales emerged on his body, and he morphed into a large black wyvern in seconds.

He froze and didn’t properly react. Everyone did. Their mental states were disturbed, their bodies broken from the battle with the beast before, and their resources spent. They even came to learn that the potions they had consumed contained more hidden poison, making them all despair further.

It was a group that Jake felt the Viper could never beat alone in a fight. The elven leader alone was a match for Villy, and if he hadn’t been the main fighter against the beast before, they would have had a close fight. But with the element of surprise, them consuming an incredibly potent poison, and their already-weakened states, the outcome was obvious.

Even then, the Viper took damage as he killed them one by one. His wing was severed and his scales bleeding as he finally stood before the elven leader, who managed to hold on till the end.

"Why… What are you? How?" the elf said in disbelief, unable to stand any longer.

"The line between what is a poison and something helpful can be very narrow and blurred. Deceiving the Perception of an amateur in alchemy is not an impressive feat in the slightest. As for who I am… Ah, it doesn’t matter now, does it?" The Malefic Viper smiled lightly, but the elf had already closed his eyes and succumbed to the poison.

Time rewound.

Jake once more saw the moment he’d activated Touch of the Malefic Viper. He focused on the process and, the second time around, felt that the simple motion had been a marvel of control. He didn’t just activate the poison within them all, but manipulated it. Amplified it. Sense of the Malefic Viper allowed him to see, Pride allowed him to extend his influence, and Touch allowed him to control.

Time rewound.

He felt it all again as more things became clear. He saw all their Soulshapes, and it was like a connection was made to each of them. Through Pride, it was formed... but Pride was not truly what created this connection. It was formed by Touch using Pride as a proxy, the two skills working flawlessly in synergy.

Time rewound.

Again and again, he saw it. He had already been on the precipice before and was just hammering out any flaws. He wasn’t even sure if he would have needed to use Path of the Heretic-Chosen to get the upgrade… but he had the uses, so why not? He also feared that the inspiration could leave him if he didn’t finish the upgrade there and then.

After thirteen rewinds, Jake got the notification as everything clicked into place, and he felt himself return to the real world once more.

Chapter 8

An (Un)expected Situation

This vision had definitely been on the shorter side, and compared to his last one where Villy got smacked around by Valdemar, it was also far less valuable. Then again, that vision had consumed two charges of the skill and allowed him to see two future Primordials duking it out, with a focus on more than one of the Malefic Viper skills.

Jake was teleported back into the dungeon as expected and was excited to get to his new skill, but he noticed something was off. Draskil was staring at him weirdly, and Irin was flying over together with Reika and Bastilla. Reika looked surprised more than anything, while Irin and Bastilla looked utterly dumbfounded.

As he was still wondering what was up, Reika poked him mentally and informed him, "Whatever you just did released a wave of a presence or something… It was yours, but different… I think they know you are the Chosen of the Malefic Viper."

His brain took a while to process what she had just said before it clicked. Oh… fuck.

Path of the Heretic-Chosen.

When he used the skill, he had tapped into his direct connection to Villy and momentarily seized it to gaze upon the Records of the Primordial. He hadn’t even considered what that could do, as all he knew was that he’d momentarily disappeared… unaware of what he’d left behind when he did that.

Still unsure what kind of explanation he should try and come up with, Irin made him fully aware he was way past the point of explaining it away the moment she got close.

Without any hesitation, she kneeled in front of him and pressed her forehead to the muddy soil, speaking in a voice that seemed both pleading and apologetic. "This one greets the Chosen."

Fuck me, Jake cursed internally as he realized he had truly fucked up. As he was about to say something, a prompt appeared in front of Jake and everyone else.

Congratulations! You have cleared the dungeon: Nine Floors of the Indigo Caverns.

Objective: Defeat the supreme leader of the mushroom men: the Mushroom Man King (Completed).

Dungeon shutting down in: 00:00:03

He saw the three seconds left just as two boxes appeared in front of them. Jake was quick and opened them both, taking the items in his inventory before he was whisked out of the dungeon.

Jake and the four others appeared outside the dungeon, Irin still kneeling and Draskil still staring. Reika and Bastilla had both been in the air when they exited and were now standing on the ground, unmoving. The unmoving part was not something unique to them, as everyone was frozen. Even the air itself had stopped moving.

"Just some simple time magic," he heard a voice say as Villy appeared right beside him. Jake turned to the Viper, who patted him on the back. "Quite the pickle you just made for yourself. You know, every time you use Path of the Heretic-Chosen, you leave behind your anchored Truesoul… but that anchored Truesoul does not have the protection you worked so hard on making with Shroud. Not that it would have mattered, as you tapping into my Records clearly leaves behind some traces, and those familiar with me are bound to notice. Now, what was the vision about? We can deal with this entire thing after; I care more about what you saw."

Still uncertain what to do, Jake just gave the cliff notes. "About Touch. It was you with a party led by an elf in golden armor. You killed a late C-grade beast, poisoned all of them with flasks and poisons, then killed them and stole the corpse as well as everything they owned."

Villy failed to hold back a smirk. "You know I am not a believer in fate, but this coincidence is a bit too perfect, isn’t it?"

"What do you mean?" Jake asked, his brain still trying to make up a plan.

"You see a vision of me killing my own party after a hunt, and now find yourself in a situation where you must choose if you want to do the same," the Viper said. "With them alive, I do not see you hiding for long. The girl from Earth managed to solve this issue by having all those humans she brought with her sign a contract, but that isn’t an option here. The demon is bound by a contract already, and signing one of confidentiality in this matter would go directly against that. So, Jake…. what will you do?"

"Oh," Jake said after hearing everything Villy said, not really caring about the last part. "Guess I am kinda screwed, then."

"You can still kill them.” The Viper shrugged. "Sure, the dragonkin may be a bit too much for you to handle, but you can go through official channels and use some of that Chosen clout to get him killed. Just ask Viridia, and I am sure she would gladly remove him or anyone else from existence."

"The chances of that happening are nil," Jake said, shutting it down instantly.

"So you value their lives above your own secrecy?" Villy raised an eyebrow.

"Well, yeah. I can just keep trying to hide or tell people to leave me the fuck alone or something. At the very least, ask them to keep it a secret. Also, you said Irin had another contract, right? Does that contract really require her to report any secret the Malefic Viper or his Chosen told her not to divulge? Sounds like a shit contract."

"Got me there," the Viper said, putting up both his hands defensively. "But I am serious when I say you just made another weak point when it comes to your hidden identity. She will be forced to report something. Soon the cracks will spread, and your mask will shatter entirely, revealing the ugly mug of my Chosen beneath."

"I will handle that when it happens." Jake shook his head. "Also, quick question—does this count as time dilation?"

"Nope. I just stopped this cavern; time moves normally everywhere else. Localized time stops are pretty damn basic tools of the god toolkit. Anyway, you made your decision to just come clean to these three, right?"

"Seems like that is what is happening, yeah." Jake nodded.

"Great. Then introduce me to your friends already," Villy said with a teasing smile.

The moment he was done speaking, time returned to normal, and everyone looked confused. Draskil’s eyes quickly darted to the person now standing next to Jake. He knelt down instantly, joining Irin, who was still pressing her head to the ground.

Reika and Bastilla stared for a moment, confused, before Jake realized neither of them had seen the Viper in his human form before, nor were they blessed and thus able to feel his presence. It was like with Meira, and they would only truly be affected once they knew who he was, so if they—

"Hello, there,” Villy said with a grin. “My name is Vilastromoz, but most people call me the Malefic Viper. Your pleasure to meet me.”

The effect was almost instant as Reika began shaking a bit before failing to stay upright, with Bastilla making an odd, scared whining noise before just straight up lying down in a fetal position.

Irin, now finally noticing something was off, looked up and saw the Viper standing there. She made eye contact for a fraction of a second before slamming her head down onto the ground again. Not a single word was spoken by her, and it was Draskil who opened his mouth first.

"Draskil greets his Patron," the dragonkin said in a tone Jake had never heard before. Rather than his usual domineering attitude and tone of confidence, he now seemed as meek as a baby lizard before a true dragon.

"You really wanted to play this casual, huh?" Jake muttered as he looked at Villy.

"No, I actually just wanted to fuck with you a little and have some fun when meeting your little friends," the Viper chuckled, clearly in a good mood. "And now that I have met them, I can’t be arsed to stay. Since you decided not to kill them, I shall leave the rest to you. See you again a bit later, and by later, I mean in two days, as I’ve got some new ale done brewing by then."

"Can you just leave already to not make this worse than it already is?" Jake exclaimed with exasperation, knowing that the Viper was saying and doing all those things just to mess with him.

The Viper didn’t even respond as he disappeared without a trace, leaving Jake and his party behind with only a final mental message to Jake: "I made a barrier covering this entire cavern, so go wild talking."

Jake took a few seconds to gather his thoughts, and in a glorious attempt to not address the elephant in the room, he began with, "So… ahem, we should discuss how we split the dungeon loot. I hurried to pick it up, and—"

"Jake," Reika spoke as she looked up with red eyes and sweat pouring down her face, unable to be nice by not pointing out the damn elephant.

With a big sigh, Jake sat down with his legs crossed on the ground. Nobody else moved, and they were all either lying prone or kneeling. "So… yeah… I got the True Blessing of the Viper. We met under weird circumstances, got along well, and here we are. Sorry for keeping it a secret, but things tend to get weird when people know, and if possible, can we just act like I don’t have it or at least not think about it too much? Let’s just return to ten minutes ago mentally, alright?"

He knew he was reaching and that it was a losing battle. Even after speaking, he knew he was not helping his situation. Jake felt utterly fucked, but he had neglected to consider that there already was one person in the group who knew and didn’t act all weird about it.

Reika stood up and took out a handkerchief to clean her brows as she shook her head. "The mere presence of the Malefic One is truly something; I can’t understand how you manage to stay upright and so casual."

Jake picked up on what she was trying to do and responded jokingly, "It’s mainly the Bloodline, but plenty of practice sure helps."

Their casual demeanor seemed to slightly affect the others, as Draskil finally looked up with questioning eyes. He stared at Jake and frowned. "Why hide?"

At least he asked an easy question, Jake thought as he answered, "Due to exactly what is happening right now. I want to actually have normal interactions with others and not whatever you guys are doing."

Draskil still seemed confused and again asked, "Why?"

"Because that is who I am. I didn’t treat you differently when you thought I had a lower-leveled Blessing than you, did I? I want it to be like that with how you treat me. Also, Irin… why is your head still glued to the ground?"

Irin barely reacted as she shook a little.

Jake was about to talk again as Reika stopped him. "Jake… can you go over there for a moment?" she asked, pointing to a corner rather far away.

Jake was confused before he looked at Reika, who gave him the kind of stare that told him he should really agree.

"Alright…" he said as he walked away. Shit, I am bad at this.

Wanting to take his mind off things, Jake sat down in the corner nearly a full kilometer away from Reika, who set up her own barrier. He had put it off due to the "situation," but now found the time to finally go over his upgrade and what he had at least gained out of this entire thing.

As expected, the notification he had heard was Touch of the Malefic Viper finally upgrading.

[Touch of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)] – With a single touch, the Malefic Viper has slain countless foes. Attempt to inject poison into a being through physical contact. The nature of the poison is determined by the user. The alchemist can only use toxic effects he has concocted or created prior. Can be used with all compatible types of mana affinities, further altering the effects. This effect is especially effective using your arcane affinity. Vastly increases the potency of transmutations made using Touch of the Malefic Viper at the cost of partly binding them to your soul. Some effects cannot be replicated. Adds an increase to the effectiveness of Touch of the Malefic Viper based on Intelligence and Wisdom. Passively provides 1 Intelligence per level in Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your touch be the catalyst of corruption as you bend the world to your will.

-->

[Touch of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] – With a single touch, the Malefic Viper seizes control of the world. Attempt to inject toxic energy into a being through contact. The nature of the toxic energy is determined by the user. The alchemist can only use toxic effects he has concocted or created prior, or further empower an existing toxic effect within the target. Allows the alchemist to far more effectively control all toxins he is in contact with when using Touch of the Malefic Viper. Can be used with all compatible types of mana affinities, further altering the effects. This effect is especially effective using your arcane affinity. Vastly increases the potency of transmutations made using Touch of the Malefic Viper at the cost of partly binding them to your soul. Some effects cannot be replicated. Adds an increase to the effectiveness of Touch of the Malefic Viper based on Intelligence and Wisdom. Passively provides 3 Intelligence per level in Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your touch be the catalyst of corruption as you bend the world to your will.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 175 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Jake once more considered how damn long those skill descriptions were getting. It was truly proof of how utterly bonkers the Malefic Viper Legacy skills were. The description itself only had minor changes, but impactful ones. It no longer said "through physical contact" but merely "through contact," no doubt reflecting the synergy with Pride. It had also added the effects of empowering existing toxins and even the part about increased control. Rather than one major improvement, which he often saw with upgraded skills, it was several smaller things that Jake had been working towards for a long time. The part about empowering toxins was something he had already done before. He had, of course, also trained to improve his control at all times, and the only truly new thing was the use of Pride. Even then, it wasn’t entirely new, considering all the training Jake had done when it came to Soulshapes.

The level to his profession was also welcome. As Jake looked at his status, he noted that he was now more than halfway through upgrading his nine Malefic Viper Legacy skills to legendary. He still needed Blood, Wings, Sagacity, and surprisingly enough, Sense of the Malefic Viper. For Wings, he had a good idea what to do, Sagacity, he had a feeling was heavily linked to the drop of blood in his Soulspace, but with both Blood and Sense, he wasn’t that sure where to take them. He decided that he should definitely dedicate more time to them, as he wanted to get all four skills to legendary rarity before reaching C-grade, just like he had gotten them all to Ancient before D-grade.

As a final thing, Jake checked and saw that his Dungeoneer title had also upgraded once again.

[Dungeoneer VIII] – Successfully clear a Dungeon suitable for your level. +14 all stats.

It was just three to all stats, but everything was welcome.

Having gone through all his menus and some internal reflection, Jake considered what to do now. He didn’t want to go through the loot from the dungeon alone and looked over towards the barrier that was still up, wondering what they were talking about as he sent some encouraging thoughts their way.

Go Reika! I believe in you!

Chapter 9

Reika & the Insurmountable Task of Trying to Explain Jake

"Your actions were needless and just made unnecessary trouble for him," Duskleaf said as Vilastromoz teleported back to his usual chambers. "Your intent, I assume."

"You know me so well.” The Viper smiled at his disciple.

"Are you disappointed?" Duskleaf asked. "You would have killed all four of them in a heartbeat just to avoid the slightest inconvenience. A choice he didn’t even consider."

"No… if I wanted him to be a mirror image of me, I wouldn’t like him nearly as much." Vilastromoz shook his head. "Sentimentality can be healthy as long as he doesn’t overdo it."

"His Path is not yours and never will be," Duskleaf said, sighing. "He is far more controlled than you ever were."

Vilastromoz smirked. "You say that… and yet I wonder what happens when he is truly pushed. I believe we shall come to discover that his and my extremes are not that different. That the lines he is willing to cross are far less controlled and restrained than you believe."

Duskleaf frowned but didn’t speak further, not entirely able to disagree.

—

Reika had been at many social gatherings in her life and done plenty of convincing and negotiating. She had worked for her clan and even argued for more research funding… but trying to convince three fanatics that meeting their god and someone who was essentially a prophet wasn’t that big of a deal was way out of her league. To make it worse, they had hung out with Jake and been casual with him for quite a while already, and this seemed to only hit them harder, as they, in retrospect, viewed their actions as insulting, if not downright blasphemous. This was clearly not something where logic could win.

After she had made the barrier and Jake was gone, it put a dampener on the mood, and Irin finally lifted her head as she stared at Reika. "You knew?"

"Yes," Reika answered.

"For how long?"

"Since before we entered the Order. Jake’s identity is hidden here, but not on our planet. Back there, everyone with any status knows."

"How…" Irin muttered as she fell silent again.

Bastilla still looked at Reika with disbelief without speaking, and Reika sighed. She considered her approach to try and salvage the situation they found themselves in. She knew that her own casual demeanor was already way off from what the three of them would expect of her, and she would use that in her approach.

Rather than attempt to spin a tale of lies or a new cover-up, she decided to just go with the truth… A slightly modified truth with a good deal of her own conjecture mixed in, but the truth nonetheless.

"You must remember that Jake and I come from a planet that hasn’t even had the system for a few years yet," Reika began explaining as the three of them listened. “I didn’t even believe gods actually existed before the system arrived, and there is a good chance Jake didn’t either. Moreover, we come from a world with a modern culture focused heavily on individualism and a belief in personal freedom and equality. At least, the parts of the world we were from. No one was inherently superior to others—we believed they weren’t, anyway—and anyone claiming to be better due to their inborn traits was heavily ostracized and looked down upon.

"The concept of others being superior is so foreign to us and also why I personally have a hard time adapting to a world with literal gods. It is a slow process, but I am getting more acclimated to it these days. I know they are superior; I know that a being such as the Malefic Viper is an existence I can barely dream of approaching, and I feel it deep in my bones every time I am confronted with a creature of superior strength and grade. But Jake does not feel this fear. You all know he has a Bloodline, and that Bloodline offers him innate resistance to auras and presences. Due to it, he does not feel the suppression of a god’s presence, and coupled with his upbringing and inherent values and culture, he simply doesn’t share the same sentiment as most everyone in the multiverse. He experiences neither fear nor reverence towards those superior to him, and in turn, he does not wish to be viewed as superior simply due to what or who he is. Let us also be fair—Jake is not the most normal person, even on his best days. I do not say that to criticize him in any way either. Would anyone expect the Chosen of a Primordial to be normal? Have any of you ever met one before? I do not know if it is just me, but if each god can only have one Chosen, is it not only to be expected that person will be unique? And that the Chosen of a Primordial will be more special than any other?"

She needed to speak rather carefully and avoid saying anything too incendiary. While Jake could get away with blasphemy, Reika didn’t believe she could. Not in a million years. She also wanted to kind of excuse why Jake acted as he did.

The thing about his Bloodline was something she had pre-approved with Jake a long time ago. She had been told the properties of his Bloodline before and knew it allowed him to resist auras. Parts of her wondered if it had other aspects as well, but it wasn’t something she would think about too much and definitely never ask about.

Reika tried to reach them, but she had a hard time reading the three members of the Order—especially the dragonkin, as she quite honestly had no idea what expressions they made or what emotions those expressions represented. Bastilla also just stared blankly as she likely tried to process everything, and Irin looked deep in thought.

I don’t need to convince Bastilla or even Draskil, Reika thought. As long as I get Irin on board and we reach an understanding, she can rope in the two others. Jake will also likely be able to convince Draskil himself.

"Irin… what are you thinking about right now?" Reika asked Irin. Even if she had an idea, she still wanted to confirm.

"I… I just saw the Malefic One in person and have spoken to his Chosen several times," Irin said as a stupid smile covered her face.

Not what I thought, Reika quickly realized as Irin kept talking.

"I even approached the Chosen with the intent to…" Irin’s eyes opened wide. "What have I done? How could I not have realized? My behavior has been utterly unbecoming… Should I beg? No, I don’t deserve forgiveness; I should just—"

"Hey!" Reika yelled as she chopped the head of the succubus, hurting her hand a bit. "Snap out of it already. Didn’t you hear a single word I said before? That he said before leaving?" Irin finally looked up, and with her attention, Reika spoke again. "You know what is really unforgivable? Thinking that if the Chosen and the Malefic One wanted to hide his identity, you could figure it out on your own. Or you believing that any actions you have done while interacting with the disguise he purposefully made weren’t something he wanted. Consider it for a moment. Jake already told you why he wanted to hide his identity before. Are you questioning his judgment?"

"I would never!" Irin said dismissively, if not a bit angrily.

"Then you still don’t get it. This part is primarily my own conjecture, but while we know why Jake wanted to hide his identity, have you considered why the Malefic One approved?" That got a few interested glances. Still addressing Irin, Reika explained, "While I do not dare claim I understand the thoughts of a Primordial, would it not make sense that this is related to the Path of his Chosen? Perhaps it has been deemed that he benefits from interactions with others without them knowing his true identity. Perhaps it is something entirely else.

“Either way, the Malefic Viper likely wants us to question his Chosen. Judge his Chosen. Allow his Chosen to grow. For him to make his own choices and walk his own Path, unaffected by his status. Do notice how the Malefic One even asked the opinion of Jake and seemed relaxed with him. Machinations far above our realm of understanding are taking place, and if we truly wish to show our loyalty, the best we can do is to act as they want of us by not seeing Jake as the Malefic One’s Chosen. Even if we do at least recognize it, we should not use it as an excuse to treat him differently.

"When I first learned he was the Chosen of the Malefic One, I had a hard time comprehending it, and after coming here to the Order, I have to remind myself every day that treating Jake like Jake the Chosen and not Jake the person goes directly against what he himself and the Viper wish. So at the very least, try to treat him like a normal person. You have his permission and the permission of the Malefic One to do this.” She was only lying a little bit, as she didn’t ever really struggle with his identity. She also chose to add on one more thing that she only sent to Irin.

"And consider the possibilities. You have an open invitation to approach and interact with the Chosen in a casual way. Are you really going to throw such a golden opportunity away?"

If Reika had learned one thing while in the Order, it was that everyone was inherently selfish. Irin was worried for several reasons, most of them to do with self-preservation and fear of what could happen to her if Jake was genuinely mad or offended. So rather than Irin seeing it as a negative that she now knew, Reika wanted her to see it as something to take advantage of. Jake could deal with whatever the outcome of that was.

Her words clearly reached Irin, as the demon seemed to focus and think it over. A few seconds passed before her eyes darted up. "Are you certain that this is truly the will of the Malefic One and his Chosen?"

"Well, no," Reika answered honestly, “but I have yet to be smitten for blasphemy, and I have treated Jake normally ever since we met. He even asked me to join this dungeon run, showing that he clearly isn’t offended by my presence or how I act."

"So you just act like you don’t know he is the Chosen?" she asked clarifyingly.

"It is more accurate to say that I act like him being the Chosen isn’t really that big of a deal. I recognize it, I know it, but I don’t make it be what defines him. That is also his wish, and I respect that.”

"Still don’t get why he hides it," Draskil muttered, finally speaking.

Can’t tell them Jake doesn’t actually think it is that big of a deal and just annoying to be a Chosen… Reika thought, instead offering a roundabout answer. "Who are we to even try? If that is the Path Jake and the Malefic One have chosen, the most respectful thing we can do is to honor their wishes."

She felt like she was talking in circles, but sometimes repetition could be helpful. Reika felt like she had made some good progress, but there was still work to do before she felt confident "releasing" the three of them upon Jake.

Jake, in the meantime, had chosen to run away to a place no one else could go.

"Why did you even bother trying to hide your identity to begin with when you can’t be arsed to actually keep hiding?" sim-Jake asked the real Jake as they both sat in the Soulspace.

"I just prefer it if people don’t know I am the Chosen. It isn’t a make-or-break kind of deal." Jake shrugged.

"It is more the lack of decisiveness," sim-Jake criticized. "You half-ass so many things. You start doing something only to quit halfway through, or you just stop bothering."

"So I should have killed all four of them?" Jake asked with a scoff.

"I am saying you should never have bothered hiding your identity at all, or have been fully prepared for it eventually coming out when you barely try to stay under the radar. You are not going to change the entire multiverse and their views on gods or their Chosen. It is natural to submit to those more powerful than yourself, and they all know it. It is the law of the multiverse, and there is a reason why natural suppression between grades exists. There is a reason we do not feel it either, as we are born to stand beside or above everyone. Better to just embrace that you are indeed superior and then go from there.”

"We are not having this conversation again." Jake sighed as he stood up within the Soulspace.

"You spent your entire life trying to fit in and adapt to a world you never fit into. Yet now, when you finally find a world you fit into, you try to apply those useless values that only led to the suppression of your Bloodline—of who you are. Why not just accept it? It is an inevitability anyway. With time, we will reach levels of power where being Chosen or not has no meaning."

"And at that time, it will at least be earned and not merely given because Villy decided to give it to me," Jake shot back.

"Fair, I at least get that. You don’t want to borrow his clout, even if I will say it is earned. Villy has recognized that we are worth it, and I get him. Like I just said, he also views us reaching the apex as a foregone conclusion, and when eternity is the timeline you are used to working with, why not get ahead of the curve and just recognize us as worth viewing as an equal right away?"

"That or die," Jake pointed out.

"True, true. Definitely shouldn’t do that," sim-Jake chuckled as he also stood up. "Anyway, enough about that. Let’s talk about what actually matters. I have been busy while you were playing alchemist, and I wanted some input."

"No, you don’t need my input," Jake said.

Sim-Jake smirked. "Heh, true. I just want to show off my progress.”

"So, you beating up the chimera again?"

"Nah, this isn’t about the fighting style this time around, but my other project," sim-Jake explained. "Watch this."

Sim-Jake closed his eyes and focused for a moment. He knelt down and jumped forward, suddenly turning all shadowy. Several copies of sim-Jake then appeared in a line between him and his destination before he finally appeared more than a hundred meters away.

"Space magic," Jake quickly concluded.

"Bingo," sim-Jake said. “It is far better than Basic Shadow Vault of Umbra, but far from useful yet. So, yeah, hold back on upgrading it. Mixing in space magic like I am is already pushing it away from its Origin in Umbra’s Legacy, but I need far more to properly make it our own."

Jake nodded. "Alright. Keep up the good work. Anything else to add? If not, I want to go study the drop of blood I stole from Villy a bit."

"Just one thing," sim-Jake said. "Fight some more C-grades with space magic if you can. I got a lot of ideas from reviewing the fight with the Phantomshade Panther."

Jake nodded in understanding, then went towards the red marble floating inside his Soulspace in a desolate area. He hadn’t really actively interacted with it that much but thought it was high time he began studying it properly. A full analysis was out of the question, but he should be able to at least figure something useful out.

He didn’t know how much time he had, either, and was quite honestly more occupied with passing the time than anything else, so he didn’t have to think about the outside world that he would have to deal with pretty soon.

Jake sincerely hoped that Reika would succeed. If she didn’t, it would really suck. He had enjoyed the dungeon quite a lot despite the shitty mushroom theme only because he had good company. Not to misunderstand, Jake liked his solo adventures, but he also liked to at least have the option of teaming up. It also had many benefits, as Jake had learned quite a few things from his party members.

If Reika failed, Jake wasn’t even sure what his plans were. Would he cut them off? Distance himself? Accept them no longer treating him like before? He genuinely didn’t know.

All he could do was hope that it didn’t come to that.

Chapter 10

Friendships & The Question Of Why They Are So Damn Hard

It ended up taking Reika another few hours to reach a point where she felt confident letting the three of them roam free. Draskil hadn’t really taken that much convincing when it came down to it—something Reika partially explained away as a consequence of coming from the newly integrated universe.

Bastilla and Irin were much harder to reach, as they had grown up with the system and the status quo, making the idea of ignoring someone being a Chosen an entirely foreign concept to them. Reika ended up giving a lot of examples of Earth and anecdotes relating to Jake to assure them that he really wasn’t the type of Chosen they assumed him to be.

Irin seemed to have the takeaway that she had just found the opportunity of a lifetime. Draskil seemed competitive, and Bastilla was… Yeah, Bastilla was still rather shellshocked and seemed to not really get the situation outside of "keep it a secret; that is what the Malefic One and his Chosen want."

Reika just hoped that, with time, she could have a proper conversation with Bastilla about it… and hopefully not have a really shitty roommate experience in the future.

Jake was woken up from his Serene Soul Meditation when he felt Reika approach. He opened his eyes and saw that she looked slightly worn out, having fought a valiant battle for him.

When she got close enough, Jake asked, "So… how screwed am I?"

"I believe it is manageable," Reika answered. "At least I believe they all understand that keeping it confidential is best, and that treating you too differently due to you being the Chosen isn’t what you or your Patron want. Whether they are actually able to overcome a lifetime of conditioning and cultural teachings and not act too differently is an entirely different thing."

"Thank you either way." Jake smiled a bit sadly. "This entire thing does suck."

"I understand them," Reika added. "At least partly. Me telling them to treat you like you don’t have status is a far more extreme version of someone telling me not to treat my great-grandfather with a high level of respect. I am not certain I could stop doing that—at least, not on a whim. So the best thing to do now is give it time. Don’t treat them differently than before, but also don’t try to put a lid on who or what you are. Instead, normalize it and make it clear that to you, it is simply part of who you are, and while you are naturally proud of it—as any Chosen would be—you also don’t want it to be your primary defining trait. That them respecting you as a Chosen and as a person means not making you only the Chosen of the Malefic Viper."

" Alright… so just give it time, huh?" Jake sighed. "Let’s get over there. Any tips for things I should or shouldn’t say?"

"Don’t downplay your identity too much, but as I said, make it clear you do not want it to impact their treatment of you. Not too much, at least. Also, do not talk about your odd relationship with the Malefic Viper. That is between you and your Patron, and definitely don’t think that you talking about how casual you are with the Viper will make them understand they can treat you casually. Also, when we go greet them, you should say…"

Jake nodded slowly as he took her words to heart. He had enough social awareness to know that he sucked at having social awareness, and even if Reika was not some expert, she was far more adept than Jake.

The two of them walked back to Draskil, Irin, and Bastilla. They did all look at him weirdly and for sure differently than before, but at least they were all standing up and not kneeling. Jake sighed again as he got close and said what Reika had told him, practically verbatim.

"I do hope this incident won’t cause an unnecessary rift between us. I am still the same person as before. The way I have treated you till now is the same as I would have even if you knew, and I will continue to treat you as friends and not merely subordinates, even if I do recognize a difference in status. I can only hope that you will do the same. Also, I hope you all understand that keeping my identity a secret is something I would very much appreciate.”

The mood was still a bit tense and awkward for a few seconds, but then Draskil finally spoke up with a grin. "Makes sense now how you killed C-grade before I did."

Jake felt relief as he answered, "Now you are just looking for excuses for losing."

"Bah, only to be expected you win; you are Chosen," Draskil said before smiling. "But I am still stronger."

"For now, for now," Jake acknowledged with a smirk.

"Excuse me," Irin said, a bit too polite compared to her usual demeanor. "We do have a problem. I am required to report what happened during this dungeon run to my superiors… What should I say to them?"

"What exactly are you required to report?" Jake asked. "How in-depth?"

"I will have to submit a report and then do an interview," Irin said. "If I lie during it or obfuscate the truth, it may have repercussions… and I doubt I will even be able to hide it due to my contract."

Jake nodded and thought for a moment before finding a solution. "Alright, then just do as usual and report the truth. I will handle it on my end."

Taking out his token, Jake dialed the highest of the higher-ups when it came to the mortals: the Hall Master. She picked up instantly.

"How may I be of assistance?" Viridia asked.

She sounded a little too excited he had called, but nothing he could do about that. "My identity as the Chosen of the Malefic Viper has been discovered by three new individuals, and I will need you to help cover it up."

"Very well,” she promptly answered. “Are they already slain, or do you wish for me to do it while cleansing them of karmic bonds?"

"No killing," Jake said, shutting down the murder-hoboing. "One of the people is Irinixis from the Humanoid Resources Department, and another the Malefic Dragonkin Draskil. Irinixis will need to file a report of what happened during a dungeon run we just had, and I want you to intercept that report and make up an excuse about how you wanted to keep track of Draskil’s progress or something like that. Maybe use his Divine Blessing as an excuse."

"As you command, I will handle it, so have no further worries,” Viridia said, not missing a beat. “Is there anything else I can help with?"

"No, that is all for this time. Thanks for the assistance."

"The honor is all mine, Lord Thayne," Viridia said as Jake cut off the magical phone call.

"Alright, I got that angle covered," Jake said as he put his token away again. He had only taken a few seconds talking to Viridia through the power of telepathic efficiency. If not, it would’ve been rude to make them all wait around.

"How?" Reika asked curiously.

"I am the Chosen, am I not? I had the Hall Master deal with it. She naturally already knows who I am." Jake said this somewhat jokingly, seeing no reason to mention that her finding out had also been a complete accident.

Irin nodded with some relief, not at all surprised. "Thank you, my Lord." She bowed before stopping herself. "Oh, I mean… I am sorry, I—"

"Irin, just take it slow, alright?" Jake smiled. "No need to fret over minor things like that. Take your time and just treat me normally, okay? And a better thing to do than talking about this situation would be to address the loot we got from clearing the dungeon. But I must warn all of you… While I have not seen the properties of these items, only their appearance, I can already tell you they fucking suck."

With a very necessary warning, Jake summoned the two items. One of them was a scepter just like the one the Mushroom Man King had used, while the other one was just a mushroom cap formed like a crown. With disgust, Jake identified them.

[Scepter of the Indigo Caverns (Epic)] – A scepter crafted from unknown wood that has fused with the Lifecore of a once mighty fungus. Through time, it has further been improved by the Mushroom Man King and empowered by the Indigo Caverns. Allows the user to directly manipulate and take control of fungi, using them as their weapon. This scepter can be attuned to specific fungi to further improve this effect. Significantly more powerful when used by one also wearing the Mushroom Cap Crown of the Fungal Lord.

Requirements: Lvl 180+ in any humanoid race.

[Mushroom Cap Crown of the Fungal King (Epic)] - The crown of the Mushroom Man King. Contains elements of his authority, making you inherently intimidating and hold authority over other mushroom men of a lower level than yourself. Allows the wearer to far more easily manipulate fungi using any form of magic. Significantly more powerful when used by one also wielding the Scepter of the Indigo Caverns.

Requirements: Lvl 180+ in any humanoid race.

His sheer level of disgust only increased after reading what they did. Without hesitation, he voiced his own stance by disowning them both.

"Not me!"

"No," Draskil muttered decisively.

"I have no need for them," Reika quickly made clear.

"It would feel inappropriate to take anything," Irin said.

All of them turned to look at Bastilla, who had not spoken a single word since Jake had come out as the Chosen of the Malefic Viper. She looked bewildered for a moment as she stared at the items and the party. "Really?" she finally spoke.

"I believe you can at the very least sell them for dismantling," Irin pointed out.

"If you don’t want them, I would be fine with just destroying them here and now," Jake added on.

"I'll just take them…" Bastilla muttered as she swept them up. Jake threw Reika a glance, and she gave him a look that made it clear the beast woman was still not entirely on board and handling the situation properly. But, as her roommate, Jake believed Reika would have plenty of time to figure things out.

He was at least happy that even after everything was said and done, they could still bond over their shared hatred for mushrooms. A true unifier.

"Alright, thanks, everyone," Jake said with a genuine smile. "Let us head on back to the Order?"

All of them agreed, and Jake tried to make some casual small talk with the succubus on the way back, but all the responses were a bit strained from Irin’s side. Draskil was a pleasant surprise, as he seemed to have come to terms with things rather quickly and acted almost the same as before.

Reika walked with Bastilla as they made it back as one group, no one bothering to race this time around. They made it back to the teleportation station before splitting up. Jake didn’t know how everything would be whenever they met again, but he could only do as he always did and just take things as they came.

--

Jake stepped through the gateway and walked to the living room before sitting down, exhausted. He had already seen that Meira and Duskleaf were busy inside the library, and he had no interest in interrupting them as he just took a breather.

He got half an hour of rest by himself before he saw Duskleaf whisk out of existence within the library. A few minutes later—after cleaning up—Meira also left and went straight for Jake in the living room, likely having been informed by Duskleaf.

"Lord Thayne," she said, bowing upon entering the living room.

"Hey, there," Jake said with a smile. "How have things been while I was gone? Duskleaf treating you well?"

"The Grand Elder has treated me very well, and I have made much progress," Meira said enthusiastically. "I also did as you said and invited over some of my fellow students."

That made Jake perk up. He looked at Meira with surprise and motioned for her to elaborate.

"We only went to study in the library due to the many tomes Lord Thayne has available, and I swear that not a single book has left the residence,” Meira explained. “I thank you once again for allowing me to invite them, and also offer thanks from them.”

Jake felt genuinely happy that at least Meira seemed to have some real friends. It was good to know that she could have some healthy relationships, considering Jake’s recent issues in that department.

"I would love to meet them the next time they come over," Jake added.

Meira seemed quite happy recently compared to how she’d been when Jake first met her, and there was a good chance that had something to do with her friends, right? Her just having friends was a major improvement.

He did notice that she’d seemed somewhat hesitant when Jake asked to meet them, but he didn’t really dwell on it. It was normal to be a little nervous when introducing your friends to who was essentially your boss.

Now, Jake was not entirely ignorant and knew that Meira likely didn’t have the same understanding of friendship as he did. This was part of the reason why he wanted to meet her friends: to see if they were good or bad influences.

"I shall relay your wish," Meira said, nervously adding, "Uhm, one of them, named Izil, also said that she wanted to meet you if possible…"

"Oh?" Jake asked, surprised. Why would she want to meet Jake? Okay, there were many reasons. She knew he had a black token, so that was likely it. But he didn’t want to judge right away and think that she was just after his status or trying to take advantage of him. Heck, she maybe had a status of her own.

"Who is this Izil?" he asked.

"She is an elf from the Altmar Empire," Meira explained, adding on with a smile, "She has helped and taught me a lot of things."

Okay, so she does have some status of her own and doesn’t seem like a shit person, Jake noted.

"Well, I already said I would love to meet your friends, so of course, I will also talk to her," Jake said, still smiling comfortingly.

"Thank you." Meira bowed again. "I shall let you know when next they request to come over."

Her phrasing did make Jake frown a little, but he didn’t dwell on it. The two of them talked a bit more before Meira had to leave for a lesson, and Jake also quickly got busy himself. He had a few Malefic Viper Legacy skills he wanted to work on improving, and he also kind of wanted to take his mind off things and be by himself a while.

At least until Meira would have friends over.

A day that came sooner than expected, as Meira told him they would come the very next day, not even two days after Jake had returned from the dungeon.

Chapter 11

An Offer Difficult to Refuse

Jake had seen a more-nervous-than-usual Meira off as she went to one of her classes. He knew it was because she wouldn’t be returning alone but had agreed to bring her friends along. It would be a lie if he said he didn’t find it endearing, waiting expectantly as he also worked on his own progress in the meantime.

He had appropriately begun scouring the library for books related to the Legacy of the Malefic Viper and had also searched for lessons related to the skills, only to encounter a rather glaring issue on both these fronts: There were no books directly about the Legacy skills, only legacies in general, and on the lesson front, there were only really some related to Palate of the Malefic Viper. Jake did stumble across a scarce few related to Sense and Blood too, but both of these were incredibly low-level ones and seemed to be more about how one could obtain the skills. Quite a ways from finding a method to upgrade it to legendary rarity.

So rather than looking for direct sources on how to upgrade his skills, he began researching the more general methods of upgrading Legacy skills and skills close to what he had. Perception-based sensing skills to find herbs or toxic materials and whatnot were extremely common and well-researched, so Jake happily dove in and began reading. He decided to first focus on ways to improve the far less impressive Poison Sense he had merged into Sense of the Malefic Viper, hoping to find some inspiration.

His enthusiasm quickly dwindled as he went into the section on practice methods. As with most things, the best advice given was just to get practical experience. However, the books heavily advised against the alchemist trying to test and improve sensing skills during combat for a variety of reasons. First, it was overly risky to try and focus on it during a fight. Second, you wouldn’t know your opponent properly and what skills they had to avoid your senses, nor their poison resistance, making progress far less reliable. Third, it was just hard to properly focus and think logically and analytically while in a battle. Using the poison on someone far weaker than yourself wasn’t as helpful for research as using it against someone of equal or superior power, which is why the alchemists who had written the book recommended the same thing: living test subjects.

They suggested "investing" in these, preferably in the form of a slave or a bound creature, to do this. As you needed someone or something stronger than yourself, it even mentioned that renting one was possible, but emphasized that another great benefit of living subjects was the ability to use the same one and track the progress that way. It reduced the number of factors that came into play from using new test subjects every time, and if one got a sapient slave that was professionally trained, they could even have skills to convey the effects of the toxins—something especially useful when experimenting with mind-affinity poisons.

As Jake read all this, he was a bit taken aback. Not by what it said, but by how it was written. It was clearly considered normal and not at all something anyone would question. It mentioned using these subjects with the same phrasing as one would use regarding any other type of tool, like a cauldron.

Needless to say, Jake was not going to get any test subjects, and the more he read about it, the more he understood why Meira had kind of assumed that would be part of her job when she first met Jake. It was, in the eyes of the Order, considered a task akin to tending the gardens or any other service the slave could offer.

Jake still wanted practical experience with his Sense of the Malefic Viper, and he ended up finding some good things. There was a training dungeon set up by the Order that one could spend AC to enter, and it housed a lot of different toxins with innate properties to hide as well as some beasts and monsters to practice on. Making a mental note, he decided to visit one of these places.

On the subject of Blood of the Malefic Viper, it was something of a dead-end, as the lessons were either about how one could possibly gain the skill or how to use the skill in alchemy. There was one lesson that seemed worth checking, and Jake also mentally noted that.

As Jake researched and did some light alchemy, whenever he got bursts of inspiration, he felt movement within his sphere. In the entrance hall of the mansion, four figures stepped out. One of them was naturally Meira, with the three others being an elf, a scalekin, and a very tall dwarf or small ogre. Half-ogre, Jake guessed.

He didn’t move to greet them, as they all headed to the library as expected. Jake saw them all walk and talk, and everything seemed nice. A cursory look made it clear the half-ogre was primarily a close friend of the scalekin, while the other elf stuck closely with Meira. Meira did seem a touch out of place, but Jake saw her smile whenever she answered, making him happy.

They entered the library, and Meira began finding some books as the other elf helped. The scalekin and half-ogre just sat down at a table as they waited. It almost looked as if they hurried Meira, but he wasn’t sure, considering he could only see and not hear anything happening.

After locating the books, they took their seats and began discussing things. Jake simply looked on as nothing noteworthy happened for the next fifteen or so minutes. Finally, Meira said something to the other elf, her customary nervous face on full display. The other elf nodded as the two of them left the library, the scalekin seemingly yelling something after them.

At that moment, Jake cursed the ever-present enchantments on all the doors and walls that isolated sound, effectively making every room the inside of an isolation barrier. Meira and the other elf headed straight for Jake’s laboratory, where he had spent the last few days. They talked a bit more, and just before Meira could knock on the door, Jake made it open telekinetically.

What? He wanted to show off a little in front of Meira’s friend.

"My Lord." Meira bowed the moment she saw him.

Jake was sitting in a rather comfortable chair behind a table, feeling like a boss about to interview a new employee. "Hello, there," he said, greeting them with a smile. One they couldn’t really see, as Jake had chosen to keep his mask on. Turning to the other elf, Jake nodded. "You must be Izil?"

The other elf bowed slightly. "Indeed. It is a pleasure to meet you… Hunter, was it?"

Oh, yeah, I used that pseudonym. Kinda forgot about that, huh? Jake thought. "Just call me Jake, and please, come in and take a seat.” He honestly couldn’t be arsed trying to conceal his real name. Irin knew it, which meant the entire Humanoid Resources Department knew it, which meant anyone with just the slightest level of clout could find out.

"Thank you," Izil answered as she entered the laboratory. She looked back towards Meira and then back at Jake. "If possible, can we speak just the two of us?"

Jake wasn’t that surprised, considering she had asked to meet him. He did wonder what she wanted and really hoped it wasn’t something weird. Chances were she wanted to take advantage of his status, even if she only believed he was a black-token alchemist.

"Of course," he still answered. "Meira, if you will."

She nodded and bowed, though she did look a bit nervously at both Jake and Izil. Meira was naive, but not stupid, and likely had some of the same thoughts as Jake… or maybe she was just afraid Izil would offend Jake, making Jake kill her. She knew who he really was, after all.

After she left, the isolation barrier activated, making no one able to spy on the two of them anymore. With great interest, Jake allowed Izil to speak first after sneaking in an Identify.

[Elf – lvl 141]

"Firstly, I must thank you for meeting me. I am aware you are a busy individual.” Izil spoke courteously, but Jake already knew there was a "but" coming down the line. "I am Izil, a royal associate of the Altmar Alchemy Association and currently a gold-token outer member of the Order of the Malefic Viper."

Jake nodded, having already introduced himself before. He didn’t see any need to explain he had a black token, as she clearly knew, though he was surprised at her being a gold token.

"I believe you already have an inkling as to why I am here?" she continued.

In a hurry, Jake tried to figure out if he should know why she was there. Nope, I have no bloody idea why or how I should know, but…

"It is related to Meira, right?"

It had to be. She was the only commonality between them.

"Correct. Just to clarify, then Meira is a slave which you own or at least have the ability to decide ownership of?" Izil asked very matter-of-factly.

Jake nodded.

"This may be overreaching, but may I ask why you are having her attend lessons as she currently is? From the research I have done, you appear to have a backer making you able to afford some splurging when it comes to Academy Credits, but even so… what is your intent?"

"You are overreaching," Jake dismissively said, feeling like he was being interrogated. "You do not need to know what I intend, but if you are worried, then I can at the very least assure you I mean no harm to Meira. All I want right now is for her to learn and grow."

"How about the future?" Izil asked. "I am aware you are from the new universe, so it is understandable if you do not know this, but the Altmar Empire has a standing order in place to free and help return elves found in involuntary servitude to the Empire."

Okay, Jake did not know that. He was a bit skeptical, but when he thought on it further, it made sense. The Altmar Empire was an empire of elves, and according to what he knew, a bit, eh… "judgmental" towards those who were not elves. For a race believing themselves superior to not want their brethren to be slaves, or maybe even viewing it as an insult if some were, wasn’t surprising. It did raise some questions as to why there clearly were many elven slaves around, but that wasn’t a discussion he wanted to start. However, even if such a standing order was in place from the Altmar Empire…

"I do not see what that has to do with me," Jake answered.

"I mean no offense," Izil quickly made clear. "I am merely saying that the reason I approach you is backed and supported by the Empire, as will be any eventual compensation. In essence, I am asking for the possibility of buying out Meira’s slave contract."

"Oh?" Jake asked, a bit interested. His plan had always been to find a way of freeing Meira. Currently, he wanted her to become a full-fledged member of the Order by herself, but if there were alternatives, he was open to them.

Izil understood that Jake was not entirely against the idea and smiled. "This proposition is not only to benefit the Empire or you, but Meira as well. She has shown quite the talent from the moment I met her, and seems to only be growing in potential. Especially very recently, she has had tremendous improvements. For her to remain a slave is simply wasteful in my eyes. If she was free, she could also return to the Altmar Empire, where even more possibilities exist. Additionally—and this is merely my own personal feelings—I am fond of her and wish to see her grow and forge her own Path. One where she is free."

Jake listened on, and while he didn’t say anything, he was debating it quite a lot internally. If Izil told the truth, it was a truly good offer. It would allow Meira to get her freedom and stop being a slave, and it would even allow her to go to the Altmar Empire. All-around good stuff, and a difficult offer to refuse. Oh, and of course Meira had made a lot of progress in recent times. She was being privately tutored by a god.

"It is worth discussing," Jake concluded, “but it is not something I believe the two of us should ultimately decide. It is Meira’s choice."

Izil looked surprised at Jake’s response, but she still nodded somewhat tentatively.

Jake then stood up and motioned for Izil to follow. "I will admit, I have kind of been hoping to meet her friends, so I shall come along when we go fetch her."

Izil now looked even more confused and surprised. "Those two people in the library with her right now aren’t her friends. Nor mine, for that matter. We were asked to group up for a collaborative project for sparring purposes, and the two of them made her an easy target. I stuck around at first to try and recruit her, but I was hesitant due to her meek personality. And as I said… I have grown fond of her. But those two are definitely not friends; I can guarantee that."¨

Jake frowned. "Explain."

"The scalekin is called Nella and is the daughter of a true dragon who got together with an influential B-grade member of the Order of the Malefic Viper, while the half-ogre Utmal is nothing more than an attendant of her family who managed to enter the Order due to sheer nepotism. Her status is not to be underestimated, and she knows it. I hear that she has even more powerful relatives, some even reaching above B-grade. In other words, they are not to be offended, even if you are blessed by the Malefic One and have a black token. While I am not sure if I can call their treatment of her outright abusive, they…"

Sighing, Jake listened as Izil explained their group’s dynamic. Nevertheless, Jake was still insistent on going. He couldn’t say he was surprised that Meira’s interpretation of friendship wasn’t normal, but he was still a bit disappointed. But more than disappointed, he was just sad. From what Izil said, they were just taking advantage of her.

Taking advantage of him.

"I implore you to not make any rash decisions," Izil said as they exited the library, sensing his negative emotions.

"I won’t," Jake said.

The two of them walked toward the library as Jake observed it in his sphere, and now with some context, Jake saw that the scalekin’s yelling likely wasn’t just friendly banter. The snickering of the half-ogre also clearly wasn’t innocent.

Still, Jake wanted to keep a cool head and not pass judgment based solely on the words of another. He would judge the situation himself and ask Meira to figure out what was going on. As they got close enough to the library, Jake noticed the door had been left slightly ajar, allowing some sound to escape.

"How fucking incompetent can you be? I can’t comprehend why the hell that owner of yours bothers to keep you around.” Upon hearing the scalekin’s words, Jake froze.

Froze—and considered if Viridia’s offer of corpse disposal was still available.

Chapter 12

A Teaching Moment

Jake was no expert in friendships. He would never claim to be. But what he did know was that the scalekin called Nella was definitely not a friend of Meira. Now, while Jake did want to just barge in and raise hell, he chose to listen to Izil and act with thought. At the very least, he should give them a chance to explain themselves.

The door was already ajar, and they soon detected Jake as he got closer. It was almost comical how the facial expression of the scalekin changed when she detected Jake and Izil coming. Rather than a sneer, she adopted a neutral smile, trying to look like less of a bitch.

"My Lord," Meira greeted once he entered. He had seen her running back and forth collecting books, and yet she didn’t carry even a hint of discontent.

"Ah,” Nella said, “good to meet you—"

"Shut the fuck up," Jake said the moment she started speaking. His aura flared for a moment with killing intent as Izil took a step back along with Nella. The only one of the newcomers who stayed unaffected was the half-ogre, and the reason for that was simple enough.

[Scalekin – lvl 152]

[Half-ogre – lvl 190]

Utmal, as she was called, was far stronger than any of the others, and Izil’s assertion that she was more of a bodyguard than anything else was very likely accurate.

Nella still stood frozen as Jake spoke, and Meira looked extremely surprised, if not downright horrified.

"Meira, have you ever had any friends before?" Jake asked her.

The poor elf now looked even more confused as she stuttered, "I… I don’t think so?"

"Then let’s have a brief lesson on what friendship is," Jake said as he turned to the scalekin. "Tell me, do you consider Meira here a friend?"

Nella, surprisingly enough, didn’t raise a ruckus, but merely responded honestly. "What a nonsensical question. Of course I don’t. Now, if you weren’t so rude despite it being our first meeting, I would maybe consider offering you the honor of my frie—"

"You can shut up again," Jake cut her off once more, getting a very angry glare from the half-ogre, which he completely ignored.

Meira looked entirely taken by surprise after Nella answered. Jake nearly felt like she was about to cry, but instead, she just nodded with realization and bowed. "I apologize if I misunderstood, and—"

"You have nothing to apologize for," Jake said, also cutting Meira off.

Izil finally decided to get involved after the initial shock of the situation. "Nella, at least admit you did purposefully make her believe you were friends, even explicitly stating it to make her give you things."

"You just have to get involved?" Nella scoffed. "And yeah, I did. What of it? This is the Order of the Malefic Viper, if you haven’t noticed. Are you seriously trying to act like lying for personal benefits is some kind of heretical sin or something? You people are beyond me; it is her fault for being a gullible idiot, not mine." She then turned to Jake and smiled. "Don’t blame me for taking advantage of your little pet project. Is it not your fault for being too wasteful?"

"I guess you could argue it is my fault for not being more observant of the trash I allow her to drag home," Jake said in a cold voice.

"My Lord, I—" Meira began, and Jake was honestly a bit frustrated, as he knew what she was about to say.

"Meira,” Jake said in a rather scolding tone, “stop. Stop putting yourself down and stop thinking everyone can treat you however you want.” He pointed at Nella and Utmal. “Stop thinking you are lesser than them. I am not having you learn and take lessons for fun, but for your own sake. It is about time you have some damn self-confidence and take some charge of your own Path.

"Those two are nothing. Trash by the wayside. If you allow trash to treat you as lesser than them, what does that make you? What does that make me, who choose to believe in you? What does it make your teacher?"

Jake felt like he had been very patient with Meira so far, but her mindset was simply too different from what it had to be to survive. Not just in the Order, but in the multiverse. If his gentle approach didn’t work, he would go a bit harder. Even after everything, Meira still viewed herself as lesser than practically everyone else. He hadn’t really picked up on this, as the only ones he really ever saw her interact with were himself and Duskleaf, and expecting her to be casual with them was a hard ask. But she had gotten better with Jake, making him hopeful.

It was just disappointing to see that hope squashed.

And speaking of getting squashed, the two unwelcome visitors clearly weren’t fans of Jake’s words.

"Big words from some new initiate who just entered the Order,” Nella said with a smile. “Do you think you are suddenly a genius unlike any other just because you managed to get a black token? People like you tend to just squander and have their feeble egos broken as they begin to fail. So what if you have a backer? You are still nothing.” She motioned toward Meira. "You are already showing your weakness when you bother with a little whore like her. You waste time and resources on useless things. I don’t even get what you are trying here? Sure, yeah, sorry for hurting your fragile ego by messing with what’s yours. I had my fun with your whore while it lasted, and I will of course respect it if you don’t want me to mess with your property."

"Nella, you—" Izil began.

"Oh, shut up already; you are even more tiring than the human," Nella cut in with scorn. "I wanted to approach you to do some networking with the Altmar empire, but you are just too damn infuriating to deal with. Always having to be the hero and protecting the little elf, but never even daring to really speak up. At least you were smart enough not to make unnecessary enemies, unlike the human."

Now, one might ask why Jake allowed her to keep talking. The reason was simple enough: He needed Meira to hear. While she had initially seemed like she wanted to explain things away and even excuse Nella, he now saw a far different expression. It was hard to read, but definitely a mix of anger and crying. What he was certain of was that she was hurting.

He did also see Izil look ashamed when Nella pointed out her own lack of truly standing up for Meira. Jake chose not to judge this particularly harshly, as at least it seemed like she had her heart in the right place. He also wanted to keep making it a teaching moment.

"I can at least respect the confidence," Jake said with a smile. "The confidence to walk into my home acting like this and expecting nothing to happen."

Nella laughed. "Last time I checked, we were allowed to come here. Are you so daft to not even know the rules of the Order?"

Izil, off to the side, also sent Jake a warning using telepathy. "Be careful. Any violence, especially killing, goes against the rules, and even if you have some influence, so does she. Keep calm."

"Oh, I do know the rules," Jake said as he walked over to Meira. He saw her still looking utterly lost with tears in her eyes as he spoke. "Meira. These two aren’t your friends. They never were. Don’t consider this a tragedy, but merely a teaching moment. Believe it or not, in spite of our unconventional relationship due to the contract, I consider you a friend, which is also why I want to give you a choice before we go any further."

She looked up at him, and once Jake was certain she was listening, he explained, "Izil and I spoke just before coming here. She offered to buy your freedom and make you a part of the Altmar Empire. Even take you back there. With the status of a citizen of the Empire, it will allow you to finally take charge of your own life."

Izil seemed relieved at the subject change, and surprisingly, Nella and Utmal also seemed interested.

"That is correct," Izil said with a smile. "The Altmar Empire has an official decree to free any elven slaves, and the second I found out you were one, I knew I had to talk to your owner. While we have not discussed any details yet, I—"

"One Credit," Jake quickly added. "That is the price for her freedom—for the complete annulment of the contract. We can discuss the details, sure, but I do not want anything for it."

Izil and Nella both looked surprised, but not as much as Meira. She stared between Jake and Izil before asking Jake, "You want me to leave?"

Jake sighed. "It is not my choice. But I can share with you that my initial plan was for you to become a member of the Order and then annul the contract. I want you to be free and make your own choices, and this will be the first time where I will truly ask you to choose after I made you choose your own lessons. You don’t need to pick right now, but can take however long you need to—"

"I want to stay with Lord Thayne," Meira said decisively, shocking Jake a bit. She had not only interrupted him, but said Lord Thayne instead of her usual go-tos. Her decision was also not what he had expected, especially given the speed with which she’d made it.

"Think it over," Jake said. "This is a chance for freedom. Here and now. If you need funds, I will help you and make sure you can go to the Altmar Empire safely. You will be able to finally be your own person. Meira, you are far more skilled than you think and can make it on your own. You don’t need to rely on others."

"I want to stay," she said decisively again before finally turning a bit meek. "Please?"

"Oh, this is all so damn touching," Nella finally burst out as she turned to Jake. "Damn, you must be a good shag to have her wrapped around your finger like that, or is she really just that pathetic?"

"Lord Thayne and I have never slept together, and I have never been with a man," Meira said, standing up for herself for the first time. In a weird way, but hey, it was something.

"So you can talk back?" Nella said, faking amazement. "And that declaration just makes this all the more pathetic. Seriously, is your dear master some limp-dicked loser who can’t even get it up? Or does he swing the other way and bought the wrong product when he went slave shopping? This must be one of the funniest days in my life."

"I… You suck!" Meira practically yelled, red in her face.

Nella just found it amusing and shook her head.

Jake looked on, a bit proud, before nodding. "If that is your choice, fine. But the part about being freed and becoming a member of the Order is nonnegotiable unless you can find another way to safely be freed. We can talk about all that another day, though, as we have some trash to take out first. Tell me, Meira—what kind of punishment do you think these two deserve?"

She was still new to the whole making-choices thing, but Jake believed in her. Also, while he wasn’t exactly keen on the two of them, the one they had wronged the most was Meira, not him. So even if Jake had a way he wanted to handle the situation, he would respect whatever Meira wanted.

"This is a fucking joke at this point," Nella said, laughing out loud. "Actually too funny. Seriously, what the fuck are you gonna do? Do you think you can even do anything? Want to call your backer or what? While I don’t want to talk badly about my seniors, I am beginning to question what error in judgment one must have made to pick you. I also find it laughable how you think you are some bigshot who is in charge here. If you truly try to start shit, it won’t just be your ass, but your backer’s on the line, as I am certain my ancestors will happily raise hell. So go ahead, make my day even better."

Meira still stared at Nella and Utmal as the scalekin spoke. Utmal just smiled at Nella’s side, making it clear she also found this entire situation funny. Jake had the clear read on them that they were truly just taking this as some kind of entertainment. Perhaps messing with Meira had just been some way for them to pass the time while getting some benefits. They had never considered it a big deal to begin with.

After a few seconds of no one talking, Nella finally shrugged and looked at Jake. "I am bored of this. Oh, well. Fun while it lasted, and I shall consider sending someone to ask for compensation for wasting my time. The level of delusion you people have is astonishing. I hope your backer comes to their senses and gets rid of you, because anything else would truly make them a moron."

"Punishment…" Meira muttered as she looked at the ground, still standing with Jake.

Her speaking made Nella and Utmal wait with anticipation until something finally happened. Meira turned to Izil with searching eyes, but the elf just looked down at the ground, making it obvious she would not involve herself further. A bit cowardly, but again, Jake would not judge her, as she was essentially a representative of her faction.

Meira instead looked at Jake, who just waited for her answer. "I don’t like them. They did wrong… but more importantly, they insulted Lord Thayne, and… the one behind him… That is not just wrong, but unforgivable. I…" She looked towards Izil.

Nella smiled, and Utmal also chuckled at her side. They still had the same confidence. Jake had not asked them to leave, and they both felt safe. The rules of the Order protected them, they had backing, and Utmal was at a higher level, even compared to what Jake was falsely displaying. They had every reason to feel confident. They had just made one major fuckup—one with such a minuscule chance to occur that no one could really fault them for missing it.

Jake smiled at Izil as he understood what Meira meant. Before anyone could react, he was in front of Izil and used Gaze of the Apex Hunter. He placed his hand on her forehead as Touch of the Malefic Viper activated, sending in a pulse of soul-soothing poison, instantly knocking her out.

"Now that, I did not see coming," Nella said with some surprise. "You also didn’t like that bi—"

"You know," Jake cut in as he saw Meira at Izil with worry and Nella and Utmal with genuine hatred, "I am nearly grateful to you. It is good for her to learn that shit people exist and to be careful of them, and you two are prime examples of shitstains."

Nella wanted to speak, but Jake didn’t let her as he released his aura along with Pride of the Malefic Viper.

"Now, you talked about rules earlier," Jake said as he walked slightly closer. Utmal placed herself in front of Nella defensively as she prepared herself. He could only laugh at her horrible stance, showing that while she was probably strong, her actual level of fighting experience was limited. "While this isn’t a rule I remember being stated explicitly, what are the punishments for blasphemy of the Malefic One?"

"Death," Meira answered instantly.

"Come the fuck on,” Utmal said. “Just because you have a lesser Blessing, you think insulting you is—"

"Nah, not at all. But calling the Viper a moron for choosing to back me? Now that, I would say is very much in the camp of being questionable." Jake smiled. "But I don’t know. I am not the one making the rules or even the one enforcing them, so let’s ask someone more qualified." Jake took out his token and sent a simple message before putting it away again. "She should be on her way, but in the meantime, I believe I shall make the executive decision of doling out some punishment of my own."

Seeing as they were in his library, Jake thought it preferable to first get them out of there. His aura flared as he used Pride and Gaze to launch a mental attack, stunning both of them momentarily. He then teleported forward and punched both of their faces as he tossed them into the hallway, sending them smashing into the wall. The construction of the mansion was at a level where he had no way to even damage it, resulting in both of them coughing up blood from the impact.

Utmal got up to respond in a hurry, but Jake was already there. His katar flew forward and stabbed her in the chest just as a large hammer appeared in her hand. His other katar punctured the dominant arm holding it as he tore the one in her chest upward, slicing her chest badly. The half-ogre tried to counter but, despite her level, made a pathetic attempt.

She was stabbed multiple times in the chest before Jake finally finished her off with an uppercut through her chin and out the top of her skull. Utmal never got a chance to fight back.

Jake didn’t even bother with the notification as he turned to the stunned Nella, who held her token in her hand.

"You are fucking insane!" she screamed.

Just then, there was movement as two auras descended. A man and a woman, both wearing robes with the motif of the Malefic Viper, appeared inside the hallway as they observed what had happened. Jake knew what they were. Enforcers.

"This madman went insane and killed my companion!" Nella screamed the moment she saw them, but she still had the energy to throw Jake a glance with glee at the misfortune she expected to overcome him.

Yet no such thing happened. Both of them merely bowed as a third person teleported in.

Nella stared at the Hall Master, but Viridia didn’t even acknowledge her presence before bowing towards Jake, joining the two other enforcers as she spoke, "I greet the Chosen."

It was at that moment that Nella knew she’d fucked up.

Chapter 13

Two Very Different Fates

The entire hallway was silent. Jake couldn’t help himself as he enjoyed the look on Nella’s face. She looked so utterly horrified and confused. It was a wonderful contrast to her formerly smug and overly confident demeanor that made it clear she believed no one could touch her, and that nothing she ever did was wrong.

"Thank you for coming on such short notice," Jake said, greeting Viridia with a smile. "I take it your two colleagues are also in the know?"

"They are both bound by a contract with the Order and have absolute confidentiality," she answered assuredly as she finally addressed what was happening. "Can you explain the situation?"

"You know what?" Jake said with a rather sinister smile as he motioned toward Nella. "I think we will have her explain it. Nella, would you be so kind as to explain what is happening here?"

Nella simply sat frozen as she stared for a few more seconds, not even recognizing Jake had spoken to her. She finally seemed to collect her senses somewhat as she looked at Jake. "You are the Chosen of the Malefic Viper?"

"Now who is the daft one?" Jake asked jokingly as he quickly turned to Viridia. "Oh, yeah, that is one of the reasons why this entire situation is as it is. She called me dumb, and I am pretty sure she also called the Malefic Viper a moron at some point?"

"I… You misunderstood. I—" Nella quickly shut up after getting a stare from Viridia.

"To summarize, she offended the Chosen and potentially the Malefic One?" Viridia asked.

"When you say it like that, it sounds bad, but yes, that is exactly what she did," Jake answered casually. “The one I killed didn’t really say anything but was just her silent cheerleader.” He had to admit, he was probably enjoying this way more than he should, and it was only helped by Meira looking completely fine with everything that was going down. Happy, even.

Viridia simply nodded and asked, "What are your plans with the two remaining visitors?"

"Leave the elf alone; I knocked her out to avoid her seeing any of this,” Jake explained. “As for our dear scalekin, I shall figure that out promptly, as you quite honestly arrived far faster than I had anticipated. So if you would do me the favor of waiting outside until we are done, it would be great. Afterward, I may need a bit of a clean-up crew.”

"As you wish.” Viridia bowed as she and the two enforcers simply teleported into the garden in front of the mansion.

This left Nella, Jake, Meira, and an unconscious Izil left alive in the hallway. One could ask if it was necessary to call Viridia there, but he decided to do so to make it absolutely clear how much Nella had fucked up. It was pure vanity and, honestly, just the fastest way to convince her he was actually the Chosen.

Nella looked up at Jake and did exactly what he expected her to do: beg.

"I… I didn’t know," Nella said as she fell to the ground and pressed her forehead against the floor. "I beg for your forgiveness and will do anything! Please, my family can compensate you handsomely, and… I… I can even become your slave!"

Jake just sighed. "You still don’t get it, do you? I don’t give a shit about you. Never did. The one you need forgiveness from is not me, but Meira. She is the one in control here."

Nella’s eyes darted to Meira instantly, and she groveled at her feet. "Meira, I am sorry; I would have never done those things if I knew! I beg you, please, I will do anything you want."

Meira looked at Jake with misty eyes as he asked her, "So, Meira, what do you want to do? These are your enemies, not mine. True, I did take the initiative with the half-ogre and got my own personal frustrations out, but this one is all yours."

"Won’t… Won’t it expose you as the Chosen if she goes free?" Meira asked with concern.

"Maybe,” Jake answered, “but I already told you that no matter what, I will respect your choice… though, no, I will not have her become a slave.”

"She doesn’t deserve to be, either," Meira muttered as she looked deep in thought, finally asking him, "Lord Thayne, why are you being nice to me?"

Jake was taken aback by the question. His usual response would just be not to bother with her. If he had just wanted her to be a member of the Order and get out of his hair, he wouldn’t do what he was doing with Nella either. While he certainly had felt a considerable amount of responsibility for her, as she had been dumped on him by the Viper, he didn’t act solely out of duty. He considered Meira a friend, even if he did know that was entirely one-sided since she viewed him as her superior in every way. So… the real reason was probably as simple as they came: He didn’t really have one. He just wanted to.

"Because I decided to be," Jake answered with a smile. "You don’t need some profound reason for every decision. Sometimes you just go with your gut and see where that leads you."

Meira nodded as she looked down at Nella before looking back at Jake. She finally gritted her teeth as she stammered out, "I… I suffered a lot before I came to serve Lord Thayne. But after coming here, I have been treated so well, and I even did things for myself. I then met Izil, Nella, and Utmal, and I thought I had finally even gotten friends… but they were just using me. That hurt more than even the poison-resistance training… and when I was being tortured back then, I hoped every day that my torturer would just drop dead."

Nella opened her eyes wide as she continued begging. "I never did anything that bad to you! I just did what everyone would do, and it was never personal or done to hurt you! Please believe me, if I had known, I would have never—"

"You would have never even spoken to me if you knew I was a slave…" Meira said sadly. "I didn’t think I had to hide it, but after you and Utmal found out, you treated me worse than before… Why did you need to be cruel? If you had actually been a friend, I would have helped anyway."

"We can start over!" Nella said, grasping at straws. "I will never disrespect you again, no matter what! Please!"

Meira just sighed sadly as she looked at Jake. "I have never killed anyone," she said in her usual meek tone.

Jake didn’t answer, just acknowledging that with a nod. It made sense she had only ever killed mindless beasts, if even that, considering her healer class.

"I am not sure I want to, either…" she muttered as she seemed to finally have made up her mind. "I think we should hand her over to the enforcers and the Hall Master and have them decide on a punishment."

Jake failed to hold back a small smirk. They all knew what that meant.

"Please! Meira, don’t do this. Didn’t you say you considered me a friend? Can you really do this to your friends? I—"

She didn’t get to say more as a robed figure appeared within the hallway and instantly knocked her out, with Viridia and the other enforcer appearing a moment later. Jake had naturally let them know that Meira had decided and conveyed her choice.

"Are you sure you want to leave the last elf be?” Viridia said as she motioned toward Izil. “We will be able to cover this incident up rather easily if all loose ends are removed."

Jake looked at Meira even if he knew the answer, and she vehemently shook her head as expected. "Nope, leave her be. It may lead to complications down the line, but it is what it is.”

"Very well. How do you want these two to have died? With honor or disgraced? We can even make it a scenario leading to severe punishment of their ancestors and families, if you so desire.”

Meira looked incredibly uncomfortable at the mention of going after their families, and Jake also thought that was overdoing it.

"Meira, you are still in the arena of decision-making here," Jake informed her.

"I don’t want their families to suffer because of what they did… They already lost someone, and that is enough…" Meira said in a rather weak voice.

Jake nodded. "Have them die with a modicum of honor. I will leave how to handle it up to you."

"Very well,” Viridia said. “I intercepted the scalekin trying to send a message out of this residence with her token earlier, and I will use that to make up a story by sending messages to relevant parties. How about them bringing back a valuable item to the Order but dying in the process? That way, we will offer slight compensation to their families on account of their deeds. I doubt they will ever raise a ruckus with this approach, and if they do, well, I shall also handle that.”

Meira nodded after Jake threw a questioning glance at her. Also, he really wanted to ask about her intercepting messages sent from the token and apparently being able to doctor messages too. Jake had not heard anything about that being a thing, as all official information indicated it was an absolutely safe form of communication within the Order. Turned out that was a fucking lie.

"That will be fine, and once more, thanks for your help.” Jake then jokingly added, “Just to let you know, I don’t plan on making this a habit.”

"I would not complain if you did." Viridia smiled as she bowed.

After a few more pleasantries and thanks from Meira to Viridia, the Hall Master and two enforcers left, bringing along the unconscious Nella and the corpse of Utmal. They even made all traces of them having ever been there disappear—corpse and all.

That just left the minor problem called Izil. Now, Jake had absolutely no plan regarding how to hide his identity from her. Not because he didn’t want to hide it, but because he had made a spontaneous decision to knock her out to at least give himself a chance. He considered what kind of story they could spin but came up short.

If he said he’d killed them and had his backer cover it up, she would instantly know that was either a lie or that his backer had to be really far up in the hierarchy within the Order. It would almost have to be a god, and considering his Blessing, he could see her figuring it out. Gods did not back someone blessed by other gods, which is why the basic assumption had always been that Jake had a mortal backer, as any god would have to be the Viper, and that surely couldn’t be a thing.

"How long will she be unconscious?" Meira asked with a hint of worry.

"Eh… not long? Hopefully. The poison isn’t harmful by itself but is good at knocking people out and making them calm as can be. It shouldn’t take more than an hour or two, I reckon.” Jake smiled, having explained all this with a relatively high level of confidence.

Something that would later turn out to be a mistake.

Irinixis sat and stared into thin air while waiting to be called into the chamber. Her time since returning from the dungeon and figuring out Lord Thayne was the Chosen of the Malefic Viper had been anything but calm, and she had been flung into a whirlwind of bureaucracy and intrigue.

For the top brass to involve themselves in the dealings of a D-grade or even C-grade was incredibly rare, if not downright unheard of. So when an order came down from the Hall Master’s office to report anything related to Draskil and his group directly to them, it had raised quite the fuss. When it became clear that Irin had been part of the dungeon group with him, the fuss had turned to her. She’d been swarmed by colleagues and superiors, eventually leading to her being called by the leader of the Humanoid Resources Department. The mortal leader, that is, as one of the Witches of the Verdant Lagoon now sat at the very top.

Irin understood why a god would not get involved, as that would make it clear that someone in the group was well and truly out of the ordinary. As it was, one could at least find explanations for why the Hall Master wanted the report directly. With the Order undergoing a renaissance after the Malefic One’s return, a lot of things were done differently than before.

Nevertheless, she was nervous about what her superior would ask her. Would she try to probe and figure out details about Draskil? The Malefic Dragonkin was at least an excellent red herring, and with the Hall Master actively helping by specifying interest was on him and not Lord Thayne, she hoped the Mistress wouldn’t ask too much about him. While Irin had plenty of confidence in herself, she didn’t at all believe she could resist the probings of the Velvet Mistress. She was an S-grade succubus, and Irin had heard she was approaching the demi-god tier. For someone like her, Irin was like an open book.

"Irinixis, please enter," a voice suddenly said, throwing her out of her thoughts. She hadn’t even noticed the attendant approaching her.

"Thank you." Irin bowed to the attendant as she got up and walked through the gate in front of her. She appeared within a mostly red room with silk-like cloth hanging from the ceiling so far above she couldn’t even see it. The room was filled with a thin red mist, and Irin saw a woman lying across a bed on a slightly raised platform.

"Irinixis, my child, I am so glad you had time to come visit me," the Velvet Mistress spoke as she sat up on her bed and tapped the spot right next to her. "Come over here and join me."

Irin was incredibly nervous but didn’t dare argue as she went over. When she got closer, she finally properly saw the Velvet Mistress. She was a succubus like her, but Irin did not dare compare herself to the woman in front of her. One could only describe her as a personification of beauty, and even Irin found her face reddening as she approached.

The Velvet Mistress was a famous figure and was known to have many lovers from all sorts of places. There were even gods on her list of usuals, and her personal network of information could rival that of some factions. Yet she had chosen to be the leader of the Humanoid Resources Department of the Order of the Malefic Viper because apparently "the one who got away" was part of the Order. It had long been a topic of discussion among the demons who this mysterious man could be, but none had figured it out quite yet, and the Velvet Mistress certainly wasn’t sharing.

Irin, who had gotten lost in thought again, finally found herself in front of the Velvet Mistress. The Mistress took her hand and made her sit on the bed beside her as she smiled. "I am sure you have many questions as to why I asked you to come. Contrary to what you may believe, I am not going to question or interrogate you. Things are changing within the Order, and everything is telling me you are finding yourself rather close to the epicenter of this change. While I cannot be sure, I feel confident enough to bet on it."

"What does the Mistress need of me?" Irin asked, unsure and a little bit uncomfortable being too close to the woman. She felt her face heat up as the Velvet Mistress smiled again and leaned closer.

"I want you," she said in a teasing tone before giving Irin some space as she stood up, leaving the young demon beet-red in the face. "I am serious. If you are truly close to the epicenter of this, you will need to be up to the task. We cannot lose out simply because we miss our chance, now, can we? So I have an offer for you, my dear.” Changing her tone to one of tempting, she asked, “I haven’t had a disciple in a few thousand years, but what do you say?"

Irin didn’t even need to consider it before nodding, as she was in a state halfway between shock and elation. Within only a few days, she had gone from just being just another random employee of the Humanoid Resources Department to sitting in the room of the Velvet Mistress and being offered a disciple position.

All because she had been randomly assigned to a certain group from the 93rd Universe. One that happened to include a certain extraordinary human that had become the impetus of change for the Order of the Malefic Viper by making their Patron return to the world.

Chapter 14

“You are never going to let me live this down, are you?” - Jake Thayne

So, some good and some bad news. On the good side, Jake had now figured out how to put other people in a coma that they didn’t seem to wake up from by themselves, even after three days. On the bad side, Jake had now put someone into a coma and didn’t really know a way to wake them up.

Izil had been "sleeping it off" on the couch for a full three days, and Jake’s initial assessment of it only taking a few hours tops for her to wake up had been a little off. In his defense, he had kind of gone in with the assumption that Izil had some kind of innate poison resistance like everyone else seemed to, but Meira made it clear Izil never worked with poisons at all. She had come to the Order to learn about poisons exactly because she lacked knowledge in that area. So, yeah, pretty big oopsie there.

The type of poison he had infused was inspired by the ethtoxin he had killed the big blue mushroom under Haven with—the kind that was incredibly hard to detect and eliminate. So hard to eliminate that Izil’s body didn’t seem to register it as harmful and had just absorbed it all into her very soul within a short period.

At least it appeared to be slowly losing effectiveness by itself, but with how slow it was, Jake reckoned her recovery would be measured in months and not days. Maybe, in hindsight, it wasn’t a good idea to infuse so much damn poison that fast just because he wanted to knock her out instantly?

Meira was beside herself with worry, and all Jake could do was assure her that Izil was technically fine. It wasn’t like she was in any danger from the toxin, and as a D-grade, she didn’t have to drink or eat. Jake had, on the third day, turned to Villy despite really not wanting to… because he knew what was coming. He had chosen to do so during a time when Meira was out and attending a lesson in case the Viper decided to do exactly what he did next.

The very second Jake tried to contact the god, Villy popped into his living room like he had been waiting. "Finally, you come crawling! Fucked up a bit, now, have we?"

"Yeah, yeah…" Jake muttered, having already accepted the incoming mockery. "I messed up and now must ask my honored Patron for any advice on how to fix it. I’m considering infusing her with more poison to counteract it, but that just seems like a bad idea."

"Definitely something you should only do if you have confidence in your abilities and full knowledge of both poisons. So, yeah, that is totally out of the question, considering your recent track record." Villy smirked.

Jake sighed again as he tried to briefly change the topic. "How did it go with those two?"

Villy knew what he was talking about and shrugged. "Viridia handled it. She made some smoke and mirrors, sent some fake messages, and reported to the scalekin’s family that she died during a mission. She then gave them some compensation and what is essentially an entrance ticket to the academy for any youngster they want to send here."

"Are you sure there won’t still be trouble down the line? I can’t see them not investigating and raising a ruckus if they find something amiss." Jake was a little worried about that. Mainly for Meira, as she had interacted with them for a long time, and he feared that they would approach her to investigate.

"I think you severely overestimate how much these factions actually care about some D-grade dying. Even if they suspect something is amiss, they won’t do anything about it. The only reason large families like that would make it an issue was if they felt slighted or to save face. What you did is quite the opposite, and one of their members dying for the Order only reflects well on them. In fact, I have a feeling they will gladly play into the story and make use of it. While the bond between parent and child may seem strong to you as a human from a newly initiated universe, it matters little to most who reach high levels of strength. I guess you cannot fault them, as when you outlive child number one hundred, it gets hard to care for each one individually, and you begin to view them more as assets than people. It is only if they prove themselves and become strong that the parents will begin to actually care. Well, that, or have talent making them worthy of recognition."

Jake frowned as he heard this. It was hard to grasp parents not caring for their kids at all. Okay, maybe they did care a little, but still. Maybe it was just his pre-system mindset and his relatively young age that made him think that. For someone that had lived for tens of thousands of years and had hundreds of children, perhaps caring less was just a natural reaction to seeing your children die. A defense mechanism, perhaps.

"Ah, but I do want to note how funny it is that you go so far to hide your identity as my Chosen and yet freely and happily make use of the benefits it offers," Villy teased.

Jake smirked in response. "Well, I wouldn’t want to hide it if it didn’t come with my life turning into a damn circus of clowns wanting to suck me off. I never hid on Earth that I am your Chosen and happily answered anyone who asked, because people there didn’t have the insane reaction to it everyone has here. Believe it or not, I am not embarrassed to have that True Blessing."

Villy smiled for a moment before he shook his head and looked at Izil, who was sleeping on the sofa. "Alright, let’s get on with the topic at hand. If you want to wake up that elf, you have a few obvious choices. Here, let me play teacher a bit: What are your options, from your limited point of view?"

Jake had already been ruminating on the topic for the last three days and, of course, had a few ideas. "With my newly upgraded Touch of the Malefic Viper, I can try to control the poison and extract it from her by isolating it somehow. I could also try to make an antidote that directly targets the energy of the ethtoxin to make it go away faster. Lastly, I considered making a toxin and then controlling that poison to wake her up by attacking her soul to get a response."

The snake god listened on as he nodded. "All very good solutions, except for the fact that the poison has entered and been integrated with her soul, making it far harder for you to do anything with it."

"Exactly," Jake agreed, having already figured that out. Usually, a poison would operate within the Soulshape and physical body of a target, but this poison had entered a deeper layer of Izil’s soul, and Jake couldn’t truly detect or feel it anymore. He only vaguely got a sense of how much remained from Sense of the Malefic Viper. And even that was only because he had made it and thus had a far easier time sensing it.

"So, you are all out of ideas that you fear won’t end up causing more harm than good?" Villy asked.

"More or less," Jake said with resignation.

"Alright… Jake, I must admit, for a simpleton that usually does the simplest shit to solve a problem, you have really gone above and beyond yourself this time." The Viper failed to hold back a laugh. "Tell me, what does the poison you injected do?"

"It soothes the mind and makes one relax.”

"Okay. So what would be the best kind of antidote to that?" the snake god asked leadingly.

"Something that un-soothes the mind and makes you unable to relax?" He was a bit confused, but then it finally clicked. "Oh… fuck me," Jake muttered as he face-palmed. "You are never going to let me live this down, are you?"

"No. No, I am not, oh, my dear Chosen.” With a massive grin, Villy asked, “So, what is the complex solution to this absolute mind-bender of a conundrum?"

"A slap or a solid shake…" Jake said, embarrassed.

"What is that? Oh, I think if you yelled loud enough or splashed some cold water on her, it could work too." The Viper laughed, but Jake wanted to crawl into a hole.

He had not put her into a coma… She was just fucking asleep. A long sleep, sure, but any external stimuli should wake her up in a jiffy the moment her soul had finished absorbing all the poison. He had essentially only "knocked her out" for ten minutes, with the rest just being her sleeping.

"Okay, change of topic,” Jake said, desperately not wanting to talk about his fuck-up anymore than necessary. “When do you think Meira is ready to apply and become an official member of the Order?"

Villy, in his infinite mercy, agreed and answered with a shrug. "I am not really following her progress, as I quite frankly don’t care, but I am sure Duskleaf knows. However, chances are she could join on her own merits by now. The only real thing standing in her way is her mindset and absolute codependency on others."

"I thought you didn’t care to know about her?"

"I don’t, and yet I know that. But enough about her—you should get back to work and actually get some levels under your belt and upgrade some of those skills. Chop, chop. I didn’t give you infinite Academy Credits and an entire Academy to play around with for you to waste time on sleeping elves and petty drama between D-grades.” His voice was quite a bit more serious than usual.

Jake frowned at the sudden sense of urgency. "Is there something coming up?"

Villy just smiled. "You are in a newly integrated universe… There is always something coming up. Now get moving, and good luck. I still got that ale ready for next time, when you aren’t so preoccupied."

"So, a sense of urgency, but I still have time to drink with you?" Jake asked jokingly.

"Naturally. Being my drinking buddy is an absolutely essential task as my Chosen." The Viper waved in farewell. "Bye!"

With that, he was gone, and Jake was left alone with Izil in the room.

"Gotta make up a bullshit story for Meira," Jake muttered. He was not going to tell her that Izil had been sleeping for three days just because no one had bothered to wake her up.

Jake waited for Meira to come home before he woke up Izil, feeding her some bullshit story that he had found a solution and eliminated all the toxins. Once she was awake, Izil looked around, confused, before going into a flurry of questions.

A lot of lying, deceit, and convincing later, and Izil left. She definitely knew the story they had fed her was false, but at some point, she had just stopped questioning them and accepted their horrible tale. He had tried to go with the official version that the Order had made and said that he had knocked her out after he revealed who his backer was, trying to keep it under wraps, and that after a heated discussion, Utmal and Nella had left.

They had then promptly accepted a mission and done it super quickly, but died in the process within just a few days. Yeah, the more Jake thought about it, the more clear it became that the story was absolute crap, and everyone knew it. Jake didn’t think Izil knew he was the Chosen, but she definitely knew something was way, way off. Enough for her to stop probing, anyhow.

"Do you think Izil and I can still be friends?" Meira asked after the other elf had left.

"I don’t see why not," Jake answered truthfully. "Just always be a little less trustful of others, okay? Even Izil. Be on the lookout for her probing for information and maybe even call her out on it if she asks. At some point, me being the Chosen will be revealed to everyone, and I am sure she will understand why you chose to hide it then."

Meira didn’t seem entirely sure about it but still nodded and thanked Jake for his help. Over the last three days, Jake had noticed some subtle but very welcome changes in Meira. Firstly, she used "you" way more when addressing Jake than before. She also came and asked for stuff at times, and didn’t seem to try and hide away most of the time when Jake was around. While he wouldn’t say she appeared confident, she was at least a little less timid. Still super timid overall, but baby steps and all that.

The following days were thankfully without any distractions or blowback for anything that had happened recently. He didn’t hear anything from Irin, and all he heard from Reika was an update that Bastilla was still freaked out but way calmer. Draskil had chosen to leave on a solo mission not long after they returned from the dungeon, and would likely be gone for the foreseeable future.

This allowed Jake to once more focus on what he had come to the Order to do: alchemy. Alchemy and improving his profession skills. Jake quickly fell into a schedule that consisted of research, crafting, practicing skills, going to lessons, and having the occasional resistance training session with Meira, often if not always coupled with Duskleaf teaching him about formations. On top of that, he had a certain simulacrum to deal with whenever he meditated.

It was understandable if one viewed this as overwhelming, but one had to remember that Jake had all twenty-four hours every day. He never slept or rested and just kept working. If he ever got tired out from a certain task, he would simply switch to something else. Slight headache from reading hard-to-understand tomes or a lesson about improving sensory skills aimed at a level far above D-grade? Do some mindless crafting. Low on resources from mindless crafting? Work on improving skills. Lack of violence? Go train with sim-Jake and fight a chimera.

Like this, days turned to weeks, and weeks soon turned to months. There was little change in what he did, but the sheer scope of tasks made things never seem samey, and he always had something interesting to pursue. Halfway between the second and the third month of this particular session, there was one shake-up of the usual schedule. One Jake had been waiting for and looking forward to.

The final skill selection for his profession in D-grade.

Chapter 15

A Real Anomaly

The levels had come faster than Jake expected during this particular training session. Maybe it was because he was actually crafting a lot this time around, but it could also be due to him simply progressing in so many areas at the same time. Not that he had any way to truly find out, as the system wasn’t very liberal with sharing information on exactly how experience worked. Shit, for all he knew, the recent "D-grade drama," as Villy called it, could have helped him progress. Anyway, it got him to 180 in his profession, which gave him another skill selection that he had very much been looking forward to.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 180 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 176 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Jake liked skill selections, even if he had to admit a lot of the initial excitement and enjoyment had begun to wane the more he got. It was rare that he was offered more than one or two skills he would even consider, and the only truly interesting skill choice he had recently was the last one for Avaricious Arcane Hunter, which made him go back and pick up the common-rarity Stealth Attack skill. That one had actually taken some thought and required not just picking the highest-rarity one every time. After skipping the fucked-up ones, like the curse- or slavery-related skills, of course.

But the level 180 skill selection was a bit different for one simple reason: It was the last one before C-grade. Each profession or class came with some built-in skills that would be offered no matter what, and often the best was saved for last. For his class in E-grade, it had been Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter—a skill that was still extremely potent, even now.

He hadn’t really had one for his profession in E-grade, but that was due to him hunting down the nine "of the Malefic Viper" skills, making him not really care about anything else. But this time around, he had no such thing. In fact, the last two skills he had picked for his profession had been about rituals and core refinement—both things that weren’t part of this core skillset. Truth be told, Jake didn’t really need that many more alchemy skills due to how all-encompassing the Malefic Viper Legacy skills were. This did also mean he had no idea what to expect when he saw the prompt and opened it.

*Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper profession skills available*

Jake would usually go through the options one by one at this point. He would write some off for being weird and more just view his offered skills as representations of the progress he had made. But this time was also different in that aspect.

The offerings were the usual ones. There was an upgrade to Graft Plant that seemed a bit interesting, a skill about creating special acids that he maybe would consider, another one about curse magic that he didn’t want, and finally, a fourth one related to Jake leading group prayers for the Viper that he noped the fuck away from.

He barely registered these as he went to the bottom skill. As mentioned, Jake had no idea what to expect from this final skill offering, and he had to admit, it was a surprise. A good one… maybe?

[Anomalous Soul of the Heretic-Chosen (Legendary)] – Heresy and orthodoxy united in one body, power claimed from both. To be both a Chosen and a Heretic requires not only mental deviancy but a truly anomalous soul to reconcile opposing concepts. A soul that only grows more unique as you walk further on your Path as a Heretic-Chosen. Due to your connection to your Patron, your mana will begin to carry faint hints and morsels of the Records of the Malefic Viper when crafting poisons, making each creation more potent. Due to your identity as a Heretic, this is not granted but taken, resulting in significantly increased mana expenditure during this process. As your soul mutates, so does it get empowered, allowing it to break convention. Going forward, every stat point in Wisdom increases your Mana Points by 12.5 rather than 10. May your very existence become an anomaly that shuns normalcy for power as you continue paving your own Path as a Heretic-Chosen. Note that this skill results in a permanent change. Losing your status as a Heretic-Chosen or your profession will make the skill further mutate and transition into a race skill.

It was weird. Just weird in so many ways. This was certainly a skill of a type he had not been offered before. It was entirely passive, from what he could see, and did something Jake always looked for in skills: It had an ability he could not in any way replicate himself.

But this one felt a tad out of left field, even if he should ask himself if it truly was. Jake walked a very weird Path, and he intermingled many concepts and Records within himself at all times. The mere fact that his Soulspace was as powerful as it was proved that Jake was an anomaly, as Villy had made it very clear that sealing something like the Eternal Hunger chimera in there was not something a D-grade should ever be able to do. He knew this was likely just a side effect of this Bloodline, but his choices also had to have contributed. Integrating sim-Jake had only strengthened him further, too.

The actual effects of the skill were in the simple department—at least, from the looks of it. It was essentially an all-around buff to all poisons Jake crafted, with the downside being an increased mana cost during the crafting process. On top of that, it granted an overall increase to his mana pool. The biggest part of the skill was clearly the mana pool from Wisdom, and this was also what he was the most worried about.

This skill would permanently alter his soul. It would give him 25% more mana, which was even more together with the existing 25% bonus from the Mask of the Fallen King. However, he knew that these kinds of alterations did not just come for free.

His soul as it was could already be considered fully utilized, so to somehow expand it had to come with losing something in return. There had to be some consequences. The system had some innate sense of "balance," and even if gods like Villy found ways to slightly skirt around these balancing mechanics, Jake was not at all at a level where he could do that. At least, that is what Jake believed. He wasn’t sure at all, though. Gritting his teeth, Jake delayed his choice for a moment as he asked his Patron god…

"Villy… are skills that permanently alter your soul generally considered good or bad?"

"I will need some more information than that," Villy asked in return almost instantly, seeming very interested right from the get-go.

"I am offered a skill that allows every point of Wisdom to give more mana than it already does, but it permanently alters my soul in return," Jake answered.

"Do you, in turn, lose some of your stamina or health?"

"No. It also allows some of your Records to get mixed in when I craft to make poison better at a higher mana cost, but it doesn’t seem directly connected to the Wisdom part. And it is the Wisdom part I am worried about."

"So, you are wondering what else you will lose to allow you to get this increased mana pool?"

"Yeah." Jake nodded.

"Firstly, did you know that while the 10 points per stat are pretty standard, it isn’t universal? In fact, it is only really a thing for the so-called enlightened races. Many beasts have innate racial skills, especially those of massive size, that make each point of Vitality give them far more health points per stat. How else do you think a massive mushroom that is around your own level can have a mana pool ten times your own? Or how a massive whale the size of a planet doesn’t waste all its vital energy to heal a minor wound? But you are right in your case as an enlightened race; it usually comes with a trade-off. The trade-off is built into the races who gain these racial skills, but for you, as a human, you have no such thing. But I think I see a way and an explanation for you to be offered it anyway without the usual trade-offs.”

Villy’s explanation was something Jake had honestly kind of figured out a long time ago. If not, then it made no sense how he could fight and damage beasts for so long without them dying.

"What way?" Jake asked curiously.

"You are walking your own Path, which is already incredibly hard as it is. Your soul is already ridiculously powerful, and you can handle this mutation without losing yourself at all. That is why you get it offered, I reckon, as without a powerful soul like yours, the system would never even give you the choice of risking such a mutation. As for the price of the skill… I think it lies in proving your Path. To put it in simpler terms, you increase the Records you need to progress, and you have to prove yourself more than before to gain each level or evolution. Along with that, faltering in your Path may lead to downright disastrous results. I am talking a full-on soul implosion or you evolving into something very unpleasant.”

Jake listened as he tilted his head. "Doesn’t seem like an actual drawback? Or more just something I already deal with as a high-tier profession? Wait, will it make each level slower to get, experience-wise?"

"It is an extreme drawback for most, and no, it will not make each level easier or harder. At least, I don’t think so. Jake, I need you to understand that you are really walking your own kind of Path here. You are forcefully channeling the Records of a Primordial through your soul without dying, you experience true Records of a time long passed, and you have a Soulspace far more powerful than any D-grade I have ever encountered. You are a Heretic and a Chosen at the same time while getting away with it. Your sheer level of ego is forcing two opposing concepts to unite within you. So I do agree… The actual drawback a soul mutation brings likely won’t negatively affect you, as you are already a damn anomaly and a freak.”

Jake was not entirely sure if the god was praising him or not, but he chose to take it all as a compliment. Also, Jake had not shared the name of the skill, but Villy still called him an anomaly, so clearly, he agreed the skill fit Jake.

"Anyway… good skill?” Jake asked. “Also, how come you didn’t pop in this time and chose to keep the conversation telepathic?"

"Of course it is a good skill. Very upgradeable, too, I reckon. Don’t worry about evolving it, by the way. Improving it should not increase the drawback at all. Why do you think all my Legacy skills can only be obtained at ancient rarity and below, where they only give one stat point per level in your profession? As for why I didn’t pop in, well, I got my own stuff to deal with sometimes. This is one such time where I don’t want to dedicate an avatar to visit.”

"Fair enough, mate. Thanks for the help as always, and good luck with your endeavors." Jake had a feeling Villy didn’t wanna share what he was up to and naturally respected that.

"See you around, and keep up the leveling," Villy said in return as the connection was cut off.

Without delaying further, Jake selected the skill.

Are you sure you want to select [Anomalous Soul of the Heretic-Chosen (Legendary)]? This skill will lead to permanent alterations to your soul.

Another prompt asked him if he was really sure, once more putting emphasis on the skill not being a casual choice. With resolution, Jake confirmed. The moment he did, he felt an odd sense of vertigo. His Sphere of Perception momentarily retracted entirely into his own body, and all of his senses were completely cut off. It lasted less than a second before his sphere spread out again like before, and all his senses returned.

He expected more to happen, but it didn’t. The only thing that seemed different was Jake now feeling a slightly larger pool of energy he could pull from and control. Jake wanted to make sure nothing had somehow gone wrong, so he checked his status.

Status:

Health Points (HP): 50198/50210

Mana Points (MP): 60123/100296

Stamina: 31851/37060

Yep, his mana had increased from around 80,000 total to over 100,000. It was so odd that having his soul change and mutate didn’t do more than it had. So very odd. Jake stared at his status for a good while longer before reaching a conclusion.

"My stamina is way too fucking low compared to my mana points now."

Okay, not a conclusion as to why he didn’t notice a soul mutation more, but as to what a big future issue would be. Currently, Jake never really ran out of mana during a fight, as he already had a large pool and further increased regeneration from the mask. Then there was the occasional poison he was infected with or the mana from the Scales of the Malefic Viper legendary upgrade, which allowed him to absorb a bit of energy from magic attacks.

This meant his current bottleneck when it came to Endurance was his stamina. Rather fitting, considering the name of the resource pool. Still an issue, though. But he had the solution—he just needed for Meira to return first.

He spent the next few hours testing out stuff and drinking mana potions to fill up his pool to see if that felt different. Jake had wondered if maybe he would feel it when it went above the 80,000 he had before the skill, but nope, not a problem.

After four hours, Meira came home, and Jake quickly approached her in the hallway. "Hey, Meira, wanna come shopping with me?"

Meira was taken aback at the sudden question. "Are you sure you don’t just want me to go out and acquire the desired products as usual?"

"Yeah, I’m sure I want to go myself this time and wondered if you didn’t wanna come," Jake answered with a smile. "I also wanted to take you shopping to finally get you some proper equipment. You are above level 140, so there has to be some good things available for your level by now that you can hopefully use for the rest of D-grade."

While Jake had leveled a lot, Meira’s speed was far faster. When Jake had first met Meira, she’d been level 109. So even if her progress was not meteoric, it was still pretty damn fast, and one had to remember that she was not grinding levels through fighting, but nearly only with her profession. She had mentioned getting quite a few class levels, too, due to her healer class benefiting from some things, but only three or four.

"Equipment?" Meira asked with genuine confusion. "Why?"

It was a pretty good question. Meira could borrow everything she needed for alchemy, and Jake had gifted her a spatial item quite a while ago for convenience’s sake. So why the equipment?

"The world sucks, and you will need to learn how to fend for yourself a bit better, so I think getting some practical experience under your belt would be healthy," Jake said.

"I… Is Lord Thayne sure?" Meira said nervously.

"Yeah. Don’t worry—won’t have you join a war or something, just do a few dungeons or go hunting a bit with a party. You will be fine." Jake hoped that would calm her down. Didn’t work very well, but what can you do?

"Okay…" Meira muttered. "What does Lord Thayne need to buy?"

Jake smiled. "A whole lot of elixirs."

What better way to get more Endurance than that?

Chapter 16

A Small Shopping Trip

The last times Jake went shopping, he had either gone to the vampire place—because he also wanted to sell stuff—or gone with Villy to get new clothes. All other shopping after that had been done by Meira for a few reasons. First of all, it saved Jake time. Second, Meira was incredibly insistent on doing it, as she was almost desperate to prove herself useful—something that had gotten better recently—and lastly… Jake had no idea where the hell to go shopping in the first place. Like, he had some ideas, and he could just go where he’d gone last time with Villy, but he didn’t feel confident. The problem was that the place he and the Viper went was fucking huge, and Jake really didn’t want to wander around for hours on end to try and find what he was looking for. Could he ask someone for directions? Probably, but that was also something Jake really didn’t wanna do. Asking strangers for directions sucked.

So dragging Meira along and buying some equipment for her was just killing two birds with one stone. The two of them left only about an hour later, with Meira taking the lead and first bringing him to a place primarily dealing with alchemical products.

The Order of the Malefic Viper didn’t have any official stores, and as far as Jake knew, there was no massive trade emporium run by them either. All the stores one could encounter were run by individuals or other merchant organizations that simply operated within the Order. All the Order really got out of it was a small tax added on each product sold and payment for the spaces they occupied. This system allowed individual merchants to use the Order to progress, and for alchemists from the Order to easily earn money by selling their products to one of many merchants eager to work as their broker. A bit like how Sultan had helped Jake.

He would probably love it if I brought him to the Order and had him get a store here, Jake thought as he entered a large street from one of the many large, gateway-obelisk things spread throughout this part of the Order.

Jake had gone to the same general area as he had with Villy. This was pretty much the epicenter of trade for the Order and filled with shops catering to every kind of customer. To call it an entire city was no understatement, as Jake reckoned it was larger than any metropolis on Earth had ever been. This city was split into several districts that were then split into grades, and each district was further split into smaller portions based on product type. Jake had gone to the D-grade part of the trade city.

"I have gone to this store many times when Teacher or Lord Thayne asked for me to get alchemy ingredients," Meira explained as they walked on the street.

Jake chose not to comment on her using what many would interpret as a less formal name for Duskleaf by just calling him Teacher compared to calling Jake Lord.

"I will be in your care, then," Jake answered with a smile.

It was honestly nice having someone just lead you around when shopping, so he didn’t have to go scouring himself and probably end up getting scammed due to having no idea what the hell anything was worth. Not that he doubted he would still come out fine. With the exchange rate of Credits from the 93rd Universe and his already-massive amount of funds, calling Jake loaded was an understatement.

While alchemists did tend to be on the wealthier side, they rarely got truly rich, as they also spent a lot. Buying materials for experiments that led to no usable products was just a pure money-sink, but a necessity to progress in your craft. Jake felt very fortunate he had yet to run into any issues in that department, as he just gave Meira however many Credits she needed and didn’t think about it much.

It was a bit weird that Jake had worked in finance before the initiation, but after the system really didn’t care much about money. Perhaps that was a testament to how little he’d actually cared about his job and life before the system. Sim-Jake hadn’t cared about money, either, but rather preferred jobs that challenged him, indicating that perhaps this sort of apathy towards money was just natural.

To Jake, money was just a means to an end to allow him to do what he wanted. Maybe he would care more if he actually needed money, but as things were, it was an absolute non-issue, and something was also telling him that he could make a lot of money if he truly needed it. If he became absolutely desperate for funds, he could probably just sell the autograph of the Chosen to some fanatical A-grades or something.

Jake was thrown out of his wayward thoughts on the importance of money when they finally reached the store Meira had wanted them to go to. It was a large building that was beautifully decorated, with a very gaudy-looking sign in front depicting a cauldron emitting dark green mist and surrounded by mushrooms and plants. It was even magically animated.

Besides the sign, which made Jake question the artistic sense of the creator—the idiot had included mushrooms—the building looked nice. He followed Meira inside, where a female scalekin attendant wearing a suit-like uniform greeted them.

"Welcome to the Cauldron’s Dream; how may I be of assistance?" the scalekin asked courteously.

Meira looked at Jake as he answered, "I am on the lookout for Endurance-increasing elixirs and, if possible, some ingredients containing ethtoxins, or at least ones useful when creating soul poisons. I also just need some natural treasures related to soul magic in general."

The ingredients were self-explanatory, as Jake really wanted to get better at soul poisons due to their potency, but his desire to buy Endurance elixirs could be questioned. Primarily to ask why he didn’t just craft them himself, and the reason for that was pretty simple: He didn’t want to. He could; it would just take a lot of time, and making elixirs truthfully wasn’t that stimulating for him.

"How many elixirs are you in need of, and will they be for D-grades like yourself, or ones of lower grades?" the attendant asked.

"Just for me, and I need enough to add approximately six hundred stat points total.”

"Certainly, I shall have an offer ready in a few minutes. If you would please follow me so we can look at our stock for the soul items. Please do not hesitate to make me know if anything catches your eye and you have further questions.” She then smiled and led Jake and Meira into another room.

Meira had explained that it was pretty normal that no price was offered right away on products, and that there would be a brief waiting period. Jake guessed this was due to variable pricing, or maybe just to do some paperwork.

"Is there a specific type of material you are looking for, or products of a certain grade?" the attendant asked once they entered a far larger room than before.

"For rarity, I will need uncommon rarity and above, but some rare and above would also be welcome," Jake answered. "As for if I am looking for anything specific… not really."

"Very well, let me see what I can do. If desired, I could also ask one of our resident alchemists to assist you in selecting ingredients?"

"No need," Jake said. Not to be an ass, but when assessing if he wanted ingredients, he trusted his own senses more than some resident alchemist’s.

The attendant simply nodded before motioning for Jake to follow her over to a large tome on a stand. She then directed Jake to look through their inventory as the pages changed. One page of the open tome depicted an alchemical ingredient with a three-dimensional picture that even gave off a faint aura and scent, while the other page contained written information on the ingredient displayed. As he changed the page, he saw that natural treasure also appeared, and if he wished to, he could open an index. No matter how many pages he turned, the book didn’t change, making it look like the tome had infinite pages.

Jake became very engrossed in this as he looked through the different offerings, ending up spending nearly two hours before he decided on what he wanted. The attendant seemed perfectly patient and ended up just chatting with Meira.

The elixirs also came rather quickly, and it was only after Jake was done browsing that he got to see them.

[Patientia Elixir (Common)] - An elixir created from a mix of common ingredients, along with a few uncommon ones and a Beastcore of unknown origin. Allows any who drinks this elixir to receive some of the innate power of the materials, enhancing one’s Endurance. +5 Endurance upon consumption.

Requirements: D-grade or higher.

It was just as Jake had expected when he was shown the one hundred and twenty bottles. All of them were exactly the same and clearly mass-produced to sell. All Jake saw when he looked at them was saved time, and he proceeded to make it clear he would buy all one hundred and twenty.

For soul items, he ended up buying way, way more. Way more than he had expected to. The reason why he even wanted these items was that he had a few goals in mind. Firstly, he needed some of it for the rituals with Duskleaf, and secondly, he wanted to work on making a certain kind of poison, and for that, he felt like he needed as many different kinds of ingredients as possible. So, yeah, he had chosen to get a lot of ingredients—around a hundred different kinds—with plenty of stock for each of them. Seventy-one were of uncommon rarity, eighteen rare, six epic, and one was an ancient-rarity natural treasure. The ancient rarity and most of the epic-rarity ones were the only cases where he bought one each. He had all of this written down on a magical sheet of paper that the big book of browsing "printed" out.

The attendant stared for quite a while at the final list when Jake showed it to her. She looked up at Jake with puzzlement. "Sir, did you make a mistake? I count over four thousand individual items here…"

"Sounds about right.” Jake nodded.

She looked at him with judging eyes and stared him up and down as if to assess him. “I mean no insult, but before we proceed, I have to be certain you possess the funds for a transaction of this size. The final tally for all these items is… over one-point-two billion Credits.”

Despite saying the number, the attendant seemed shocked, and Jake was also somewhat surprised. Cheaper than he had thought.

One had to remember that Jake had left Earth with about four billion Credits after the Treasure Hunt auction. But those were Credits from his universe. After exchanging them for Credits used in other universes—all of which had the exact same going rate—he had, in actuality, about four hundred billion, given the one-to-one hundred exchange rate. So to spend a billion or two on alchemical stuff wasn’t that big of a deal to him. What else would he spend money on anyway?

"Yep, that seems fine," Jake said. "Does that include the elixirs?"

"Yes…" the attendant said, taken aback. "Is sir certain?"

"Yeah," Jake once more confirmed as he proceeded to use the system-feature thing to show that he indeed had the Credits available.

The attendant did a one-eighty in attitude as all her doubt disappeared, and she displayed a massive grin. "In that case, allow me to process you, sir."

With the attendant smiling giddily, Jake completed the purchase and got all of the stuff he had wanted. It was delivered in a special spatial storage bag that Jake quickly emptied into his own inventory, as the herbs would do better in there.

Jake and Meira left after that, and Jake failed to hold back a grin as she saw the attendant dancing with joy inside the building behind them. Never had it been more obvious that the store had a commission policy.

"That is all I really came shopping for," Jake said to Meira on the street outside. "Now it is all you. We need to get you a full set, excluding the spatial necklace, right?"

"Lord Thayne, is it really necessary?" Meira asked nervously.

"Meira, I just spent over a billion Credits while you waited patiently for me to finish. You have worked for me for quite a while now, and I have yet to really give you anything, haven’t I? So don’t hold back. Even if it is not for fighting, good equipment can help you with everyday tasks.”

"Okay…" Meira relented, having learned that there was no real arguing with Jake once he had made up his mind. Also… while it was faint, Jake did feel a bit of happiness in her voice.

The two of them headed back towards the gateway obelisk they had used to teleport into the trade city and walked through a gateway leading to another part of the district. After waiting for a few minutes for the queue to clear, that is. Despite having many obelisks and each obelisk having four gateways operating at once, there were still people waiting simply due to the number of people that came through. To say that the city was buzzing with activity was an understatement, and Jake understood why shops absolutely loved being placed there. Even while inside the alchemy shop, he had seen several people come and go.

After passing through the gateway, they found themselves in a new area and headed towards some shops Jake and Meira had picked out before coming. Meira had asked Izil for advice, and Jake had asked Reika to ask Irin. He had considered contacting Irin personally but had stopped himself, as he felt like that would lead to an entire conversation, and he really just wanted to go shopping.

Anyway, they headed to the shops Irin had suggested first, as Jake reckoned she had to know the good spots. After all, out of everyone Jake knew who was around his own level of power, Irin was the one who had been in the Order for the longest.

Reika had given Jake a list of three from Irin, and it did not take long to find the first one. It was a large red building with many customers going in and out. Most of them were women, but some had men accompanying them.

A women’s clothing shop, Jake quickly concluded as he headed inside with Meira. Once inside, Jake saw that it truly was a high-tier establishment, and an incubus quickly walked up to greet them when they entered.

"Welcome!” he said in a friendly tone. “You two look like new faces. First time coming here?"

"It is," Jake confirmed.

"Were you referred by someone?"

"A succubus friend named Irinixis mentioned the place," Jake said truthfully. Not a referral, but he had learned about it from her, and Jake didn’t think she would recommend a place for Reika to visit if there was no way to get in. Oh, yeah, that was what Reika had done—asked Irin where she could go if she went with Jake to get some equipment.

"Ah, I see!" the incubus laughed. "Come on in, then! What are you two looking for? Something for the gentleman or the lady?"

"Equipment for her," Jake said as he motioned towards Meira.

She looked pretty nervous as she regarded the high-class entrance hall. Jake himself also scouted the rest of the building with his sphere but found that everything on the second floor was just a distorted mess, while the first floor was just a bar of some kind, a few meeting rooms, and overall nothing interesting. The reason why it was distorted was due to the liberal use of space magic to expand all the rooms and save on real estate. It had been the same thing at the alchemy shop.

"I understand," the incubus said as he looked Meira over before glancing at Jake again. "Just follow me, and I am sure we can find just the right things."

Chapter 17

Equipment for Him & Her

Jake had a confession. He had never actually been shopping with a girl before in his life. Well, besides with his mom, but that wasn’t really shopping together, more going shopping at the same place separately. Even when he had a girlfriend, it had never happened. Perhaps another indicator of how poor that relationship had actually been.

This meant he really didn’t know how this sort of thing usually went down. Like, what was he supposed to do? Just follow along? Should he wait outside? As he was utterly clueless, he chose to simply follow the incubus, as that guy seemed confident in what customs were. Meira looked as clueless as Jake, as she had likely never actually gone clothes shopping due to her life before coming to the Order, making them both absolute newbies.

The incubus led the two of them into a private room. It was as lavish as every other place Jake had seen in the establishment, but the entire room was a bit off compared to what Jake had expected. It was large and had a few couches, with a mannequin as a centerpiece. That part was semi-normal, but Jake had no idea why the hell there was a king-sized bed in the room. It gave him a bad feeling, but he tried to explain it away. Probably just doubles as a hotel or something.

He knew he was just grasping at straws, and his final attempt to deny he had gone somewhere very unplanned was shot down the very next moment.

"Considering it is your first visit, let us start out light," the incubus said as "clothes" were summoned on the mannequin. He used the words clothes very loosely, as there wasn’t a lot of it. What was displayed was a mini-dress with a few crucial parts missing, especially in the chest region.

Jake just stared as Meira turned red like a tomato.

"Basic, yet irresistible in its simplicity," the incubus said with a polite smile. “This one is a very popular item amongst humans and elves alike, so what say you? If you want to, you are even allowed to test out some of the items we offer in the room provided, but you must buy them if anything gets damaged.”

"If Lord Thayne wants me to…" Meira said in an almost whispering voice before Jake spoke up.

"Big misunderstanding!" Jake exclaimed. "Huge one. We are not like that at all, and came for actual equipment, not… this. You know, things that give stats and stuff and help when something attacks you."

The incubus seemed taken aback at what Jake said and asked clarifyingly, “You were referred by Irinixis, though? I apologize if there is any confusion, but we deal not in armor, but equipment with quite a different use—one I dare claim just as important as combat."

"Not questioning that, just saying it isn’t what we came looking for," Jake quickly said. "I apologize for wasting your time."

"No worries, young man," the incubus said, unbothered. "If you change your mind, you are free to visit once more. Both of you. Now, if you are looking for equipment for the young lady, may I ask what type? What does she specialize in?"

"Healer and alchemist," Jake answered, happy that the incubus didn’t make a bigger deal out of the awkward situation than he needed to.

"In that case, I can recommend a quaint little store just down the street run by a friend of mine," the incubus offered as he waved his hand and displayed a magical 3D map.

Jake recognized it instantly as one of the stores Irin had also recommended, making him clarify, "Just to make sure, they just sell normal equipment, right? Gear for the battlefield, you know."

"They do indeed, though I would once more argue that the battlefield of the bedroom is one too often neglected," the incubus said semi-jokingly.

Jake didn’t comment on it but just excused himself once more as they left, getting a few light jabs on the way out and stares from other patrons who no doubt made assumptions about the human and elf exiting a private room. Once they were outside on the street, Jake couldn’t help but joke with Meira a bit to relieve the tension. "Well, that was a screw-up. Sorry for that; we’re never going back there—that is for sure."

"Yeah…" Meira nodded.

He felt like she almost seemed disappointed—proof that he still wasn’t that good at reading social cues sometimes. Not paying it any mind, Jake and Meira headed to the second shop. It was a lot smaller than the establishment they had just been in and also had a lot less traffic.

It was small and quaint, with only a single story, and Jake and Meira headed inside right away. It was just as small and homey inside as it was from the outside, and it had fabric stacked on shelves all around. Jake had been in a few tailor shops in his life, and this one sure fit the bill.

He had already seen the one person in the store through his sphere, and she also noticed him and Meira when they entered. A small dwarf came out of the backroom with a smile a few seconds later and greeted them. "Ah, welcome! What can I do for the lad and lassie?"

Jake briefly scanned her and took note that she was C-grade. Contrary to other dwarves he had met, she was wearing a light dress and was far from as bulky. Still bulky by human standards, but probably considered a stick by dwarf standards.

"I need some equipment," Meira said.

It was something they had talked about while going there—that Meira needed to ask for herself. Jake thought it was awkward to act like he was out shopping with a kid who couldn’t speak for herself regarding what she wanted. He knew it was because Meira didn’t want to actually decide what to get since Jake was paying, but he hoped he had put those doubts to rest.

"What for?" the tailor asked as she looked Meira up and down. Mostly up, considering the height difference.

"Uhm, everyday stuff and probably some fighting, I think…" Meira said, looking at Jake.

The dwarf nodded and asked Meira some more basic questions, like what stats she was looking for and what special effects she wanted. Jake just listened in as Meira answered everything and, as subtly as he could, began making his way towards the door. Meira noticed him, and Jake just smiled and gave her a thumbs-up before leaving her to do her own shopping. He’d already had enough awkwardness for one day and wasn’t going to be forced into a changing room or anything like that.

Considering he had some time to kill and was in a shopping area anyway, Jake decided to do some shopping of his own for a bit of gear. He had a few pieces of equipment he had been walking around with for a while and quickly settled on one of his older pieces: gloves.

[Gloves of Quintessential Arcane Manifestation (Epic)] – Gloves made from a powerful synthetic cloth. These gloves are incredibly thin, nearly unnoticeable, and incredibly resilient against all attacks. Will become immensely more durable if infused with arcane energy. The Crystalized Essence has been fully integrated. All constructs using your arcane affinity and your hands will last longer and be more potent. The gloves can store a large amount of arcane energy that can be released immediately. Channeling unattuned energy into these gloves will grant it your arcane affinity. Enchantments: +125 Intelligence, +75 Wisdom, +50 Willpower. Quintessential Arcane Manifestation.

Requirements: Lvl 115+ in any humanoid race. Quasi-Soulbound.

They were good. Arnold had gone above and beyond when he made them, but frankly, their effect just didn’t cut it anymore, for the most part. The blast he could shoot out of them was pretty much the same as what he could do by himself, and the only true value was how durable they were when he infused them with arcane energy. There was also the part about arcane constructs made with his hand becoming stronger, but as with most things in the system, that was all relative. When he got them, it had been noticeable, but now that he was several times stronger, it was utterly irrelevant. In ten or more levels, borderline none of its properties—aside from the stats—would do anything.

So Jake decided to check out a shop he himself had been looking at before they went. He had said that the Order did not run any stores themselves, but that did not mean members of the Order didn’t run their own stores and that members didn’t tend to have the biggest ones.

Jake headed for one of these shops, which he knew was run directly by talented members of the Order. It was new and had a pretty special requirement for those who were allowed to shop there: You had to be blessed either by the Malefic Viper or a god subordinate to him. He feared that he was walking into a madhouse of fanatics, but he also knew they had good stuff in there. Draskil had even mentioned it once during their dungeon run and said he’d gotten a legendary item from there.

Before he left Meira alone, he had placed a Mark of the Avaricious Hunter on her. He had zero confidence in finding her without it.

After going through another gate and walking down a large street even more filled than those before, he saw the building he was looking for. It wasn’t hard, considering it was a massive, castle-like building with the motif of the Order of the Malefic Viper proudly displayed right above the entrance. A massive tower shot up from the center of the castle, too, making it a landmark. Quite impressive, considering the building had only been around for about a year.

Not many people went there, but all who did were stared at when allowed entrance. With a sigh, Jake headed for the castle, and once he got close to the entrance, he felt a faint pulse scanning him. He was not blocked and simply walked through the entrance to enter a large hall. The moment he stepped inside, he felt many presences all around him—not from people, but from the statues lining the hall on each side depicting different gods. At the end of the hall stood the statue of the Malefic Viper. It depicted a gigantic, simple-looking black snake coiled up and facing whoever dared enter the castle.

Well, if this isn’t a way to try and humble anyone who enters, I don’t know what it is, Jake thought, getting flashbacks to the lesson with Viridia and the statue of Villy there. As usual, Jake didn’t care about the presences, but he still quickly understood what was happening. He chose to walk slowly through the hall before reaching a new gate and entering, trying to at least look a little worn out from the endeavor.

Only after going through the gate could he see the new area due to how spatially expanded it had been. And oh, boy, was it expanded. Jake entered an utterly massive, curving tunnel of sorts, extending what seemed like an infinity upwards. He also sensed that his Mark on Meira felt far further away than before. Far, far further.

"Greetings, Blessed by the Malefic One," a voice said as a figure teleported in. Jake instantly felt the pressure and knew this individual was a full-fledged B-grade. The person wore a hooded robe with the insignia of the Order on it, but nothing else was visible, not even their race.

"Hello, there," Jake said in return with a nod.

"What has the young master come looking for?" the hooded attendant asked.

Jake had studied a little and knew this place was quite unique, and Draskil had also said that the ones running it were high rollers of the Order.

"Equipment, preferably gloves. Also, if there are any items capable of awakening Records within an item to further enhance them, that would also be supremely useful.” While Jake had come looking for new gloves, he wouldn’t say no to also finding a way to upgrade his boots.

"The second request may be hard to fulfill, as such items are rarely found in D-grade," the B-grade said. "But for the gloves, we have plenty on offer. Please, do tell, what kind do you need? And do you walk the Path of the Malefic One, having embraced the Legacy?"

Jake wasn’t sure why the second question mattered, but he answered both. "I do possess the Legacy skills, and I need gloves primarily to help boost my physical stats. It would be best if they are highly durable."

The attendant nodded. "Please follow me."

Using a few hand motions, a portal appeared right beside the B-grade, and the person motioned for Jake to step through. Jake felt no danger or like anything was amiss, so he did. Once on the other side, he found himself in a far smaller area reminiscent of a trophy room. There were pedestals all over with items on display, all of them behind barriers a bit like what the vampires had used to preserve their items. It was the kind of barrier that helped items not lose their enchantments and power.

Jake could not even Identify any of the items due to these barriers. It wasn’t that he couldn’t properly see or sense them, but that the barriers themselves messed with whatever Identify did. Rather than getting full information, it only gave a brief snippet.

After using Identify on a few of the pedestals, all of them holding pairs of gloves, Jake got the gist of it.

[Gloves – Ancient - Medium Armor – Magical – Pride of the Malefic Viper – Requirements Not Met]

[Gloves – Legendary - Medium Armor – Magical – Touch of the Malefic Viper]

"Do note that the young master may only purchase a single item," the attendant said.

Jake prepared to ask why, then quickly understood: resale value. But he was still a bit confused about the descriptions provided. "Can you explain what the information given means?"

"The first three, I believe self-explanatory, while the fourth says if the gloves give physical or magical stats, with the final one displaying which Legacy skill the item is tied to,” the attendant explained. “Do note that in order to use the gloves, you need the Legacy skill at the same rarity as the gloves. If none here are usable, we can visit a lower floor. Do note that if you do not possess the required level to wear any item, your Identify should reflect that.”

Jake nodded once more in recognition. Made sense. He looked at a few more items before one truly caught his eyes.

[Gloves – Legendary - Medium Armor – Physical – Scales of the Malefic Viper]

They were all-black gloves and looked incredibly light despite being classified as medium armor. Thin black scales covered the item, looking almost like a pattern on the leather. Jake liked how they looked, and the description made him very hopeful it would do just what he wanted. It gave him good vibes.

"That one," Jake said as he pointed to the gloves.

"First, I must make sure the young master has the funds. Each legendary item here is priced at a billion Credits. Also, be aware that once the item is revealed, you must either purchase it or leave with nothing.”

Jake quickly displayed that he had the funds and didn’t see any scenario where he wouldn’t buy the gloves for a measly billion Credits. With a nod, the attendant took out a token. The barrier shimmered away, allowing Jake to finally properly Identify the item.

[Gloves of the Malefic One’s Grace (Legendary)] – By the grace of the Malefic One, your scales shall be your instrument of invincibility. Created by an incredibly skilled crafter possessing the Blessing of the Malefic Viper, these gloves contain but a fragment of the Primordial’s Records. Made from the hide and scales of an apex wyvern, infused with its toxic blood, and enhanced by a powerful, refined core, these gloves are incredibly resilient. Allows Scales of the Malefic Viper to be cast directly upon the gloves at a significantly increased effect. While using Scales of the Malefic Viper, the effect of all stat points granted by these gloves are increased by a significant amount. Only one who has shown sufficient proficiency in Scales of the Malefic Viper may wear these gloves. Enchantments: +300 Toughness, +300 Vitality, +300 Strength, +300 Agility, +300 Endurance. Scaled Hands of the Malefic One.

Requirements: Lvl 175+ in any humanoid race. Skill: Scales of the Malefic Viper (Legendary+).

While Jake did have a limited understanding of how much things were worth, he did know that legendary items were always priced in the billions within the multiverse. The Auction had allowed everyone on Earth to get banger deals on stuff, but this offering was at the same level in pure value. One billion was a steal.

"Satisfied?" the attendant asked.

"Very," Jake said, smiling, "but is it truly only priced at a billion? This may be presumptuous of me, but the materials alone must have cost more than that severalfold."

A part of him even wondered if maybe the item was cursed or something, but the attendant explained, "These items have a limited userbase, and it is not in our interest to keep them vaulted up. They are for those who have been recognized by the Malefic One or those loyal to his excellency, and it is only in our interest to help them on their way. For you to already have achieved legendary rarity in Scales of the Malefic Viper despite being in D-grade is incredibly commendable, and proves you are worthy. So, yes, they are underpriced by the standards of many, but priced exactly right by our standards. This place was never made to make money to begin with."

Jake nodded in understanding, not one to say no to a good thing. "Well, I am for sure buying them."

The attendant nodded and bowed. "May they serve you well, he who is blessed by the Malefic One."

Chapter 18

Something Wrong

Meira was nervous after Lord Thayne left her alone. She had been shopping many times before, but never for herself. Wasn’t it just a waste of money to get her equipment? Currently, she only got a bit of Wisdom from her spatial necklace, with the rest of her items not even counting as equipment. Receiving that necklace had already been far more than Meira would expect, but at least she saw the usefulness in that. It allowed her to more effectively transport materials for Lord Thayne, as it even had a storage specifically enchanted to store alchemical ingredients.

"Follow me, lassie; let’s get you sorted," the shop owner said as she hurried Meira into the back room. Meira just followed along with the far smaller woman, still not sure if all of this was a good idea.

"Relax there," the dwarf said with a calming smile. "Young masters like that like to treat their girlfriends nicely, so you better take advantage while you can."

"I… He doesn’t think of me like that," Meira denied, embarrassed. He had made that clear when they had gone to that other shop. She was mad at herself for thinking that Lord Thayne had taken her there with those kinds of intentions. Nearly as mad as she was for feeling dejected that he hadn’t.

"Really?" the dwarf asked. "Well, color me surprised. Either way, he gave me the heebie-jeebies, so there is no way he is average, and people who aren’t average got money to treat those they care about. And he does care about you. Any damn idiot can see that. So stop dilly-dallying, and let’s get you a proper set, alright?"

Meira looked at the dwarf for a moment, considering her words. It was true that Lord Thayne didn’t think of her "that way," but it was also true he had always been very nice to her, so maybe he did care? Just in another way? And if he did that, it should be fine to get some equipment if he asked her, right?

"Okay," Meira said with a smile as the dwarf got to work, and the two discussed what kind of equipment would suit Meira best.

They spent a good while going over everything, and the dwarf even showed her different pieces of jewelry she had in stock that would go well with what Meira needed. It was all a bit overwhelming, as many of the items were probably more expensive than Meira would have been if the Order had just decided to sell her to someone over giving her to Lord Thayne.

Yet it also felt oddly liberating—a feeling she thought she would never feel—to be there alone. Buying things for herself. She hoped to make Lord Thayne proud and want to keep her around, which was the primary reason she worked so hard. But after the entire incident with Nella and Utmal, she had been thinking if maybe it was okay if she did some more things for herself? Izil also tried to convince her she should be more selfish, or at least not as selfless.

Maybe she could begin to get stronger for herself? If Lord Thayne wanted her to no longer be his slave but instead a full member of the Order by her own merits, she would need to be more independent. She would need to make her own choices and be a member because she wanted to. But she was afraid that becoming a member would mean that Lord Thayne would have her leave. Have her get her own residence or enter the dorms or something. Meira desperately didn’t want that to happen, so she would have to selfishly find a way to make Lord Thayne want to keep her around even after she was no longer bound by a slave contract.

She wanted to stay no matter what she had to do to make that happen. It was selfish of her to want more from him than what he had already given and promised to give her… but he did want her to make her own choices and do what she wanted. And what Meira wanted more than anything was to stay, so this selfish wish of hers was okay… right?

--

Jake walked out of the castle-like building wearing his cool new gloves. On the way out, he had already done a bit of experimenting and found that they were actually very similar to his old gloves. He could instinctively use Scales of the Malefic Viper only on the gloves, and he instantly felt the scales already sewn into the gloves fill with energy and strengthen to an insane level. The gloves stayed flexible like before, but he felt like his hands had become near-impenetrable. Of course, any blunt force would still hurt like hell, and if he tried to block a sword, he would find his fingers broken, but for anything magical, it would be insane. He could also use it to grab sharp edges and whatnot, as he had already done with his old gloves.

The stat effect was also interesting. Whenever Jake used Scales of the Malefic Viper, he felt a slight increase in power based on how much of his body he covered. It was super small when he used it only in local areas, but Jake reckoned that if his entire body was covered, he would get roughly a hundred more in each of the five stats the armor gave. It was small but there, and frankly, the biggest thing about the gloves was the insane amount of stat points they offered to begin with, along with their sheer level of durability when Scales were used.

He considered if making an entire set of armor like the gloves would be a good idea, but maybe it wasn’t the best, as the mana drain when he infused the gloves was rather intense. A full set of armor would be able to drain dry even Jake and his anomalously large mana pool at an alarming speed.

Feeling good about himself, Jake saw no need to delay as he headed back towards the shop Meira was in. His Mark worked as a guide after he went through the teleportation gate to the same area she was in, allowing him to quickly make it there. She was still inside the shop, and Jake decided to wait outside until she was done.

He leaned against the wall of the building and closed his eyes as his mind sank into his soul. Once inside, he was met with the sight of an almost-exact copy of himself who was, for some reason, repeatedly hitting the ground as dark pulses of energy were released from him, blasting him into the air.

Sim-Jake had changed to look even more like Jake than before. Looking at him felt a tad weird to the real Jake, as he knew his other version was slowly disappearing. His personality had become more and more like Jake’s own over the last few months. It had already been similar, but now they barely talked anymore, as there was no need to. They now only discussed two things: melee combat and Shadow Vault. And melee-combat talk had become less and less frequent as of late, as Jake quickly picked up on sim-Jake’s teachings through the ongoing assimilation.

Jake looked at his simulacrum, who was naturally aware he was there. His other version stopped his practice and turned to Jake. "Don’t look glum like I am dying or something; we both knew this was the ideal outcome."

"Still," Jake sighed.

"It is what it is," sim-Jake said, shrugging.

The next moment a katar appeared in both of his hands, and Jake mimicked his motion as they charged each other. Their weapons clashed as if mirrored, the two katar tips perfectly impacting each other and sending both of them stumbling back.

Sim-Jake moved faster for the follow-up, but Jake was ready as he countered, getting the upper hand. He managed to land a minor wound but was pushed in return when he tried to capitalize on the one hit he got in.

Their fight continued for about twenty minutes, with both of them slowly taking damage. It looked very even until Jake made a minor slip-up and was cornered. He had slowly been losing ground, and after a combo more than a hundred hits long, he’d found himself unable to respond before a katar penetrated his skull.

"Fuck," Jake muttered, thinking he was gonna win this one. Both their wounds had also already healed. They weren’t real wounds anyway.

"Still improving," sim-Jake said, smiling.

True, Jake thought as the simulacrum turned around and continued whatever he’d been doing before. Jake had no idea what it was, but he did know that the simulacrum focused nearly one hundred percent of his time on Vault now. He had to, as his memories of the simulated world were slowly fading, and continuing to improve the fighting style was now meaningless. Now all he had to do was pass down the final pieces before fully handing the mantle to Jake.

He stayed a bit longer to look at his simulacrum, genuinely having no idea what he was doing. It was like all the Records pertaining to Shadow Vault had been integrated into sim-Jake for him to perfect. It was to the level of the real version of Jake feeling unsure about even using the skill. He got the sense that he was lacking some of the instinctual knowledge the skill gave about how to use it, but he naturally couldn’t know what he didn’t know. However, what he was sure of was that the day sim-Jake ceased to be, his Basic Shadow Vault of Umbra would upgrade, and in the same way, then the day Shadow Vault upgraded, sim-Jake would lose his remaining basis of existence that kept him separate from Jake.

"Keep up the good work," Jake muttered with a sigh before he left his Soulspace, having felt Meira and the dwarf exit the back room within the store.

Jake opened his eyes and went inside the store just in time. He saw Meira carrying a whole bunch of things, all placed in separate boxes.

They also saw him enter the store, and Meira looked somewhat nervous. "Lord Thayne! Please inspect the items and let me know if these are acceptable."

"You are the one shopping here, not me. Whatever you picked is fine as long as you didn’t get a full set of legendary gear in an attempt to bankrupt me.”

"I would never do that!" Meira semi-yelled with indignation before finally realizing it was a joke, making her blush in embarrassment. She clenched one of the boxes and asked in a nearly whispering voice, "Please look at them a little?"

Jake resigned himself and nodded. Meira took out a white dress from one of the boxes and proudly showed it off. It didn’t look that much different from the usual dress she wore—at least, not in design—but the item was clearly far superior. Identifying it, he actually felt a little proud of her.

[Sorcerer’s Dress of Merciful Intent (Epic)] – A dress crafted from the silk of a juvenile Ethspawn Spider, further enhanced by a talented crafter. Grants impressive resistance to most magical attacks and dissipates a portion of the physical force of all blows made against the wearer. Passively absorbs a portion of all attacks, be they magical or physical in nature. This energy can then be infused into a healing spell to empower it. Enchantments: +250 Wisdom, +100 Intelligence, +100 Willpower. Merciful Intent.

Requirements: Lvl 140+ in any humanoid race.

He had to admit that when he had left Meira alone to shop, he had feared he would return to her having selected a full set of common-rarity equipment with a few inferior-rarity items mixed in. Jake was happy to see she had selected equipment of proper value. It wasn’t overly extravagant either. One had to remember that Meira was not a monster like Jake and needed far fewer stats than he did from his equipment. In many ways, a full epic set of gear would be just as good for her as a full legendary set. Sure, the legendary gear would be better overall and have better special effects, but the difference wasn’t massive, and there was also the fear of making Meira a target if she had stuff that was too good.

"Looking good," Jake approved with a thumbs-up.

"Should get the little lassie all settled for a good while," the dwarf said with a smile. "Gives above her total stat limit, leaving some room for her to grow into. The rings are both purely defensive, too, so don’t worry about her getting targeted as a healer. They will all find themselves dead before getting to kill her. And if all else goes wrong, the earrings have an enchantment to automatically teleport a distance away if she is in mortal danger. Limited uses with recharge time, but a real lifesaver."

Jake nodded and thanked the shopkeeper. He did not doubt she had done her job to try and convince Meira to get better stuff. Okay, sure, it was her actual job to make Meira spend as much as possible, and it was a bit weird for Jake to be grateful to her for making him spend more, but such was life.

"How much for everything?" Jake asked.

"Full set of epic armor, an ancient ring, epic ring, and a set of ancient-rarity linked earrings with emergency-teleportation ability… comes down to roughly one-point-nine billion Credits for the entire thing. If we cut the most expensive item, the earrings, it will only be—"

"Nah, it’s good; we’ll take it.” Jake smiled as he paid the shopkeeper.

The dwarf looked somewhat surprised at how fast he had just paid without any comments. Not that Jake thought much about it. He had spent nearly that much on alchemy items earlier that day, and this was a full set for Meira that she could use for a long time. Totally worth it.

He saw the shopkeeper lean in and whisper something to Meira that he couldn’t hear, as the C-grade dwarf hid it. Meira turned entirely red in her face before quickly backing away, making Jake wonder what the dwarf had said, but looking at Meira, she didn’t look like she had any intentions of sharing. She didn’t even dare look at him for some reason.

"Thanks for your patronage," the dwarf said with a big smile. "And do come again. I love big spenders."

Jake chuckled at the shamelessness as he said his goodbyes and headed out of the shop. Meira put all of the boxes in her spatial storage, intending to take them out once they got home. Something they did right away, as neither of them had any more business in the city for now.

The two of them headed back to one of the gateway pillars and teleported straight home to the mansion. Jake went to the living room as Meira went off to her personal residence to change into her new clothes. That was also when Jake learned that Meira had never learned how to rapidly use a spatial storage to switch equipment or even equip a weapon. He noted that he should definitely teach her that.

With some time to spare, Jake took inventory and began making some plans for his next period of crafting with all of these new materials. He also now had ingredients for some ritual stuff with Duskleaf, and he was ready to begin the initial parts of the ritual for the Pollendust Bee Queen. There would be several stages to the ritual, and this first part was pretty much just about filling the creature with energy and Records to further build upon.

After thinking about his plans for a while, Meira returned to the main house. Jake saw her in his sphere long before she reached the living room, but he was still taken aback when he saw her with his eyes. She wore the white dress she had shown him along with the jewelry he had been told about. Before, she had only been wearing her simple clothes, but now she truly looked like a young elven mistress from an influential clan.

"Does it look okay?" Meira asked shyly.

"Yeah, you look great," Jake said, smiling as he gave her not one but two thumbs-ups, only making her blush more. It was clear she wasn’t used to compliments from her reaction, and Jake had to admit it was kind of cute.

Nonetheless, Meira seemed happy. Jake was just happy she was happy, and the two of them once more dove into their routine of alchemy and practice. Everything was going smoothly, and Jake felt relaxed during this time, until one day… something felt wrong.

Very wrong.

Chapter 19

In an Instant

Jake had spent another month rapidly progressing since his shopping trip. The most monumental event was when Jake finally laid down the ritual circle framework for the Pollendust Bee Queen. He had prepared enough cores and, with some of the materials he had bought, could begin the initial stages.

It was a bit like how Mystie had used her ritual for a long time before Jake came along. Jake would do something similar but at an even higher level. The ritual circle itself had a radius of about ten meters and was placed on his lawn, surrounded by a barrier he cheated to get made by just having Duskleaf erect it. This initial stage would last quite a while and was likely going to be the longest.

Besides the ritual, Jake had just been slamming out potions and working on a special kind of soul poison he really wanted to make. It was harder than he had thought it would be, but he still felt he was getting closer to his goal.

With this also came some levels. It felt like they had been coming even faster than before recently, and Jake theorized it was due to how expensive the materials he experimented with were. Again, he didn’t know; all he knew was that three levels in a month was pretty damn good.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 181 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 182 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 177 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 183 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

One other thing Jake had also done during this time was a lot of heavy drinking. Only some of it had been alcohol, with the majority being Endurance-increasing elixirs. And damn, had it paid off.

Status

Health Points (HP): 54011/54050

Mana Points (MP): 95231/100484

Stamina: 47021/48320

--

His stamina had increased by more than ten thousand points since he went shopping, the main contributor being 555 stat points gained from elixirs, maxing out his current limit for his levels when it came to consuming them. This was before percentage bonuses, so he had to add another 45% to that. All in all, good stuff. As for his Free Points… Jake had been weak and, in a moment of indulgence, tossed all 175 stat points he had saved up into Perception.

He had no regrets.

Yet even after all of these things had gone so well and Jake felt like everything was going great, he felt uneasy that day. It was a terrible feeling he could not pinpoint; he just knew something was wrong. Off. Jake felt restless and couldn’t focus, so he asked Villy, who didn’t provide any useful answer. He then turned to Miranda to ask her how things were on Earth and was told nothing was amiss.

Next up was Sylphie, and while they couldn’t exactly speak, she also wasn’t worried. Sylphie was still hanging around with Carmen, so it shouldn’t have anything to do with her either. Jake then checked on everyone in the Order he knew, only to get confused responses. Nothing was wrong anywhere… yet Jake felt as he felt. Something was horribly wrong, and it frustrated him to not know what the issue was.

And with every moment, that feeling of wrongness built.

Miranda felt flustered after Jake contacted her for the second time that day to tell her that something was wrong. He gave no details or even an idea of what the issue was; he just said something was wrong. Miranda had gotten to work and checked in on everyone, having even contracted Caleb, Jake’s brother, to make sure things were calm. He said nothing was wrong. Same for Casper and the Risen.

The Noboru Clan also didn’t have any issues. She was well and truly lost and considered if perhaps she had to go to the Holy Church and the Augur to try and figure out if there truly were any problems. She even went as far as to check where the two hawks, Mystie and Hawkie, were, but they were still in the forest. If they were in danger, then Miranda had no idea what to do anyway.

In all honesty, Miranda was worried about Jake. What if something had happened to him that caused some kind of mental disturbance? That didn’t seem to be an issue, though, as he was perfectly lucid. Lucid… but troubled and worried.

She kept trying to find the problem, recalling Lillian, Hank, Hank’s children, and most people she and Jake both knew. He had said that his feeling of wrongness was likely connected to someone he knew being in danger, but that was it. All she could do was take precautionary actions.

Miranda was still researching and trying to find out what was wrong when, suddenly, the ground shook. Are we under attack?

Without any hesitation, Miranda activated one of her skills to get the status of the city and saw only one place with a disturbance. The teleportation building connecting Haven and the Fort had been utterly destroyed. Even the usually well-protected one at the Fort was now nothing more than rubble.

She instantly teleported down to her ritual chamber to prepare for an attack as several tokens in her inventory vibrated. With bated breath, she checked them and saw the same message from everywhere.

"Under attack—"

"Teleportation circles—"

"Cut off—"

The Noboru Clan, Court of Shadows, Valhal, Risen, and even the Holy Church.

Miranda scrambled to understand the situation and quickly realized one thing: In an instant, the entire teleportation network of the planet had been destroyed.

An hour earlier…

Sometimes, one must choose a lesser evil.

Arthur checked his watch and saw it was time. The researchers and space mages had been hard at work for the better part of a year, and finally, their hard work would be realized.

"Activate the circle," Arthur said.

The more than a dozen space mages complied as they got into position. Soon, the circle began pulsing with power, a cube in the center functioning as the anchor to connect two very far-off places. The cube had been given to him during the Myriad Choices event for this exact purpose. The magic circle would only be active for a few seconds… but it was enough.

Eighteen figures appeared, and a second after, the entire underground chamber shook as cracks formed all over. The mages who had helped perform the ritual all fell unconscious to the ground as healers rushed in to take them out. The formation was well and truly broken, too, but it had done what it was supposed to.

"We meet again, Arthur," the man—if he even was that—leading the entourage of new arrivals said. His orange skin made it clear he was not human, and neither were any of his comrades.

Arthur knew every single figure that had just appeared could singlehandedly battle the strongest party that the United Cities Alliance possessed. But such a force was necessary, especially their leader and the odd shifting elemental-like being of ash. Both of them were figures he knew few could rival.

"Welcome to Earth, Celestial Child," Arthur said as he bowed, using the title he had been informed the alien named Ell’Hakan went by.

"A single sun and a single, powerful moon." Ell’Hakan smiled as he looked up, his gaze seeming to pierce the several hundred meters of soil above them to gaze at the sky. "I thank you for your welcome, and I believe all preparations are in place?"

"We have held up our part of the bargain," Arthur said, nodding. "By the end of the hour, everyone will need to be in position, so we must not delay."

"Naturally." The alien man nodded with a smile as Arthur led him to the chambers above.

A hard decision had to be made, and Arthur had simply seen no other path than the one chosen. A cancer had invaded their planet in the form of divine fanaticism. And like cancer, these organizations would fight each other to eventually leave the body they inhabited dead, broken, or mutated beyond recognition. So he had chosen to battle this cancer by introducing a metaphorical chemotherapy—a harmful method that he at least had a semblance of control over. One he hoped would give their planet a new life.

Once they reached the chamber above, Ell’Hakan turned to three of his followers. "Go."

The three of them nodded as they all teleported away. Space mages, all three of them.

"What do you intend for them to do?" Arthur asked.

"Something for the future. Only a fool doesn’t plan for tomorrow." Ell’Hakan gave a comforting smile. "Do not worry. I will keep my promise, and their task is of no consequence to our plan. Once our business concludes, and if we are successful, you shall have this world, just as the contract dictates."

Arthur nodded, feeling assured. "Very well. The Disciple should arrive soon."

As if he had predicted the future, a young man walked into the room. Arthur once more felt pressured, as he knew this person was at the very peak of D-grade already. Just a single step away from his evolution, and a vital piece in their strategy.

"Greetings, Disciple of Eversmile," Ell’Hakan greeted the young man with a bow. "Have you made the preparations? Assembled them all?"

"They are ready," the young man named William said as he looked at the being of ash. "I take it you will be the one to lead them?"

"Such is the arrangement,” the Unique Lifeform rumbled. “Lead me to them, human.”

The more time passed, the more assured Arthur felt. Despite not a single one of them being in C-grade, they had a chance. But the Chosen was powerful, and so was this Fallen King. There were also many other factions…

Ell’Hakan noticed Arthur’s doubt and comforted him. "As long as you do your part, so will we do ours. Remember who stands before you. Now… let us begin our story of conquest and liberation."

Miyamoto sat in meditation within his chambers. The wind was blowing hard as the flowers swayed, the world itself in contrast to his inner calm. He had been contacted earlier by Ms. Wells of Haven and informed that Jake believed something was wrong.

The Sword Saint would not disregard the Hunter’s judgment and was prepared.

He opened his eyes as the ground rumbled. Yells went through the entire compound, and the city of Saya was in chaos as the security forces moved to find those responsible or identify their city’s attacker. All he heard in the distance was that the teleporters were all destroyed.

Miyamoto slowly stood up and sighed. "Who are you people?" he spoke as two figures appeared. Both with orange skin. He frowned as he felt their power. These people… Stronger than the Judge of the Court.

"We come at the behest of the United Cities Alliance as well as our lord, the Celestial Child, Ell’Hakan," one of them said. “By his grace, we offer you the opportunity to surrender and to join us in our quest to purge this world of divine influence.”

Miyamoto frowned. "What does this purging consist of?"

"The death or escape of all those who serve their gods as puppets," the other one of his two visitors answered. "We do not care for those blessed by gods with no alliances or factions, such as the Primordial you call your Patron."

"You are starting a war," Miyamoto said, his frown deepening. "One that neither Noboru Clan nor I will take any part in."

"Very well," the first person spoke again. "It shall be told you died with honor."

Miyamoto drew his blade as the two were upon him, and in an instant, he was blasted out of his personal compound, flying through the air and out of the city. He landed in the plains outside the city as the two figures appeared at his sides.

The Sword Saint got into a defensive position as the two charged again, the old man ready this time.

Caleb had instantly put the true Skyggen in full lockdown after Miranda contacted him—a choice that would prove incredibly wise, as not long after the attack arrived, the fake Skyggen had its teleportation arrays all blown up in an instant, and even the secret circles set up by the Court were destroyed.

He moved quickly to evacuate his parents, wife, and child to a shelter. Just in time, too, as he got reports of incoming attackers. Yet they did not move to actually attack but had simply stationed themselves outside.

As the Judge of the Court of Shadows, Caleb was usually informed about something like this happening… but he had been taken by surprise, and from the sheer level of coordination, this was not some minor attack. They had simultaneously struck nearly every settlement and every single faction at once. He had no idea what these people were planning, but he soon got an idea as more and more intel arrived.

It was a full-on attempt at a planetary takeover.

All over the part of the planet inhabited by humans, similar scenes took place. Armies appeared in cities out of nowhere as residents showed their true colors. The United Cities Alliance had long been considered the largest singular faction and was now showing it. In many places, they simply caused civil unrest. Others went and directly attacked the local City Lord to take control, effectively expanding the scope of the alliance.

In the cities that were too powerful or with a populace that could not be infiltrated, far more common forms of warfare were deployed as each city was cut off. Many City Lords that had simply allied with a religious group surrendered immediately once under pressure, as they had no way to get swift reinforcements and feared for their lives.

Within less than half an hour, the once well-connected planet with a sprawling teleportation network was turned into a planet of isolated islands with vast distances between each of them.

"Earth under attack, teleportation network down planet-wide, Sword Saint MIA, Caleb isolated, and yet to establish any contact with other cities," Jake heard from Miranda as his feeling of wrongness was at an apex. The message almost gave him relief, as he finally knew what had caused it.

There was not a hint of hesitation as Jake went to the teleporter in his residence. The moment he reached it, he tried to activate it but felt like the connection was slightly unstable.

"Villy, something is wrong with the teleporter. Can I still use it?" Jake asked with slight panic.

"It will take you to Earth, if that is what you ask," the god answered promptly. As if he had been waiting. “It will even take you to your city.”

"What is happening on Earth?" Jake asked, knowing the god knew.

"Jake, there are things mortals and gods have to deal with. This is not something that involves me. But… good luck. I believe in you. Do your best." Villy then cut off the connection, leaving Jake frowning even more than before. Villy seemed almost worried? But he did understand the part about this not being an issue for the god to deal with.

Without hesitation, he activated the teleporter and was sent through the void. The journey was thankfully uneventful, and Jake touched down right in front of the monument erected to allow his teleportation and—

BOOM!

Right behind him, the monument exploded. Debris and rock flew around his ears as he took in everything his sphere saw. Flying pieces of the broken monument, soil and dust spewed up from everywhere, and red flames soaring up into the sky from the attack that had broken the installation.

Jake turned his head almost robotically as he saw three figures land amongst the rubble of his now cut-off way off Earth. He stared at what the man in the front was holding as that something was thrown toward him. It landed a few meters in front of Jake and rolled on the ground, and he looked down at the lifeless eyes of the monument creator’s severed head. Chris’ head.

"Welcome home, Chosen of the Malefic Viper," a calm, familiar voice said as Jake looked up and saw the Chosen of Yip of Yore—Ell’Hakan. "I did tell you we would meet sooner than you expected. My condolences for the builder; he was useful while it—"

Jake didn’t give the man a chance to speak as he charged. A few hours ago, he had been doing alchemy in peace. Everything had happened so fast, and Jake had barely had time to properly register what was going on. But… he didn’t need to.

His eyes burned with pure anger as a katar appeared in each hand. Arcane Awakening activated at full power immediately, as there was no hesitation or doubt.

He was going to kill every single one of them.

Chapter 20

Celestial Alignment of Yore

Jake had not really known Chris that well. He was just a guy Jake had saved by coincidence when he killed Abby and her father after they attacked Haven. Later on, he had then given the young man a Blessing from the Viper, and Chris had made the monument to allow Jake to teleport out of their universe. To call him a friend wouldn’t be entirely correct… but he was Jake’s guy. He had worked for Jake. He had only been targeted because of Jake.

So Jake would get revenge for him.

Ell’Hakan was ready for Jake’s attack despite how swift it had been. So were his two followers, as both of them exploded with power, activating their boosting skills while moving to intercept. One of them had a sword and a shield, with the other one a healer based on the magic she deployed.

Jake didn’t care about these two, instead heading straight for Ell’Hakan. He teleported past the warrior and met a barrier from the healer as Ell’Hakan took out a staff and slammed it into the ground. A wave of red flames hit Jake, but black scales already covered his body as he, with a single hit, shattered the barrier. But before he could land a blow, he was attacked from behind by the warrior.

Fuck you, Jake thought as he completely ignored the blow and kept up his assault. He stabbed forward and managed to scratch his opponent before the orange fuck turned into flames and flew backward at a rapid speed. In return, Jake got an annoying cut across his back before he spun and kicked the shield of the warrior, blasting him away.

Charging again, he chased after Ell’Hakan with reckless abandon. Spears of flames flew towards him, but he once more ignored them, as dodging would only slow him down. The only thing that mattered was killing the person in front of him.

Yet the fuck kept fleeing, and the warrior and healer kept getting in his damn way. For every second, his anger grew. Like a volcano constantly at the edge of an eruption, the heat was just building up. He ignored everything that would not lead directly to damaging Ell’Hakan, as nothing else would give him the slightest reprieve.

The damn healer made his life difficult. Even when he stabbed the warrior several times, he just got up again, and Ell’Hakan was constantly turning into fucking flames to run away. What was worse was the constant taunting. Jake did not truly register the words; he just knew they were taunts.

His vision turned red as he felt on the edge of eruption. His inability to simply kill his opponent only angered him even more. At this point, nothing else mattered.

His body pulsed with power as he prepared to push himself further. He was about to increase Arcane Awakening above 60% when, suddenly, a feeling of danger emerged from within. As if cold water was thrown in his face, Jake abruptly felt a bit of clarity. In the middle of a chase, he closed his eyes.

He is controlling your emotions, you fucking idiot, he told himself in that still moment.

Jake remembered what his opponent could do. His emotions were still out of control and flaring up. He felt angrier than he likely ever had… but from the anger came an odd sense of calm once he realized why he was mad. Jake opened his eyes again and locked gazes with the nahoom in front of him.

Seeing he had stopped, Ell’Hakan also got a break. "The wild beast has calmed. Once more, you show unique restraint. Though I must confess, I expected more than a charging, mindless—"

"What do you hope to accomplish with this shit?" Jake asked, genuinely unsure. Why the hell would he bother invading their planet in the first place?

"We each walk our Paths. While you might be a hunter, I am not. In this instance, I am only here to work as a liberator. Did your world not like this sort of thing? Foreign countries invading others at the behest of freedom fighters merely to exploit the land? War under false pretenses for personal gain? That is all I am here to do. To free this world from you. At least, that is the story that is told. Truth is subjective, and all that matters is what one can make others believe." Ell’Hakan was more talkative than Jake would expect. The problem was that he was just talking, nothing else.

"You didn’t answer shit," Jake spat out.

"Fine, I shall give you one hint." Ell’Hakan smiled. "Third World Congress."

Jake wasn’t sure what the guy meant until his eyes opened wide. Was this fuck trying to get voted World Leader by installing his own City Lords or something? Was that even possible? And did it matter? No… because he would die here today.

His katars disappeared as he equipped his bow and took out a poison bottle he quickly tossed in his quiver, having learned to soak the arrows within a long time ago. The warrior and healer were behind him, ready to engage.

Jake marked all three of his targets as he took a deep breath and looked at Ell’Hakan. "You are right about one thing: Our Paths do differ. You are good at talking shit, and I am good at killing shit-talkers."

He then felt what was almost a wave of pure anger hit him, trying to flare up what was there before. But Jake barely registered it as he stepped forward and teleported. Rather than teleport towards Ell’Hakan, he went backward more than three hundred meters and appeared behind the healer and warrior. An arrow was already nocked, and a Splitting Arrow shot towards the woman.

The warrior moved quickly to the side of the healer to defend her, but Jake stepped once more and teleported before shooting again. A barrier emerged around the healer and warrior as Jake stepped and shot three more times from five different angles.

He stopped and shot one more time. The first shots were all explosive arrows, and the barrier was blown up right away, leaving the two pelted with arcane energy. The very final shot Jake had released was the one stable arrow of the bunch, curving under the shield of the warrior to hit him in the abdomen and making him stumble back.

Ell’Hakan did not stand still as he raised his staff. It was only now that Jake noticed something odd. While it was the middle of the day, the sunlight was far more intense than usual. It had a red glow, and the air almost shimmered from the sheer heat.

Sun-affinity magic, Jake concluded as he dodged back just before a beam of burning light descended from above. It burned a hole nearly a dozen meters into the ground right where he had been standing, making Jake frown. The attack was a lot stronger than expected, and from how Ell’Hakan felt, it was clear the man was at a higher level than Jake. Not just one or two levels, but at least over a dozen. His two companions were similarly higher in level than Jake.

But he was not deterred.

In his anger, he had activated Arcane Awakening fully, putting himself on a timer. This was just another fight. One he could win.

The warrior hit with the arrow earlier quickly got healed as Jake continued his attack. He wanted to take down the healer first, but the warrior clearly knew his task was to protect her, so he just decided to kill both of them at once. It was problematic that he was facing the ideal three-man party of a damage-dealing caster, a defensive warrior, and a healer. With none of them being significantly weaker than the others, it made it hard to exploit a weak link.

Magic sprang up all around Jake as he put that larger mana pool to use. His wings appeared and pumped out poison to create a mist covering the entire area. Ell’Hakan himself was too damn hard to lock down and damage, but the healer and warrior? Not so much.

He bombarded them with arcane bolts and exploding orbs—not to damage them, but to obscure their vision and give him openings. The first Arcane Powershot landed on the healer not long after, but the woman recovered quickly, even after the stable arcane arrow tore off a large part of her chest. The second Powershot hit the warrior, only penetrating deep into his shoulder and making him spin in the air before he stabilized.

Arcane charges were building in both from his Marks, and his special little bottle from earlier carried an extra toxic surprise. Ell’Hakan himself failed to hit any attacks no matter what he did. His attempt to manipulate Jake’s emotions had also failed. Jake was angry. Utterly pissed. But he kept his head cool anyway, as he had quite the practice with rampant emotions.

"I admit, you are stronger than our prior conversation, as well as our intel, led me to believe," Ell’Hakan spoke just as Jake blasted away his two companions with an arrow stuck in each.

Both of them looked tired, and having their boosting skills going for all this time had clearly worn them out. Jake, on the other hand, with his monstrous mana pool and massively improved stamina pool, managed fine. The only one not really pushed yet was Ell’Hakan, who seemed oddly disinterested in the fight. He was just participating in the background to help his companions if it got too dangerous, keeping Jake on his toes and holding the fight at a standstill where the healer could keep up with Jake’s damage output.

"When are you going to stop pussying around and fight me?" Jake asked the fucker.

"When the time is right," Ell’Hakan said, smiling. Jake saw straight through the bluff. He felt more confident than before and knew that the orange fuck wasn’t that much stronger than his companions. The magic he used was also big and flashy, consuming a lot of mana. Even if he had a boosting skill, Jake would be fine.

Jake moved again to push his advantage, as he wanted to finish off the healer before any of them had the chance to escape. It wasn’t yet time to activate his secret weapon… No, he would save that for the very end and take them by surprise. It wasn’t like he needed to hurry anyway, given how big of an advantage he had, so even if he could admit he was not entirely sure as to the efficacy of his poison, all should be fine.

In fact, he would barely even consider it a fight anymore. He was so superior, and—

Jake’s eye opened wide in realization. His emotions had once more been influenced, making him overly confident… but he realized it too late. In an instant, he felt his entire body freeze. He looked upwards and saw an absolutely massive magical circle and two more people floating far above, having been hidden out of his sphere all this time.

"A profound sense of danger towards attacks, a spherical detection skill with a range between two and five hundred meters in radius,” Ell’Hakan said. “Powerful skills making you a hard opponent to take by surprise… but not impossible."

Jake now saw he was holding some kind of orb in his hand that was linked to the magic circle above, as they pulsed in synchronicity.

Space itself seemed locked down around Jake as he struggled to release himself. He felt isolated from the outside world, as if he did not belong there, and yet he did not feel like he was in any danger. Jake could not even step down to teleport away… if that would even work.

"In the outskirts of the first Pylon city of Earth, the Chosen of the Malefic Viper and the Celestial Child battled,” Ell’Hakan said. “In a fight almost equal, the Celestial Child, Ell’Hakan, came out on top. In a moment of cowardice, the Malefic One’s Chosen fled in fear, abandoning not just his city, but humanity itself. A selfish coward indeed… one not worth ever rallying around."

Jake wanted to talk but was unable to. It was as if he wasn’t even in the same space as everyone else. Like he had been shifted to a different reality while still being able to see and hear everything.

"I do hope you hurry," Ell’Hakan said with a smile. "The World Congress shall be your deadline to set history right."

Space began to shift and move as, far above, a projection appeared. It was an entirely blue moon, far smaller than the moon of Earth. It began to move at a visible speed, and Jake faintly felt himself being linked to it. Chained to it. Like the tide was controlled by the moon.

"Celestial Alignment of Yore."

The orb on Ell’Hakan’s orb shattered as he spat out blood, and Jake felt himself be pulled. He wanted to yell but could not move a single muscle. He wanted to move his mana, but it refused to respond.

Just as he was about to be dragged away, Jake focused his eyes and noted that the space around him was faintly distorted. The very second he began to be dragged, he could move once more, and in that very final moment, he raised both his hands towards his opponents as they glowed green.

Touch of the Malefic Viper.

He also detonated his arcane charges from the Marks but was unable to see the result. Within half a second, he lost sight of Ell’Hakan, the Fort, Haven, and everything else. He kept accelerating as if dragged by heavenly chains across the landscape. Everything blurred and distorted. All he saw were moving colors and silhouettes, his mind unable to process everything.

Then, suddenly, it stopped.

But the momentum was not gone. Jake fell to the ground like a meteor, his speed surpassing one. He saw the ground a millisecond before he impacted it, only able to slightly angle himself as he hit it. Jake took a rolling fall, bouncing off the ground and flying several more kilometers before his second bounce. He felt his shoulder dislocate from the first impact, but after the second one, he could slightly decelerate himself with blasts of mana.

After a few more bounces, Jake landed on the ground and saw that he was lying on a large dune of sand. He breathed heavily as he rolled over, trying to stand up while spitting out some sand that had gotten into his mouth. Jake spat it out along with a good deal of blood from his internal injuries as he tried to orient himself. Trying to understand what the hell had just happened.

In an attempt to get an idea of where he was, he felt for Sylphie’s location using their Union Oath. His eyes shot open as he stared directly down at the sand below him. She was… nearly straight down. Very far, too.

It took him a few moments to comprehend what had just happened, and the moment he realized it, he gritted his teeth in frustration, not even caring about his injured body.

He had just been flung to the other fucking side of the planet. Jake cursed and clenched his fists as he tried to calm himself down. It was then that he felt a connection form.

Miranda’s voice came through to ask, "Jake, what happened?"

Jake then realized where he had just been fighting. "Tossed to the other side of the planet… Get out of there now. Escape Haven and move towards the center of the Grand Mangrove River. Say I sent you."

"Alright," Miranda answered without any hesitation. "We shall… They’re here, cutting off the ritual. Will contact once safe."

With that, the connection was severed, and Jake was alone. He flopped down on the sand again and smashed his fist into it.

Everything was fucked. His only consolation was that he had at least given those two annoying fucks a nice parting gift.

Ell’Hakan breathed with difficulty as his head pounded him using the orb. The item was now broken, but it had done its job. He smiled as he watched the Chosen being flung away. But at the very last moment, he felt it. An overwhelming determination as the human raised both of his glowing hands.

But… he was isolated in the space of Yore, so nothing should—

Cao’Estill and Ult’Oriel, his best healer and third-best warrior, suddenly collapsed to the ground as their bodies began bleeding from every orifice. Their blood pooled like thin water, their flesh rotting and their eyes glazing over.

All he could do was look on as both of their bodies decayed and turned to nothing but mush in front of him within seconds, leaving only rotting, unrecognizable shapes behind.

Ell’Hakan narrowed his eyes and frowned deeply. Plans… must be adapted.

But they were still on track. This was only the first step, after all.

He turned his gaze towards Haven as his two companions who had worked on the array joined him.

"What are your orders?" one of them asked.

"Follow me," Ell’Hakan said. "Let us finally pay this Haven a visit."

Chapter 21

Across the World

Miranda had been observing the battle from afar until, suddenly, a huge magic circle appeared and blocked out her view. When it disappeared, Jake was gone, and she hurriedly contacted him with worry… only to discover he had been put out of commission and was now somehow on the other side of the planet.

Having seen the battle, Miranda was confused about how Jake had fought but did not question it. She knew their opponent had a Bloodline that influenced emotions in some way, so she chalked it up to that. Not that it mattered right now, as she had more important things to do.

Jake’s warning before any attack arrived had allowed her to gather people in time. Hank and his children, Neil and his party, Lillian, and Phillip had arrived in her underground ritual chamber. When Miranda had seen Jake and the alien invader fight, she’d moved right away to have Neil prepare their escape path in case anything went wrong. She only vaguely remembered Jake mentioning this Grand Mangrove River and how he had passed through and met some friendly C-grades, but he seemed adamant that going there would be the wisest.

"I will need more time," Neil said as he worked at high speed to set up the teleportation circle within the chamber. It was the same kind he had used all the way back in E-grade to reach Haven in the first place.

"Alright," Miranda said as she sat down with crossed legs in the middle of her own ritual circle.

The altars all around her flared to life as she began to work her magic, first creating a massive green barrier that protected the main city of Haven. Her eyes glowed green as she took out several orbs and tossed them onto each of the altars, preparing to show the invaders why attacking a witch’s lair was considered a bad idea.

Casper frowned deeply as he looked at the approaching army.

Priscilla joined him in the city spire with a worried look on her face. "Most of the Ghastpillars are already destroyed, and we won’t be able to get the defensive array up and running in anything less than a week."

"I know," Casper said as he kept staring. He had known this day would come. They both had. It was something that repeated itself time and time again. An event that every new universe seemed to go through. A tribulation the Risen always had to overcome.

They were hated by default. As undead, preconceived notions about their existence were always present, and they were viewed as evil simply for existing. So for the natives of a planet to seek their destruction should not come as a surprise, even if Casper, Priscilla, and all the leaders of the Risen on Earth had hoped they could finally have a peaceful integration. With Jake and others having so much influence and no negative feelings towards the Risen, there had been good reason to hope… but alas, the cycle repeated.

"The Holy Church joined them too, huh," Casper said with disappointment as he saw some of the people approaching. A large group. He counted at least ten thousand D-grades from the Holy Church alone, backed up by even more from the United Cities Alliance. Even if Jacob had warned him during the last World Congress that the Holy Church was planning something against the Risen… he did not expect this.

"Did you hear more from the Augur?” Priscilla asked. “I thought he would stop an attack, or at the very least warn us.”

Casper shook his head. "Nothing from him at all. I can’t even contact him anymore."

By now, they had an okay understanding of the unfolding situation, and for whatever reason, it seemed like the Holy Church had made some kind of pact with the United Cities Alliance to wipe out the Risen. This did not mean they had allied with the United Cities Alliance… just that they were willing to help an enemy to crush an even more hated enemy.

It should not be surprising. It was simply history repeating itself.

Casper closed his eyes as dark energy revolved around him. He looked back and saw their own fighters begin to gather, preparing for battle. They were outnumbered significantly and were not truly an army like the Holy Church or United Cities Alliance. Especially not after many internal issues had popped up due to plants from the damn Alliance, including the destruction of many defensive buildings.

"We just need to buy time," Priscilla assured him.

"I know," Casper said, nodding. But he couldn’t help but wonder… what the fuck was Jacob doing? What was he planning?

"This time is crucial for you to ensure your C-grade evolution is as successful as possible," the Bishop said as he guided Jacob through the grand hall. "As an Augur of Hope, you may be able to feel when people walk astray or need guidance, but to also know of what options they then have is entirely different."

Jacob nodded in recognition as he followed the old man. Despite looking like just an average priest, he was a B-grade Bishop of the Holy Church and the leader of the Chapter that Jacob found himself in. Bertram was also off with some of the local templars to train, making them both busy men.

For a long time, the Holy Church had worked on a solution for people to potentially leave the 93rd Universe, and only a week or so ago, the first gate had successfully been made. It was still limited to D-grades and could only send through a few people every day, but it was something. There was also the issue of it being one-way, but that was only a temporary challenge that mages both on Earth and in the wider universe were working to overcome.

"The students you will meet are all struggling and performing below expectations,” the Bishop said. “Some are veterans of many years, while others are new blood who showed great promise but suddenly began to squander. These were carefully curated, and we believe in your ability to set their fates right and lead them to the best Paths possible for them.” He smiled. "We expect much of you, Augur of Hope."

Jacob once more nodded. "I shall do my utmost."

"Good. It is also time you begin to look outwards. To not only focus on the small planet from which you originate. The Holy Church can be found in every universe, and there will always be places that need hope.”

Jacob agreed, but he would want to return to Earth anyway, as there was lots of unfinished business there and many people he cared about.

The reason why he had left Earth was to ensure a successful evolution to C-grade. Earth was limited in many ways, and Jacob had been implored to go after the gate was established. While he did have some reservations, he also knew he would only be gone for a few months at most, and considering the peaceful state of Earth, the council had a limit to how much it could mess up in that time, right?

Two flickering wisps observed the movement across the vast mountain range. Monsters of all sorts had assembled, but not to fight. To observe. An army had arrived, teleported by what had to be a powerful C-grade. They had appeared extremely close to the Fallen King’s territory and not hesitated to attack. A few Pylons were stolen before the King made his move and tore the pathetic cretins to shreds.

But they kept coming, all led by another powerful leader. The monsters of Earth were no monolith. There was no dominant faction, no agreed-upon alliances or customs for how they would operate and interact. Unlike humans, they had no rules. There was only power. Power would get you followers, as other monsters would seek to be under your wing. Be it for Records, treasures, or simply safety. This was why they gathered around powerful leaders.

The Fallen King was one such powerful leader with many beasts, elementals, and other monsters loyal to him.

Loyal until another monster capable of challenging his position presented itself. The Fallen King had never truly viewed this as a threat. C-grades would not come to challenge him, as while there were no set rules, there was simply nothing in it for them to hunt down a D-grade. Even if that D-grade was strong enough to challenge a C-grade. There was also the fear of failing to kill him and the Fallen King returning for revenge. With the enhanced intelligence all C-grades experienced, it was no surprise none had been foolish enough to challenge him yet.

Until that day.

The army that had dared invade his domain was led by a creature unlike anything the Fallen King had met before. Shifting ash, a living storm of half-burning embers, and a form that remained ever-changing. The Fallen King recognized this foe as the creature assembled itself into a form floating in between two mountains.

A Unique Lifeform. Like himself.

[Ashen Phantom Devourer – lvl 199]

At the same level as him, too. Both standing at the precipice, refining themselves and reaching for perfection. Proving their Paths.

"A Devourer by choice," the Fallen King spoke, his voice spreading throughout the mountain range for tens of thousands of monsters to hear. “Your Path is apparent to all. Laughable, as it is a foolish one.”

"A King who has already Fallen once dares speak of foolishness," the Ashen Phantom Devourer spoke as the sky trembled from its release of power. “Be honored, and become sustenance for my Path.”

"Fallen… and having learned from his fall," the King answered back as his own power manifested, and the trembling sky was pushed back, space itself cracking from the clashing power of two Unique Lifeforms at the peak of D-grade.

They had no true reason to fight. They had never met, knew nothing of each other. And yet there was no doubt or hesitation in either of them. It was not a question of why or intent; neither needed any reason or justification. All that remained was the fight to discover which of them was supreme.

Jake felt like shit and just wanted to charge into the horizon to get back, but before doing anything else, he had to heal. Arcane Awakening had ravaged his body quite a bit, and the entire flung-across-the-planet thing had certainly not helped. He felt lucky he had landed in sand and not smashed into rock or maybe a mountain, but a part of him also doubted it was luck. The words Ell’Hakan had spoken made him believe the plan was never to kill him.

He quickly chugged a healing potion and entered meditation, considering what kind of bullshit skill had been used on him. It did not seem like something a D-grade should be capable of at all. Was it due to that orb? The ritual circle? Or was it just a skill of an insanely high rarity? It had Yore in the name, so what if that was the skill granted by Yip of Yore from his True Blessing? Jake had gotten a divine-rarity skill, and even if Ell’Hakan did not get that, it had to be at least mythical or something, right? Maybe above mythical but below divine, assuming there were rarities in between.

There were so many doubts in his mind, but one thing was clear as day: Jake had been countered. From the very moment he appeared, he had been playing along with whatever Ell’Hakan had planned. He hated the thought, but chances were that Chris had only been killed with the intent of pissing him off. If he had not done that, Jake would have just appeared confused about why the orange guy was there. But with the death of Chris, Jake had blown his fuse immediately and attacked like an absolute idiot. He had not acted according to anything he had practiced at all, instead just tunnel-visioning from start to end. It was an utter failure on his part.

What made it even worse was that Jake had no fucking idea what it was all about. If the plan had always been to fight him, only to toss him away, why fight in the first place? To buy time? Did they even need to buy time with fighting? If Ell’Hakan had just talked, Jake would have been delayed plenty. And what did he hope to accomplish by sending Jake away? To take over Haven? Hurt those who lived there? If that was what he wanted, he could have just broken the monument before Jake could return to Earth. He’d clearly had time.

No, he had wanted Jake to return, and he had wanted to send him away to where he was now. But for the life of him, Jake could not figure out why the fuck he would want that. Just to try and spread rumors and ruin Jake’s reputation? Why the fuck would he think Jake would care about that?

Jake was annoyed beyond belief as he tried to focus on something more positive. Like the fact that he’d at least gotten in a nice blow at the end. He had killed two of them, and he knew from their level of power they were not weak. Cultivating people of that power this early on in the integration meant a significant investment. No matter what, it had to have been a loss that stung.

Checking his notifications, he saw he’d also gained a level.

*You have slain [Nahoom - lvl 191 / Sworn Celestial Mender - lvl 183 / Servant of the Celestial Child – lvl 199] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level.

*You have slain [Nahoom - lvl 187 / Royal Shield Guard - lvl 175 / Servant of the Celestial Child – lvl 199] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level.

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 173 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 178 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

He was a bit confused at seeing them both have the same profession, and both having it maxed out. Jake had heard from Miranda that she had gotten skills related to Jake, so was this the same thing? It had to be, right? Or was Celestial Child just some title Ell’Hakan had stolen from someone else? More questions he had no answers to.

As for how he had killed the two of them…. Well, let’s just say he had gotten some good stuff out of his long alchemy sessions and his extreme spending.

Jake had made a little extra something shortly before returning from the Order. He only had a few bottles so far and had just used one, but the effect had been more than satisfactory.

[Sleeping Night Toxin (Rare)] – Sometimes, the most potent poison is that which is never felt or seen before it is too late. Mixing eth, hemo- and necrotic toxins, a potent yet harmless poison has been made. Will be in a hidden sleeping state by default, making it near-undetectable. If injected into a foe, it will simply linger within the Soulshape, slowly dispersing harmlessly. However, if awakened, the toxins will all spring to life, seeking to kill their target with necrotic and hemotoxic properties. Will cause direct damage to both the Soulshape and physical body of those infected once awakened. Has an increased effect if the target is unaware of the infection upon activation.

It was Jake’s magnum opus so far when it came to poisons. It had combined everything he had learned and was far more challenging to make than anything else he had. Jake’s own success chance when concocting it was in the single digits, percentage-wise, and each concoction only gave him one or two bottles. Not to mention the cost. The toxin was also far more complex than anything he had made prior. Shit, he had even somehow mixed in a bit of that stealth attack concept.

As with other creations, the poison’s weaknesses and limitations translated to more overall power once these aspects were circumvented. Rather than slowly infecting someone with poison and damaging them little by little, this poison was instant. It would harmlessly spread throughout until Jake activated it using his newly upgraded Touch of the Malefic Viper. He had considered making a poison like this for a long time but had only truly begun after upgrading the skill.

He continued his meditation for a while longer and felt in pretty good shape again. He had only really expended stamina and mana during the fight, and his health was fixed quickly with the earlier potion. Opening his eyes, Jake stood up and stretched a bit. Rustling his cloak, he also got out all of the damn sand. Finally, he studied his environment: desert all around for what had to be thousands of kilometers in each direction.

Jake knew there was nothing else to do but get moving.

Yet as he stood there and considered what direction to move in, he felt faint tremors below. He wondered if it was coming for him, but he felt the movements go elsewhere. Looking out into the desert, he saw some stones spread around but nothing else.

Suddenly, the ground rumbled, and three yellow pillars that seemed to meld into the background shot up from the ground as if coming up for air. Large, wriggling forms more than a hundred meters long, all three of which Jake quickly Identified.

[Veilskin Sand Worm – lvl 197]

[Veilskin Sand Worm – lvl 196]

[Veilskin Sand Worm – lvl 192]

Jake stared at them a bit in awe as he saw something else out of the corner of his eye. Hundreds of kilometers away, it looked as if a tower was suddenly erected as a massive form emerged. Its length had to be measured in kilometers.

[Behemoth Sand Worm – lvl ???]

Similar scenes played out around Jake as he realized he had found himself smack in the middle of sand worm territory… which made him realize that sometimes you have to find the good in the bad. Jake had a lot of pent-up frustration and a long journey ahead of him.

The worms wouldn’t help with the distance, but they sure as hell would help with the frustration as he took out his bow. He knew he needed to figure out how to not get fucked over again by Ell’Hakan… but no matter what, more power would help whatever anti-fuckery method he found.

Chapter 22

Just Sand-Witch Things

Due to the suddenness of the attack, many of those behind it still remained within Haven. They believed they could simply lie low and hide, acting like normal citizens until their side came out on top. It had worked for a time… but only because Miranda had been distracted.

Every action carried intent, and this intent followed you like a dark fog. Not to normal people… but to Miranda, there were traces left behind at the broken teleportation circle for her to track. Creatures that existed only in minds and dreams had seen what they had done. It did not take her long to locate those who had been behind the destruction of the teleporters.

They were mostly normal people, some not even D-grade. Miranda could admit that the security around their teleporters had been shit. No one had expected an attack, and she still found any potential explanation for the attack nonsensical. Haven had done all it could to stay neutral, so why the hell target them?

Annoyed but pressed for time, Miranda would not have the opportunity to interrogate them. Considering their goal of escape, she would not have time to either as she made the call.

The man hid his face as he walked through the busy, panicked streets. Everyone was confused, as they had only heard that the Viper’s Chosen had returned to Earth and engaged the alien invader. This confusion turned to something akin to panic when the fight stopped and a barrier encompassed the entire city.

None of it was his concern. The citizens were safe; they were never the targets. He saw them as victims, the lot of them.

People sought their homes, and so did the man. He got inside and quickly closed the door, then activated what defensive measures each house was equipped with. After taking off his cloak, he headed toward his living room.

Plopping down on the couch, he let out a sigh of relief. He and the others had not been discovered yet, and considering the lack of response, he doubted they would be. All he had to do now was wait.

Feeling relatively safe, he got up again and went to grab a bottle from his fridge. Well, it was just a box with a magic circle to cool it down, but it worked as a fridge.

He walked over and opened it just as he heard a knock on his door. The door to his bedroom. His eyes opened wide as he whipped his head towards the door, with his hand still reaching for the bottle stashed in the back of the fridge. Yet rather than a bottle, he felt his hand meet something soft.

The man barely had time to turn his head before two hands grasped his wrist and dragged him into the fridge, slamming the door behind him. A faint sound emerged from within before the door opened again, revealing nothing but a severed hand clutching a bottle.

--

Miranda quickly eliminated all of them after summoning the Drowned Swamp Maidens, using one of her more efficient rituals to kill those significantly weaker than herself and within her domain. Exactly how the skill worked wasn’t something Miranda entirely knew. What she did know was that it called upon the spirits of the Drowned Swamp Maidens, which were more conceptual apparitions than anything truly real. They were living ideas.

Getting rid of the terrorists—because that is what they were—had only taken her around a minute. In that time, Ell’Hakan and his two followers had not rushed over but simply walked up to the edge of the barrier at a leisurely pace.

She observed as the man stopped in front of the barrier. He raised his hand and touched it for a faint moment, waiting five or so seconds before speaking. "Ms. Wells, I believe you should be able to hear me. Am I correct?"

Miranda briefly opened her eyes and saw Neil was still hard at work, having even put his party members to work placing down materials in the circle. Closing them again, she decided to buy time. At that moment, when she felt his hand touch the barrier, she also felt a pulse enter it, making her tremble. She did not know what it was and decided that if the guy wanted to talk… she would talk. Well, she wouldn’t talk.

Focusing, she took out a small doll and infused some magic into it. Placing it in the middle of the circle, she said an incantation and immersed her mind.

In the outside world, a figure faded into existence. A human-sized doll looking quite a bit like Miranda appeared, more than a little scary with its oversized buttons for eyes and amateur craftsmanship. Miranda had had to sew it herself, and damn, was she bad at sewing.

But the doll worked, and its mouth moved to say, “Is it not a basic skill expected of a City Lord to have some level of perception within the domain they rule?”

“It is," Ell’Hakan spoke, looking at the doll. "I must say, this is my first time ever meeting a witch, and I am already intrigued. I would like to apologize for before. I believed it necessary to show that I have ways to break barriers such as this to make you come out for a talk. Ah, on that, I would advise you to not rely too much on the Pylon for city defenses. As a noble with a significantly higher rank and a profession that allows it, I possess skills to combat it quite effectively. Instead, I would work on making your own skills the primary basis of the barrier, with the Pylon only acting as an auxiliary energy source."

Miranda looked confused at the man speaking. Enough to doubt if Ell’Hakan could influence her through the puppet. But she quickly ruled that out simply by how she assumed it worked. If his ability was to influence emotions, he had to influence the soul, and the puppet she had sent did not contain anything to influence. Which begged the question…

"Why are you telling me that?"

"Friendly advice from one ruler to another," Ell’Hakan answered. "And a good icebreaker that shows my intent. I want to make an educated guess and say you are currently working on a method of escape or some kind of counterattack. Probably escape, considering I just defeated the Chosen of the Viper."

"You did not defeat him; you just delayed him and pissed him off," Miranda countered in a curt tone.

"I did what I intended. Today was not the time for an actual fight.” The man nodded in recognition. "I will just lay the cards out on the table. I have no interest in causing you any harm, Ms. Wells, but I have made a deal with the United Cities Alliance, as they call themselves. They very much would like to see you dead."

"Are you really going with the ‘it’s not personal’ line?" Miranda scoffed.

"Not really. I am going with the line of saying that you should escape. I will not stop you. But I will warn you that the United Cities Alliance will try to take you down. From what I heard, the Chosen’s influence on this planet would be significantly weakened, and his current political position ruined, if you were to die.”

"Doesn’t sound like a reason to suddenly spare me and not break in here and now," Miranda answered. She briefly disconnected from her doll, and Neil signaled that he’d soon be ready.

Entering it again, she saw Ell’Hakan shake his head and chuckle. "We both know that entering wouldn’t lead to a pleasant experience. For either of us. What you are capable of is not pertinent information, and I would prefer not to take such an unnecessary risk. The Verdant Witches are notorious for their mysticism, and you are no different. With me having no interest in attacking you, simply waiting for you to leave seems like the best course of action. Ah, but do be warned that if you choose to stay, I will have to act at one point or another.”

"You want me to just leave Haven in your hands?" Miranda shot back. That was exactly what she was going to do, but she had to at least act like the man didn’t have the upper hand. Also… she wanted to know what he was planning.

"I will lay no claim on anything here today. Someone from the United Cities Alliance will come and take charge for now. No one has any interest in killing the citizens, so rest easy.”

"Grand words coming from someone who is all about bullshit lies and making up stories."

"But I do speak the truth, as no story matters if there are none to remember and tell it," Ell’Hakan simply said.

"A story that is a lie. What are you even hoping to accomplish? Ruining our reputations? Even if you succeed in doing that, how will it matter? Can you truly call that an actual victory? To me, it all seems like the pathetic actions of someone too weak to battle Lord Thayne head-on."

Miranda hoped to get a bit of a rise out of the guy. Maybe make him temporarily lose his cool and overshare. She had confidence that even if he wanted to attack now, she could hold him off long enough for Neil to be done.

"Fighting… holds little meaning," Ell’Hakan spoke. "A fight is always just a single line in the history books. A declaration of the outcome after the fact. Tell me, how many were truly aware of our brief battle here today? A few dozen? Add on a few bored gods gazing upon events they truly don’t care about, and it is little more than a handful. My words of the battle will echo more true than anyone else’s. All they know is that a fight took place, and it ended up with me left standing and the Malefic’s Chosen gone. I know what you are hoping to accomplish, but let me assure you, a story is better told if not spoiled beforehand. Killing the Chosen would have been a waste. I am not telling a small tale, but a true epic."

"One where you try to define what is the truth," Miranda said.

"Precisely." Ell’Hakan smiled. "I have enjoyed our brief conversation, even if it was rather one-sided. I would advise you to leave now or show your hand, as I can delay no longer before my partners get dissatisfied with my dallying."

He snapped his fingers, and Miranda’s doll caught fire and burned down in an instant, throwing Miranda back to her real body. In the middle of the ritual circle, her small doll had now turned to ashes. She only had time to orient herself before she felt another pulse go through the barrier. The pulse seemed to attack not the barrier’s energy, but the very framework.

"How long?" Miranda asked.

"Done—was just waiting for you," Neil said.

Miranda nodded as she hurried over to the teleportation circle. Just before stepping on it, she briefly spoke a final spell before getting teleported away along with most other notable characters in Haven—besides Sultan and Arnold.

No one liked sand. As spoken by a not-that-wise man long ago, it was coarse, rough, irritating, and got everywhere. And that was normal sand. Magical sand was even worse. Not because it was finer and somehow more everywhere, but because it sure as hell was coarser and rougher by a significant magnitude.

And then there were sandstorms. Sandstorms on Earth before the system could be devastating, but a post-system sandstorm was on an entirely different level.

Jake was already in an even worse mood than usual when it arrived. He had tried to hurry through the desert while hunting down sand worms, but the fuckers were borderline impossible to kill. Even the peak D-grade ones, Jake could not easily get rid of. Their bodies were massive, and they clearly had an equally massive health pool, but the worst part was their behavior. He had yet to have a single one even try to fight back. He had even tried to attack a C-grade, done all the preparations, been as ready as he could, only for him to land a single Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter before the worm dove straight down and swam away, never to be seen again.

That was when he truly realized… these worms did not at all care about fighting. They just ate stuff. Jake had wondered how that would even work, as the surface was bound to run out of natural treasures and high-energy items at some point.

Which is where the sandstorms came in.

It was like the very horizon had moved towards him. A towering wall of sand reaching into the sky for several kilometers had barreled towards Jake as he tried to fly through the desert. He had reacted quickly and tried to mimic the worms by boring into the ground and hiding until things blew over. Which should work, right?

Wrong.

Because this sandstorm was a true marvel of the elements. It was a zone of earth and wind mana that mixed and created what could almost be called a moving domain. A true wonderland for creatures that relied on these energies. Or one to spawn such creatures.

Elementals simply came into being within the massive sandstorm, and while the sand worms did not want to fight, these elementals sure did. As though a giant vacuum cleaner had been turned on, several elementals sucked up all the sand around Jake and pulled him out of the desert.

He felt sand hit his body, damaging him as it impacted with nearly supersonic speeds. Sand even found the eyeholes of his mask and hit one eye, forcing him to close it. Jake was well and truly pissed as he used his one good eye to Identify one of the elementals attacking him.

[Sand Elemental – lvl 184]

One would maybe think that this kind of environment was bad for Jake. And they would be right. But that did not really matter much when all he faced were D-grade elementals.

Arcane Awakening in the stable mode activated, and a faint arcane barrier covered his entire body. This passive shield was usually not a big deal, but when it blocked thousands of small "attacks" every second? It allowed him to effectively ignore the environmental effects and move to kill his foes as he did the one thing that always worked: blow them the hell up with destructive arcane arrows.

Meanwhile, Jake made his way out of the sandstorm. As he traveled through it, he saw entire sand worms had been dragged out of the ground and into the storm, as well as hundreds of other creatures. The sand worms seemed to make it out, though, as they worked together and used sand magic of their own to help others escape. Elementals consumed the creatures that could not get away, and it was as if the sandstorm itself absorbed some of the energy whenever something died.

However, while the sandstorm took, it also gave, as it left behind treasures. Treasure generated from the sandstorm itself that simply dropped onto the sand and was left behind. If not for being stuck in the middle of the damn storm, Jake would have marveled at the ways the ecosystem had evolved.

After more than an hour of struggle, Jake finally made it out of the sandstorm and saw the massive natural phenomenon just continue sweeping across the desert. His momentary sense of relief from being out was promptly broken as he realized he had been flying back in the direction he had just come from to get out of the damn storm.

"Fuck me," Jake muttered as he wondered what to do. As he was flying up in the air, he saw dozens of sand worms begin to emerge below to consume the natural treasures dropped from the sandstorm. As Jake stared at them, he got an idea. An idea that just might work.

He just needed one of them to eat him first…

Chapter 23

Into the Ground

Getting a massive sand worm to eat you was actually way easier than Jake had expected. Not that Jake should have expected much from the get-go; it was a stupid expectation. All he had done was just land on the sand, get semi-close to a natural treasure while using Arcane Stealth, and boom—a worm popped up and swallowed him. It was a level 198 worm—so damn close to evolution, too.

The worm nearly instantly noticed it had caught something it didn’t want and tried to spit him out. However, Jake held on inside its massive maw as he spoke, "Hey! Worm! Make a deal!"

It did not react aside from continuing to thrash and trying to spit Jake out. That was when he realized that the sand worms had no ears and probably not even a sense of hearing, making him switch to telepathy.

"Worm. Make deal. You help me, I help you. If not, death."

As he said the words, Jake took out a handful of earth-affinity herbs and tossed them down the gullet of the worm. It was a gamble… that paid off immediately, as the worm stopped moving. By now, Jake was hanging onto the flesh walls of the giant worm’s mouth as he spoke again.

"If you help me get that way," Jake sent telepathically as he poked the side of the giant worm’s mouth with a weak arcane bolt, "I will feed you. Okay?"

It should not come as a surprise that the giant worm could not speak. Jake was really gambling on this idea, as he assumed that these sand worms were dumb as bricks and—

"I apologize; I think there is some kind of misunderstanding,” a deep, rumbling voice said in Jake’s head. “I did not mean to try and eat you… Actually, what are you?"

Wait, what? Jake questioned himself.

"You understand me?" Jake asked, confused.

"I think? I am more questioning how you can speak. You aren’t a worm. Or are you? You don’t look like one, but I have seen weird worms before…"

"I am not a worm, no," Jake made clear. "I am human and ended up here by accident. All I am looking for is a way out of the desert."

"Human? What are those?” the overly curious worm asked. “And why leave? You can’t move properly outside. A few tried. Oh, unless you get stronger and evolve; I saw one able to do it. Are you evolved?"

Jake had to admit, when he began his plan, he had not expected to have a conversation with a worm. He had more hoped to communicate his intent and perhaps find a way to nudge the worm in the right direction while bribing it with stuff.

"I am not evolved, no, but I can move properly outside,” Jake said. “I cannot move properly here, though, which is why I need your help. If you can help me get out of the desert, I can give you good stuff in return."

The worm fell silent for a few moments, still just sitting there while poking out of the sand like a tower with its mouth wide open, allowing Jake to fly out at any moment. "What kind of stuff?" it finally asked.

Jake smiled to himself as he took out one of the orbs he had looted from one of the many earth elementals he had killed while traveling with Carmen. "Things like this," Jake said as he threw the orb down the long tunnel that was the worm’s mouth.

Seconds passed before the worm answered, "Okay. I will help you, human. Also, don’t I have to? If not, I will die."

He had kind of forgotten he had threatened death before. Jake had really only done it since that kind of intent was something animals tended to understand.

"I promise I won’t hurt you at all. Instead, let’s make this something to benefit us both."

"Sounds better than death—that is for sure," the worm said, Jake detecting a hint of sarcasm in the voice. Had he found himself a sassy giant sand worm?

The next few minutes passed as Jake talked with the worm and got a better idea of how their species worked. The worms were actually damn good at magic and moved primarily through some kind of earth telekinesis to push them forward using the sand, allowing them to travel at frankly insane speeds for their size.

To hunt for treasures better, the worms all stayed in contact through some kind of telepathy network. It worked by linking them up with one another while in the area, and often a single C-grade always stayed close to the larger groups of worms to help them in case anything went wrong. There were creatures besides the sand elementals that hunted the worms, but most never chased down into the sand; so as long as the worms could warn others in time, they stayed safe. All in all, Jake learned to not disrespect the intelligence of giant sand worms.

In return, Jake told the worm of things outside the desert while he guided it.

Using threads of stable arcane mana, he anchored himself to the side of the worm’s mouth and got into a comfortable position. Contrary to what one would expect, the inside of the worm was not moist at all, but rather as dry as the desert outside. The walls of the mouth were also rough and tough like rock, likely from repeatedly swallowing sand. Something the worm would avoid doing with its passenger inside.

That is how Jake managed to catch a ride inside a giant sand worm as he traveled what had to be a few kilometers under the sand. They shot forward with the speed of a bullet through the desert, and Jake faintly felt a few worms around them at times, but being inside of one made them all ignore him. The worm did say that a few detected him, but the worm just explained it away somehow. Jake chose to trust his driver in this, as, honestly? It seemed like a stand-up worm. Would definitely rate it five stars.

He felt good enough to enter meditation, where he finally found time to ruminate on one of his most pertinent issues: What if Ell’Hakan could do that weird transportation skill again?

It didn’t seem likely, but Jake saw no reason to gamble on that one. Even if he didn’t have more orbs or a ritual circle, it was a huge risk anyway, simply because Jake had no way to currently combat whatever concept the skill relied on.

While there were aspects of it, it wasn’t space magic. Jake had a strong feeling that even if he managed to break through and use One Step, he would not have been freed. Maybe he would have moved a bit, but the skill would still have taken effect and flung him away, making the few hundred meters he managed to teleport insignificant.

One Step was a skill that was purely space magic. It relied one hundred percent on the concept of space to travel, so if space magic was just a part of it, it wouldn’t allow him to get out. He needed something far different.

Considering his first escape skill was Shadow Vault, Jake popped into his Soulspace and—

"No," sim-Jake said the moment he appeared.

Jake exited his Soulspace again and considered his second option. One he had seen be used to escape a very perilous situation before when used by its maker.

He was naturally thinking of Wings of the Malefic Viper.

The attack on the Risen had started as expected. The weaker individuals took the frontlines from the side of the Holy Church and United Cities Alliance while the Risen tried to preserve their numbers and strength. They tried to only send out the stronger parties from their side, as this was not a battle they could win. Only delay. Priscilla stayed back to organize everything, while Casper had chosen to take to the battlefield.

It’s a bit weird, when I think about it, Casper thought to himself as he released his curses upon the opposing army.

He was a Risen and what many would call a bringer of death and misery with his specialization in curses. Yet Casper realized that he hadn’t actually killed any humans since the tutorial. Not even during the Treasure Hunt had he taken a single life due to how the Risen had approached the event.

Until today, that is.

War was a common occurrence in the multiverse. He knew the Blightfather and the undead faction as a whole condoned these kinds of wars and viewed them as a good thing. It helped weed out the population and, in turn, gave rise to individuals that were not only more powerful, but also more talented. War was far more than a single fight. It was a long struggle and something that forced you to train both your skills and mind. Those who came out of a war on top either had their mentality steeled or broken.

Casper himself was an example of the latter. He had already been broken once during the tutorial. He knew he was not made for war. He hated it. He despised the senseless killing of people fighting for things that were either lies or that they barely believed in. Most of the invaders from the Holy Church or United Cities Alliance were only there because of what their factions had lied about or due to sheer ignorance. They had no personal reason. Casper hated every moment he spent on the battlefield… which only made him stronger.

It didn’t help that he was really fucking good at it.

Curses were fueled by emotions, and the battlefield was a very emotional place. Casper simply had to fuel the fire as he took advantage of the area. One had to remember that the Risen were the defenders, and even if many of their defensive measures had been sabotaged, far from all had been struck. The most potent defenses, only a handful were aware of. One of these defensive items was called the Thousand Splinters Pillar. To the naked eye, it looked like a giant, rotten tree trunk, but to Casper, it was a battery of infinite weapons.

Casper flew above the battlefield with the large pillar floating behind him, sending splinters raining down towards the battlefield. Every time a splinter hit someone, they were struck by a mental attack. Those unable to resist lashed out and began attacking those around them mercilessly, as it altered their perception of who was an ally or friend. Worse, the curse energy in each splinter would be amplified every time the person attacked someone.

Within the first half an hour of the battle, Casper killed hundreds. Within the first day, over a thousand. It slowed down with time as they adapted, but Casper was just stronger. Some were not even D-grade, and Casper quickly realized something was off but kept fighting. At the beginning of the second day, after a long rest where others had to take to the battle, he pushed forward and killed more and more, soon leaving behind the other Risen. If he was ahead of the others, he could limit casualties on their side.

Keeping up and pressing his advantage, Casper soon found himself close to enemy lines. He stopped, and at this moment, his Spirit Mark resonated, and he heard Priscilla speak.

"Retreat for now. They are just throwing bodies at us to tire us out, both mentally and in resources."

Casper instantly agreed and began to make his way back. He stared at the battlefield below and saw corpses everywhere. Most were from the Holy Church, but Priscilla was right… These were just meat shields. Proof once more of the ruthlessness of the Holy Church when it came to war. They were willing to make any sacrifice as long as they won. Their own elites had also cowardly stayed back since the moment Casper rejoined the battle.

One of the defensive measures they still had on the side of the Risen was a single Orb of Second Awakening—a one-time-use item that would send a specially attuned death-mana pulse out to reanimate those who had died as undead. Not Risen, just mindless monsters. But the Church and United Cities clearly knew this, as flames constantly swept across the battlefield, burning the bodies of the fallen, followed by pulses from the priests of the Holy Church to "purify" the souls. It was cruel but effec—

"Watch out!" Casper suddenly heard mid-retreat.

He did not react in time, but a shield still appeared and blocked a beam of light that had been headed straight for him as one of his preprepared spells activated. Casper’s eyes opened wide as a second attack arrived, this time from directly below. He retreated towards the battlefield once more as a sword of light cut the area in which he had just stood. The air shimmered as a figure emerged from invisibility. As he appeared, so did his comrades.

"Thousands dead to isolate me in an ambush…" Casper muttered.

Five people had appeared, and he recognized three of them as the party members of Bertram. It was the healer Noor, the swordsman Lucian, and mage Joshua. Notably absent were the two strongest people in the party, Maria and Bertram.

The two replacements were also an archer and a warrior.

"Thousands of fates realized as they enter the Holyland with honor," the priestess, Noor, said.

Goddamn fanatics, Casper cursed, seeing no need for further words. With the pillar still floating behind him, Casper counterattacked as he prioritized getting back to safety. Lucian cut him off and tried to strike Casper, but was intercepted by a wooden barrier that exploded in his face.

Joshua released a beam of light that forced Casper to dodge as he sent cursed stakes in retaliation. The archer and warrior also joined the fray and tried to pressure the Risen, but the difference was clear. Which only made Casper frown more, as they should know they didn’t stand a chance. Which meant it was as he and Priscilla expected…

"Do you need my help?" Lyra asked him from within his pendant, but Casper refused.

"Save your energy in case they have a trick up their sleeve," Casper answered. “They have something planned, and I may need you to get us out of here.” He had not overextended without a backup plan.

Lyra acknowledged this, ready to unleash her power if anything went awry. Casper handled the fight fine on his own, but killing any one of them was an issue. He lacked in the damage output department, as he was the type of fighter to slowly build up curses in his foes or lead them into traps. With no time to set up traps, Casper just had to fight with his wooden stakes and general curse magic as he ever so slowly tried to get away.

The group had only revealed themselves the moment Casper had begun retreating, so it was clear something was up. He tried probing out responses as he used a boosting skill and pressed Lucian hard. Giant stakes appeared all around Casper, and he connected them to the pillar floating behind him to send out pulses of pure curse energy.

Casper was about to explode the entire thing… when he sensed something was off.

"You fucking bastards," Casper muttered as he looked down. Thousands of motes of light had appeared, floating in the air as Noor spoke an incantation.

"Holy martyrs, heed my call!" the insane priestess yelled as the many motes of light began moving.

Casper had underestimated the depravity of the Holy Church. These people were not just meat shields; they were straight-up sacrifices. He knew this kind of magic; it was something the Holy Church had deployed before. Each of the killed members from the Holy Church had carried on them a mark that effectively turned them into dead people walking to bring out more power, and when they then died, all their remaining energy would be focused into the mark. The holy "purification" earlier had not been to cleanse their souls or whatever, either, but simply a way to prime the motes.

The motes of light flew up and entered a mark on the swordsman Lucian. Casper was perplexed for a moment until he realized what they were doing. These people are batshit insane.

Lucian began glowing with intense light as Casper tried to back away, but the four others moved to stop him. Each of them had activated all their boosting skills to try and keep him still as Lucian’s aura grew with every moment.

Just as he was about to unleash it all, Casper snickered a bit.

"Lyra. Now."

Casper’s body suddenly glowed green as a ghostly form appeared above him. Lyra opened her mouth and let out a fitting unholy scream that sent out a wave of soul energy. At the same time, the pillar exploded, sending splinters in every direction. Everyone was stunned and pelted with splinters as Casper’s entire body turned green and transparent before he flew straight down towards the ground.

Lucian broke through the stun effect and chased him, surpassing Casper’s speed and catching up to him rapidly. The Risen pressed himself even more, and he felt his body burn from the sheer presence of the man, who looked like a miniature sun. Lucian’s blade closed in just as Casper reached the ground… and continued.

The blade impacted the soil and shook the battlefield with a huge explosion, sending shockwaves out. A bright light flashed before it subsided, leaving only a deep hole in the ground as well as a struggling Lucian. He tried to strike again, but his arm broke mid-swing as his body started to turn to motes of light. A few seconds later, not a single trace of him remained, as his body had been consumed by the holy power.

Back behind the walls, a ghostly green figure emerged right next to Priscilla. It was naturally Casper, who quickly turned corporeal again before slumping to the ground. "Those absolute maniacs actually fucking did it."

"We expected it," Priscilla sighed, still clearly troubled by the sheer level of fanaticism displayed by the Church.

Casper nodded as he looked over at a certain cave. "Is it time we make our grand exit?"

"Most have already been evacuated," Priscilla answered.

"Go now," Casper said. "I will help the rest retreat from the battlefield as you lead the last ones in there."

"We’re really doing this," Priscilla said, uncertainty clear on her face.

"We tried and failed," Casper said. "So let’s just stick to the original plan. We should have just accepted long ago that Earth would never be a home for us anyway."

Chapter 24

Making (Unpleasant) Business Deals

When Jake thought about it, Wings of the Malefic Viper was honestly a weird skill in his repertoire. Mainly in that he didn’t really need one of its primary functions anymore: the ability to fly. Jake could just do that using mana manipulation.

This meant the skill now only served as a way to pump out poison mist. It did add a bit of maneuverability while flying, but it was not that major. Jake knew that a lot of the skill’s allocated Records went into simply summoning the wings in their phantasmal form and adding them to the Soulshape, but that wasn’t exactly something Jake "needed" either.

Jake still used the wings a lot due to their relatively low upkeep, which meant the only time he really spent resources on them was with the initial summoning and when he pumped out poison. The poison pumped out also wasn’t exactly impressive. It mostly just served as a way to keep his current poison active and the occasional area-of-effect attack.

Upgrading the poison mist aspect of the skill did not appeal to him either. Besides, if he upgraded his Blood of the Malefic Viper, he would inadvertently also upgrade the mist. There was also the approach of trying to make them more durable, or perhaps increasing the maneuverability and overall flight speed. There was even the approach of going the same direction as Draskil, where his wings allowed him short-range teleports and speed-ups in battle. His version was clearly one specialized for movement in combat and taking advantage of his existing physical stats. But that wasn’t the direction Jake wanted to take.

During the vision where he’d seen Villy getting smacked by Valdemar, he had seen Wings of the Malefic Viper used as an escape skill to great effect. He had felt how the wings had somehow been activated, and a "tunnel" of sorts had been formed that allowed him to escape. Jake wanted something like that.

He wanted an escape skill—not necessarily to run from a fight he could not win like Villy had, but to escape situations that rendered him stuck or sealed in some way. Like the skill Ell’Hakan had used, which had seemed to isolate Jake from the rest of the world for its duration.

One Step was already better at long-distance movement anyway. It was a legendary skill specialized in travel, while Wings had so many other aspects. There were some issues with upgrading it, though.

Having already been shown the skill twice, Jake was not sure if he could see it again. It did say that he could only view a vision of a skill once, but did the one he had count? It felt like that one had been more about Fangs of the Malefic Viper than Wings.

Nevertheless, Jake tried to use the Path of the Heretic-Chosen skill as he focused on Wings of the Malefic Viper. Not necessarily to use it, but to see if he even could—and to his disappointment, the skill did not activate right away. This left him even more unsure, as he still didn’t know if it was because he didn’t fulfill some requirement to see the vision or because he had used his one chance on the skill.

He also tried to reflect on the feeling he’d had during the vision, but it was all too blurry for him to remember. His focus back then had been on Fangs of the Malefic Viper and Fang of Man, not Wings, so even when he had felt the escape technique, his mind had partly been elsewhere.

"You busy?" the worm suddenly asked while Jake meditated on the issue.

"Only a little," Jake answered. "Why do you ask?"

"You said you wanted to hurry, right? The problem is that up ahead is the territory of scorpions, and they like to hide in the sand and attack if we try to go through, so we tend to avoid them. Avoiding them and going around will be slower…” Leadingly, the worm added, “But if the human is strong, then maybe…"

"Let me guess, they have a C-grade leader of some kind?"

"Yep, and it is very dangerous. One of the big worms tried to scare them off once but was hit, and it took weeks to recover from the nasty venom. We aren’t that good at fighting, if you haven’t noticed, and trying to swallow them wouldn’t end well, as they have tough bodies and are very poisonous even when eaten. A few worms have eaten some of them, and it never ended well.”

"So I guess this is all for the wellbeing of worm society?" Jake asked somewhat teasingly.

"Their leader may or may not also be guarding a very tasty-looking rock that I wouldn’t complain if I happened to eat," the worm admitted, making its intentions clear.

Even if worm society was very altruistic and they believed in sharing, there was still some greed when it came to unique, powerful natural treasures. The C-grades tended to monopolize these, according to what the worm had told him, and the only exception was when a treasure was found that would allow another worm to break through to C-grade. Another C-grade among them was far more valuable than the limited growth of one of the existing C-grade worms, and often these treasures didn’t really benefit one already in C-grade that much.

The rock the scorpion guarded was one that fit the criteria of both C-grades and those wanting to evolve being able to use it, according to his worm buddy. It was also one that no other worms dared go for due to the scorpions guarding it.

Jake considered it for a moment. "Fine. Tell me everything you know about them," he said, wanting to at least go in with information.

While Jake had not lost his "fight" with Ell’Hakan because he was weaker, being stronger would potentially have allowed him to avoid getting thrown away entirely. No concept or advanced magic truly mattered before supreme power. If Jake had been a C-grade and just released a massive wave of destructive arcane mana, he would have broken any spell Ell’Hakan could ever conjure up.

Also… Jake still wanted levels, and doing some killing would surely do him good. He felt like he needed it too. Besides, he had the excuse of helping out the worm that was already helping him, and the worm even mentioned this way would be faster. Did the worm specify how much faster or how much of a detour it would be? No, not at all. And he didn’t ask either.

"Okay! So, the scorpions are not that large, only a few times bigger than you, and the most dangerous part is their stringer. The pincers look dangerous, but they aren’t actually that bad, as they can’t really grab our skin… Oh, but they could probably cut off your small parts. So also watch out for those. To make it worse, their skin is not really skin but more like rock, and…"

Jake listened along, considering if fighting them wouldn’t just be a quicker way to find out, as, quite frankly, they just sounded like normal scorpions. Massive scorpions, but still scorpions.

Soon to be dead scorpions.

Caleb sat before the man that he knew had been the impetus of this entire conflict. Why the hell he had asked for a meeting was beyond him, but Caleb had agreed nonetheless. As the Judge of the Court of Shadows in this branch, he was obligated to. The reason was that the leader of the United Cities Alliance had not come to invade the Court. He had not even necessarily asked Caleb to meet.

He had simply approached them as a client.

Arthur sat across from Caleb in a small tent constructed between the group from the United Cities Alliance and Skyggen. Both had men stationed nearby, but Caleb wanted to avoid a fight if necessary. He had to admit that, looking at Arthur, he wasn’t sure if he could kill him. Not because he was strong or anything, but due to the many items he possessed.

Not that Caleb would let that show as he confidently spoke, "I find it brave for you to meet me under four eyes like this.”

"Why?" Arthur asked. "I am not meeting Caleb Thayne, the brother of the Malefic Viper’s Chosen, but the Judge of the Court of Shadows. I am here as a client looking to hire the Court. Nothing more, nothing less."

"And yet you show up with an army," Caleb said a bit mockingly.

"I had to gauge the response. Let me make it clear right now: I feel for you, but your brother is not the man you once thought he was. I am sure you are aware of what the Order of the Malefic Viper is. It is an organization focused not on working together and prosperity, but on domination and death. Recently, after their Patron returned, what did they do to strengthen themselves? They forced every other faction on the planet that the Order was placed on to submit or die. Those who refused, they slaughtered or enslaved. While you may hold the belief that your brother is not a person who would do that, I do not. I look at a history spanning trillion of years and see a pattern.”

Caleb fell silent for a moment before answering, "I do not contest that the Order of the Malefic Viper has unpleasant means, but for there to be any conquest, there must be intent. Jake has absolutely no interest in taking control of this planet. He would rather have someone else become the World Leader than manage any of it himself. He is a fighter and a hunter through and through."

"As long as he remains, no other faction can gain control, as he will always be here, always hold influence,” Arthur said. “Even if he truly does not care, it doesn’t mean others won’t. Being the Chosen, there will be significant interest in our planet once they are aware he is from here. His lack of interest will only fuel their desire to take over our world if just to say they did. But let me concur for a moment that Jake Thayne is no threat. He is not the only reason for this. Can you say that others will not try to dominate our world? The Risen? Or, worse yet, the Holy Church?"

"I don’t know them that well," Caleb confessed. "The Risen, that is. The Holy Church will try to take over the planet; that is something I have no doubt in my mind about. It has been their MO since the very first Era. Which leads me to… Isn’t Jacob your son? You know, the leader of the Holy Church on Earth? Are you willing to kill your own son for fear of losing control of, what, a piece of rock floating in space?"

"Jacob is a prime example of what is wrong with these ideologies spawned from religion. He is now nothing more than a puppet. But you are right. Even if I got the opportunity, I could never bring myself to kill my own son, which is why I made sure he was not on the planet when all of this began. He is just a cog in the machine, and the Holy Church will gladly make use of him by just deploying him elsewhere. I hope he finds peace but never returns.”

Caleb listened along, not even aware that Jacob was off the planet. It kind of made sense, based on the recent movements of the Church. Even so… Caleb still wasn’t certain what the man wanted of him. "You still haven’t said what you mean by coming here as a client."

Arthur smiled and took out a piece of paper. "I want to clarify that it is not that I despise all organizations run by gods. I would actually argue it makes sense in this world to have the highest echelon be made up of gods. My problem is with the religious aspects. The missions of these gods. The Court of Shadows is more a business than organized religion, and you operate not based on faith, but a far more understandable concept: money. I am here to hire the Court of Shadows to assist the United Cities Alliance in our mission to take control of this planet by having you get rid of certain problematic characters that will stand in our way come voting for World Leader."

He handed Caleb the paper, which turned out to be a list, and Caleb took it almost instinctively. He skimmed some of the names but recognized only a scarce few—City Lords belonging to the Holy Church and City Lords who had refused to join any other faction. Notably absent was anyone Caleb actually knew.

"As I mentioned, I understand,” Arthur said, adopting an apologetic tone. “Even if this is all business, we are still humans. Asking you to hunt your own family or friends is something I know you couldn’t do, even if it conflicts with the mission of the Court.”

"But you still want me to assist you. You, who have allied with someone intending to kill my brother.”

Arthur raised an eyebrow and shook his head. "Kill? No, no. Killing Jake Thayne would be utterly moronic. I am not willing to gamble on someone from the Order of the Malefic Viper not suddenly deciding to pay us a visit in a century and blowing up the planet just for slighting their god. But forcing him to abandon the planet? Now that is a whole other story. Now, if Ell’Hakan does manage to somehow slay him, I do not see it necessarily leading back to us, but to him. This would not be my ideal outcome, but an acceptable one."

Caleb considered it for a moment. He could see Jake just leaving Earth altogether if he could no longer find a good reason to stay. He had already gone to the Order several times. There was still one problem, though. "Bold plan that still does not address the elephant in the room: Ell’Hakan."

"A means to an end," Arthur said with little concern. “His intentions and mine are aligned in this, and he and his comrades will get what they want without it impacting humanity too negatively in the long run. There truly is no need to worry about Ell’Hakan. Don’t think I allied with him out of desperation. Everything is in a system-enforced contract, and so far, he has stuck to the plan.”

Caleb sighed, not believing Arthur had even a tenth as much control of the situation as he believed. "Let’s say you succeed in forcing Jake off the planet, and your alien helper sticks to all his promises and leaves too once all this is done. What stops Jake from just coming back in the future? What stops the Order from still wanting to claim it?"

Arthur smiled confidently. "I do recognize that the multiverse is not a place where some fledgling faction can just emerge on its own without finding itself conquered. So I have found an ally. An ally that does not care about conquering the Earth, and one with its Origin in humanity."

It took Caleb a moment to figure it out as he frowned. "Why the hell would they agree to that…"

"All want a foothold, and I offered them good terms. As long as I become World Leader, our deal stands. And Valhal is more than welcoming of any outside force wishing to invade their land, be it the Holy Church or the Order of the Malefic Viper."

Caleb frowned even deeper. He wanted to protest, but just then, he felt a prickle for the first time in a while. A divine message. As he heard the words, he gritted his teeth and opened his eyes even wider than before.

"As the Judge of the Court of Shadows, I accept your contract… but we are increasing the fee. Significantly," Caleb said with annoyance.

"If there is anything we do not lack, it is Credits," Arthur answered as he extended his hand for a shake. "May this be the start of a great working relationship."

Caleb looked at the hand before swatting it away. "I have no interest in any kind of relationship, professional or not. You are making a huge fucking mistake, and it will come back to bite you in the ass. The only reason I am accepting the contract is because I am the Judge. Being nice about it isn’t in the job description."

Not seeming offended in the least, Arthur simply nodded. "Sometimes, we must do business we are not particularly fond of. Accept losses and do things we are not proud of in the moment, but that will lead to a greater future. That is what true leadership is about. I thank you for meeting me here today, Judge of the Court of Shadows. Be it with your blessing or not, I wish you luck in your task, and I genuinely do hope for a fortuitous future. For all of us."

With those words, Arthur took his leave and left Caleb with a long list of names. He took out a special token and checked, only to quickly see that a contract had indeed been signed—not by him, but by another Judge of the Court of Shadows. One not even in their fucking universe. All with the approval of Umbra.

"Fuck me." Caleb sighed as he stood up and went back towards Skyggen. Sometimes it really sucked to be a for-hire guild of assassins.

Chapter 25

Painting the Desert Blue

Factions in the multiverse varied widely. Some factions integrated themselves nearly everywhere quite easily, such as the Court of Shadows. The Court of Shadows found themselves present even in territory and planets run by the Holy Church as long as they kept themselves covert. It was an unspoken agreement that the two factions had kept for many eras, allowing the Church to get rid of individuals they would prefer not to send members after themselves. Let’s just say there were many circumstances where having assassins for hire was just more convenient.

Valhal was also the sort of place that could have "halls" or small groups operate within other’s territories without dominating land themselves. They did occupy some land—unlike the Court of Shadows, where none knew the true location of their headquarters—but not as much as others. The reason for this was simple.

One could be born into the Holy Church. Born into the Risen. Born into the Altmar Empire. But this was not true for Valhal, the Court of Shadows, or the Order of the Malefic Viper. One could have an easier way in, but that did not mean one was born into it. They were organizations that people could join and leave, closer to companies or guilds than empires and countries. Granted, their member contracts could be limiting, but there was always a way out.

Most organizations were also reasonable to some extent. They respected some universal rules set in the multiverse. But… some organizations could not truly be classified. One, in particular, stood out largely due to its power.

Ell’Hakan had been warned that in Haven, there was one person he was not to interfere with no matter what. One person he should even actively make sure the United Cities Alliance did not bother either.

Because some factions were what could only be classified as utterly insane. Usually, factions like these would crumble and break apart, as insanity was not a good attribute for a leader to have, but there was one major organization in the multiverse that, despite its insane methods, managed to thrive.

An organization that had wiped out entire species for looking too much like one of the gods they prayed to. One that willingly had its members go to the domains or sacred sites of their gods despite half dying in the process. One that would be crazy enough to start a war in which trillions would die and swear an eternal blood oath to wipe out you and anyone with a karmic connection to you from the multiverse… over a statue. A work-in-progress statue.

It was naturally the Primordial Church. And the one person Ell’Hakan had been warned about was none other than Felix, the sculptor who was apparently working on a statue of the Malefic Viper—a statue shown by the Chosen himself. This mattered particularly much because the Chosen had, according to rumors, been the first person to see the Viper in eras. This meant that in the eyes of the Eternal Servant, the Chosen was the only one who had truly "seen" the Malefic One, as he had met him both before and after he returned.

Ell’Hakan had been told all this directly by his Patron after the Eternal Servant himself had come to warn him. Warn him that the sculptor was to remain undisturbed until his task was complete. The nahoom had not known what to think about this, as he had honestly not even heard about this sculptor before arriving on Earth. In fact, he had been on his way to meet someone he had heard about and taken a particular interest in.

A certain man of technology by the name of Arnold.

A common misunderstanding was that spiders were insects. They were instead distant relatives of insects, classified as arachnids. Another common misunderstanding was that scorpions were insects, but they were arachnids and far closer related to spiders than something like an ant.

On second thought, most people probably did know this, but Jake didn’t. At least, not the second part about scorpions being arachnids.

Post-system, these things were often mixed together, and these classifications kind of stopped mattering, but it was fun trivia nonetheless. One difference also remained in the number of legs. Like spiders, scorpions had eight of them, and like spiders, these legs were honestly kind of weak and their joints rather exposed.

Jake leaped backward as he dodged the incredibly fast stinger aiming for him, quickly gaining distance from his large foe.

The scorpion had a sand-colored body, and its stinger stood more than twenty meters tall. It had a massive, utterly monstrous body, and the pincers were large enough to snap a human in half if caught. Several humans at once, probably.

Plating covered its entire body, making it look like an invulnerable tank, and Jake did indeed discover that trying to damage its armored parts was useless, with even his Powershot blocked and only leaving a nick. Now, for the far smaller scorpions, Jake could still blow them apart, but the C-grade in question was the real deal.

[Giant Sandstream Scorpion Lord – lvl ???]

Jake slid back across the sand after dodging another attack and heard the cheerleading voice of the worm in the back of his head, despite it hiding several hundred meters down and kilometers away. Yes, these worms had a very impressive range when it came to their telepathy, and no, it did not want to contribute to the fight at all. Not like it needed to.

Throughout the battle, he had landed dozens of stabs with his katars, and it wasn’t hard to hit the gaps between the armor with the occasional arrow. Their fight had been going on for a good while by now, and the difference was quite clear, even if there were some issues.

Streams of sand—probably what gave the massive scorpion its name—whirled around the scorpion and gathered as spear-like weapons that stabbed forward to try and catch Jake. He easily dodged backward and took to the air as he bombarded the scorpion below with stable arcane arrows.

The scorpion angled itself to block with its chitin armor and formed a dome of sand around itself to stop his attacks while trying to heal itself of some of the poison in its body. Jake smirked and simply began charging Arcane Powershot, having already seen the scorpion’s lack of ability to block it with its sand magic.

As expected, it penetrated the wall of sand and struck the scorpion in the stinger, making it screech in pain as even more poison was delivered into its system. Now, Jake had mentioned issues, and one issue was that he had wasted an entire bottle of his special soul poison.

It turned out that it sucked against large foes due to the far larger Soulshape, and the scorpion also had significant innate poison resistance. Enough for him to not be able to build up a proper charge before triggering it. This is why he had just returned to Hemotoxins to at least make it bleed a little more. Oh, another funny fact was that scorpions had blue blood. This had no impact on the fight besides the sand taking on a new color. It was just a bit of trivia.

Thinking about it, this was Jake’s third time fighting a C-grade. The first had been the Phantomshade Panther, and the second the mushroom man he’d obliterated with Draskil. No, he didn’t count the termites. And as the fight with the scorpion continued, it became clear this specimen was weaker than both of the C-grades he had truly faced before.

Moreover, Jake was stronger than he had been in those fights, and the scorpion was not that well matched up against him due to his ranged options. It seemed that these scorpions nearly only fought melee foes, and those they fought with ranged options, their sand magic could face. He had noticed a distinct lack of flying creatures anywhere in the desert, but that was likely due to the one-sided nature of the environment. Birds with the earth affinity were super rare for hopefully obvious reasons.

So just flying around and keeping his distance allowed Jake to whittle down the massive scorpion a little at a time. Still, it wasn’t entirely one-sided… and definitely not a fast fight.

Jake shot a barrage of explosive arrows once the scorpion dispelled its wall of sand and moved to attack. The stinger struck forward and penetrated the sand Jake had just been flying above. A black liquid was excreted that somehow pulsed through the sand, and Jake felt it continue through it to hit anything hiding below ground.

All he had to do to avoid it was not touch the sand, which kept him off the ground. It was also smart to not stand on it, as it gave him more time to dodge the sand manipulation.

The scorpion wasn’t stupid—no C-grades were—and knew it was in a very disadvantageous situation. After Jake managed to blow one of its legs off, the scorpion decided it was time to leave, attempting to dig into the sand and get away.

Jake reacted quickly by doing something many would probably find incredibly wasteful. Flying down, Jake smashed both his fists into the ground and released massive amounts of stable arcane mana into the sand. The scorpion tried to manipulate the sand but found itself unable to move it, as Jake had effectively frozen the ground with pure stability. This did not mean the scorpion couldn’t use sand anymore, as it was able to summon it out of thin air, but it sure as hell wasn’t going to dig anywhere.

Also realizing that Jake was faster, it chose to stand its ground and finally go all out. Its entire body suddenly began shaking, and Jake saw parts of it turn into sand. Jake frowned as the stinger seemed to disintegrate and simply become one with the desert below. Soon after, its pincers followed.

Jake’s danger sense exploded as he jumped, barely avoiding an emergent stinger. A stream of sand went towards him, and he dodged out of the way, only for a pincer to pop out of the sand flying in mid-air.

Looking down, he saw the scorpion’s stinger. Both claws were entirely gone, and it just looked like a big mound of armor, its joints also gone. Yet it still moved its amputated limbs, and in tandem, these limbs were summoned from any sand all around Jake.

It was actually a really cool trick, and probably how it had hunted down so many worms who dared enter its area. Too bad its sneak attacks didn’t work on Jake, as sneak attacks tended to not work on Jake.

Deciding to finish the fight, Jake dove down towards the main body of the scorpion, dodging all attacks on the way. Arrows didn’t do the job, as its armor seemed even stronger in this form, leaving not a single opening. All it had were a few stumps sticking out, which were also covered in armor. It was like trying to hit a safe.

Jake had a way around that, though. He landed on the scorpion and pressed his hands to its body. Touch of the Malefic Viper activated, and the poison went straight into the armor and began corroding it. Dark green cracks appeared within seconds, and Jake felt it turn brittle enough for a good punch to break it.

To the scorpion’s credit, it also swiftly reacted in a way that Jake had not expected. Sand appeared on both sides as two massive pincers emerged and tried to rip Jake off, making him dodge under them and smirk as he kept pumping in poison. The stinger then regrew instantly—not on the tail, as expected, but out of the damn armor right behind Jake. It was a far smaller version of it, but it also moved faster than Jake was ready for.

He was hit on the back as the stinger pumped deadly venom into him. Jake reacted by pumping more poison into the scorpion. While Jake found his poison relatively ineffective at actually doing damage to the scorpion, the C-grade also quickly discovered it had little luck.

Jake did have to admit that the venom was stronger than anything he could make as his skin turned black and his insides began turning to mush. Emphasis on began. Nearly all other D-grades, even peak D-grades, would find themselves turned into piles of goo within a second of being struck with the stinger. It was a true kill-move that sadly relied on something Jake was very resistant to.

Both of them pumped toxins into the other for several more seconds before Jake had to disengage. Eternal Hunger—in its katar form—was summoned as he punched straight down. It penetrated the armor of the scorpion after it had been weakened and made cracks spread. Several more hits shattered a huge part of the armor, and Jake finally cut off the stinger and took to the air.

The scorpion tried to roll over and protect its newly made weak point, but Jake was not having any of it. He used Gaze of the Apex Hunter as a large arrow appeared from his quiver. One he had been saving for this moment. It was naturally Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter.

Frozen, the scorpion could not move in time when Jake shot the arrow down. It hit right in the weak spot and sank into the scorpion’s body, creating an even bigger hole and sending out an intense wave of energy that ravaged its insides. Jake followed up with a few explosive arcane arrows that hit inside the hole and hence exploded inside the scorpion’s body.

It struggled and writhed in pain, but it was too late. Jake activated Mark of the Avaricious Hunter as the scorpion flashed with arcane light for a brief second, making it screech out in pain more. All it took after that was a few more well-placed arrows and a bit of time.

A minute later, the building-sized scorpion finally collapsed on the sand, and Jake got a notification.

*You have slain [Giant Sandstream Scorpion Lord – lvl 202] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 174 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

He didn’t know if he should be annoyed or not at only getting a single level from a kill on a damn C-grade. Then again, it had only been a good half an hour’s work. A bit longer, if you also counted the forty or so D-grades Jake had had to kill before he faced the Scorpion Lord, but he barely counted those due to how easy they’d been.

Sitting down on the sand, Jake took out a health potion and quickly drank it as he closed his eyes and focused on eliminating the venom still in his body. It would take a while, and during the process, he had to keep Arcane Awakening active, so he was in a bit of a hurry. He had not taken that much damage during the fight itself besides the last attack, but he was still tired as hell and would need some rest.

Focusing in meditation, Jake practiced actively using Palate to eliminate the poison in his body while he waited for a certain worm to be brave enough to come over.

Minutes passed as Jake stabilized himself enough to move properly. He had still taken immense internal damage from that last stinger attack and felt like it would probably take a few hours before he was back in peak condition.

"You did it!" the worm happily said from afar.

Jake had also finally stopped tuning the worm out, as it had constantly been bombarding him with "Watch out!" and "Hit now!" and… well, that kind of thing. He had never had a backseat warrior while fighting, and he would prefer to never ever have one again.

"That I did," Jake answered. He already felt the worm move closer, making him also head to their target.

A large stone was standing there in the middle of the desert. Somehow, it stood upright and looked like a tall, slender boulder that someone had placed there. On it were a few natural markings, and it did give off an intense amount of earth-affinity energy as well as something else Jake could not quite recognize, even if it did feel like a familiar concept. Jake had no idea what it was, but he could see why the worm wanted it.

"Now that the Scorpion Lord is dead, you got all you wanted, and we can move on?" Jake asked.

"Well… about that…" the worm began, embarrassed.

"There is more than one C-grade scorpion, isn’t there?"

"Maaaybe? A few?"

"And more stones, too?" Jake asked with a sigh.

"Now, that would be a happy coincidence… Imagine if there were several of these stones, which were kind of maybe linked or something, and getting all of them would be super good or something like that. That would be crazy."

"Are you still trying to claim this way is faster?" Jake asked with exasperation, but he also had to admit he found the entire situation amusing. He had planned to take advantage of the worm to transport him, and there he was working as a mercenary for his driver.

"Well, that depends… C-grades are a lot faster than D-grades, you know? And I am sure I would be super fast if I somehow happened to reach C-grade, which would definitely speed up the journey, and to do that… you know, you can kill scorpions, and I can eat stones. Seems like a perfect fit.”

Jake just closed his eyes, tilted his head, and stared at the sky above.

Guess I am painting the desert blue with scorpion blood.

Chapter 26

A Sandy Sand Worm

After the initial panic from having the entire teleportation network destroyed, things in the many cities across Earth were pretty calm again for a while. Most didn’t even know why the attack had happened, and those who did quickly moved to apprehend those responsible or calm the masses. The cities belonging to the United Cities Alliance also willingly destroyed their own teleporters to sabotage the forces of Earth after making sure that they were ready internally.

Food had been stocked up if they still needed that, and defenses had been strengthened. They also had enough materials to tide over their crafters for the coming conflict. In time, the teleportation network would be reestablished, so they just had to wait.

One of the issues the teleportation network had helped address was beasts and other monsters attacking settlements, but that wasn’t really that big an issue anymore. The beasts had been united by stronger alphas, and large groups had been formed, none of which attacked human settlements. Especially not after the last World Congress, where they had voted on the Unusual Unions Path, which had resulted in many people evolving into classes that worked well with beasts or professions that could make things beasts wanted. This had even formed diplomatic relationships between many cities and “beast hordes,” as they had begun to be called.

All of this is to say that the only beasts who bothered cities were solitary ones or smaller packs. Sometimes, natural phenomena also spawned elementals or the like that attacked cities, but nothing large or organized. There were also many D-grades around by now, and even the weakest cities had a few. This is why what came next was a massive surprise to many.

A guard stood in a tall watchtower, looking all around in boredom. He hadn’t seen anything try to attack for over a month, and his only real job these days was to report whenever caravans or something, anything, approached. He had thought that with the destruction of the teleporters, he would have more work, but that clearly wasn’t the case. Not that no work wasn’t good. They were just a small settlement that was lucky to have a Pylon with about four thousand people living there, of which only five were D-grade. So nothing was probably the best outcome.

As he stretched a bit and looked to the side, he saw some dust being kicked up. The land was dry all around, and he wondered if it was another dust storm. Those could be nasty, and sometimes even had a few elementals in them.

Yet as he saw it come closer, he froze. A massive form emerged from the dust cloud, tens of meters tall. It looked like a gigantic moose and was no doubt well into D-grade. Behind it, hundreds of smaller beasts were revealed, all charging with their leader. All of these were E-grades, but some D-grades were also there.

The guard doubted his eyes for several moments before he collected himself and yelled, "Attack! We’re under attack!"

With slight panic, he sounded all the alarms, and the town went into lockdown. The D-grades present, who had simply been working on their professions, hurried out, and the City Lord rushed up the watchtower. Standing beside the guard, he stared out and also saw the beasts.

"Get everyone ready," the City Lord said with fear as he gritted his teeth.

--

Similar scenes played out all over the planet. No beast tides had been seen for many months, but now they had suddenly restarted. The fragile peace that had been established by the most powerful monsters crumbled in seconds as if a spark had been lit.

Or, more accurately, as though whatever had been holding them back had disappeared.

Thousands of cities suddenly found themselves unprepared after having relaxed their defenses following the last World Congress. Armies of elementals, tides of beasts, and other monsters took advantage of the stockpiles of resources in all these cities. Their attacks were indiscriminatory and went for every faction. The Holy Church, Noboru Clan, United Cities Alliance, and completely unaffiliated factions or individual cities found themselves under assault.

Nobody seemed to know the trigger for this, and quite frankly, most didn’t have time to care. All they knew was that the monsters humanity had finally begun to soften up to had suddenly done a one-eighty, once more viewing human settlements as nothing more than food and experience sources.

Jake didn’t know why it kept happening… Okay, he did know; he just felt a bit weird about it. Why was it that whenever Jake entered a new area with a new type of monster, it turned into Jake effectively committing genocide?

The worm was happy, sure, and Jake wasn’t that sad about it since they still made good progress, both in levels and distance. All the Scorpion Lords were of roughly equal strength, and what little variance they did have wasn’t of any consequence as Jake grew stronger and more accustomed to them between every kill. Moreover, after the first kill, Jake was familiar enough with the scorpions to open every fight with an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter, instantly giving him an advantage.

There ended up being a total of nine stones and nine C-grade Scorpion Lords. Along with the hundreds of high- and peak-tier D-grades Jake also ended up killing, he had truly done a number on the local scorpion population. In some ways, he had been lucky to stumble across so many weak C-grades to hunt. They were barely evolved and he was a good matchup. Plus, they were weak for their grade.

This hunting spree had also naturally led to quite a few levels gained.

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 175 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 179 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 176 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 177 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 180 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 178 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

As always, killing more of the same enemies slowed his leveling speed, and the fights got easier. But it was inarguable that hunting C-grades was way, way more effective than D-grades. Not once had he gained a level after a D-grade kill despite killing hundreds, yet another level came after every C-grade.

Now, finally, they had the stones the worm wanted. Jake had temporarily taken the second one they came across for himself, eating it with Palate of the Malefic Viper to get an idea of what they were and how they worked. He had it eaten for around six days before they reached the final rock, and during this time, Jake got some idea of what they were.

Meteorites.

The concept he had felt from them was some kind of space affinity or maybe astral affinity. Gravity affinity? A mix of it all, probably. Either way, they contained powerful energies. Jake could likely find some ways to use the meteors himself, but it would take a lot of work, and he had already promised the worm.

The entire hunt had only taken roughly a week, during which they made it a few thousand kilometers into the scorpion territory. Each of the stones was above five meters tall and one and a half meters across, making them small enough for Jake to store in his spatial storage. The worm had made it clear that all of them had to be gathered before eating.

Standing before the final stone with a dead Scorpion Lord in the background, Jake turned to the very excited worm. It had only popped out the top parts of its body with a closed mouth, making it look like a hill had just emerged next to Jake.

"So, here we are," Jake said as he stood in front of the meteorite.

"Yep…" the worm said a bit nervously.

"Relax, I am not going to take your meteorites." Based on his observations and some insight from Palate, Jake continued, “I feel these were once part of one large meteorite and broke apart when they entered our atmosphere. Or maybe something else broke them.”

"Yeah, one of the big worms said that these stones were once united, and to bring out their full power, one had to bring them together again," the worm answered. “The scorpions were just dumb and didn’t like each other, so they never shared. Not like the stones aren’t good individually, just best together.”

They had only spoken a little over the last week, mainly about random, unrelated topics and for Jake to learn about worms. Jake had spent most of his time meditating and trying to figure out how to upgrade Wings of the Malefic Viper between recovering from fights, not leaving enough time to have any long talks.

"I have been thinking," Jake said. "Do worms have genders?"

He knew that earthworms pre-system were hermaphrodites, and he had been wondering if maybe these worms were too.

"Worms are worms," the worm answered very accurately. "Ah, but the big ones can decide, I heard. They got a skill to change shape or something, and using that skill, they kind of make a preferred form that can have a sex. Not sure why they would. Do humans have genders? Wait, let me guess—they do, and you are a… female?"

"Missed the fifty-fifty," Jake chuckled.

"Really? I thought you had to be a female due to your mushy and soft form. Males are meant to look strong and rough, right?" The worm’s words sounded a bit insulting, but Jake didn’t feel the slightest amount of mockery in the tone, just genuine curiosity.

"Females are even mushier and softer," Jake answered, feeling a bit weird about saying that out loud. Telepathically. Wanting to change the topic, he asked something else. "I don’t think I ever got a name either. What do other worms call you?"

"What?" the worm asked, even more confused.

"You know, a name. A way to identify who you are and differentiate you from other worms.”

"I am a sand worm," the worm said. "Wait… Oh, I think I get it! Like, what we call stuff we find or something? A made-up term—umm, name?"

"Exactly!" Jake said, glad he got through.

"We don’t have those. Seems kind of dumb; why do you need them? Any worm can differentiate another worm in the network, and our soul signatures are entirely unique, so if we want to mention a specific worm, we just relay their soul signature. Way better than names, I think.”

"I… That is actually super fucking smart," Jake admitted as he thought about it. He could identify people using only their mana signature, which was part of their soul signature and utterly unique. If the worms could relay this signature using telepathy and only spoke using telepathy, then why the hell would they need names? At least, not between them. They only had to give names to dead objects, and Identify provided ones for free just by using the skill.

"Right?" the worm said happily.

"But I still want you to have one," Jake stated.

"Why?"

"For when I meet other people in the future, and for my own internal thoughts, I want to have a name to refer to you as.”

"Humans are weird. Do all humans have names? What is your name?"

"My name is Jake, and yes, all humans have names. At least, all humans I know.”

"Oh… so does that mean I should call you human Jake? Or, wait, are you a Jake and not a human, then? Like, my Identify does not work on you, and is that because you are a Jake? And are there more Jakes out there like you?" The worm clearly didn’t entirely get the concept of names.

"No, no. There is only one of me, and Jake is nothing but a name. I am a human, and my name has nothing to do with my strength or anything; it is just something my parents gave me. That is how names work. They are given by someone close to you, most likely your parents, and then you have that name until you die or decide to change it.”

"So I could just get a name, if I wanted?” the worm asked with great interest. “Just by saying I am suddenly supposed to be called something else and not Sand Worm?"

"Yes," Jake said.

The mound that stuck out of the ground wriggled slightly. "What should I pick, then? How about Super Sand Worm? Or maybe Best Sand Worm? Oh, I know, Awesome Sand Worm!"

"Maybe think about it a bit more after you have heard other names to get an idea?" Jake said with exasperation.

"Are my ideas bad? Oh, well. Wait, you said that names are given, right? Can’t you just give me one?"

"I am not sure that would be a good idea. I have repeatedly been told that I am bad at giving names.”

"So you have given names before! That must mean you are experienced at it. Just give me one, then. But after you give me a name, can you let me have the tasty rocks? You said that people give names to those they care about, so if you give me a name, it must also mean you care about me, right? Or doesn’t it work both ways?"

Jake felt like there were several leaps in logic with that argument, but he didn’t bother trying to correct it. Instead, he thought of a name. The first thing that sprung to mind was Wormie, but his vast experience in naming things made him know he was not allowed to do that. Not anymore.

He also knew it had to be a unisex name. Thinking long and hard on the issue, Jake took inspiration from the environment and the worm in front of him as he settled on a perfect name. A name that was actually a real name, a historically unisex name, and a name that would truly fit the worm, in his eyes.

"Let’s just call you Sandy," Jake said with pride. Truly, his naming sense had improved by leaps and bounds since the day he’d named Hawkie.

"Doesn’t sandy mean that something is made of sand, or is like sand? I am pretty sure it is. Like, this place is sandy…”

"Ah, but it is also a name," Jake said. "And even so, aren’t you kind of sandy? So it even helps describe you, doesn’t it?"

"Hm, I am sandy… Okay! I am Sandy from now on. Hello, human Jake. I am worm Sandy!" The worm, now named Sandy, released something akin to a giggle. "Hehe, this is weird. Sandy, Sandy, Sandy… What happens if I forget it, though?"

"I will remember it for you," Jake assured the cutely nervous worm. "Now for the true bounty. Are you ready for your stones?"

"Yep!" the worm said expectedly. "Sandy is ready!"

Sandy had managed to reach level 199 over this last week, primarily by stealing things from the dead scorpions, and Jake had a strong feeling it was ready for evolution. Sandy was also certain it was ready to evolve, and the meteorites certainly weren’t ordinary items.

Jake took the meteorites out of his inventory, and the moment he did, they flew towards each other right in front of him. Jake was sent scrambling back as a loud crack sounded, and the meteorites merged into each other. Taking precautions, Jake stepped back the moment he took out the final meteorite from Palate, but luckily it simply flew to the larger one and merged with it.

The second all the meteorites were gathered, a pulse was sent out, and the entire area seemed to shake. Jake was curious and walked closer to it, feeling pulled as he got closer.

"You won’t take it?" Sandy asked nervously.

"No," Jake answered, “but give me a second."

"Hurry! I can already feel that others are coming," the worm warned.

Jake nodded as he placed his hand on the meteorite. It felt hot to the touch, and it was as if his hand stuck to it. He wouldn’t say he felt connected to it, but he did feel a call of sorts. He now realized the meteorite didn’t only feel familiar due to the affinities of energy. There was something else. Something that resonated with him.

Closing his eyes, Jake activated Touch of the Malefic Viper almost instinctively as he sent some of his energy into the meteorite to connect with its energy. He wanted to make it better, and he felt part of himself being drained. Like in a trance, he infused it with energy until a distinct sense of weakness overtook his body.

He fell to his knees as he was knocked out of his trance and checked his resources in horror.

Status

Mana Points (MP): 249 /102437

--

What the fuck did I just do? Jake asked himself.

"What did you just do?" the worm also asked him.

"I am not sure," Jake said with furrowed brows, “but hurry up."

"Okay!" Sandy said as it dove underground for a moment before emerging right in front of Jake, swallowing the meteorite whole. It had not grown, despite them merging, but had turned a darker color.

Jake tried to stabilize himself and watched as Sandy froze. Minutes passed, and Jake quickly took out a mana potion to at least be able to stand up properly and look intimidating if other beasts came. It was good that the corpse was still nearby, and Jake could pose until Sandy was ready.

"So?" Jake asked the worm after it seemed frozen for over five minutes.

Another minute passed before Sandy’s entire body shook. "Be right back!"

With that, the entire sand worm disappeared, leaving a large hole in the ground that rapidly began to fill with sand again. Sandy was entirely gone, having no doubt gone to that special evolution place.

And not even Villy knew what Sandy would return as.

Chapter 27

A Whole New Worm

Jake waited expectedly for Sandy to return. As he waited, he also considered an option he hadn’t even thought of before… What if Sandy turned hostile? There was a legitimate risk that the worm would return stronger than Jake, as the evolution could lead to intense power growth. No, it would definitely lead to immense power growth.

Moreover, Sandy didn’t need him anymore. He had helped the worm reach C-grade and even went and gone something incredibly stupid: pouring all his mana into the damn meteorite. Oh, and then there was the issue of C-grades apparently coming, and as he stood there, Jake could even feel a few approaching auras.

Did I fuck up badly? Jake asked himself.

He had originally only approached the worm to give him a lift. Their entire relationship had been transactional. Shit, Jake had even threatened Sandy. He knew that if someone else had threatened him to either help or die, Jake would have fought, or at the very least looked for every opportunity possible to strike back.

Feeling genuinely nervous, Jake considered just taking off on his own. He was damn low on mana and didn’t wanna fight any C-grades showing up, so leaving would probably be safer. Logically, he should leave or at least hide.

Yet he stayed there, waiting. Because despite his worries, he had a good feeling about Sandy. Sandy seemed like a decent worm, and unless Ell’Hakan could somehow mess with Jake’s emotions across the planet, he felt confident in that assessment. Not that he would have time to get away, as Sandy was now back.

A figure appeared, slowly fading into existence. Instantly, Jake noticed the difference. First of all, Sandy’s body had actually grown a little smaller, now "only" about a hundred meters long. The body was also less bulky, with the entire form quite slender. Color-wise, Sandy had taken on an odd black-purple hue with the occasional small, glimmering dot here and there, looking like small diamonds were embedded in the skin. The skin itself also looked far tougher than before, now more like rock than simply very rough skin.

But what struck Jake the most was the aura. He felt as if the area around Sandy was bending slightly and looked off, and he saw some of the sand slowly begin to float up towards the worm. Sandy noticed and stopped attracting it, then twisted and turned to check out its own body. Another difference was that all of this took place up in the air, with Sandy moving as if somehow still "swimming."

Jake used Identify on Sandy, trying to get a feeling for what he was dealing with.

[Juvenile Cosmic Genesis Worm – lvl ???]

Jake stared at the name, not at all sure what to make of it. First of all, it was long. Were long names good? Probably. But stranger than the number of words were the words themselves. Cosmic and Genesis were both words that certainly held a lot of "power," and the juvenile part hinted that a fully grown Cosmic Genesis Worm had to be at least B-grade. Those trying to become dragons became true dragons at B-grade, indicating that a Cosmic Genesis Worm was likely at or around the level of a true dragon.

And true dragons were damn strong.

"Hey, Sandy, you well?" Jake asked as he saw Sandy keep twisting and turning.

"It looks funny when it moves," Sandy answered in a very amused tone.

Jake looked around, confused, and saw nothing move besides the giant worm.

"What does?" he asked.

"The air sand. Umm… just a bit, checking the skill… Hmm, cosmic dust, it calls it. And sand is pretty much dust, right? You can’t see it? It is everywhere, even all around you, right now. Look, like this.”

As Sandy said this, Jake faintly felt space around him begin to harden as if becoming denser. He wrapped his hand in destructive arcane mana and swept it sideways, destroying whatever Sandy was doing.

"You can see it!” Sandy said, continuing with rapid-fire telepathy, “Or maybe feel it? Hm, weird. Anywho, what did you do with the meteorite before? The amount of earth affinity was near-eliminated, and some foreign concept I am not familiar with was just overflowing. Ah, don’t get me wrong; I am not complaining or anything. I am way better now. Oh, did you know I had five evolution options, and only two of them didn’t have sand in the name? Also! Who is the Malefic Viper?"

Jake couldn’t help but just smile a bit. He had to admit that Sandy felt strong now, but Jake didn’t feel the slightest hint of danger. It wasn’t necessarily because the newly born Cosmic Genesis Worm couldn’t threaten him, but there was not a hint of animosity. All he felt was relief at Sandy not changing.

He answered her questions, explaining who Villy was in quick terms, and was glad that Sandy knew what gods were, as apparently a few worms had been blessed. As for why Sandy asked… some-fucking-how, an option called "Malefic Transport Worm" had appeared, and it was better than any of the three "expected" evolutions. The description had talked about turning Sandy into a living transportation vehicle or some shit like that, and thank fucking Villy Sandy had not picked that.

"Cool, so you are the Chosen best friend of this god?” Sandy said. “Sounds super nice… Oh! Bummer! I totally forgot!"

Jake knew what Sandy had forgotten, as the many auras had been approaching for a while, and now one was close enough. In the distance, a large form rose, far larger than Sandy despite them both being C-grade worms. It was one of the massive C-grade sand worms, and it faced the flying worm for a while as they no doubt talked telepathically.

Now, it had to be noted that all sand worms were blind. Blind and deaf. But they had some magical sense that gave them a huge sensory range anyway. For the sand worms, it was through the sand, and Jake guessed that Sandy had retained that same sense… Sand, having been replaced with this cosmic dust, which was essentially space? He wasn’t sure.

Time passed as Jake just stood there, waiting. Sandy sometimes made some slight movements but was otherwise completely frozen. He felt a bit out of place but didn’t want to disturb their talk.

Things seemed to get heated, as both worms wriggled at each other before Sandy explained in a huffy tone, "We’re leaving!"

"What happened?" Jake asked, confused.

"Get in my mouth!" the former sand worm said angrily, clearly more than a little upset.

Jake didn’t want to argue. Sandy opened its mouth and inhaled, and Jake felt himself being dragged in. He could resist it but wanted to see what kind of new things the worm could now do. Yet, at the same time, Jake felt a faint telepathic connection form with the massive C-grade in the distance. It was only one-way and translated to a brief message: "Thank you, and take care of them. Show them the world."

Not sure what to make of it, Jake allowed himself to be dragged in, and he noticed that despite Sandy growing smaller, the inside hadn’t. Jake stared down the worm’s gullet, which resembled a dark, massive cave, but the moment he fully entered the mouth, he felt himself shift, then found himself within an odd circular room that looked like it was made of stone.

A spatial pocket of some kind, Jake noted.

Inspecting his new surroundings, Jake quickly realized there was no way out. No doors or openings anywhere in the dark, purplish rock. Yet he also got a feeling that he could break these walls—and the entire pocket—if he really wanted to by overloading them with destructive mana.

After roughly a minute, he heard Sandy talk again. "I would never! Jerks, the lot of them! Sand worms suck!"

"Will you tell me what happened now?" Jake asked.

"Okay… I was so excited, right? Just evolved, everything seemed great, and then my old safekeeper appeared, and I am so excited to share my own awesome evolution, but do you know what the bastard said? That I am no longer a sand worm and have to leave! That the desert isn’t a place for me anymore. I just got disowned by my own family because I am a better worm! Humph!"

Jake frowned a bit but now understood the other C-grade worm. Sandy had grown beyond the desert. Rather than being confined to sand, their world was now everywhere in the cosmos.

"This is your fault," Sandy said, sounding sad. "I could have become a Massive Veilsand Sand Worm, you know? Now, where am I supposed to go? Can I even go anywhere? My quest says I am still not allowed in certain areas of the planet."

"The world is far larger than you think," Jake said. "You are a Cosmic Worm now, not a sand worm. The entire universe is your home, and while there are some areas you cannot go to right now, that is only temporary."

"Still your fault," Sandy insisted. "Guess it all works out for you… Now I have nowhere else to go and no other plans. So, where are we going?"

Jake couldn’t help but smile at the speed with which Sandy adapted. "Before that, can you make it so I can see the outside world?"

"See? Oh, yeah, you got those eye things; I remember someone mentioning that some creatures have those. Here, let me try something."

The entire cavern-like dome he was in began shifting colors, expanding and retracting a bit. Then, finally, parts of it began to turn transparent. It then spread to encompass the entire cave: walls, floor, and everything. From Jake’s point of view, it was like he was floating in mid-air.

"That works?" Sandy asked.

"Yep. I do wonder, why do you have a skill to transport people like this?"

"Oh, it is not to transport people but to trap and super slowly eat them. Like, I can do this…"

Jake began to feel something change. He noticed that his mana, stamina, and health were all being drained at an incredibly slow speed, but drained nonetheless. Then it stopped, and Sandy gave some more insight.

It was similar to Villy’s Palate, where one could slowly absorb energy and even some remnant Records, except Sandy would drink the energies of eaten living beings and actually extract experience from that. From the sounds of it, Sandy still got little to no experience from killing things outright, and relied more on finding and eating natural treasures. And eating living creatures to slowly extract energy from them, it seemed.

"How many can you eat at once?" Jake asked.

"Depends on how many rooms I make… but probably around a hundred rooms right now? Not sure; I am going by my guts. Heh, guts when I am talking about my stomach skill. Anyway! Where are we going?"

"That way," Jake said as he telepathically conveyed a direction.

Sandy picked up on it and began worming through the air. It was like Sandy could swim through the air itself, though Jake had to admit the speed was not that impressive right off the bat.

Jake decided not to rush Sandy, as he could feel the worm was getting used to the new evolution. Instead, he wanted to test something else. He took out his cauldron and began crafting a batch of mana potions. The process was simple as usual, yet his goal wasn’t really to brew it, but to test the effect it had on Sandy.

"Hey, Sandy, can you absorb the extra mana from me doing alchemy?" Jake asked the worm as it wormed its way forward.

"Hm? Oh, yeah, I do feel something in the stomach. I have to absorb it manually, as I don’t have that effect active right now.”

Jake once more felt the suction effect from the walls, and the mana that had spread in the room from Jake’s crafting was absorbed. "Okay, now let’s try something else. Do be on alert and tell me if anything bad happens.”

Whenever Jake made poison, it had the effect of leaving the surrounding area a bit… contaminated. Back in his valley, he had his circle of death that killed all grass in a large area, and in the Order and even his lab back in Haven, the entire place was designed to resist and contain his poison. This whole effect only got worse as time passed, and Jake knew that if an S-grade crafted poisons without bothering to try and contain the environmental effects, entire planets could find themselves contaminated.

He began his crafting as usual and felt that Sandy was keeping an eye on it. The toxic vapors soon entered the air without the worm saying anything about it. As he kept going, he felt a bit of it be absorbed into the transparent walls and disappear. Still nothing.

Jake finished his crafting and finally asked, "So?"

"All fine? The energy took a bit to filter, but otherwise, it was all good.”

Relieved, Jake nodded.

"How far are we going, anyway?" Sandy asked.

"Hm… far," Jake answered. He had not actually truly reflected on how far it was… and damn, was it far.

Due to the size of the Earth having grown to ridiculous levels and him having been flung to the other side of the planet, Jake estimated he had a little less than two million kilometers back to Haven.

Now, this did seem extreme, but it wasn’t actually that bad. Jake could easily travel faster than a thousand kilometers an hour using One Step repeatedly, so without rest, he could move around twenty-four thousand kilometers a day, or just shy of one hundred and seventy thousand a week. Factoring in fights and some issues, along with a bit of rest here and there, passing just a hundred thousand kilometers a week was likely more realistic. This would mean it would take Jake around five months to return… which happened to be just shy of the World Congress that would happen in roughly four months. At least, he remembered it being in around four months. He did not have a timer counting down or anything, and he had to admit that his timekeeping when highly engrossed in alchemy wasn’t the best.

"Damn far,” Jake said. “I have around two million kilometers, and I am not sure how much of that you can come along for, being a C-grade and all.”

"Hm, okay," Sandy answered. "Do we have to hurry?"

"A little? But I also think it would be a good idea to make some stops along the way to hunt some C-grades. It all depends on how fast you can travel."

"So, I can go fast?"

"Well, yeah. Is it fine if I just do alchemy and meditate meanwhile?"

"Is alchemy that the thing where you make the mana come out? Sure! It is tasty. I want to practice too.”

"Alright," Jake said with a smile. Sandy was currently flying only about two hundred meters a second, which was slower than Jake using One Step by a lot. He hoped that Sandy would be fast—

Everything suddenly seemed to warp, the terrain all around them moving incredibly fast. Sandy shot forward as if digging through reality, carried by space itself. Jake had no way to estimate how fast they were going… but it was fast. Faster than Jake could travel even if he pushed himself fully with One Step and Arcane Awakening.

"Can you keep up this speed?" Jake asked, wondering if Sandy was pushing it.

"Yeah? This isn’t that fast, is it? Definitely faster than before, but I am an awesome worm now, so it makes sense, right? I can go faster but not for as long, and I am still learning, okay? So no judging.”

"Alright,” Jake said, accepting Sandy’s very logical explanation. “Don’t hesitate to contact me if there is anything.”

"I will tell you when I need someone to kill another C-grade so I can steal its stuff, and I can get some proper compensation for you getting me disowned," Sandy said with the usual joking sassiness.

"You do you." Jake kept smirking as he watched them fly for a little longer. Even if their speed was a lot faster, it was still just desert with a few large, rocky red mountains all around for as far as the eye could see. Even Jake’s eyes.

Closing said eyes and entering meditation, Jake began once more working on upgrading Wings of the Malefic Viper. Over this period, he had gotten some good ideas, but the problem was that he had no way to practice. In order to truly practice and figure out if his ideas would work, Jake would need some kind of isolated space which he could try and escape from, but where the hell would he find something like tha—

Wait a second…

Chapter 28

Searching for a Path

At the higher grades and levels of power, the scaling of survivability and damage output was not balanced. Killing an F-grade human as another F-grade human was easy. Just stab them in the heart, and they died.

For an E-grade, you had to stab them a few times in the heart and maybe land a few more blows before they went down for good. D-grade, it got even harder, and nothing short of blowing off the head of another man would work as an instant kill. And even then, many could survive losing their head, depending on their skills and stat distribution.

C-grades losing their head rarely meant death. The Soulshape became stronger and easier to regenerate, and each part of it was less vital than in prior grades. Even the functions of the brain were all gone by C-grade, allowing one who had lost their head to keep moving. Sensory organs still mattered, and regenerating the brain and head was a huge burden, but most humans could overcome it.

Now, this was humans. Beasts were even harder to kill, with elementals harder than beasts. Due to how survivability scaled, it meant that the other party escaping was the likely outcome unless one party was at least a good deal stronger. Assuming the losing side decided to flee, that is.

All of this ultimately meant that when two beings of similar or equal power met, there would be no true winner. This was doubly true when the two beings facing off were Unique Lifeforms at the peak of D-grade. Both of them could slaughter weaker C-grades easily, and even higher-tiered C-grades wanted to avoid them due to their uncertainty in killing a Unique Lifeform. Failure would mean a delayed death just a few years later when the Unique Lifeform caught up, and victory would mean nearly nothing, as even if their strength was equal, killing an opponent in a lower grade wouldn’t be rewarded by the system.

What they would instead do was take a side and support the Unique Lifeform for future benefits. Unless there was more than one, that is. If the supremacy of the Unique Lifeform was challenged, it would sow doubt as to whether supporting the Unique Lifeform was worth it, and even more so, then this would be a good chance to break off and attempt to do your own thing. To pursue personal goals… To get revenge.

The Fallen King and the Ashen Phantom Devourer had battled for nearly four hours, with neither getting any advantage during the first encounter. The mountains were torn asunder, and thousands of unlucky observing beasts died in the process. After the fourth hour, the Ashen Phantom Devourer chose to disengage. A day later, it attacked again, and their fight resumed.

It was like a never-ending cycle. The Ashen Phantom Devourer was a being that was near-impossible to kill. Its body was more like a living domain than an actual physical entity, making dealing damage incredibly difficult. At the same time, the King of the Forest had a powerful, constantly active barrier, and even if one managed to break it, all one found was a bark-like armor that offered incredible resistance to all damage.

This made it all a battle of endurance, and with both of them able to escape easily, no true winner would be found unless one party made a breakthrough or found something to truly exploit. They both knew this, which is also why they wanted to keep fighting. It was rare that a Unique Lifeform could find a being able to stand up to them, and even rarer to find another Unique Lifeform. Other Unique Lifeforms were the closest they could ever get to kin, and this sparked an intense, innate desire to prove themselves. Prove their Paths, and prove that they were superior Unique Lifeforms.

Neither cared that their fight left a power vacuum ripe for exploitation, and that those who’d once found themselves held back now chose to act.

William stared at the ritual circle as he operated it, karmic magic revolving around him. The oversized squirrel sat in its middle for a moment before opening its eyes, anger burning within from what it had just experienced. Not directed at William, but someone it had forgotten and now remembered. It bowed towards him before leaving, going towards the teleportation chamber.

What am I even doing? William asked himself for what felt like the umpteenth time in the last… year? Years? A long time, for sure.

Shaking his head, he decided not to think about it too much. Whenever he made his own decisions, things just turned to shit anyway, so it was better for him to just do as was told by someone wiser: his master.

The ritual circle he was operating on was one he had been working on for a good while. It had been the final requirement for his Profession Evolution Quest, and had taken all of his skills to pull off. Of course, it wasn’t the only thing he could have made; all it required was for him to make something related to his profession at a sufficiently high level.

His Class Evolution Quest had also been easy. But his Race Evolution Quest was just… He didn’t get it.

Race Evolution Quest

As you reach the end of D-grade, you have walked a Path seeking perfection. A Path of discovery of yourself and what you want to be. Yet you have not found it. Without determination and vision, there is no Path. Without desire, there is no progress. Without willingness, there is no life.

Objective: Find your Path (0/1)

William had already found his Path, so he didn’t get why the fuck he hadn’t completed the quest yet. If he had completed it, he would be C-grade and one step closer to being useful to his master. But no matter how much he tried to figure it out, the quest remained uncompleted. It made absolutely no sense to him, and he had asked his master, but his master just said that he had taught William enough to figure it out on his own. This only frustrated him more, as he felt like he was disappointing his master.

Just focus on your work, and you can figure it out later, he told himself as he prepared for the next somewhat confused beasts to enter the ritual circle. William worked his magic as he pulled on the karmic strings and increased their strength. He gathered them into an almost spherical shape, which he then used to weave a tapestry and allow the beast to see. And see, it did.

Its eyes filled with animosity, and it even threw William an angry glance. Not that he could blame it. He had allowed it to experience something that most would perhaps want to live without, but these beasts had all requested it. Not knowing had simply been more painful than now finding out.

As for what he made them experience? Memories. Memories of their lives before the system arrived.

To say that humans had treated animals shitty before the system was an understatement. William knew that he’d been the furthest from a saint back then, but the crimes he had committed were nothing compared to some others. Individual researchers had killed thousands of mice, and just how many fish had been caught every day? How many deer had been shot and killed? How many animals hunted or farmed simply for their hides or horns?

The answer was a fucking lot. Humans had been fine treating animals like shit. What would happen if you decided to kill a mouse that snuck into your home? Nothing. What would happen if you decided to use your BB gun to shoot down two squirrels? Nothing. There were no laws against it, and if there were, the worst that happened was a fine.

At least… there’d been no true punishment before.

Now you had a small baby squirrel that remembered seeing its parents killed by teenagers. A baby squirrel that had grown to late D-grade. William’s job was only to make them remember their entire lives and then give them an outlet and a new goal. He would find anyone related to the beasts using the karmic connections. Anyone who had hurt them or abused them before the system. The C-grade jellyfish would then teleport them to the vicinity of this area for them to carry out their revenge on humanity.

But… there were still questions that haunted him. He knew what he was doing. He knew the purpose of what he was doing. He knew the goals of Ell’Hakan and his master’s expectations. He knew what the beasts were planning and about so many other things.

Yet he still didn’t know…

Why am I even doing this? Why am I helping some alien? Why is all I am doing still not enough? Why am I still afraid and still having nightmares?

And there was another thing that bothered him a lot. One that had annoyed him ever since the time he went to see the Augur of Hope. A man he had killed. The Augur had greeted him without a care for their history and shown only pity. He had then helped William find some people, but the last words he spoke as they parted still rang in his mind.

"I hope you find your Path once more. You were climbing a mountain back then, but all I see before you now is a bridge with the ropes cut."

William hated that the Augur had to speak without actually saying anything. The last time they met, he had said that William already had a Path… and now he suddenly didn’t, despite finally finding meaning with his master. Then again, the Augur was still some D-grade; what the hell did he know compared to a Primordial?

No, he just had to work on the tasks given by his master, and he was sure he would find his Path. He had wanted to visit this former girlfriend of the Malefic’s Chosen, but simply did not have time due to the many tasks he was given. Not that it was a high priority.

According to Ell’Hakan, their recent encounter should put the Malefic Viper’s Chosen out of commission for at least three and a half months, with the expected time being over half a year. William did not fault the alien for not fighting the Malefic One’s Chosen outright. He was a damn monster. But he did think it a bit stupid to just piss him off like that. In fact, he was pretty damn certain Ell’Hakan’s plans would fail miserably, as if there was one thing William was sure about, it was that when it came to that monster, nothing ever went as expected.

Not that it was truly any of his concern. William just did as he was told.

Jake considered where he was for a moment.

He was trapped in a different space… one where One Step would not simply allow him to step out. One would have to do something special to get out—or just go crazy with destructive energies, in Jake’s case—and if not, they were trapped.

Jake grinned and summoned his wings. Time to upgrade these bad boys and escape Sandy’s stomach!

He didn’t know if it was just dumb luck, but this was a perfect opportunity for him to practice. He informed Sandy of what he wanted to do, and Sandy responded by playing along. Jake felt the walls harden and the space stabilize even more than before.

Jake instantly knew escape just got a lot harder. If it had just been space magic, Jake could’ve maybe found a way with One Step, but it wasn’t just space magic. There were other concepts mixed in too. If there weren’t, Sandy would be a Genesis Space Worm and not a Genesis Cosmic Worm, after all.

He could still probably overload Sandy with destructive mana or go HAM with poisons or something, but even then, he wasn’t sure how much damage that would even do to the worm. Sandy had honestly become a bit of a monster. The sheer level of power this stomach skill required was immense, and he reckoned nearly no D-grade would be able to escape on their own.

All he could say was that he was glad Sandy was on his side. Because damn, would it be annoying to have a worm kidnap friends and family and fly away if you pissed it off. Which reminded him not to annoy Sandy too much.

Dispelling his wayward thoughts, Jake refocused his mind on the task at hand: the Wings of the Malefic Viper upgrade. He knew that he had to take it in a quite different direction than it currently had. There was not a hint of space affinity or anything like that in the wings currently, and if he was being totally honest, he wasn’t even sure the upgraded version was all about space magic either. There was likely some space magic involved, but as with many things, it was just never that simple.

Jake once more tried to correctly remember how he’d felt during the vision where he experienced the skill. He had definitely felt the wings fill with energy. Way more than usual. Back then, the Viper had summoned them as phantasmal wings just to use the skill, too.

As he remembered more and more, one detail stood out. The Viper had changed color to green during the process, and at first, Jake had just thought that an effect of the then-S-grade’s immense mana. But the Viper was far too good at energy control for that. So why had his body turned green? Jake also vividly remembered the Viper shooting into the distance, meaning it was not teleportation but more just insanely fast movement—movement that made space part… not helped by space, as one would expect from a skill using the space affinity. Perhaps it was more related to Shadow Vault? No, that didn’t seem like it either, especially after sim-Jake said he was of no help.

He felt somewhat stuck. It was clear he was missing something crucial, and he was a bit mad at himself for not focusing on the skill more during the vision back then. Okay, then again, Fang of Man and Fangs of the Malefic Viper upgrading from one vision was great, and he couldn’t fault himself too much, but still.

Jake tried many different things as time passed. About a day went by before Sandy found a big C-grade sand lizard guarding some kind of natural formation of crystals or something. Jake had no idea what it was, but Sandy got excited and practically spat him out like he was a damn pocket monster to fight for his worm master.

Anyway.

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 179 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 181 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

A good bit of exercise later, and Jake was back in the stomach, where he began testing again. He tried to infuse different concepts and see if that felt right, but nothing did. The entire idea of infusing something entirely new into the wings also felt wrong. Every other upgrade had built upon what was already there. Expanded it. If it added something new, Jake could at least see it being linked with everything else in the skill. None of his current ideas were linked to any of the core functions of Wings.

As time passed and he practiced, he kept coming back to the issue of nothing he tried building upon what was already there. He tried to see if there was some hidden feature he had not discovered, some mighty flapping technique he had missed, but there was nothing. All infusing mana did was create more poison. As Jake thought this, he had a eureka moment.

He considered if the Viper hadn’t actually used any of what Jake expected… What if he had done the exact opposite? Used only what the wings already had, but in an entirely different way? A far more extreme way.

What if he had simply pumped out a poison removing everything between him and his destination, corroding a hole through reality itself?

Chapter 29

A Logical Conclusion

It was an absolutely crazy thought. Poisoning space itself… No, poisoning reality. To target every single facet of reality and effectively create a vacuum of concepts between you and your destination.

That is also why the mist was used. The mist was from Blood of the Malefic Viper and thus contained Records of all poisons Jake had ever interacted with. With the Trial of Myriad Poisons, Jake had interacted with countless variants, and it wasn’t like he had slowed down much after that either, still eating everything slightly toxic in his path.

Jake began his science and tried to work on how one would supercharge the wings the way the Viper had done, but also found it a problem to control the mist and form a tunnel between himself and where he wanted to escape to. Did he need to make a cylinder of poison or something that isolated everything around it? No, that would take way too much power…

What about shooting a cannon of poison in the direction and then diving after that? It could work, but space tended to reform too quickly, and if his opponent was actively trying to stop him, he would need an insane amount of poison mist to do that. The mist also kind of sucked, to begin with.

He then returned to the very important detail of the Viper turning green. Why had he done that? Some shield to protect himself from the poison?

A few theories popped up immediately, but none fit. Jake was deep in thought and tried a few things as his wings pulsed with power, sending mist out. Ultimately, he decided that he first needed to make some kind of poison able to corrode through reality. Saying it so casually was damn weird, but he was serious.

Passive mana tended to not be that strong as long as you targeted the right things. This was why Alchemical Flame was so damn good at breaking down objects, as it directly targeted the passive mana and the concepts keeping things whole.

So, Jake needed a poison that targeted passive mana that didn’t fight back. Maybe he could apply concepts from Alchemical Flame directly there…. Yeah, that actually seemed doable. There were many plants and poisons geared toward naturally corroding things. Acids that went through stone that a C-grade could not even scratch like it was nothing, poison mist that would turn a block of metal an S-grade would dream of crafting a weapon from into Swiss cheese. These existed everywhere, and Jake had consumed plenty.

But even if he made this, what about non-passive mana? Like where he was trapped right now? That kind of mana would fight him actively. Could he even make something that eroded the wall of Sandy’s stomach? He knew he probably could with Touch, but as mist?

Jake groaned in annoyance as he felt Sandy’s mental ping. He obliged and found himself outside once more, instantly noticing that the area had changed to rocky terrain. Before him was a large C-grade bird of some kind.

"Go human! Use bow attack!" Sandy said with excitement as Jake pulled out his bow and added another C-grade to his list of slain foes before getting back in his pokeba—stomach.

He did have to admit that Sandy was damn good at analyzing his strength and picking opponents.

Back in the chamber, Jake felt more relaxed after a bit of killing, seeing the entire thing with new eyes. It was like having a good night’s sleep and then waking up to look at your project again. Jake considered different poisons he would need in the mist, and it quickly became clear he would need many concepts at once. No, he could not have all be active at once; he needed to make an adaptable mist that targeted everything at once but only actively targeted what it encountered.

And then he came back to that damn green color. Why the hell did the Viper glow? Was it because… No… it made sense?

Jake had been looking at it all wrong. The Malefic Viper had not made a path of escape using the mist. He had not made a poison mist that eroded everything; he became the poison mist. Rather than dripping acid on the evil to get through, the Viper became a semi-solid ball of acid that was dropped onto it. So even if the metal above reformed, he would still get through.

The Viper had wrapped himself in it. Like a cocoon, the poison mist surrounded him in a supercharged state. That was why the Viper glowed green; his entire body had turned into toxic mist, and he used his power to keep it strong.

As Jake realized this, he felt like something clicked in his mind. He instantly checked Path of the Heretic-Chosen and saw that his intuition had been correct.

Do you wish to experience the Legacy of the Malefic Viper? Uses remaining: 3

Did Jake think he could upgrade the skill without experiencing another vision? Sure. Probably. But Jake also kind of feared that he would lose the skill with his C-grade upgrade, or maybe lose the uses. So he wanted to use all of them, even if it was a bit of a waste.

Ah, who was he kidding? He just wanted to see Villy get embarrassed, have his ass handed to him, and be forced to escape.

Even with everything happening on Earth, the inside of the workshop appeared entirely undisturbed. Arnold was still working on his latest creation when he got an expected visit from a recent arrival to their planet.

Ell’Hakan had to admit that he found the entire construction quite novel. A massive metal dome with impressive enchantments all over. The material itself also looked incredibly tough, and he doubted that anything mundane could break through. It was truly a defensive stronghold, and even he would have issues breaking into it within any reasonable timeframe.

Luckily, he did not have to break in.

As he approached, the dome simply opened up to him. There, he met the assistant to the machinist, as the human named Arnold had been dubbed.

"Welcome, sir; how may I assist you?" the assistant asked. She was obviously aware of what was going on and knew that trying to keep Ell’Hakan out would only delay the inevitable. Besides, it was simply smarter to allow him access.

"Impressive construction, and even more impressive techniques present on the inside,” Ell’Hakan said. “I thank you for allowing me in without any needless delays. Do tell, is the machinist available?"

"I will inform him of your presence," the assistant said with a bow and a smile as she briefly left the welcome room.

Ell’Hakan felt the doubt and hesitation in her, but also some relief. A good emotion to amplify, as it could lead to other positive thoughts and feelings. Having the assistant possess a good view of him wasn’t necessary, but nice to have. No, the one he truly cared about was Arnold.

Ell’Hakan had done his research and found this man far more outstanding than anyone seemed to give him credit for. He was blessed by Void God Oras—something that even his Patron found utterly baffling, as no D-grade human should be able to handle that. The ones a Void God usually blessed were either incredibly powerful members of the enlightened races and at far higher grades, or creatures explicitly suited to them, such as rare elementals or other monsters.

The reason he approached this machinist was obviously for his mind. Because one other thing he’d discovered was that the man had no true loyalty to the Malefic’s Chosen. He simply worked for him and did some commissions. There appeared to be no true relationship there; it was purely transactional. The fact that he had stayed even after the City Lord left was further proof that Arnold simply did not view himself as part of the Malefic Chosen’s faction. So if he was offered good enough terms and had his emotions swayed properly, there was no reason for him not to switch.

"Sir, he is ready to receive you," the assistant said with another bow, having returned less than a minute after leaving.

Ell’Hakan thanked her as he entered the workshop. He had prepared for a trap—just in case—but found nothing even as he scanned his surroundings. The moment he was in the workshop, he found himself overwhelmed by the sheer number of projects going on. It was astonishing one man could do so much at once, and the complexity of every project was incredible.

The planet Ell’Hakan came from was not a very technologically advanced one. He had learned that quickly after the integration. So while this all overwhelmed him, it also strengthened his desire to recruit the man. The Celestial Kingdom lacked people like him, as no natives were technologically minded, and Ell’Hakan had a feeling this man alone could lead to a technological revolution.

"It is truly my pleasure to finally meet you," Ell’Hakan said as he saw the machinist. He did not look like much, but as mentioned, it was not his body but his mind that was worthy of respect.

"What do you want?" the man asked curtly. If not for his Bloodline, he would have thought the man was hostile, but no. There were no such emotions. In fact, the emotional spectrum he felt from the man was incredibly narrow and muted.

But it was there. Ell’Hakan had a faint fear that the man somehow didn’t possess emotions at all, as that would partly explain his ability to have a Void God as his Patron. It turned out that even if he was peculiar, he was still a human with emotions to bite onto and manipulate. To Ell’Hakan, the slightest thing was enough.

"I am incredibly impressed by your work, and I come with an offer," Ell’Hakan said, knowing not to mince words with the man to avoid testing his patience. "I am aware your ties to Haven are shallow at best, and you are primarily here due to the resources offered, yes?"

He did not even need the machinist to answer to know it was true. His emotions gave it away.

"If that is the case, I can offer you something better,” Ell’Hakan went on with a smile. “The backing of not just a single city, but an entire world. A planet full of natural resources for you to explore and exploit to your liking, with near-endless funds. And all I ask in return is a bit of conditional loyalty.”

That was when he felt just the emotion he wanted. Desire. Greed. This man was stoic, but alas, still human, and he would fall to human desires like any other. But there was also a lot of distrust. Arnold seemed to be in thought as Ell’Hakan tried to soothe his worries.

"To show my sincerity, we can start with a temporary working contract," Ell’Hakan said convincingly. “Simply let me hire you for a while. Come and see my planet once I return, and if you refuse to work for me anymore, I swear I will help you gain passage to anywhere else.” He then took out a small, star-shaped token and handed it to the machinist. "At the very least, consider the offer."

Arnold looked at the token and took it. A faint sliver of trust had wormed in. It was weak, only confirming his thoughts that Ell’Hakan would give him time to think and was not there to cause him harm, but that alone was a springboard. He amplified Arnold’s emotions and used his Bloodline liberally to the level of getting a slight headache. The machinist was a tough one compared to the Malefic’s Chosen. If Arnold was a faint candle of emotions, then the Malefic’s Chosen was a roaring inferno.

"I will," Arnold finally answered with a genuine nod.

"To further show my sincerity…" Ell’Hakan said as he summoned a number of metals from his planet that none of his current crafters could work with. He felt the man’s interest instantly, and Ell’Hakan could not help himself but smile as he subtly left.

He had a good feeling Arnold would make the right choice.

Arnold sat alone after the alien left. He felt a strong sense of trust in the man but paid it little attention. Checking the recording of the conversation, he did not necessarily find anything amiss either. Arnold considered the offer and checked some provided information in the token. It even included a potential draft of an offer as well as a method to contact Ell’Hakan.

The offer was good. Brilliant, even. Far more than Lord Thayne and Haven had offered, or would likely ever offer him. Their resources were limited, and it had primarily been the merchant Sultan helping him out by selling Arnold’s products and buying raw materials. To say he was supported by Haven and Lord Thayne would be simply incorrect. At least, not in an institutional capacity. Lord Thayne had personally helped him, but that had been transactional in nature.

If Arnold went by his guts, the answer was a no-brainer. He had far more trust in Ell’Hakan supporting him than Lord Thayne losing interest and just leaving for good. Arnold would definitely accept the offer if he had to choose.

But he didn’t choose. Because truly, what he felt didn’t matter and should never be a factor in his decision-making. Arnold started out with the most obvious facts and made a detailed analysis of his own thought patterns, identifying that his emotional responses had been adversely affected, further cementing that he should not use his flawed mind to decide.

Additionally, he analyzed the offer, truly finding it worth it even from a far more objective standpoint. The benefits would be more than Haven would offer, but that was only in the short term. Using his current working model for predicting behavior and going by all the information he had, there were few positive outcomes.

Ell’Hakan had made the Malefic’s Chosen an enemy, and it did not take an Eye of Oras to see all the potential risks involved in that. Lord Thayne was simply too unpredictable in every aspect for Arnold to make any conclusions or properly assess him. He did not make the decisions Arnold would expect in nearly any situation. He was an utterly illogical human. And if there was one thing Arnold wanted to avoid in his calculations, it was high-variable outliers ruining the entire model.

Looking over the data one final time, Arnold simply nodded and returned to his work. The decision he came to was simple.

Just don’t choose a side.

Lord Thayne would not ask for him to choose one, and Ell’Hakan had a standing offer, so why decide now? The only reason he would be forced to make a decision was if either party lost. In which case, he would choose the person not losing.

With Lord Thayne, however, the only valid parameter to rule him the loser would be his death, while for Ell’Hakan, it would also include him fleeing the planet. The reason for this difference?

All data indicated he could survive an angry Ell’Hakan coming after him.

All data indicated he couldn’t survive an angry Jake Thayne hunting him to the ends of eternity.

Chapter 30

Just Winging It

Jake was rubbing his hands as he looked forward to seeing Villy in a perilous situation that forced him to escape. Entering the vision, he was not sure what to expect. Maybe Villy getting beaten up? Him waltzing into the territory of some far more powerful monster, making him tuck his tail between his legs?

As the vision appeared, it was neither of those. He saw Villy flying through an odd area with purplish mist everywhere. Comet-like balls of ice flew all around him—some of them several kilometers across, while others were far smaller. Jake also saw that sometimes space itself seemed to crack, and small vacuums opened up, sucking in mist and some of the smaller comets.

He had a hard time figuring out what was going on. Villy was in his C-grade Wyvern form and looked incredibly distressed as he dodged comet after comet. It was like he flew aimlessly. A few minutes passed before a giant comet suddenly exploded, only to reassemble into a vaguely humanoid form. Villy did not hesitate to release a breath on the newly born… comet elemental? Ice elemental? Either or, he quickly dealt with it, but that didn’t at all give him reprieve.

Finally, Villy seemed to spot something. With high speed, he flew to the side and, to Jake’s surprise, encountered a massive wall of purple ice. Flying alongside the wall, Villy soon found a small cave and stopped before it.

His body began morphing and shrinking, and within five seconds, the familiar humanoid form of Villy appeared. Familiar, yet foreign. He looked young in the vision, and Jake had a strong feeling this was the earliest vision of the would-be Primordial he had ever experienced.

Villy collapsed and leaned against the inside wall of the small ice cavern, breathing heavily. He closed his eyes for a moment before summoning a large metal plate of sorts to block off the hole, sealing himself within the cavern.

Sitting back down, the Viper surprisingly fell asleep as time accelerated. Once the Viper woke up again, he quickly took out some kind of magical device. It looked like a compass of sorts, and Villy frowned as he looked at it. After a bit, he took out another few weird devices, and his frown only grew.

"Fuck," he said as he groaned and brought both his hands to his head. "The exits should have remained for at least another week… Did that bastard lie to me? I swear…"

Just those few words made Jake put two and two together and realize what was happening. The Viper was in some kind of minor world or dimension, a bit like Yalsten but probably far smaller. Also, clearly far more unstable compared to Yalsten in its heyday.

Jake knew about these kinds of places. They were often small dimensions that resided in the infinite layers of space. One could not break into them, with the only way in being certain natural entrances that sometimes opened, and one could also only exit through these small holes. These dimensions tended to be of incredible value exactly because of this. Any small world that had been isolated for a long time was bound to have given birth to several potent natural treasures, especially as many of these small worlds had singular, dominating affinities yet rarely had beasts or monsters. There would still be enemies, but often only very specialized ones, such as the elementals or creatures born to guard the treasures.

It appeared that Villy had entered one such place with bad information and found himself screwed over and trapped. Which maybe didn’t sound that bad if the world would open up again, but there were a few minor issues. First of all, how long would it take? It could take longer than Villy’s natural lifespan. One had to remember that Aeon Clok had killed people far more powerful than himself by sealing them in a world a bit like this and letting the passing of time handle it.

Then there was also the issue that these places could get far more dangerous during their lockdown period, and based on the comets going wild and Villy seeming panicked, Jake assumed this was the case.

"I need to get out of here," Villy muttered to himself as he stood up and took out some more magical devices, including the compass. "It hasn’t been that long… or is the layer meant to be this weak?" Jake saw the Viper deep in thoughts, considering his options, before steeling himself. "It could work."

Wings appeared on his back, making him look a bit like Jake with his wings out.

"Those fuckers… They somehow accelerated and sealed the entrances," Villy said as he double-checked some weird magical circle on a map. "At least, halfway sealed them."

Jake was beginning to question if a C-grade Villy could truly escape a naturally sealed-off world like this. One had to remember that after Yalsten was sealed off, no one could escape, not even the A-grades. Yet if this was not a natural sealing, but simply one accelerated by mortal hands, then it should still be possible.

Villy sat down in meditation with his wings summoned, and Jake felt the energy and toxic blood move within them. Time seemed to move in odd ways, as days passed with the Viper focusing on his wings. Jake got the feeling this was not some sudden burst of inspiration, but rather him picking up the work on an ongoing project. The Viper had either worked on an escape skill like this before or had already completed several elements of the skill.

However, what was important was that it was not done, allowing Jake to feel part of the process. The first thing he picked up on was that each wing was different. It was like the Viper poured in different energies and manipulated the blood with variance, with each wing having different mixes of concepts as a result. Jake felt them both and noticed what differed.

One wing held blood that would be able to corrode passive energy, and the other wing held blood that would corrode mana with intent. Jake was momentarily confused, then realized why this was actually brilliant. Poisons of similar natures tended to amplify one another, while those of opposite natures would attack each other. This did not fully apply due to the sheer variety of concepts in each wing, but it eliminated most of the potential conflicts that could arise. Also, the Viper’s infused intents in each wing were now physically separated, and focusing his intent to accomplish the two tasks in separate wings was far more efficient and easier.

Next up was the process of creating the cocoon. On this note, Jake had thought that the fast movement Villy had displayed in the first vision was part of the skill’s effect, but that was quickly proven wrong. Nothing done would actually make him faster, but due to the nature of the magic, it would rapidly increase speed momentarily. The mist would erode everything in his path, effectively allowing him to fly in a vacuum of concepts. Considering the limited time the cocoon would last, fast movement right off the bat was also a necessity, and then one just had to let the momentum carry forward.

The vision progressed more or less as expected as Jake watched the Viper adapt and make the Wings’ skill effect on the fly—pun intended. Feeling it like this, Jake had to admit that the Viper had truly been a monster. The toxic concepts that had taken Jake days to identify were found within hours by the Viper, and his level of energy control when it came to the toxic energy was utterly insane. He was at least slower than Jake in some places, but they were few and far between.

After what Jake estimated to be roughly five total days in the cave, the Viper opened his eyes and got ready. Scales covered his body as he flew out of the cave and into the storm of comets. He dodged them more easily now due to his smaller humanoid shape, but it was clear he was not as fast in this form.

He flew for a quarter of an hour, periodically checking the compass he had brought until he was at the right spot. It was a weird, fractured point in space that looked almost like a broken phone screen with microcracks everywhere.

The Viper took a deep breath as he got close and slowed down. That was when time also slowed down, and Jake felt the skill being used for the first time. Both wings were infused with a lot of energy, and Jake’s eyes opened wide at discovering how he infused it… He summoned several wings pretty much on top of each other at the same time.

An explosion sounded as both wings blew up from energy overload. Jake felt the pain, as he experienced Villy’s body like it was his own. The Viper rapidly gathered the energy and wrapped it around himself like a barrier. When he did so, Jake saw his body turn green and knew it was not due to his body changing… It was simply Jake seeing the effect of everything being corroded all around him.

A second explosion sounded out when the Viper shot forward towards the broken space. A faint trace was left in his wake as he went into the fractured exit point. The poison around him revolved at nearly impossible speeds, each particle of mist able to break down the fundamental laws of reality itself.

Once the Viper entered the fractured point, he simply phased into it. Even if the Viper was strong, he was not strong enough to break a space tunnel like this… but he could burn a small hole into it and pass through. Space reformed behind him like he had never been there, and Jake only saw a faint glimpse of darkness before Villy appeared in the outside world, surrounded by large, snowy mountains. Behind him, a crack in reality had been formed, but it healed within a fraction of a second, so fast a simple blink would miss it.

The cocoon of mist dispersed nearly instantly, and the Viper began to fall to the ground, clearly exhausted. Jake felt a profound sense of weakness all over, and moreover, like a part of his Soulshape had been sacrificed to make the escape possible… which was when Jake found the final piece of the puzzle.

What he had been stuck on was how to control the poison. He now realized he didn’t control it at all; it would control itself. What the Viper had done was sacrifice the wings to infuse parts of himself into them. His own will and desire.

The last thing Jake saw was Villy turn in a certain direction, murder in his eyes. Clearly out for revenge against those who had dared to try and trap and kill him.

Everything then rewound, and Jake saw the vision again. Even if it appeared long, the entire vision had only been about fifteen minutes total, considering all the fast-forwarding.

Jake slowly hammered out the errors. He smiled as the vision ended, confident, and returned to the real world.

He appeared sitting inside Sandy’s stomach, and instantly the worm launched into a tirade.

"Wow, what did you do? I felt something super weird just now, like, you were gone and then back or something? That was sooo weird… You were still kind of there, but not really, you know?"

"I did special magic," Jake answered jokingly.

"Boo. You should share.”

"How about I share with you the results? Can you stop for a moment, so I can test this out? Just be warned, I will try to get out of here, and I can’t promise this won’t be a little painful. I may just make a hole or something on my way out.”

"Oh, go ahead; I will try and stop you, right?"

"Go ahead," Jake said confidently.

Jake focused as his wings appeared. The skill had already upgraded the moment he returned, and the learned knowledge turned instinctual. Everything happened instantly with the system’s assistance: Dozens of wings superimposed upon each other and exploded, forming a cloud of mist around him. He then sent himself flying forward towards the wall of the stomach chamber.

He observed everything carefully. He felt and saw himself impact the stomach wall, and the moment he did, it seemed to simply disintegrate. Everything turned black for a moment. No concept reached Jake—not even light. He felt entirely isolated from everything, and even his sphere went haywire for a second. He felt the mist fight against everything and slowly consume itself to burn him a path, and then…

And then he was in the outside world.

Jake stopped and saw he was still in rocky, mountainous terrain, as the mist had already dispersed upon escaping. He took a moment to collect himself and saw the giant worm flying just above, and as he looked up, he also felt Sandy’s attention on him.

"You escape—I mean, got out!" Sandy said with surprise.

"That I did," Jake answered. He had to admit that he had expected the fatigue to be more prominent. Then again, he had a monstrous mana pool.

There were no marks anywhere on Sandy, and Jake wondered why that was.

"That was so weird!" Sandy said, explaining to him what had happened. "I was just waiting and wondering what you were doing until you disappeared again and then just popped right out of my skin! Like, it makes no sense; it was like you weren’t really inside me at all…"

Jake considered it for a moment before he understood the explanation. He had not even interacted with the physical body of Sandy, only the Soulshape, and one couldn’t even say he had done that… it was more like he had been spat out of the Soulshape. He had to admit, even now, that he still didn’t entirely understand how the skill worked, and he had a feeling the Viper hadn’t one hundred percent either when he made it.

Not that Jake would complain. He finally opened his messages and saw the upgraded skill.

[Wings of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)] – Refusing to remain earthbound, the Malefic Viper sprang wings to devour the skies. You too refuse to be earthbound. Allows the alchemist to summon two phantasmal wings and take flight. While active, you can burn the blood within the wings and release potent toxic fumes. The toxicity and effect of the poison are based on Blood of the Malefic Viper. Toughness and maneuverability of the wings and speed are based primarily on Agility but receive a bonus from all physical stats. The wings count as part of your body for all relevant skills. Passively provides 1 Agility per level in Prodigious Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May the sight of your wings be the harbinger of death.

-->

[Wings of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] – Refusing to remain earthbound, the Malefic Viper sprang wings to devour the skies. Refusing to be bound or trapped anywhere, the wings of the Malefic One shall always leave a path of escape. Allows the alchemist to summon two phantasmal wings and take flight. While active, you can burn the blood within the wings and release potent toxic fumes. The toxicity and effects of the poison are based on Blood of the Malefic Viper. Toughness and maneuverability of the wings and speed are based primarily on Agility but receive a bonus from all physical stats. The wings count as part of your body for all relevant skills. Allows the alchemist to further infuse and sacrifice both wings to create an opportunity to escape if in a perilous situation. Doing this makes resummoning the wings impossible for a variable duration, dependent on Agility and the amount of energy infused into the wings upon the sacrifice. Passively provides 3 Agility per level in Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your wings be the harbinger of death and instruments of escape to feed another day.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 184 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 185 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 182 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Wings was a contender, if not a winner, for longest skill description by now. The added description did not say much he didn’t already know, but it did explain one thing he was unaware of… He couldn’t summon his wings again. It was like the Soulshape framework itself had taken damage from using the skill. The more Jake looked at it, the more insane it seemed. The Viper had found a way to summon a new appendage to the soul and then used that added appendage as a way to sacrifice a part of the soul. Jake had known before that it was possible as a concept, but he’d never seen it used like this. The most common variant was severe boosting skills that could leave long-lasting damage to the soul.

The problem with the soul was that one really had to just give it time to heal. While there were treasures to hasten it or very special things like the Soul Renewal he had used on the King, the best medicine was truly just time.

Oh, and then there was the added Agility, which Jake would definitely not complain about. Two levels in his profession were also a welcome addition, if a rather expected one.

"So…" Sandy said after a while.

"Sure, sure, go ahead and gobble me up again," Jake said, sighing as the worm happily ate him like a tasty snack. Once he was inside, Sandy began moving again, continuing their adventure across the world.

"Hey, human Jake, can you tell me more about that weird magic before?"

Jake wanted a break anyway and obliged. "You see, my good friend Villy—the Malefic Viper we talked about before—has given me a Legacy that has a lot of skills and…"

They talked and relaxed, and Jake realized he only had one thing he felt a bit sad about. The vision of Villy had not really been the embarrassing moment Jake had hoped for, but more just the snake god showing off how skilled he was.

Oh, well, better luck next time. There had to be a vision where Villy was caught in a really embarrassing moment, right?

Chapter 31

Godly Interference & Advice

"This is complete bullshit," Carmen said as she stared at the golden projection.

"It wasn’t my call, but it comes all the way from the top," the projection of Sven said, shaking his head. "This may sound curt, but it is partly because of you. Your personal relationship with the Malefic’s Chosen is both a merit and a demerit. On the one hand, it ensures us a spot in this world, but on the other, then if someone else gets in charge, we may be ostracized."

"Still complete fucking bullshit," Carmen now raged. "Do you really think Jake will just be all fine with us supporting this orange Cheeto fuck? Do you think he will just go, ‘Oh, well, what can you do?’ and let us go about our day like nothing? Fuck no—there will be hell to pay."

"You are talking as if his victory is a given," Sven answered. "Even if he is stronger than this Ell’Hakan, it does not mean he will beat him in the political arena. Besides, it is not even Ell’Hakan we are supporting, but Arthur, another human. We are not betraying anyone, for we were never on the side of Lord Thayne to begin with. He will get even better terms than Arthur if he comes out on top, and with Miranda likely around, she will be a voice of reason."

"Funny," Carmen scoffed. "You think he gives a shit about some terms or benefits? Jake is an impulsive kind of guy, and if he thinks you slighted him, that is the only thing that matters."

"Carmen, we are not getting anywhere if we talk in circles." Sven sighed. "The decision has already been made, and none of us can do anything about it. All we can do is make the best out of the situation. The top brass thinks this will have the highest overall chance of success, so that is why we are going with it. You can agree or disagree, and it changes nothing. If you want to do anything, it should be to make sure Jake stays positive towards us if he wins."

Carmen just kept frowning as she abruptly turned off the projector with a huff, still thinking it was fucking bullshit.

"Ree?" Sylphie asked, still sitting beside her and not entirely getting everything that was going on.

Sylphie had chosen to stay with Carmen since Jake left, and the two of them had used Paradise as a home base while exploring. Renato was the kind of two-faced asshole Carmen expected and did not choose any side at all, only fortifying the city itself in case anyone chose to target them. Not that she cared; he let her and Sylphie do as they wanted, and Carmen’s mother was doing way better. She had settled down and now just worked as a tailor. The original plan of bringing her to an area Valhal controlled had been delayed due to the Salvento family having a lot of assets to claim and Renato being very good at convincing them to stay "just a little longer" all the time.

"I don’t know, Sylphie," Carmen said, sighing. "This entire situation is fucked up, and they just expect me to sit tight and do nothing? You know what? How about we go fuck up some of their cities? Go punch some City Lords to give them a bit of their own medicine?"

"Ree!" Sylphie screeched, excited, probably just wanting to get in a few good fights.

"Let’s do i—"

Carmen’s eyes opened wide as she felt a headache come on. She knew what it was and gritted her teeth as she heard the voice of Gudrun.

"Carmen, I understand your feelings. You remind me much of my husband, you know? Like Valdemar, you never see the bigger picture because you personally don’t have to. But this entire scenario is quite delicate. Earth is a melting pot right now, and in an untenable situation if one has even the slightest foresight. The Holy Church and Risen would never get along, and not even the Viper’s Chosen could create peace among two factions that have warred for trillions of years. In the same way, some humans will never come to accept the Order of the Malefic Viper either. They will never be able to disconnect the Chosen from the Order, for historically, there has never been any such separation. You know him as a person; they know him as a symbol.

“Conflict is inevitable and healthy, and this entire conflict will only lead to Earth entering a more stable state. No matter who wins. All we want to make sure of is that no matter who wins, we keep an opening. If the Chosen chooses to close this opening, then so be it. Removing ourselves as an organizational presence from Earth is truly not that big of a loss, and as per the doctrine of Valhal, you would be able to stay if you wanted. Anyone would. And remember, we have not actually chosen a side; we have, in fact, done the opposite and said that we will support either side that wins. If the Malefic’s Chosen is the kind of individual that will make a "me or them" ultimatum, then I will only feel strengthened in this decision. For that is not the kind of man we would want to work with in the long term. So, Carmen, all I am asking of you is to do nothing. For remember, what you do will be the actions of Valhal. I cannot tell you what you can or can’t do, but I can implore you to think about it. If you are truly confident the Malefic’s Chosen will win, then just sit tight and keep trusting in him to handle it."

It was a damn long message that came like a huge package. Carmen took a while to process it all and wasn’t sure what to think… Gudrun had been incredibly hands-off for Carmen, and she was surprised any god from Valhal would suddenly contact her, much less the wife and de-facto leader of the day-to-day operations of Valhal.

This is why Carmen found it suspicious, and even if she had a damn headache from receiving a divine message, she still responded. "You do care about Earth… If not, you wouldn’t go this far as to contact me and try to explain things.”

Carmen got an amused chuckle in return as Gudrun answered, "No, we care about the people on it… which is also why I mentioned that you could stay on Earth even if Valhal was made to leave. People like Jake Thayne care about the people they choose to care about. He has chosen you as someone he cares about. So even if Valhal leaves Earth and you stay, we won’t have lost anything worth mentioning. And if the Malefic’s Chosen loses, I think it wise for you to bring your loved ones and leave Earth altogether, even if we do enter a partnership. For the safety of both you and the potential new leader of your planet."

"The way you talk makes it sound like there is even a chance Jake loses," Carmen still argued.

"There is. Maybe not this time, but the Chosen of Yip of Yore is not one to be taken lightly. Yip of Yore isn’t either. He is a very unknown character to many, and what many do not know is that he showed up to Valhal and challenged Valdemar to a duel not that long ago. The mere fact that he still lives today should be proof that he is not the jester many believe him to be, but can represent a genuine problem even to gods who stand at the pinnacle.”

Carmen wanted to argue more, but her head was pounding. Gudrun also knew this and retracted her presence, leaving Carmen alone. She gritted her teeth and clenched her fists as she turned to a worried Sylphie.

"Change of plans… Fuck those cities and let’s just go slaughter something else," Carmen said with much annoyance. She was pissed off and really felt like getting her frustrations out on some unsuspecting beasts. Besides, she and Sylphie should be able to handle a few weaker C-grades by now.

Someone else was also finally contacting his Patron after quite a while of no talking. After having a lot of long conversations, Jake finally initiated contact with a certain god.

"So, got another vision," Jake said as he reached out to Villy.

"Related to Wings, I see," Villy answered.

"Yep."

"Are you busy or something?" Jake asked, feeling like Villy was far less talkative than usual. He had not reached out, even after Jake got his Wings upgrade, which he usually did. Nor had he commented when Jake had helped "make" Sandy.

"I am just waiting for you to address… you know," Villy said.

"Oh. That. Yeah, alright. So, it is quite clear to me that this Ell’Hakan guy had prepared for a long-ass time, and clearly did not hold back when it came to divine guidance. I am going to guess that this Yip of Yore had blessed people on Earth that helped to act as mouthpieces and relay messages for a while.”

"That is precisely what they did," Villy answered with relief. "I will admit, I had expected you to be a bit angrier. You were taken by surprise, and someone died, with Earth being thrown into quite a situation. All something we both know I was aware of and could have warned you about."

"Well, yeah," Jake said with a shrug. "And you kind of did by telling me to stop slacking off, didn’t you? Also, we decided before that this falls into mortal affairs. The one thing I am wondering is, why does this Yip not care and help his Chosen so much?"

"His goals for his Chosen are different from mine, and his Path is also very different. I cannot give you the exact reason, as I don’t know it, but he is up to something.”

"I see," Jake answered.

"There is also the fact that you two are not equal. You are the Chosen of a Primordial. My Chosen. This was never a fair fight to begin with, and he was just trying to even the playing field, expecting me not to do the same out of pride. I also trusted you to handle it yourself. Even if you suffer temporary setbacks, you should be able to overcome them. People may die, but as harsh as it may sound, that is something I am fully willing to see happen as long as you keep moving forward. And about Yip himself, I will have him handled. I can feel he is cooking up something, but he is not the only one skilled in the kitchen."

Jake considered the Viper’s words for a moment. "Is that also why no one else was warned? Aeon should have seen it coming. Or Stormild, if that damn elemental was paying attention. Shit, didn’t you say Oras is the master of seeing stuff? Did none of them really warn their own people on Earth?"

"Nope, not a single warning was given to anyone. Mind you, the Witches of the Verdant Lagoon also noticed it would happen but said nothing. And I hadn’t told them not to, either. You just must understand that giving warnings like that isn’t really a thing and is even frowned upon by the system. Not even for the Holy Church. It goes against convention, and if a settlement falls and a few billion members of a faction die, so what? It is a minor loss of no consequence, and in the eyes of many, just a healthy culling of the masses.”

"I get it, jeez," Jake said with a sigh. "Let’s move on to a happier topic. Thoughts on my new ride?"

"I will admit, it is not actually a race I am familiar with," Villy confessed. "Mind you, Cosmic Worms are nothing new and only semi-rare across the multiverse, but a Cosmic Genesis Worm is a first for me."

"Any idea how I made it happen?" Jake asked.

"A few, but nothing concrete. Ultimately, we both know it is related to that monstrous Bloodline of yours as well as your arcane affinity. Rather than me trying to come up with theories, I find it better you just figure out the truth and then tell me.”

"That I can do.” Smiling, Jake continued, “Oh, well, back to killing stuff and flying with my wormy friend until it is time to kick Ell’Hakan’s ass and boot him off the planet.”

"Sounds like a plan. But I will give you one warning, as Yip clearly doesn’t care about conventions. People like Yip and Ell’Hakan are annoying fucks. They are planners, through and through, and a head-on approach never tends to work out well. Their victory conditions also tend to vary widely. If his goal is just to institute a World Leader, then why would he ever fight you? There is no need to. So think about why he does what he does far more. Think about what his plan may be. I am not telling you to try and be a planner yourself, as quite frankly, you would suck at it, but I am telling you to broaden your field of view. You killing Ell’Hakan would be your best victory condition, and he knows that. Thus, he will act and plan according to that. Additionally, this kind of planner tends to have strategies with multiple win conditions, some better than others, but all acceptable, with more fail-safes than you can imagine. Chances are the final confrontation with him will not happen on your terms, and I am not sure you can do much to change that besides making sure that even if it is on his terms, it is also on yours and you are not taken by surprise. Anyway, that is all I am gonna say, and good luck.”

"Thanks, and good luck to you too," Jake said in return, having a feeling Villy was also up to something behind the scenes. He did say he would handle Yip of Yore, after all.

Their connection faded, and Jake reflected on how Villy had actually been relieved at Jake not blaming him. Jake did not see why he would. Villy had not been the one who told Ell’Hakan to come to Earth, he had not been the one who made the United Cities Alliance morons, and he had not sent Jake to the other side of the planet. True, Jake was targeted because he was the Viper’s Chosen, but that too was something Jake had picked to be. He could have renounced the Blessing at any time before reaching D-grade, and now as a Heretic-Chosen, he had already embraced the Path and whatever issues it could bring to be a Chosen. Sure, he still wanted to avoid the responsibilities, but that was only to be expected, as who likes responsibilities?

No, the only ones Jake blamed were the United Cities Alliance and Ell’Hakan. They were the ones who had started shit, and Jake would gladly throw that shit right back in their faces. He just had a bit of a distance to go, and some progress to make.

"Hey, Sandy, be a bit less picky for hunting spots," Jake said.

"Hm? Why?"

"I need one level for something good," Jake said with a smile. He had killed one weak C-grade without getting a level and knew the next one would give him that level-up. Which would mean it was finally time to get his last class skill from Avaricious Arcane Hunter.

Chapter 32

Hunter Level 180 Skill Selection & Being Hunted

It had only taken Sandy about a day to find good prey for Jake, and it wasn’t even guarding that good of a natural treasure according to the worm, heavily insinuating he should feel thankful.

His opponent had been this weird, wooly thing that he couldn’t quite figure out, but it had bled and suffered from necrosis the same as everything else, and with it only being level 201, Jake had quickly taken it down. Quickly being a relative term, as the damn ball of wool had still been damn tanky. Anyway, with it finally dead, the last level came.

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 180 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

And it was skill-selection time.

*Avaricious Arcane Hunter class skills available*

Jake was naturally excited. These last skill selections always felt special, and this profession skill had not disappointed with his freakish soul mutation skill. Jake did not necessarily want a similar skill for his class, but something more directly related to combat. Maybe an upgrade to Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter? Oh, how about a skill, any skill, that scaled with Perception? He would very much like that. He had some Free Points saved up, and if he happened to get a skill that scaled with Perception… well, he had an excuse.

So, without further ado, he dove in and saw five options. It was as expected, and true to tradition, he went through them.

[Minor Arcane Seal (Rare)] – Through the concept of stability, none shall find a path of escape. Allows the Hunter to create a seal by infusing stable arcane mana into a chosen target or area around the Hunter. Consumption of mana is dependent on the object or area the Hunter tries to seal. The durability of the seal is dependent on Wisdom and mana expenditure. Adds a minor bonus to the effects of Minor Arcane Seal based on Wisdom and Willpower.

And the first one was a solid dud that Jake quickly skipped over. He already knew how to infuse stable mana into stuff.

[Hunter’s Blade-Fang Style (Epic)] – To you, your weapons are your fangs, and your fangs are your ultimate shield. A defensive combat skill that revolves around countering and dodging your foe to keep distance and minimize damage taken. Unlocks intermediate proficiency in the Hunter’s Blade-Fang Style and adds a small bonus to the effects of Agility, Strength, and Perception when using a bladed weapon.

The first interesting option. It was an actual melee fighting technique skill. It had a slight overlap with Fang of Man, with the stat effect increasing while wearing a weapon. In cases like that, the strongest skill would take priority, and while you would gain a small bonus from the other one, it was minor. As for if he wanted to pick the skill? No. There was a chance Jake could upgrade it to the style he had made with sim-Jake, but there was also a risk the innate knowledge from this skill could lead him astray. One had to remember that Jake’s fighting style was dependent on his Bloodline, so no normal skill would ever be offered that truly fit him. Unless it actually referred to Jake directly in the description, he wouldn’t even consider it. Hence, he moved on.

[Grand Arcane Explosion (Epic)] – Through sheer power and an abundance of resources, you can overwhelm your foes. Overload your surroundings with unstable arcane mana and detonate it all to create a massive explosion. This attack is especially effective against the environment but also causes significant damage to anything else caught in the blast. Adds a bonus to the effects of Intelligence and Wisdom when using Arcane Explosion.

Skill makes Jake go big boom. Jake no need; Jake already know how to go big boom.

[Arcane-Shadow Vault of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter (Ancient)] – Your prey believes it can escape your avarice—a foolish assumption, as your pursuit is endless. Through practice and sheer power, the Avaricious Arcane Hunter can turn into an Arcane Shadow to either attack or defend. Allows you to vault forward a short distance between you and your destination. Phasing through physical or magical obstacles will result in either destroying the obstacle or impeding you entirely. Your methods are crude and destructive, allowing you to create an arcane explosion at your target destination based on the distance traveled. Adds a bonus to the effects of Agility, Endurance, and Intelligence when using Arcane-Shadow Vault of the Avaricious Hunter.

WARNING: This skill is unlocked by, and will serve as an upgrade to, your existing Basic Shadow Vault of Umbra, resulting in the loss of the skill.

And there it was. Jake had expected to see this kind of skill offered, and it came as expected. This was the reward for sim-Jake’s work so far, but it was clearly not good enough. He knew that sim-Jake would not accept his Legacy merely being some ancient-rarity skill. In fact, he was pretty sure his simulacrum would want to beat him senseless if he picked it. Hence, he moved on just as everyone would expect. Because, as always, the best was saved for last.

[Relentless Hunt of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter (Legendary)] – The Avaricious Arcane Hunter is relentless in his pursuit of a stronger foe, and it only ends when he so desires. Once a target is found, the hunt shall only end in death. When hunting prey, you only grow in deadliness. Allows the Avaricious Arcane Hunter to accumulate momentum during a hunt by slowly finding an opportunity to strike. This momentum can then be turned into a tangible weapon. Successfully landing blows while not taking damage yourself hastens the accumulation of hunting momentum. Can consume all hunting momentum to significantly empower a single attack to deal devastating damage. Momentum can carry over if a new hunt begins shortly after another one ends. All skill effects increase as your foe’s level grows higher. The base speed at which hunting momentum is accumulated, as well as the maximum amount of momentum possible, is determined by Perception.

Jake read the skill over carefully.

If one asked Jake what his biggest problem was, it would be huge finisher attacks. Arcane Powershot was damn strong, but not some massive finisher, and while Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter had filled that role for a good while, it wasn’t at the level of some other attacks he had seen. Carmen had her Fist of Ragnarok, his brother had that huge lighting attack, and many beasts also had supremely powerful attacks they could only release as a final gamble. Shit, that weird space-tunnel attack by the Panther had been insane, even for its level. Jake had kind of wanted something like that, and while he realized this skill would not give him some massively powerful blow, it was still good. Depending on how effective it actually was, of course.

There was only one huge plus. It was a skill that scaled purely with Perception and allowed Jake to translate that Perception into actual damage. Some of his class skills and his archery skill already did this, but this added another layer. Moreover, nothing said it required one to use a ranged weapon, so Jake could also land a far more powerful melee blow using this Hunting Momentum. Yes, that was now the official name of the momentum Jake accumulated during the fight.

Needless to say, Jake picked the skill because why the hell wouldn’t he? It was a no-brainer and clearly the best. The moment he did so, he felt the instinctual knowledge enter his head. Honestly, there wasn’t much to it, and he knew that to truly get a feel for the skill and how good it was, he would need some actual combat. What he was sure of was that his overall damage output had just increased a lot.

After his talk with Villy, Jake had also changed his mind about just charging back. It seemed like Ell’Hakan and Arthur did have lines they refused to cross, and he had to trust other people in his life to be able to fend for themselves. Caleb should protect Jake’s family, and Miranda could handle herself, especially if she managed to get to the Grand Mangrove River. In there, she should be absolutely safe. He also wondered why, even now, no one had tried to take the Pylon in Haven yet. As long as he wasn’t put on that thirty-day timer, he truly wasn’t in that much of a rush. And if it was taken, he could just get it right back.

Speaking of Miranda… Jake had already reached out for her to contact him once available. If Ell’Hakan was making some plans, so would Jake. Ell’Hakan had clearly done a lot of research into Jake and even had his Patron help, but his research was limited. There were things not even the gods knew or could find out.

So why not make use of that? Of course, for him to truly figure out a method of approach, he would need to speak and strategize with Miranda. He just hoped she had gotten to the Grand Mangrove River safely.

Miranda regretted not forcing Sultan along. Not to have his companionship or fighting power, but solely to use that flying ship of his. Neil had managed to teleport them far, and they were making good distance with him teleporting them a few more times, but outside of these teleports, they were slow.

The problem was with Mark and Louise—Hank’s son and daughter, respectively. Neither of them had reached D-grade, making them far slower than everyone else and forcing Hank to carry one, with the other handled by Christen, one of Neil’s party members. Miranda was not at all a physically proficient fighter, but even she outclassed the two of them several times over.

Now, being slow would be fine if not for the fact they were being chased. It was clear that the United Cities Alliance wanted her dead, just as Ell’Hakan had warned, and a group was in hot pursuit. Clearly, the United Cities Alliance had some teleporters still around somewhere, or at least some way to teleport around, as they quickly gave chase despite teleporting so far from Haven.

This meant that despite their head start, they were slowly getting caught up with. It was unsure if they could fight this group, but Miranda doubted it. Neil and his party were good fighters, but not at all at the level of true elites, and information on them was also abundant, making her sure Arthur had factored them in. Miranda herself also wasn’t a good fighter in a straight-on battle like this.

Luckily for them, they reached the Grand Mangrove River before they were overtaken by the other group.

"Shit," Neil cursed the moment they entered the mangroves. "I felt a teleport about… more than a kilometer, less than ten, right behind us."

"Can you teleport us further in?" Miranda asked with concern, looking at Hank and the others.

Neil shook his head. "No, this place is messing with my space magic quite badly, I can use it locally, but it is like the entire area is warped slightly."

During this time, they’d never stopped running, just diving further and further in. Far enough in for monsters to appear and hassle them, but fortunately, Neil and his party were there to handle it. Eleanor, Levi, Silas, and Neil handled most everything, with Lillian also offering some support, but she was limited in what she could do.

The water below them stirred as Miranda felt movement behind them through it. It was lucky that the area was swamp-like, giving her some benefits as a Verdant Witch—but far from enough to fight without proper preparation. Thinking quickly, Miranda took out some bottles she had gotten from Jake a long time ago for experiments. They all contained his blood infused with Blood of the Malefic Viper, and she had nearly forgotten she even had them after she discovered how useless they were if anyone other than Jake used the blood.

Crushing all the bottles, she spilled the liquid all over the water. She knew it could attract something they didn’t want to attract, but it could also do just the opposite. Just after she did this, a large crocodile emerged from below—one nearly at the peak of D-grade.

"Hank, take Mark and Louise and keep running!" Miranda yelled to the builder as Christen tossed Louise to him. Hank complied and started running further away… not only because of the croc, but also what came from behind.

Sadly, he did not get far. The water rose in front of him like a barrier as it crackled with lightning. Hank turned back in a panic, and so did everyone else who was not too busy with the crocodile.

A group of five appeared, all of them giving off strong auras.

Miranda recognized them as the group with Arthur during the Auction. All of them had powerful equipment, and there was even the caster with the Fulgarian Deepcaller class that Jake had sold the Akashic Tome to. He was also the one who had made the barrier of water. She identified a few of them and knew they were in trouble.

[Human – lvl 174]

[Human – lvl 178]

But she still believed they could at least put up a fight… until more presences appeared behind the wall, having circled around with incredible speed. Miranda squinted and gritted her teeth as she saw them.

[Infernomaw Hound – lvl 199]

[Frostmaw Hound – lvl 199]

[Thundermaw Hound – lvl 199]

Three large, dog-like creatures, each of them more than five meters tall, guarded their path of escape. Miranda prepared her magic to hold them off as she released a pulse of Verdant energy. It entered the water below, but the Fulgarian Deepcaller slammed his staff into it, sending a pulse of lightning through and nullifying her mana.

He smiled confidently as Miranda frowned. "A pleasure to finally meet you, Ms. Wells. I am Mahowny, leader of the first advance party of the United Cities Alliance. Took us quite a while to finally catch up, but here we are.” He turned to the others in the group and smiled. "We are not merciless. It is only the City Lord of Haven and her assistant we are after, and the rest of you are free to leave.” Almost tauntingly, he added, “But should you choose to stand in our way, we will show no mercy."

He was full of himself, and Miranda wanted to do something. Just then, however, he opened the barrier a bit, and all three Hounds jumped in and killed the crocodile. It was an obvious show of strength, and they all knew one side was superior.

"I still don’t understand why you find this all necessary,” Miranda said. “You are choosing to work with an unknown Chosen from another planet, and for what? Do you truly think this will end well, even if all your plans work out? He is using you, not the other way around.”

Mahowny just smirked. "One of the good things about being a soldier is that my job is not to think about those things. I just follow orders and get the job done, and in this instance, my job is to kill you. Truly, it is nothing personal. Now, you can either decide to give yourself up and have your followers here leave… or fight. I am fine with either option."

Miranda tried to look like she was deep in thought. She felt herself being closely monitored by the party in front of her. All five of them were above 170, but the biggest problem was the three hounds. If she tried to use any magic, she did not doubt they would react and pounce. The other side clearly knew that they risked taking a loss or two if Miranda or the others had any trump cards, making them prefer that she just surrendered.

All Miranda could do was to make use of this and drag out the time. All she remembered about the Grand Mangrove River was that Jake had made a friend there, and she had hoped to draw them closer using the blood.

"Time is up," Mahowny said after Miranda did her darndest to look conflicted for around a minute. Miranda prepared herself along with the rest of her group, as the other side was about to engage. "You have made your choice, and now it is time to—"

He didn’t get further before he clamped up. Everyone stopped in their tracks, with the three hounds suddenly lying down on their respective branches, whimpering. An aura had swept into the area, making Miranda’s eyes open wide. It was stronger than anything she had ever felt on Earth, and she had no doubt the source was well in the C-grade.

She slowly turned her head and saw the figure that was the source of the aura through the thick roots of the mangrove. Miranda did not know what to expect, but it was not that. A young woman with snow-white skin and scattered scales across her body walked on water like it was solid ground. Her hair was long and white like the rest of her body, and her eyes were red with reptilian pupils. She wore a dress that looked like it was made of snakeskin, swaying behind her as if weightless. She looked like something out of a fairytale.

[Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake – lvl ???]

The young woman—no, C-grade monster turned humanoid—watched them all, seemingly looking for something. Or someone. Finally, her eyes landed on Miranda.

"Who are you?"

Chapter 33

Snake Girl = Danger Noodle

Miranda’s mind was a bit jumbled from the powerful aura, and it took her a moment to formulate a response. This resulted in her not being the first one to answer.

"I sincerely apologize for disturbing your area," Mahowny said as he bowed. His party members followed suit, their nervousness palpable. Sweat poured down their brows as they also realized that this monster was more than any of them could handle.

It had to be mid-tier C-grade… which meant it was above level 250. The group from the United Cities Alliance could probably handle a weak C-grade using their hounds, but the snake was an entirely different issue. It was leagues above anything they could even touch.

"We are only here for this woman and will leave once done," Mahowny further said. "And we are more than willing to compensate you for allowing us this."

The snake did not even turn to him, continuing to stare at Miranda.

Miranda felt the pressure and finally came up with an answer. "Miranda Wells… I work for the Malefic’s Chosen."

As if a switch had been flipped, the humanoid snake’s eyes opened wide. "Really? Is he here?"

"No, sadly not," Miranda said, the pressure on her instantly alleviated.

The snake deflated. "Oh…"

Miranda saw that Mahowny and the others had turned white as sheets, now matching the complexion of the snake girl. They looked like they were already about to plan their escape, having realized they were in a very perilous situation.

"I was being chased here by enemies of the Chosen," Miranda said, quickly pouncing on the opportunity to remove the elites from the United Cities Alliance. "They aim to kill me and hurt the Chosen through that."

This got a response out of the snake, who turned her head to the party of five.

Mahowny instantly raised his hands in defense. "This is all a misunderstanding. I—"

He didn’t get further. Miranda wasn’t sure what happened, but one moment he was talking, and the next, there was no head on his shoulders. The movement had been too fast for her to see. It wasn’t even certain if it was teleportation or just incredibly fast movement.

"Did you know that humans have these unwanted movements in their aura when they lie?” the snake said in an insidious voice. It looked like she hadn’t even moved as she stood there with a severed head, parts of the spine hanging out. “I learned that from the ones I acquired to perfect this human form.”

Her rhetorical question did not have a chance to be answered as movements came from below. The aura of the Alabaster Snake had completely masked them. Three C-grade snakes shot up from the water, and within less than five seconds, the hounds and human party were all dead.

Miranda could only stand there and stare as it happened. She had hoped for assistance, but the response had been prompt and unexpectedly harsh. There was no questioning or doubt in the snake; she had simply acted and wiped them out unceremoniously.

She saw that Hank looked incredibly worried, and Neil’s party still had defensive positions. Sloppy ones, as they all knew that if any of the snakes that had just appeared chose to attack, none of them would survive.

Are these the "friends" Jake talked about? Miranda asked herself, already knowing the answer. He had mentioned it so casually, like it was no big deal… but the snake in front of them was far more powerful than anything she could have imagined.

The three C-grade snakes that had appeared were all far larger than the small and delicate-looking Alabaster Snake, but they all showed respect to her and bowed before ducking their heads underwater once more, dragging the corpses along with them.

"Humans are really questionable," the snake said with scorn before looking at Miranda. "Ah, but not you. Just the normal humans, if you know what I mean. Anyway! You said you are here because of the Forefather’s Chosen? Why are you here if he is not?"

Miranda was not sure what to answer, but she quickly read the mood and emotional state of the powerful C-grade. "There is a conflict going on right now, and the Chosen is preoccupied with handling other matters, including an enemy Chosen that serves a god who is antagonistic towards your Forefather. Due to this, the city I managed for him could no longer properly protect itself, and he asked us to go here."

The snake listened attentively before tilting her head. "But why here?"

Miranda smiled, happy the C-grade had asked. "Because he trusts that you can keep us safe while he is gone."

The snake reacted a bit more strongly than Miranda had expected. With starry eyes, the snake clenched her fists and put on a massive smile that looked more than a little odd. "Re… Really? He trusts me?"

"If not, he would not send us here," Miranda promptly answered. "It is truly my pleasure to meet a confidant of the Chosen. As I said before, my name is Miranda Wells. May I ask what your name is?"

Miranda had to admit that a cold shiver ran down her spine as she asked the question. If Jake had met this snake, there was a chance he had also given her a name, and no matter how dumb it was, she didn’t doubt the female snake—given her personality—would be all giddy and proud of it. She swore that if he had named the snake Snakie or Scaley or anything like that, she would be unable to hold her poker face and would smack him over the head the moment they met again, Chosen or not.

"A name?" the snake asked, still all happy about what Miranda had said. "I sadly do not have one of those. Most simply call me by my race, as I am the only one in these parts. You can refer to me as it, too, if you so desire."

It was almost funny to see how the female snake now tried to act all professional, as though she were welcoming guests into her humble abode. Which was exactly what she did in her mind, Miranda reckoned.

"Please follow me back to the center of the mangrove," the Alabaster Snake said. “Ah, we even have a few humans there, and lodging for your kind.”

"Really?" Miranda asked with genuine surprise. Humans living in a C-grade-infested danger zone? She had a hard time seeing that.

"Yep, you will see when we get there," the snake girl said, smiling. She looked towards the water for a moment before the three large snakes emerged again. Alongside them, a wooden barge had also appeared, seemingly out of nowhere. "Get on for a quicker trip. Ah, did you know the Chosen rode it too? We helped him the last time he was here, and he was so nice."

"I can imagine," Miranda said, having to fake her smile a little. How in the hell did Jake end up making friends with nearly every monster he didn’t just kill? Heck, even the ones he killed, he somehow ended up making friends with posthumously, as in the case of the Fallen King.

She and the others got on the barge and traversed the Grand Mangrove River far faster than expected. The snake girl ended up joining them on the barge and was incredibly talkative once she learned everyone there had met Jake before. Neil was the first to truly reciprocate, curiously asking about the area and the odd spatial fluctuations he felt.

It turned out that the mangrove forest truly was a mysterious place. The water was far, far deeper than it should have any right to be. It was likely spatially expanded somehow, and so were some areas of the Grand Mangrove River in general. Small clearings from a distance could turn into large, open areas once one entered them and vice versa.

The place they were being taken to was one such clearing. It was close to the center of the Grand Mangrove River and the lair of the Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake. Miranda also learned along the way that the snakes had pretty much fully taken over the entire Grand Mangrove River, having hunted down all powerful C-grades that could prove to be threats. The rest, they had left alive, effectively to fatten them up for future slaughter.

It didn’t take them long before they reached their destination, and Miranda was astonished when she saw it. After entering a clearing, the area opened up and revealed what looked like a massive, clear lake with sunlight coming down from above. Floating barges and platforms with buildings filled the clearing, making it look like a small city had been constructed.

Miranda saw well over a hundred people walking on the barges, and there was clearly too much space for the number of people. She also noticed something else… The moment they appeared, all the humans rushed out of their homes and sat down on their knees at the edge of the barges, many of them shivering.

"How come these people are here?" Miranda couldn’t help but ask.

"Oh, I had them brought here,” the snake said. “Humans who tried to pass the river but were captured. After the Chosen was here, I realized that I didn’t truly understand the world or the humans, so I decided to get some. While humans are dumb, they can also know a lot. Oh, I even got this form after studying humans a whole bunch!" She shared this last bit with a big smile.

"So, they are staying here against their wills?" Hank asked curtly. Miranda threw him a glance to shut up, but the snake had already heard him.

"Well, I brought them here against their wills, but I guess they can try and leave? Not that I see them making it out without getting eaten or recaptured.” The Alabaster Snake laughed, clearly finding it funny.

"I see," Miranda said before anyone else could speak. "Could you please bring us to a place where we can relax? We have been on the move for a long time."

"Of course!" the snake girl said enthusiastically. "I prepared a special place in case the Chosen returned! Humans are really good at making things; I will admit that."

Miranda nodded along, glad to have everyone else stashed away. She had a feeling that the snake girl wasn’t going to leave them alone, though, so she would bite the bullet and handle the C-grade. She feared what any of the others could say, and if the snake got mad for just a single second, it could tear any of them apart.

"If you are interested in learning more about the Chosen, I am more than willing to share,” Miranda said. “In fact, I will have to contact him soon using one of my skills, and you are more than free to come along. I can even relay a message.”

"Really?" the snake asked with glee. "I would love to!"

She was almost swaying with happiness as she sat there, and it bought Miranda enough time to get the others off the barge and into a mansion-like building that did not look like it should be able to float. Once they were all gone, Miranda and the Alabaster Snake headed towards another large, unoccupied building for Miranda to finally get back to Jake.

And probably have an incredibly long conversation with an overly enthusiastic, highly erratic, and extremely dangerous C-grade snake.

While waiting for Miranda to get back to him, hopefully having reached the mangrove forest safely and met up with the albino snake, Jake decided to have some fun.

One of the things Jake liked the most about new skills was the honeymoon period. He remembered when he had just gotten One Step Mile or Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter, and the fun time he’d had experimenting and using the skills for the first time, truly pushing them to their limits.

Relentless Hunt, as Jake had chosen to shorten yet another overly long skill name to, was a skill he naturally also looked forward to having fun with. There was much to figure out, and Jake went in with glee as he stood before a large bear. A large bear breathing fire. Oh, and there was lava coming out of its mouth at all times, and even some running down its hide.

Finally, it was about the size of a warehouse.

[Emberdust Magmabear – lvl ???]

Jake estimated it to be around level 210, and it was probably the strongest C-grade he’d faced so far in pure power—though he had a feeling he was facing a good matchup. Observing it from afar, he saw it bathe in a volcano and then soak in the sunlight for a few minutes before eating some metal out of a mountain. Not a single creature dared get close. Sandy had told him that something good was hidden within the lava of the volcano, and the worm acted all coy like it was doing him a favor, while Jake knew Sandy just wanted whatever was in that damn lava.

Now, while this was undoubtedly a fight, it was also a journey of exploration. A chance for Jake to see what he was truly capable of. An opportunity to fully explore his new skill and learn its limitations and when it was best used.

The massive beast looked like it could give him just that opportunity.

Jake engaged it from afar with a fully charged Arcane Powershot, blasting a hole in its body right off the bat. The blood that came out was thick and burned like lava, but the Hemotoxin Jake had poisoned the arrow with infected it nevertheless. His Sense of the Malefic Viper also made him aware the poison worked as intended, proving it was truly a being of flesh and blood despite its appearance.

As his strike hit and the bear roared, Jake also felt it right away. Odd energy welled up inside of him, and it even seemed to now exist in the atmospheric mana—always there, yet unable to be seen before now. He knew right away it was this Hunting Momentum.

He did not hesitate to pour just a little bit of it into his second attack. The bear tanked the hit just like the first, and Jake did notice the effect. The Hunting Momentum was not a concept or an idea like Stealth Attack or even the Mark of the Avaricious Hunter, which just added extra damage. It made all aspects of the attack stronger. The arrow flew faster, penetrated deeper, and dealt more damage, and even the poison on it appeared to have a slightly heightened potency. The momentum’s effect on the poison was slight, and Jake noticed it was also brief.

Several more attacks were released as the bear charged, leaving a path of lava behind it. The ground itself erupted, shooting up lava towards Jake and forcing him to retreat. The bear was incredibly durable, and even as he inflicted injury after injury, it was still barely affected. It also quickly became clear Jake was not the only one "building momentum," so to say.

The bear was heating up. Its very skin began to glow red as its lava-like blood boiled, and it soon began to give off an orange mist that burned the very air. This mist spread quickly and was carried by the wind. The mist emanated like a shockwave when the bear roared, combusting any time it encountered a physical object and setting that unlucky object on fire.

Jake retreated further and further as he kept attacking from range. His arrows flew through the mist, and to his annoyance, he noticed that it burned off the poison, but the arrows themselves—the stable versions, at least—managed to survive.

His opponent was far larger than him, but also far slower. As long as Jake kept his distance and bombarded it with ranged destruction, his Hunting Momentum and Arcane Charge from the Mark would build, and the poison he did manage to land would accumulate. He had a feeling this kind of beast was one that excelled in battles of attrition, simply outlasting and slowly burning down its foe. Too bad it had met Jake.

No, too bad Sandy had decided the worm really wanted to eat its treasure.

Looks like we are in for a long one, Jake thought as he smirked to himself. He was definitely not complaining.

Chapter 34

Taking Status & Making Plans

Jake breathed heavily as he stared out at the vast landscape before him. The remnants of the battle. An area the size of a semi-large city was scorched and burned, and in the middle of it all lay a giant beast, its very blood only adding to this environmental destruction. Even in death, its blood burned the ground, having retained the same destructive properties.

The final attack of the bear had been quite something. It had exploded and released an attack reminding him a bit of the Scorched Plains attack from the bow he’d lost when the Sword Saint cut it in two at the finale of their duel.

Seeing this destruction made him reflect a bit. During the vision with Palate Jake had seen, Villy and the C-grade fighter had ended up destroying a massive city and the surrounding environment, and Jake did have to confess he had wondered why he felt so far from being able to do that despite approaching C-grade himself.

This fight gave a bit of insight into how close he was actually getting. If he truly wanted, he could cause absolutely massive destruction with his arcane energies. The thing is, he didn’t, as that was a waste of energy.

Villy had mentioned this before and said that massive, flashy attacks that caused widespread destruction were not proof of strength, but proof of horrible control. Now, some attacks did get big due to their naturally chaotic nature, and a part of the attack’s power lay in pushing yourself beyond your limits of control, but this was only the case for rare attacks that often couldn’t be used more than once a fight.

No, rather than making a large explosion that covered a large area, it was better to make a far more intense explosion in a small area. That way, as long as you hit, the attack would deal way more damage. Someone should really have taught the bear that, as it was certainly a victim of making huge, flashy attacks… Then again, what if it was used to only fighting massive foes like itself? In that case, large attacks were probably more effective.

Anyway. The fight had taken nearly an entire hour, and Jake was all the happier for it. Because oh, boy, did he have some data on Relentless Hunt.

Firstly, on the accumulation of Hunting Momentum. While Jake was fighting or even just observing his enemy, preparing to fight it, the momentum would build. While in the tracking and observation phase, it was incredibly slow—dozens of times slower than when he was actually fighting. During the fight itself, the Hunting Momentum would accumulate passively, but the speed at which this happened varied.

If Jake landed blows and did damage, it would speed up, while it would slow down or even halt entirely if Jake was hit, with the slowdown based on the severity of his injuries. If it halted or slowed down, it would slowly pick itself up again as time passed and he kept avoiding blows, while it would speed up very quickly if he began to land attacks.

That was how the accumulation worked. Now for the actual effects of the Hunting Momentum.

The first thing here was the maximum amount he could have at any time. It was natural to have a cap, because if not, couldn’t Jake just silently observe a peak C-grade for a year or two, build up an utterly insane amount of Hunting Momentum, and then proceed to launch an arrow that could break the moon in half?

Yeah, so it made sense there was one. However, this is not to say the cap was low, because one had to remember one detail: The maximum was determined by his Perception. All parts of the skill were determined by his Perception. And if there was one thing Jake had a lot of, it was Perception.

Now, Jake did not know what the expected cap of Hunting Momentum was, but he felt like his was quite a bit higher than that. A lot higher. He had managed to cap it out during the fight because he’d tried to not use it, then released a single attack that expended all of it. This brings us to the actual effects of the skill.

The effect was varied based on the attack it was applied to. It wasn’t just a percentage amplifier, but in some ways, it still kind of was. Jake could not turn a normal stable arrow into an arrow of certain doom, but percentage-wise, the benefits of Hunting Momentum were greater than Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. Overall, though, Jake would say Hunting Momentum was best used with his already-powerful attacks, because, holy hell, had that Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter been powerful.

When Jake had used the Hunting Momentum, he’d felt the oversized, wood-like arrow almost thrum with the concept. Like an invisible wind embracing it, he had felt the power within. Further using Arcane Powershot had only made it stronger, and when he let go of the string, it had flown forward faster than anything Jake had ever shot before. It seemed unimpeded by anything, and even the remnant destructive arcane energy left by Arcane Powershot was empowered, allowing it to pass unbothered through the combusting mist.

It had hit the bear before it could even react, and the giant beast had been blasted back, lifting it off its feet and launching it several hundred meters backward. It had survived but been heavily injured, and Jake had finished it off shortly after that. As for how much stronger it made the attack percentage-wise, Jake couldn’t tell for sure… but it was significant. It wasn’t just the increased damage that mattered; it was the increased speed, the increased energy around the attack, and the momentum, which made it more penetrative and more resilient to getting whittled down by barriers or domains.

He had also discovered one other major thing: The momentum worked on an "attack," which came with both some good and some bad traits. Good traits? A melee strike counted as an attack. This did not just mean the attack did more damage, but once more that it was also faster. His punching motion simply sped up, allowing him to truly take his opponent by surprise. It meshed very well with his counter-style.

Bad traits from it working only with attacks? Touch of the Malefic Viper did not work with it at all, as it was not classified as an attack. Activating his Arcane Charge from Mark did not count, because, again, not an attack. Activating or amplifying a poison using Touch also didn’t work. Moving to block, even with the intent to counter, did not work, even if the counterattack follow-up was affected.

Anyway, there were more things to the skill, but Jake believed he would have ample time to use it moving forward. He and Sandy had made plans, and those plans included a lot of killing during their travel. But to fully carry out their plan, Jake would need to talk to Miranda first.

Speaking of Sandy, the worm had decided that eating all the lava in the volcano was also a necessity, so he was stuck waiting even more for the hungry worm to finish up. Waiting anyway, Jake chose to take a look at his full status for the first time in a while.

Status

Name: Jake Thayne

Race: [Human (D) – lvl 183]

Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter – lvl 181]

Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper – lvl 185]

Health Points (HP): 30251/55140

Mana Points (MP): 30279/104437

Stamina: 10938/50240

Stats

Strength: 4689

Agility: 7656

Endurance: 5024

Vitality: 5514

Toughness: 4129

Wisdom: 6684

Intelligence: 5814

Perception: 11867

Willpower: 5709

Free Points: 0

Titles: [Forerunner of the New World], [Bloodline Patriarch], [Holder of a Primordial’s True Blessing], [Dungeoneer VIII], [Dungeon Pioneer VI], [Legendary Prodigy], [Prodigious Slayer of the Mighty], [Kingslayer], [Nobility: Earl], [Progenitor of the 93rd Universe], [Prodigious Arcanist], [Perfect Evolution (D-grade)], [Premier Treasure Hunter], [Myth Originator], [Progenitor of Myriad Paths]

Class Skills: [Basic Shadow Vault of Umbra (Uncommon)], [Traditional Hunter’s Tracking (Rare)], [Arcane Stealth (Rare)], [Superior Stealth Attack (Rare)], [Enhanced Splitting Arrow (Rare)], [Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter (Epic)], [Arcane Powershot (Epic)], [Big Game Arcane Hunter (Epic)], [Arcane Hunter’s Arrows (Epic)], [Archery of Expanding Horizons (Epic)], [Descending Dark Arcane Fang (Epic)], [Fangs of Man (Ancient)], [Mark of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter (Ancient)], [Moment of the Primal Hunter (Legendary)], [Gaze of the Apex Hunter (Legendary)], [Steady Focus of the Apex Hunter (Legendary)], [Arcane Awakening (Legendary)], [One Step, Thousand Miles (Legendary)], [Relentless Hunt of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter (Legendary)]

Profession Skills: [Path of the Heretic-Chosen (Unique)], [Herbology (Common)], [Brew Potion (Common)], [Alchemist’s Purification (Common)], [Alchemical Flame (Uncommon)], [Craft Elixir (Uncommon)], [Toxicology (Uncommon)], [Cultivate Toxin (Uncommon)], [Concoct Poison (Rare)], [Malefic Viper’s Poison (Epic)], [Soul Ritualism of the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist (Ancient)], [Advanced Core Manipulation (Ancient)], [Blood of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)], [Sagacity of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)], [Sense of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)], [Wings of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Touch of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Legacy Teachings of the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist (Legendary)], [Palate of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Pride of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Scales of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Fangs of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Anomalous Soul of the Heretic-Chosen (Legendary)]

Blessing: [True Blessing of the Malefic Viper (Blessing - True)]

Race Skills: [Endless Tongues of the Myriad Races (Unique)], [Legacy of Man (Unique)], [Identify (Common)], [Serene Soul Meditation (Epic)], [Shroud of the Primordial (Divine)]

Bloodline: [Bloodline of the Primal Hunter (Bloodline Ability - Unique)]

--

Looking through it, Jake mostly took notice of the ever-expanding length, but what also stood out were the many rarities, especially in his class. While for many, an epic skill would be considered excellent, to Jake, it felt lackluster by now. The rare and below skills were even worse. Enhanced Splitting Arrow was one he often used yet had not upgraded since shortly after reaching D-grade, and despite it being a common attack in his arsenal, it was still only rare. Arcane Powershot was his go-to archery skill, and that was also only epic rarity. He could excuse himself for not upgrading Shadow Vault, as he had sim-Jake on that, and his tracking skill was also one he felt like he would upgrade when the time was right, but he felt like he really needed to work on many of the others before evolving. At least his core skills needed to be refined and upgraded.

All more tasks he would take this coming hunting period to address. He had a feeling that many of the skills wouldn’t even necessarily be that difficult to upgrade as long as he consciously tried to do so. He had already refined many of the skills significantly just by using them often, so with a bit more effort and some experimentation, it should be possible to at least get a few good upgrades in.

As Jake was considering all these things, he suddenly felt a small nudge. He instantly smiled and responded. "Miranda? Good to finally hear from you. Did you arrive at the Grand Mangrove River safely?"

"Don’t worry—we got here safely," Miranda answered promptly. "We were saved by a certain snake that you seem to know. One with a humanoid form resembling a young girl or woman. Is that something you might know about?"

Jake thought for a moment before frowning. "Does not ring a bell… Wait, is the race of the snake Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake?"

"Yes."

"Oh, damn, and she already got a human form? That is actually impressive," Jake said in admiration. "I knew she was talented just due to her high level, but it seems like I underestimated her. Maybe the Blessing also helped, but I reckon it is mostly her effort."

It was the truth, too. One thing Jake had learned about monsters while he researched the Pollendust Bee Queen was that their abilities to make use of natural treasures varied widely, and were highly dependent on the talent and ability of the monster to actually refine and make use of these treasures. A bit like how one craftsman could turn a pile of ingots into a legendary sword, while a far less skilled smith would only be able to make it epic.

Other factors like compatibility with the treasure also factored in, but talent and skill were considerable elements. The most important skill was naturally energy control to properly absorb a treasure, and as with many things, good energy control carried over and also mattered when it came to using the universal Polymorph skill all monsters got at C-grade. Villy had told him that it often took years for a beast to properly design and refine its humanoid forms to be usable. So for the Crimsoneye Snake to do it in only a few months? Very impressive.

Oh, on a side note, Jake had no idea how good Sandy was at energy control or absorbing treasures. Not that it seemed to matter, as the glutton would just make up for it with quantity.

"I should mention the snake is currently listening in and very pleased by your assessment," Miranda answered. "I was told to relay that she very much appreciates your praise and would gladly welcome you to visit if you ever get the time. Not those exact words, but that is the sentiment, at least. She very much wants you to visit."

"Alright. Keep up the good work, both of you. I will definitely visit when I come to get you and the others after all this is over. Now, can you tell me a bit of what happened after I was thrown away? Give me the downlow."

Miranda proceeded to give Jake a description of all that had happened recently. How the snake had killed the pursuers from the United Cities Alliance, how Ell’Hakan had not wanted to kill her but warn her, and even how Arnold had contacted Miranda using one of his communication devices to say that Ell’Hakan was still staking it out near Haven, likely waiting for Jake to return.

Jake considered all this and began asking some things of his own. He knew Miranda had ways to contact the Sword Saint and many others around the world. She had said that the old man was missing in action after presumably getting ambushed in his residence, but Jake didn’t put much stock in it. There was no scenario where he saw that old monster dying to a bunch of goons, even if they were the top elites of Ell’Hakan.

Which begged the question… Why attack him without using their full force? The answer was simple: They didn’t know how strong he actually was. One had to remember that the only time the Sword Saint had revealed his full power was during the duel at the end of the Treasure Hunt, and only a handful of people had been present then, none of whom would’ve shared it publicly.

Miranda agreed with Jake’s assessment and even added to it. People did know a duel had taken place, but only the "result."

The result being that the Sword Saint was apparently crippled for a long time afterward. In reality, he had simply been recovering from using his Transcendence, but in the eyes of the world, he had lost and taken grievous injuries. That is at least what Miranda believed the public interpretation was, and Ell’Hakan was right about one thing: If enough people believed something, it became accepted as the truth.

Jake knew that he himself was not some grand strategist, and neither was Miranda, but they didn’t need some perfect plan either. They just needed a plan that was good enough and relied on things they knew Ell’Hakan could not predict. Gaps in his knowledge.

"Say, the Fallen King and that other Unique Lifeform are still engaged in some kind of battle, right?" Jake asked Miranda.

"Yes, according to what I was able to gather, they were still locked in a standstill," Miranda answered.

Jake nodded and considered for a bit. "I have an idea."

If there was one thing Jake was certain of, it was that Ell’Hakan expected a rematch with Jake. The man likely believed Jake was the only human on Earth that stood a chance against him, with all C-grades locked away. The only other entity who could threaten him would then be the Fallen King or maybe Sylphie, but Sylphie was far removed from Haven.

So Jake’s plan relied on one simple concept.

Just don’t fight him.

He shared his idea, and Miranda seemed somewhat receptive, even if there were things to refine. They talked for a while longer until Miranda made him aware the Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake had left, finally prompting her to ask, "Jake, just to make sure, you have not named this snake yet? Not even in your own head?"

"No?" Jake said with confusion. But he soon got it and smiled. "If you want me to think of a name, just ask, and I wi—"

"Definitely not. Actually, wait… No, do think of a name, but I have sole discretion when it comes to accepting it or not, alright? And promise me not to share your name ideas with anyone else but me until the choice is final, alright?"

"I guess?" Jake answered, thinking she was overdoing it. He had gotten better at naming things; one just had to look at Sandy. Sandy was a real name! That was definitely an improvement, right?

Unluckily, Jake did not have more time to talk before his ride arrived to eat him up once more. Jake said his temporary goodbyes to Miranda, forgetting to mention his "faster way back than expected" was within the stomach of a massive C-grade worm and going on his merry way.

For his plan to succeed—or for any plan to become more probable—he needed two things: levels and power.

It was power-hunting time.

Chapter 35

Schemers

Across the planet, the chaos brought on by the United Cities Alliance and Ell’Hakan continued. Beasts attacked like never before, and millions died within only a week as many settlements fell, unprepared and too weak to resist. Those who held on still took losses, and the survivors all had a newfound hatred. The work that had been made to establish positive relations between monsters and humanity was thoroughly broken.

The problem was that people did not see the actions of beasts as those of individuals, but those of a monolith. A tribe. They put all monsters in a box and vilified them in their minds as aggressors. This was not much different from what humans had done to other humans before the system. People loved to hate others, and it was just easier to hate an entire religion, country, or appearance than recognize that each person was an individual making their own choices.

And this feeling was reciprocated by the monsters.

They, too, viewed humanity as something they wanted to wipe out. Their reasons varied, but their goal was the same. Some saw humans as destroyers, a scourge on the planet, having ruined their natural habitats before the systems. Others had been mistreated and abused by humans all their lives. A small part just looked down on humans as weak and pathetic creatures not worth keeping alive. Others still did not truly care much; they just wanted to hunt without restrictions. As with any good hate group, they didn’t need a unified ideology, just shared hatred.

With every beast that killed a human, humanity’s hatred of beasts grew. With every human that killed a beast, the beasts’ resentment of humanity grew. One would maybe think that monsters getting angry at humans killing beasts while defending themselves wasn’t fair, but how was it different from what humans usually did?

Human hunting parties entered the territory of monsters often. They killed hundreds of beasts or elementals or whatever they came across that gave them experience before retreating to their cities. It was so normalized no one questioned it. The monsters certainly didn’t, as fighting and the law of the jungle were just the rules of the multiverse.

What they did question was the Fallen King then coming and trying to tell them they had to leave all human settlements alone. Leaving some alone was fine, but all of them? Would the humans have accepted the same terms? A unilateral ban from entering monster territory and hunting them within their homes?

The answer was no.

This was not a question of right or wrong but simply reality. Humans and monsters both needed to kill to progress, and humans had a tendency to want to avoid killing other humans, making them target monsters instead. This was how the universe had worked for eras, and there would never truly be peace between all the different races. Especially when the enlightened races kept their sense of superiority, thinking the life of a human or elf was more valuable than that of a beast. War and conflict were simply inevitable.

Unless, of course, a powerful enough influence could make humanity and all monsters back down and search for prey beyond their own planet.

Miyamoto felt the token in his spatial storage vibrate once more and decided to take it out this time. He had chosen to wait out and assess the situation before making any further moves, but it appeared it was time to discuss their circumstances.

"Ms. Wells, to what do I owe the pleasure?" he answered, allowing her to take the initiative.

"It pleases me to know you are doing well, Sword Saint,” she said. “To the world, you are still considered missing in action and potentially dead.”

"I am aware," he answered as he smiled to himself. "And it is intentional. So please, do me a favor and keep it as such."

"Alright?" Ms. Wells said with some confusion. "May I know what happened after you were presumably attacked?"

"A fight, followed by information," the Sword Saint answered, remembering what had happened.

Two powerful individuals charged at him. The Sword Saint had his blade ready as they circled him. Both of them were melee combatants like him, and from their small initial clash, he became fully aware they would not be easily taken down.

One of them wielded two blades of ice, while the other was a pure fighter without any obvious magical characteristics. Seeing the opponent using ice magic, he quickly realized these people were aware of his abilities. One of the greatest counters to water was not extreme heat, but extreme cold. It would make his attacks rigid and impede the flow. This opponent was here to counter him directly; that much was evident.

Flanked on each side, he blocked one as he stepped back to avoid the blow of the other. His original assessment that they were about as strong as the Judge from the Court of Shadows was correct. The difference was that they were both already using their boosting skills, wanting to finish this battle quickly, and even if that made their strength explosive, it was far from the level of the Judge when he went all out. They were more at the level of his usual fighting strength.

Blades of ice began to revolve around him as the ice swordsman took a step back, and the other engaged with a curved sword in each hand. The man’s speed was impressive, and the Sword Saint was forced to block until one of the ice blades attacked from behind. Angling himself a bit, he was hit in the lower part of his back. A non-vital area.

He only activated his boosting skill at a low level. His opponents still attacked with an upper hand as they pushed themselves to their extremes. The Sword Saint took injury after injury as trump cards were revealed from the other side, and soon enough, he was blasted back, his left arm severed.

"We expected more," one of them said as he approached with the tip of his ice blade pointed at the Sword Saint. Injured and a bit tired, but otherwise fine. The man had continually frozen and interrupted Miyamoto’s magic, stopping his attacks for the other side to get the advantage.

"Why are you even doing this?” the Sword Saint asked with heaving breaths. “The Noboru Clan is not part of any religious faction. We are an independent force. Would the United Cities Alliance not want us on their side?"

"No one cares about your pathetic little clan," the other attacker spoke. "You are the only one worth killing here. With you gone, they will fall into shambles, and we are already aware of the internal struggles your family faces. It won’t be hard to convince them to back the alliance with their Patriarch dead and gone."

The Sword Saint nodded before answering with gusto, "I will never let that happen!"’

He released a massive wave of water that pushed back the two of them, temporarily allowing him to escape their sights and retreat. The old man ran through the plains, but he was simply too slow. A blade of ice flew from behind and hit him in the shin, making him fall over. He rolled to the side to avoid the non-magical warrior’s scimitar but still took a nasty cut. In a final gamble, he tried to take one of them down with him, but he was too slow. He managed to cut the shoulder of the ice warrior but was stabbed in the heart by a scimitar. The old man tried to do something, but before he could, the second scimitar swept up and severed his head.

"Got the notification?" the ice warrior asked.

"Yes," the second warrior said, nodding.

Acknowledging, the ice warrior took out a token and seemed to communicate through it. A few seconds passed before he smiled. "It has been conveyed. Let’s get out of here before—"

The corpse of the old man suddenly moved, a spear appearing in his hand. The second warrior was stabbed in the back as his eyes opened wide. The corpse quickly stood up and healed, a head regrowing and his body changing. Rather than an old man, a figure with red eyes and black hair stood there. He smiled, showing off his fangs.

Swiftly, the ice warrior took out the token again, but before he could relay anything, his arm flew into the air, still holding the token. He screamed as he turned and saw the Sword Saint standing there, an arm still missing but otherwise unharmed.

The ice warrior tried to retaliate, but the old man bent his knees and spoke,

"Thousand Waves Slash."

A wall of ice appeared, but the Sword Saint cut through it like paper and blasted the the warrior back. He then followed up and landed several blows before cutting off the head of the man he identified as a nahoom. Turning to the other warrior, who was struggling with the former Monarch of Blood, he quickly went over and teamed up, cutting off the man’s legs and arms.

After knocking him out but keeping him alive, the Sword Saint looked at the former Monarch, who sat down on the grass, breathing heavily.

"Who would have thought me acting as your doppelganger for so long would come into play like this?" Iskar, the former Monarch of Blood, said.

Miyamoto and Iskar had, for a long time, acted together. Both were old souls and had a lot in common, with Iskar having a wealth of knowledge stashed away in his head. He did not remember everything, but with time, the former A-grade recalled details. His existence was an interesting one due to its link with the Divine item left by Sanguine, but he was a full-fledged lifeform when outside of it—and not a weak one, either.

His skillset was incredibly vast and varied, including high-level illusion magic coupled with hypnosis. Enough to fool the two attackers into thinking they had actually killed Miyamoto.

"Let us leave," the Sword Saint said as he saw movement from the direction of the Noboru Clan. He planned on staying dead in the eyes of the public, and leaving behind only one unrecognizable corpse should keep up the illusion, at least for a time.

Moreover, leaving just one corpse meant he had a prisoner—a prisoner likely holding a lot of valuable information.

Miyamoto explained this to Ms. Wells, not believing there was a need to keep it a secret from her. Jake trusted her, and so far, she had shown herself worthy of that trust.

"I don’t understand why you need to fake your own death even to your clan… Do you fear it would leak if they knew?" the City Lord of Haven asked.

"Yes and no,” the Sword Saint answered. “The main reason is quite a bit more straightforward. The Noboru Clan is not truly a faction, but just people rallying behind me; at least, it has begun to feel like that. They require me to be their Patriarch to continue their existence and rely on me far too much. Moreover, there have been more internal struggles as we have grown. There were even those pushing to join the United Cities Alliance. So I wish to see how the clan will act when I am believed dead. I want to see if the clan is worthy of keeping alive as it currently is, or if I will have to reconsider my approach.”

Miyamoto had considered it for a long time. After his duel with Jake in the Treasure Hunt, he’d realized he needed to be more selfish and truly pursue what he cared about. His power would be the power of the clan, but it had become too much. They had begun to treat him as more than an elder. However, he still did not want to rule the clan with an iron fist. He could have, but he wanted autonomy and for himself to have some freedom. He wanted to know his clan would not crumble if he was to die.

After a bit, Ms. Wells said, "There is bound to be an internal struggle… and with the recent beast attacks, many will die. The Noboru Clan may not survive without you."

"Death and life are simple realities of the system," Miyamoto explained. “No faction is not built upon a mountain of corpses, and should the Noboru Clan fall simply due to my absence, then as much as it pains me, I must recognize it is unworthy of existing. Even if it ceases to be, our heritage will not. However, should the clan come out whole, it will be stronger than ever.”

"I see," she simply answered, recognition in her voice. She seemed to understand.

"Now, Ms. Wells, I do not believe you contacted me only for an exchange of information. I have interrogated one of my ambushers and learned of their plans to make Arthur the World Leader, as well as Ell’Hakan’s desire to defeat Jake. From what you tell me, Jake also seems to have a plan, so please, do share. What do you intend to do to handle this Ell’Hakan? He seems like a tricky one to deal with.”

"So, Jake proposes to…"

She explained, and the Sword Saint could not help but smile after she was done. It was simple, and it gave the Sword Saint something he would very much like. Hence, he was more than on board. "It shall be my honor and privilege."

Vilastromoz observed as Jake began his hunting spree, not wanting to interrupt. He was busy with his own matters anyway, as he also had to make preparations for what was to come. This was part of the reason he had not contacted Jake for a while, though the primary one was that he was unsure how Jake would react. The god had to be honest… feeling genuine worry about how someone else would react was something he hadn’t felt in a long time, and he had kind of missed it.

The Viper would lie if he said he didn’t feel a slight level of responsibility for what was happening, but he would equally be lying if he said he didn’t think this conflict was a good thing. Strife would push one forward, and a slight level of urgency could be healthy at times. Not that he feared Jake would become complacent—he seemed to still have the same internal drive for progressing that he’d the day they met, but it could help speed him up without any negative consequences.

Simply forcing Jake to think a bit differently was good. He would meet many who were like Ell’Hakan, in that they didn’t have any interest in fighting him fairly but still wanted to make trouble for him. The Viper had had many such foes during his rise to power, and even now, he still had many such foes. He also understood that this entire conflict with Yip of Yore’s Chosen was entirely due to Jake being the Chosen of the Viper.

Yip and his Chosen relied on stories. Legends. It gave them power and made them progress, and the Viper saw the mirror image that was being made. Because he knew that Jake was not the only one being targeted in this conflict. While the Chosen wanted to fight and likely kill Jake to prove himself and his Path…

So did Yip of Yore aim to kill a Primordial to prove his. And Villy was his chosen target for that—a logical one, too. He was the perfect target, if he evaluated it a bit himself. Yip needed a villain, and the Viper was quite villainous when he wanted to be, if he had to say so himself. The Viper also knew that Yip was not doing this haphazardly. Everything was part of a greater framework. A larger story.

A grand epic, if you will.

Honestly, it made Vilastromoz somewhat sad he was targeted. Because while Yip and his Chosen were very similar, Jake and Vilastromoz were most certainly not. They were nearly exact opposites.

Jake preferred to face his opponents head-on. As for Vilastromoz? Well, so far, all he had done since returning from seclusion was handling his issues head-on. But this was not because he preferred to do it this way; it was just simpler and faster.

However, if he faced an opponent worth the effort?

That is why he found it sad that Yip had chosen him. Sad that people had forgotten who he truly was.

Because if Yip of Yore thought he was a meticulous planner, he had not met the schemer known as the Malefic Viper.

Chapter 36

Rebuilding & Lots of Killing

Countless factions dominated the multiverse, but few were as unique as the Risen. They were the living dead, and that came with both bonuses and demerits. Some bonuses included a natural lifespan equal to your True Soul’s natural lifespan, meaning you would live as long as possible, and aging would only come to pass due to the person wanting it. Combat-wise, they truly did not have many differences from other enlightened races, aside from some changed natural affinities and stats. They were neither stronger nor weaker, and history had also shown that their natural average level of talent was roughly comparable to that of humans and elves.

As for demerits, the largest inherent one was probably their inability to procreate naturally. Two Risen could not simply make a child. Instead, it took a far more complicated process. It was possible, mind you, but not as easy, and it required a specially created item that both would-be parents poured a part of their essence into. Even then, it wasn’t like an actual child would be born and grow up normally. They would be born in their full adult form, albeit with a nascent consciousness like that of a child.

Their other way to procreate was for others to willingly become Risen. However, this too was not as simple as some common misunderstandings and prejudices that existed in the multiverse had made it out to be. One of the most widespread beliefs was that the Risen could forcefully create more Risen by raising the dead.

It did not work like that. The only way for someone to become a Risen was to willingly accept to become one, and only while still alive. You had to participate in a ritual, during which the system would allow you to change. It always required the person to willingly choose, and the ritual would even fail if the individual taking part was being mentally manipulated in any form.

Sadly, many still thought the Risen could forcefully make more of themselves by killing others. True, they were talented in raising undead, but while the Risen were classified as undead, no raised undead could ever be classified as Risen or an enlightened species. They were all monsters, unable to possess a class or profession.

Most undead in the multiverse naturally hated the living and wanted to consume them. They were scourges and natural disasters more than anything. A beast or elemental would not choose to hunt down those significantly weaker than themselves for no reason. Meanwhile, an A-grade undead monster would gladly consume several planets with nothing more powerful than a C-grade on it just to kill everything there. This was also due to another trait of the undead: a lack of intelligence. They were, more often than not, acting on pure instinct, even when reaching S-grade.

So publicly making an enemy of the Risen for also being undead was easy as pie. And the Risen knew.

Casper and Priscilla had known it too, which was why they had planned for the eventuality that they would be pushed out of Earth from the very beginning. This was why they had wanted to create the dungeon, as it was part of their plan, and when the Treasure Hunt happened, they’d gotten the chance to get a damaged World Core by combining all the fragments they had found there.

It was a golden opportunity they had leapt at, and it had gone far better than expected. It had truly given them a path of survival far more viable than any of their other plans, and while Casper did admit he would miss Earth, he had no regrets.

Casper flew high in the air as he stared at the black skies with only a few clouds here and there. No stars were visible, but they would work on that with time. Down below were rolling hills of soil, and familiar grass was growing, identical to that of Yalsten.

Turning his head, he saw the edges of the realm and knew it was still slightly unstable. The usable area was only a few hundred square kilometers right now, but it would expand with time as everything stabilized. As the tree grew.

So, what had the Risen done?

They had made a new world using the World Core from the Treasure Hunt. One that now existed within the infinite void, like Yalsten, but this one was still linked to the 93rd Universe.

Each world had to be anchored somewhere in the real universe, or it would be forever lost in the infinite void—effectively killing everyone within, as they had no way in or out. Unless someone managed to become a god, that is, but chances of that were nonexistent. These anchors could be detected and destroyed by outside forces if they located them, dooming all who resided in the world. So the Risen had done something smart. Something classified as clever use of system mechanics.

The anchor had been placed within the cave they had then turned into a dungeon. This effectively made it inaccessible, since when the dungeon was created, a barrier would form that was impenetrable to nearly anyone. The way anchors worked meant that one could still get out, as the anchor was more of a coordinate, and if they wanted to teleport out, they just had to place the person a little to the side of this coordinate, thus having them outside. If they didn’t, the person would just appear within the cave, but oops… the cave was now the location of a dungeon, so the system would kindly relocate them just outside the dungeon entrance.

Oh, also, even if their world had been cut off, they still had one final failsafe: Casper himself. He carried the Blessing of the Blightfather, so even if they were lost within the infinite void, the Blightfather could use the Blessing as a beacon to locate them.

Casper could never claim this had been his own ingenious idea. It truly wasn’t something revolutionary either, as many factions had done this, and truth be told, there were still ways to mess them up. Just not for anyone on Earth. Not yet.

There was still the risk of Earth being taken over and them just becoming sitting ducks, which was when the other part of the plan came into effect. The Risen had worked on raising ghosts since the day they returned from the tutorial and made the city. Ghosts had a few properties, but one of them was that they were pure energy. Pure energy, and very effective rocket thrusters in large enough numbers.

That’s right—the dungeon that the Risen had made had already left Earth right after they evacuated everyone. The Holy Church had been too busy advancing to catch a large, spherical rock being lifted into the air by hundreds of thousands of ghosts. By the time they reacted, the sphere was already too high. Every single ghost had died during the ascent, and there’d been many risks—such as being stopped by beasts or the ghosts dying in the hazardous environment closer to the edge of the atmosphere—but they had made it.

Now they were nothing but a rock floating through space like another unsuspecting meteor. Currently, they had no direction or control, but with time they would. This world was one they would use long term, serving as one of the new major home bases of the Risen in the new universe.

With the former Root of Eternal Resentment planted and hopefully able to create a new tree, Casper was hopeful. They had the backing of the Blightfather and were currently working hard on a teleporter directly from the hidden world and to the Ghostlands, entirely circumventing the 93rd Universe and still giving them a place to go and progress.

Casper smiled as he saw Priscilla busy far below. Lyra appeared at his side, joining him to watch their new city slowly being constructed. They only had around a hundred thousand people with them, and space was a bit tight, but they would live. Live and prosper.

To commemorate where they had come from, they had also picked a very unoriginal but fitting name for their world:

New Yalsten.

Jake sat chilling on top of a massive tree as he stared out at the ocean in front of him. Sandy was busy eating an entire field of fruit trees, and Jake didn’t bother the worm as he smiled to himself. Life had been good.

By now, it had been about a month since he had his first talk with Miranda after she reached the Grand Mangrove River, and the thing that surprised him the most was that nothing had surprised him during this time. At least he did learn some stuff that explained things.

The Pylon of Civilization at Haven had been hidden even more than before. It had not been moved, but Miranda had created a decoy Pylon of sorts and placed it under her main office, sealed beneath her ritual chamber. She told him that she had felt people try to get to it, but nobody had succeeded yet. Jake had not even known about her doing this, but honestly, it made sense. Not even Ell’Hakan would think Jake had hidden the Pylon under his lodge in a nearly unprotected state.

They had also discussed Miranda talking with the Sword Saint and the old man being on board, having even faked his own death using the power of the former Monarch of Blood. However, she had failed to get in contact with Casper as the token he had was no longer reachable. He was still around, mind you, just out of range. Where he was, Miranda didn’t know, but from what they had learned, the territory of the Risen was effectively gone, having been successfully invaded by the Holy Church and United Cities Alliance. At least, that was the official story. Jake wasn’t entirely sure what to think after Miranda told him there was now a big hole in the ground where the Risen had once been.

Jake was sad to see Casper gone, but he should still be alive. Villy had at least told him that. Well, okay, not alive, technically, but still around.

Caleb had been suckered into working for the United Cities Alliance, and honestly, Jake didn’t really see the problem. He was just doing his job, and it wasn’t like what he did would hurt Jake or those he cared about. The Court of Shadows was a business, and Jake knew that Caleb refusing could only result in him having to leave the Court.

The Court of Shadows was what could be classified as a true neutral faction in that they only cared about money. Villy even mentioned that if Jake wanted to slap some fat stacks on the table, he could just hire them to also target the United Cities Alliance, including Arthur himself. However, there would be one thing holding them back in the future.

They had a rule against accepting the task of assassinating the leader or someone part of the leadership structure of a planet they operated on. This was simply a concession to allow them to stay on planets without conquering them themselves. Jake also reckoned this was why Arthur was fine with keeping them around. If the United Cities Alliance won and he became World Leader, they would not target him but only function as an asset operating out of Earth, as there was an element of deterrence if people knew the Court had a branch stationed somewhere.

So even if Jake was not a fan of what was happening, he understood why it was like that and wouldn’t blame Caleb for what he chose. He did what was best for his family—their family. Jake also knew that while his brother believed in him, it was best he made decisions for his nuclear family first and foremost. Maja and Jake’s little nephew were his priority, and if Jake somehow ended up dead or forced to leave the planet, Caleb needed the Court to back him.

It was all complicated. Valhal had also taken a complicated stance on the matter. One of absolute inaction. He was informed that they had been hired or brought on by several cities to help defend them from the attacking beasts, but that was it. Villy had once more talked with Jake and suggested they had an approach they could take if they wanted: offer them a deal too. But Jake had no interest in this either.

No, he had been thinking and was beginning to have some realizations. Some things he had to do if he wanted to stay on Earth or even be able to call it a home he could visit. Things to allow those he cared about to find safety there and not have it be what it currently was: a mixture of forces with era-old conflicts that would never get along, with some newborn factions tossed in that also vied for control. Jake would have to make some decisions.

Anyway, the Holy Church was also still acting all shady, and from what he had heard, they were planning something of their own. The Noboru Clan had fallen into shambles over the last month with lots of internal conflicts, and it was all messy as hell. Speaking of messy, even the Church apparently had problems, and Jake had not heard a single peep about or from Jacob. It was like he was gone. Then again, something must have happened, because he would definitely not have authorized an attack on the Risen.

Another person Jake had not seen or heard from was one other quite unique character on the planet: Eron. The now third person with a Bloodline residing on the planet after Ell’Hakan had arrived was notably absent from everything. Miranda had tried to figure out what was happening, but she had no idea… All she knew was that no one had seen him for quite a while.

Jake had been curious enough to ask Villy, only to get an unexpected response. Not even the Primordial had any idea where he was and found himself unable to locate him. People with Bloodlines were harder to find by default, but Villy clarified that he should still be locatable. Unless, of course, he had been hidden by someone at or around the level of Villy himself. It was enough to interest Villy and make him do some independent research, and what the Viper found out was that he was definitely gone from Earth, and likely from the 93rd Universe. As for where he had gone, along with all of his followers, Jake had no idea. Truth be told, Jake had never really talked with or about him that much outside of their brief interaction in the Treasure Hunt. Eron had just been doing his own thing until he was suddenly gone.

Oh, and as for the question of whether he was dead… Eron? Dead? Yeah, Jake definitely couldn’t see that happening, and his guts also told him the insane healer was still kicking.

To summarize, a lot had happened over the last month, and Jake could probably have been back in Haven already if he had wanted to. He had purposefully waited and wanted to make sure everyone was ready. He had even managed to get word to the Fallen King about his plans, with the Unique Lifeform now on board. Though the Fallen King also had apparently not at all been in a rush, oddly happy with the stalemate of facing another Unique Lifeform. Then again, how often could someone like the Fallen King find someone of equal level that was his equal? Well, every day, if he stayed around Jake. Not that Jake would bother to fight him all the time. He was too busy killing to just do fighting.

During this month, Jake had not slacked off at all. He did discover the oddity that it felt like he progressed faster again for some reason. In between killing C-grades or while waiting for Sandy to get a treasure, Jake would usually either talk with Miranda, recover from a fight, ponder on some issue, or do alchemy. Alchemy was what he did if none of the others were required, which is why he was surprised at getting three entire levels.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 186 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 187 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 184 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 188 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

A level every ten days from not even being that focused on alchemy was odd. Granted, Jake had primarily been crafting items and not really experimenting, but it was still a lot. Jake had even spent a bit of time checking in on sim-Jake and pondering how to get his last three "of the Malefic Viper" upgrades when he was meditating. No real progress there, though. Some initial ideas began to form, but he was not really that focused on them.

His true focus had been hunting and improving his class skills. As for how that had gone? Well, in the hunting department, the levels spoke for themselves.

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 182 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 193 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

And with that naturally came the race levels.

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 185 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 190 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Twelve levels gained in his class and three in his profession over a span of thirty or so days was incredibly good and nearly brought him back to his early D-grade days. Jake had been surprised several times at getting a level, even if he had killed a few dozen C-grades by now—C-grades more powerful than anything he had faced before.

Relentless Hunt was truly a powerful skill and gave Jake far more damage than he had initially expected. It allowed him to break stalemates, land unexpected blows, and far more easily control the flow of a battle. Moreover, the longer he kept the fight going, the larger his advantage became if he didn’t need to use the Hunting Momentum.

He was also beginning to realize that the skill was quite a bit stronger than it was meant to be. For several reasons. Its innate balance came from assuming one would still get hit once in a while, hence slowing the generation of Hunting Momentum. Something Jake was very good at avoiding due to his Bloodline.

Additionally, then, it was probably not intended for the person using it to have a Perception stat at the level of Jake’s. He had, of course, tossed every free point gained in it without any regrets and was now close to having 13,000 Perception, making it nearly as high as his two second-highest stats combined. Stats that were already highly inflated due to Jake’s many stat amplifiers.

Jake truly felt justified now in going so hard on Perception and proving all the naysayers wrong. Perception was, and would forever be, the best stat.

As for class skills… Jake had gone even further above and beyond expectations, and the results spoke for themselves.

Naturally, his success was partly due to his high Perception.

Because. Again.

Perception best stat.

Chapter 37

Chronicles of Skill Upgrades

Upgrading skills was always a difficult and time-consuming process. You had so much to evaluate and so much to do, and Jake’s method of upgrading was considered even harder than the standard approach. He insisted on only doing it during combat, and only reflected on how to upgrade the skills on a surface level in between fights.

This would usually be an incredibly ineffective, if not downright horrible method, as it carried so many more risks. Especially when you did this only while fighting enemies at a higher grade. However, to Jake, this added element of danger only made him focus more. It allowed him to truly feel and experience the movements of energy in a more profound way, and his senses felt sharpened. Probably because they partly were.

It was not a joke, either, when he said Perception was a big reason why he could upgrade the skills the way he did. Rather than take a long time experimenting and theorizing, he could feel and perceive the skills and how they worked, potentially finding snags and room for improvement, along with discovering potential areas to build upon for an upgrade. Perhaps more importantly, it allowed him to faster rule out dead ends and ideas that were too hard to pull off with his current level of skill and grade.

As for how many skills Jake had managed to upgrade during this month? Three in total. Each upgrade used different methods and approaches but resulted in the same outcome: Jake growing stronger. All were skills parts of Jake’s usual toolbox, and perhaps his most essential ones in a fight.

He had been a busy hunter, and the first skill was one he used all the time.

Splitting Arrow, or more accurately, Enhanced Splitting Arrow. Currently sitting at rare rarity since just after Jake evolved to D-grade, where he had upgraded it from uncommon rarity to allow the split to work with his Arcane Hunter’s Arrows. That upgrade had allowed the arrow to split and retain innate magical properties.

It was a simple yet effective skill.

[Enhanced Splitting Arrow (Rare)] – A skill most often used by archers, now usurped and reformed by the Avaricious Arcane Hunter. Allows you to clone your arrows while in flight, allowing them to retain innate magical properties. Each arrow strikes with the power of the original. Adds a small bonus to the effect of Agility and Wisdom when using Enhanced Splitting Arrow.

Paths of improvement? Several. Jake had many ideas. One of the first that sprang to mind was to allow it to clone even the poison on the arrows and other external magical properties. As an example, Jake could not split an Arcane Powershot, as the Powershot added properties to the arrow that were not innate. Okay, while he could probably still split it, all it would do was make the attack weaker, so it wasn’t worth it.

However, this method of improvement quickly hit a snag: One of the biggest strengths of Splitting Arrow was speed and how subtle it was to use. If Jake wanted to make it so much more powerful, the skill would require a lot more energy to use, as Jake paid in mana and stamina when he split arrows, and depending on the poison, the cost could get insane. Sleeping Night Toxin would be so darn expensive to clone. Jake was not even sure he had the mana pool for it. So he quickly moved away from doing that.

Which is when Jake remembered his most important motto: keep things simple. Why would he need to really change the skill? He just needed to improve it. Make it better than what it was. So why not just do that? Focus on improving every aspect there already was—something that would become a theme with these three upgrades. For Splitting Arrow, he felt like he needed to truly understand the process that caused the arrows to split and improve upon that.

Jake did have utterly bonkers Perception, so it was only right to put it to use. He thoroughly analyzed the moment his arrows split, following the entire process from start to end. Since gaining it, the skill had already gotten a lot stronger. The resource cost was lower per split than the day he got it, and he had an easier time splitting more arrows than before. This alone was perhaps enough for an upgrade if he pursued it more actively, but Jake went in another direction. One he also believed would shore up even more room for future upgrades and improvement. A path where Jake had taken a lot of inspiration from the Sword Saint and the duel they had. The result had been better than expected.

[Splitting Arrow Rain (Epic)] – A skill most often used by archers, now usurped and reformed by the Avaricious Arcane Hunter. Allows you to clone your arrows while in flight, allowing them to retain innate magical properties. Each arrow has variable strength and can be further split into less potent versions. If the original arrow is shot upwards, it can be split to create a far more potent arrow rain. Adds a small bonus to the effect of Agility and Wisdom when using Splitting Arrow Rain. Increased damage based on Perception and the distance the arrows fall from when creating an arrow rain.

Before, Jake hadn’t had a good area-of-effect skill besides just a lot of arcane magic. Now, Jake had what could thoroughly be classified as a disaster-level attack. Pre-upgrade, each Splitting Arrow had the power of the original, but with this version, Jake could vary it. He could make ten arrows with the power of the original, or a hundred arrows with about twenty percent of the originals… because, yes, they actually retained more power than math would otherwise suggest.

The upgrade had come during a fight with a massive water elemental while crossing a small part of one of the oceans of Earth. It had been larger than any creature Jake had faced before, relying solely on its massive resource pools to survive. Jake had bombarded it with thousands of arrows every few seconds and shown it that he, too, had a lot of resources to spend. And mana potions.

Something had to be said about watching a rain of arrows that each exploded upon impact. With a bit of practice, Jake could truly make it look like it rained as he shot the arrows into the air and let them drift down on his foe. His archery skill was also an important aspect of this skill, allowing him to bend the original arrow and make it fall faster and at slightly different angles than just straight down.

The elemental had died simply due to being bombarded for long enough and from far enough up in the air—because, yes, Jake just flying really high up in the air and shooting down counted as creating an arrow rain. Granted, Jake would have been screwed against the elemental if it had just run away underwater, but Sandy had done Cosmic Generis Worm stuff and made it so the elemental could not flee underwater by messing with space itself to effectively solidify the liquid. The more time Jake spent with the worm, the more he realized how messed up of a creature Sandy was.

Anyway. Splitting Arrow was the first skill Jake improved, and once that was done, he moved on to another staple.

Arcane Powershot.

If there was one skill Jake would say was truly the core of his fighting style, it had to be this. Jake had gotten Powershot all the way back at level 10, right after he got out of the Challenge Dungeon. Since then, it had been his best archery skill, if Jake said so himself, but more than anything, it was his skill. He had upgraded it twice himself already, and out of all his skills, he didn’t have one he felt more familiar with. Without lying, he would probably want to keep Arcane Powershot over all other archery skills he currently had, even if that would be illogical.

Either way, it was probably his best combat skill. All others had conditions or only worked well when used with others, but where would he be without Powershot? Probably at a far lower level, if not dead. It was only right to give the skill some love, and this time around, Jake took a note out of a Primordial’s book: Valdemar.

The thing about skill upgrades was that there were several ways to do it. The most usual way was to add more to the skill, like how Jake had just improved Splitting Arrow to be able to split more and added the arrow-rain function. But there was another way.

Refine and improve. Not changing the core of the skill itself, but simply making everything about it better. Concepts did not even need to be added; you just had to better understand those that were already there. Out of all the Primordials, Valdemar was the best at this. He was a simple man, and as a simple man, he had simple skills.

His go-to was a simple chop. Jake had seen this simple chop smash through the barriers of the Malefic Viper, tearing apart his flesh and bones as space and reality itself bent and buckled under his power. This was not simply because he was strong, but because of the skill the would-be Primordial used. It looked like a common-rarity skill, but in reality, it had likely been mythical or beyond during their confrontation at S-grade.

Jake had gone in a similar direction to Valdemar and thoroughly analyzed Arcane Powershot. As mentioned before, Jake was already intimately familiar with the skill and only sought to improve every aspect. Arcane Powershot was inherently a bit chaotic due to the destructive arcane energies, but that was primarily due to Jake’s lacking control. The more stable energy he could actively control and pour in, the more destructive energy he could stabilize and infuse into the attack. The end result would still look chaotic, and the purpose was still to push himself to his utmost limits—something Arcane Powershot had not really allowed him to do for a while.

He wanted to go back to the days when he’d felt his own muscles burn, his skin peeling off from destructive energies, and his bow struggling to not break apart from the sheer level of energy infused. After days of slowly refining the skill and dozens of dead C-grades that became victims to his Path, the system rewarded his efforts.

[Arcane Powershot (Epic)] – Stamina the fuel, mana the guide, arcane the power. Evolved from Infused Powershot, it now uses a higher concept of mana to amplify itself. The higher the magnitude of the charge, the greater the stamina and mana expenditure. Arcane Powershot’s power is dependent on the charging duration, but due to your arcane mana’s inherent power, the base power without any charging is significantly higher than Infused Powershot. Adds a small bonus to the effectiveness of Agility and Strength as well as a medium bonus to the effectiveness of Intelligence when using Arcane Powershot.

-->

[Arcane Powershot (Ancient)] – Stamina the fuel, mana the guide, arcane the power. Using your arcane energy, charge a devastating attack using a bow that pushes your body, will, and control to their limits. The higher the magnitude of the charge, the greater the stamina and mana expenditure. Arcane Powershot’s power is dependent on the charging duration but has a powerful baseline due to your arcane affinity. Adds a medium bonus to the effectiveness of Agility and Strength as well as a substantial bonus to the effectiveness of Intelligence when using Arcane Powershot.

There was no interesting fight that had spawned this upgrade. Jake had not made it to battle a certain foe like the massive water elemental. The upgrade had come during one of his many times using it to first engage a foe, and everything had just clicked and fallen into place.

The change in the description was intriguing. Primarily how nothing had really changed functionality-wise, yet it was quite different word-wise. All references to Infused Powershot were gone and now replaced with their own text, indicating that the skill was now more divorced from Infused Powershot than before. The changes were so few that not even the skill name had changed; the rarity had just upgraded.

Did Jake complain about this? No. No, he did not. His only possible area of criticism was the lack of inherent Perception scaling in the skill, but it was acceptable for now. The skill did still kind of scale with Perception simply because it empowered attacks that scaled with the stat.

In that fight where it had clicked, the energy had moved more smoothly than ever before. First, a stream of pure stability had entered his muscles, bones, skin, and bow. A fraction of a second later, the destructive energies had come, but Jake had protected himself already. The two energies had interacted and rapidly reached equilibrium as Jake mixed stamina and mana far more efficiently than before he began practicing the upgrade. His efforts were rewarded when the skill upgraded and system assistance kicked in.

The Arcane Powershot Jake had released had been by far the strongest he had ever used outside of one using Hunting Momentum, and Jake was already beginning to see a path to a goal he had formed for himself. Something he had done in E-grade and wanted to repeat in D-grade if possible:

Kill prey a grade above himself with a single shot.

The final skill to be upgraded was a bit of a surprise: Arcane Hunter’s Arrows.

Jake honestly hadn’t been actively going for this one; it had just kind of happened as he worked on his other skills. This skill was one of those semi-passive ones that he didn’t consciously think about, but seeing as it was his source of projectiles ninety-nine percent of the time, he probably should consider it more.

The skill was honestly a bit… meh? Like, there wasn’t much to it, and it barely fit him as an Avaricious Arcane Hunter. It fit the Arcane Hunter part, but there was nothing avaricious about it. The avaricious tag usually just meant he dealt more damage to foes above his own level and sometimes less against those at a lower level. Most often than not, the tradeoff was just that the upgrade only worked on those at a higher level, making it a demerit by omission.

What Jake had gone for this time around was better introducing his class into the skill along with his increased level of control. Once more, he dove into the vast treasure trove of Perception and better analyzed the arrows. Jake had already applied many concepts to them before and was rather used to them. He had found ways to infuse the Stealth Attack concept better and now worked with Hunting Momentum, practicing a bit by first making a bunch of Arrows of the Ambitious Hunter since the skills were a bit similar. The difference was that the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter was a single, far more powerful arrow, and one that also contained the concept that allowed him to deal more damage to enemies of a higher level. Jake wanted to take that element and apply it to Arcane Hunter’s Arrows.

Jake did have to be careful not to change the skill too much, though, as one of the best things about the Arcane Hunter’s Arrows skill was the instantaneous summon. If the skill lost that functionality, he would probably have to switch back to just using a quiver that conjured arrows, which would suck.

As he was trying to work this concept into the arrows, he also began to ask himself why he only ever shot arrows that were either stable or destructive. Like, he knew it was best to go all-in with one element, but why have it all be static? Jake could make stable balls of arcane energy and then make those explode. His arcane bolts were stable one moment, destructive the next. That shouldn’t be too hard to also do with arrows, right?

Nope, it wasn’t. Considering Jake had spent an entire month focusing on upgrading skills, his mindset was already mentally well-adjusted to focus. And after he became able to change the equilibrium of the arrows, he tried to also apply the avaricious element. He thought it would be hard, but that very day, he had gotten the upgrade.

[Arcane Hunter’s Arrows (Epic)] - A mage and a hunter both, you combine your talents as you conjure your tools of destruction. Allows the Avaricious Arcane Hunter to conjure arrows made of highly condensed arcane mana, focusing on either destruction or stability. A stable arrow will be sharp and durable, while a destructive arrow will explode upon impact. Conjuring arrows consume mana, and the conjuration is instant. Adds a bonus to the effectiveness of Intelligence and Wisdom when using destructive Arcane Hunter’s Arrows. Adds a bonus to the effectiveness of Wisdom and Perception when using stable Arcane Hunter’s Arrows.

-->

[Avaricious Arcane Hunter’s Arrows (Ancient)] - A hunter embracing control over all energy, you combine your talents as you conjure your tools of destruction. Allows the Avaricious Arcane Hunter to conjure arrows made of highly condensed arcane mana, focusing on either destruction or stability during the creation process. A stable arrow will be sharp and durable, while a destructive arrow will explode upon impact. Conjuring arrows consume mana, and the conjuration is instant. The user can change the balance of the energy within the arrow remotely. Deals slightly increased damage against foes at a higher level. Adds a bonus to the effectiveness of Intelligence, Wisdom, and Perception when using Avaricious Arcane Hunter’s Arrows.

Jake had to admit that this one was the cheapest upgrade out of all of them. The amount of system assistance that came in was insane. This was one of those instances where the upgrade path had been predetermined already, almost just waiting for Jake to discover this way to improve it.

The result was slightly more powerful arrows that were better against foes at a higher level, which naturally meant more damage to everything. The ability to change the balance of destruction and stability on the fly was also a great addition for quite a few reasons. Where Jake applied this upgrade the most was, of course, by shooting a stable arrow, and once it was close to its target, he made it explode. No, Jake could not blow up an arrow already embedded in his foe. He tried, and it failed every time.

This one was still a new addition, and Jake had more science to do before he figured out everything.

Every single skill upgrade also improved all existing properties, even if new ones were added. This month of hunting had been perhaps the most fruitful period Jake had ever had in D-grade when it came to improving his fighting power. Jake still wanted to improve some things, but time was limited. Soon enough, he would have to resolve everything going on with Earth.

"I am done eating!" Sandy said to Jake while flying over, having consumed the entire field of fruit trees.

Jake stared out over the ocean and smiled at the worm as he shook his head, telling himself to focus on what lay ahead. They were about to head across the ocean for the first time.

The geography of the Earth had truly changed a lot, and one of the changes was the placement of land and ocean. You could walk nearly anywhere without crossing an ocean, as paths connected almost everywhere, but there were still parts without a reliable way across. These narrow points were all they had crossed so far, but to go further, they had to head straight through the open ocean. That, or potentially take a long way around. Jake would lie if he said he wasn’t looking forward to their sea trip at least a little.

On a side note, the "ocean" Jake had crossed with Carmen was not truly an ocean. Jake realized that now. It was more just a massive lake still connected to the ocean, though, by old-world standards, that lake was indeed ocean-sized.

"Did you know that even before the system, we knew so little about what hid in the depths of the ocean?" he asked his wormy companion. “Had so much of it still unexplored? Some even said we knew more of space than the depths of our own seas.”

"No?" Sandy said as Jake felt the mental version of an eyeroll. "How would I know? I am a sand worm. It would be very weird if I knew what you humans were up to before the system."

"My point is," Jake said, waving off the worm, "I am looking forward to seeing what monsters may roam over the vast oceans."

"I am more wondering what kind of tasty things these monsters are hiding away," Sandy said with glee. "But no going into the water. No way we are doing that."

"That, we agree on," Jake said.

There was no fucking way he would willingly face a C-grade in underwater combat.

Chapter 38

Sky Whale & Old Acquaintance

Sandy was definitely the most lopsided creature Jake had ever come across. Okay, maybe something like the Termite Hive Queen was equally lopsided, but Sandy was definitely so specialized and weird that it boggled his mind.

Most creatures Jake knew could fight. Like, fighting was a basic skill of the multiverse, right? Jake had yet to come across a single C-grade that couldn’t at least fight back in some way. But Sandy? Sandy and fighting were not a thing at all.

And yet, out of every C-grade, Jake did not want to mess with Sandy and make the worm an enemy. Because he was damn sure that would only result in everything he held dear getting eaten and the worm flying away unbothered.

Sandy was good at three things. Like a sand worm, a Cosmic Genesis Worm was incredibly good at moving about. Jake thought his new Wings skill was good at escaping, but Sandy had several skills that allowed escape.

Second, Sandy was incredibly resilient. The rock-like hide was not for show, and Jake found that even with Arcane Powershot, he could not break through, even if Sandy did say "ouchie" when he hit the massive worm. That was the upgraded version of Arcane Powershot, too.

Third was finding and collecting resources. Jake could sense natural treasures due to his boots and Sense of the Malefic Viper, but damn, Sandy was on a whole other level. The worm picked up on things of value up to thousands of kilometers away, and Jake had a feeling it could be even further.

What Sandy was not good at was fighting, but the worm also sucked at detecting enemies. Luckily, or unluckily, it was nearly impossible to find a natural treasure not guarded by something powerful, and Sandy had a good sense of how valuable a natural treasure was and, thus, what kind of power level one could expect the protector to be. Sometimes Sandy was still wrong, but that is where numbers one and two came in, allowing the worm to just leave. The one time they’d accidentally bumped into a mid-tier C-grade, probably around level 250, Sandy had just flown away. The beast had chased for a while until it realized it was wasting its time.

All of this is to say that Sandy was only good at running—worming—and eating. But damn, the worm was good at it. He had pimped himself the best ride around, and he clearly felt he was getting closer to Sylphie with every passing day. Now that they found themselves crossing the ocean, Jake also saw an entirely new part of Earth.

Amazingly enough, Jake had avoided underwater combat for the entire first day of their journey. This part of the trip would be a lot faster than the one prior, as Sandy quickly realized that unless you were willing to dive into the depths, there were few treasures in the open ocean.

Sandy had only found a single island that didn’t even have a C-grade on it, just a whole bunch of D-grade birds that made them avoid it. No reason to mess with the local wildlife without any rewards.

This resulted in Jake spending a lot of time working within Sandy’s stomach. He considered working on upgrading some more skills, but without fighting, Jake had a tough time doing it. Jake’s entire fighting style was also just so damn instinctual that trying to take a logical approach and research a skill seemed too foreign to him.

Thus, he focused on alchemy once more. Everything was peaceful, as nothing tried to attack Sandy, and what did try did not have the slightest chance of catching the Cosmic Genesis Worm. At least, everything was peaceful… until the third day, when suddenly Sandy called out to him.

"Out. Now," the worm said as Jake was thrown out. He didn’t even have time to stabilize himself before his eyes opened wide, and he turned his head and saw it.

Still only half-emerged, an utterly massive creature exited the infinitely deep ocean below. Its skin was blue and rough, with fins and a massive tail still hidden in the water below. It looked like a blue whale, just oversized to the extreme, with its emergence reminiscent of a large island choosing to take to the skies.

[Sky Whale – lvl ???]

Jake estimated it to be a bit over ten kilometers long, and it was by far the largest creature Jake had ever encountered. As for if he would fight it? No fucking chance, because the aura it gave off was also far above anything.

It was a late-tier C-grade, well beyond level 300. No matter how many skills Jake upgraded, he had no confidence in facing such a foe. This was also why Jake froze and gritted his teeth as he felt the whale’s attention on him. The beast was still over a hundred kilometers away and moving incredibly slowly, but he still saw its stadium-sized eye turn to look at him.

"Sandy, why are we stopping here?" Jake asked the worm.

"It asked for you.”

"What?" he said, surprised.

"Said they had been tracking us for a while and wanted to talk… I did want to run, but it seems friendly enough, you know? Anyway, I was promised a treat if I got you out, so get talking.”

As Sandy confirmed he had just been sold out, he felt the whale reach out to him mentally. Jake accepted, wondering what the beast could possibly want from him outside of eating him. Wait, blue whales were herbivores pre-system and pretty chill creatures overall, so maybe this one was too? So he hoped.

"I greet thee, Malefic’s Chosen," a deep voice echoed in Jake’s head. It sounded like the whale was talking to him from inside a large cave or something. The voice was also obviously male.

"To what do I owe the pleasure?" Jake responded in kind. He felt no animosity but instead a lot of caution from the massive Sky Whale. Clearly not fearful of his power, but his identity.

"If you would allow me to speak frankly?" the whale asked.

"Of course," Jake allowed, now even more curious.

"We have felt the waves of change for a long time. We, being those who reside within the vast waters of our planet. From the beginning, we were aware a war would come, and it has already spread to our waters. Factions have been born, and lines formed. I do not mean to ask you for anything, but I do have a request.”

Also speaking frankly, Jake said, "What could I possibly do for you that you cannot do yourself? You are the most powerful creature I have seen on this planet so far." If the whale asked him for help in a fight or something, then he had to admit he was way out of his depths. Pun intended.

"The ones who will ultimately take control of this planet will not be those like me. When that happens, I fear what our fates will be. Perhaps I myself could leave behind this world and explore the wider universe, but many trust in me and hide under my fins for protection. What I am asking of you is not assistance in any task, but simply to allow us to stay once the time comes. In return, we shall support you in taming the parts of the world you do not wander yourself, Malefic’s Chosen.”

Jake frowned, even more confused. He felt like this all came out of nowhere, and he wasn’t even sure how they had tracked him or known he had been inside of Sandy. No one had been observing them besides Villy, and he had a hard time seeing Villy informing a C-grade Sky Whale about him out of the blue. Yet clearly, it had known he was coming and intercepted him. The whale was also aware of the entire Ell’Hakan and United Cities Alliance situation, from the sounds of it. He had to know how.

"This has nothing to do with your request, but I have to know… how did you track me and know we were coming? Who told you? How do you even know the situation on land when you reside within the oceans?"

"I apologize sincerely, but I am unable to answer that question," the Sky Whale answered, now fully emerged from the water. “Just know that neither my Patron nor those following me are against you. All we seek is a path of survival and, hopefully, a healthy relationship moving forward with both the Chosen and his Patron. What I can share is that my Patron is no threat to you nor the Malefic One, and he realizes his station.”

Jake pondered and couldn’t figure out who or what it could be. What he could do was guess, and his guess was that the whale had a Patron that wasn’t a god Jake had heard of before. Potentially not even that powerful of a god, but simply one that hoped to foster a good relationship with Jake and Villy. Why he had chosen to back Jake and not this Ell’Hakan if he knew both, Jake had no idea. Maybe he just wasn’t a moron?

He admired the massive body of the whale for a moment as he wondered how damn deep the oceans had to be to facilitate such an enormous creature living within it. Much less the treasures it had to hold for such a monster to reach its level of strength.

"I understand," Jake answered, feeling the nervousness of the whale decrease.

"I thank you, Malefic’s Chosen, and godspeed in your journey. Allow me to offer you and your companion tokens of goodwill.”

The Sky Whale then opened its ridiculously large mouth. Out flew two objects, one being a large pearl the size of a volleyball and the other a crystal container about the size of Jake himself. It looked naturally formed, but it contained an odd, dark blue liquid that instantly triggered Jake’s Sense of the Malefic Viper. Needless to say, he could not hold himself back from identifying it.

[Lifeblood of the Emperor Urchin (Ancient)] – The Lifeblood of a slain Emperor Urchin, an incredibly poisonous creature only found in areas with extremely dense water affinity. Its very blood is toxic to consume and especially toxic if directly injected. The Lifeblood is of a neurotoxic nature. Has many alchemical uses and is especially potent when combined with other neurotoxins or poisons with the water affinity.

Jake was not one to say no to a good thing and gladly accepted his gift. Sandy had already zoomed forward and eaten the pearl without a care in the world. Jake shook his head and put the crystal container in his inventory.

"Thank you, from both of us," Jake said with a smile. “I am sure we can figure something out if you are sincere. Me knowing who is backing you would also help, but I can accept it if you want to stay secretive.”

"No, I am the one to thank you,” the Sky Whale said. “I have been allowed to say that my god is indeed far more aware of you than others, and you have briefly brushed Paths before. You and your Patron have both helped him, perhaps unknowingly, and he wishes to pay back that favor.”

Still no idea who it could be, Jake thought. Considering the whale said unknowingly, he assumed it truly was a god he had never met or interacted with. He was also confused at Villy having helped this mystery god. Moreover, he didn’t get the feeling the whale was lying. Why would it lie? What would it get out of it?

They exchanged some more pleasantries before the whale took to the air. Yes, rather than dive down underwater, it flew upwards into the vast skies above, doing whatever Sky Whales do.

"That was a nice whale," Sandy said.

"Yeah, very whalecoming," Jake agreed.

"That was bad… Like, I can feel you snicker through the connection, and you should not feel proud about that one at all," Sandy scolded him with exasperation.

"Whale, then, I guess I will fin-ish this conversation here," Jake said, unable to hold back a grin.

The worm did not respond, just cutting the connection and gulping him down. Jake did not resist as he was tossed into Sandy’s stomach, still smiling proudly to himself.

"I do wonder what god that whale was associated with," Jake wondered out loud. It was a mystery that would likely take a long time to sol—

"Hey, Jake, remember that god Karroch that was in charge of your tutorial?” Villy came in. “Yeah, that is the god that blessed the whale and apparently a shitload of other beasts on your planet.”

"Wait, that beastmaster kind of guy?” Jake instantly asked in return. “Why would he say I helped him, and moreover, why would he say you helped him? Well, unless you did help him… Is this him paying you back a favor or something?"

"Not really. As the god in charge of your tutorial—despite him being trumped and just working for Eversmile, the Holy Mother, and others—he was the one in charge on paper. Which means he got rewards based on the performance of the participants. You becoming a Progenitor was a major boon to him. Then, afterward, I killed the Brimstone Hegemon, an enemy of this god. One can say that we both changed his life. You allowed him to break through and no longer stagnate in strength, while I removed an enemy trying to hunt down and kill him. He truly got lucky by crossing paths with you and me."

"Huh, guess you learn something new every day. So, what is he trying to do? Get on your good side through me? Or just repaying some perceived favor?"

"Bit of both, from the looks of it. Just let him; Karroch is an unaffiliated god that does not belong to any Pantheon, and honestly, him helping you out can be very beneficial. As a beastmaster, his Blessing can help beasts tremendously, and the guidance he can offer is also better than what most other gods can. You must remember that one of the primary abilities of beastmasters is to make their beasts stronger and allow them to grow in strength. If that Augur is a guide for the enlightened to find their Paths, a good beastmaster is a guide for beasts.”

"I see," Jake said. "But are these beastmasters not effectively just tamers forcing beasts to fight for them? Is it a good idea for a beast to be influenced by someone like that?"

"Beastmasters tend to have two classifications of beasts: tamed beasts and companion beasts. Companion beasts have a connection more like the one you have with the Sylphian Hawk, while the tamed beasts are indeed just expendable chess pieces. Companion beasts are naturally what these beastmasters care about the most, and the kind of Records you can expect if blessed by one.”

"Good to know," Jake said.

"Anyway, I just thought I would let you know, as it was something god-related. I shall let you get back to your travels. Keep up the good work.” Villy then cut off the connection. It was just a brief talk but rather enlightening.

Jake also failed to hold himself back. "Hey, Sandy, can you do me a favor and tell the Sky Whale to say that I am happy Karroch benefited from my Path?"

"Who is Karroch?" Sandy asked.

"A mutual acquaintance of the whale and me."

A few moments passed. Sandy always made the walls transparent and allowed Jake to look outside, and he saw the Sky Whale, now far up in the air, react as Sandy spoke to it. A few more seconds passed.

"The whale talked about you truly being a monster or something like that, which makes no sense, as you said you are a human, right?” Sandy relayed to him. “Humans aren’t monsters.”

Jake just shook his head. "Who knows? Maybe I am also a giant whale in disguise."

"Doubtful, considering whales aren’t scared of water," Sandy scoffed.

"I am not afraid of water," Jake argued. "I just recognize I am not adept in fighting in it."

"Sounds like something someone who is scared of water would say."

"It is not about fear, but—"

"Maybe you are… what was it… a chicken? Yeah, maybe you are a chicken in disguise? Because you sound like a chicken right now.”

"No, it is not that. I—"

"Chickens also don’t like water, right? What a coincidence…"

Their "argument" continued, with Jake not realizing he had fallen into a trap—or being too stubborn and prideful to back down—until it was too late.

Chapter 39

Teaching How to Human & Angry Shark

She had to ask herself if maybe she was the one who had something wrong with her. Yeah, maybe it was her? Miranda just couldn’t see any other way for everything to make sense. Because if it wasn’t her, then what the hell was wrong with everyone Jake introduced to her or made friends with?

They had spent over a month in the Grand Mangrove River by now, and things had been mostly fine. Emphasis on mostly. Because the Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake was far more peculiar than Miranda had initially estimated. She had to admit that she’d originally been afraid of the snake girl, constantly having to be on guard and act confident. Facing a C-grade, especially a mid-tier C-grade, was no easy task for her, but she’d had to endure it for her comrades.

That was a month ago. After spending a month with the snake?

"No, you can’t just eat one of their arms to teach them a lesson," she said with exasperation as the C-grade snake sat on her knees, attentively listening. “That is not how humans learn at all.”

"But Big Sis, what if they are being really bad?” the snake girl argued. “Like, at least eat the hand, right? It grows back, so it isn’t that bad, is it?"

"It is still a no," Miranda said with a sigh. "If you want to be a good ruler, do not use fear as your only tool. That is what idiots do, and you aren’t an idiot."

"Okay…" the C-grade said, seeming to reconsider what kind of teaching methods would be good for humans. Ah, but not human adults, mind you.

The snake girl seemed to be under the impression that the best way to teach human kids was corporal punishment. Some idiot had mentioned to her that kids sometimes had to touch a hot stove to learn it was hot, so the brilliant snake naturally interpreted that as meaning the best way to teach a kid about heat was to smash their faces onto a stove repeatedly until they were deathly afraid of kitchen appliances.

As for why the snake cared so much about learning "how to human," as she put it? Because she was clearly obsessed with Jake and proving herself useful to him. Miranda was not even sure how to interpret the snake’s emotions… Love? Infatuation? Neither felt right. Obsession was truly the only word she thought fit.

One good thing about this obsession was that she wanted to do all she could to make Miranda happy, and her level of respect for the City Lord was through the roof, as she seemed to view Miranda as a "senior" in the Jake fan club.

Her respect for Miranda was good, though… because the snake girl had a lot to learn before Miranda would dare unleash her on the wider society. She had done a lot of questionable things, and Miranda would be far more frightened of the C-grade if she didn’t have the demeanor of an unknowing teenager. One area she had really messed up in was her recruitment methods.

At first, Miranda had assumed the snakes had maybe helped or rescued people who had been trying to cross the Grand Mangrove River and found themselves in trouble. Nope—it turned out that the snakes were the trouble. They swooped up any humans they came across and forced them back to the center of the mangrove forest, and they’d even had them construct the small settlement that could now be found there.

If this wasn’t bad enough, then the Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake’s method of studying the human body had been to literally study the body. She had initially consumed several women and girls to learn about human physiology, and once she felt more familiar with the form, she’d forced women to help her refine it. This was partly done by her investigating how the human women’s bodies looked and having them explain things… which included cutting them open with a healer on standby.

It was only after this, having begun to learn a bit about how humans were supposed to act, that she stopped. No one had ever even mentioned to her that what she did was wrong by human standards, because who the hell would dare tell a C-grade when she was out of line? Who would dare claim her actions were wrong, and that what she did would be morally reprehensible by any reasonable moral standard? Well, that person ended up being Miranda.

Things in the settlement had improved after their arrival, and the mood had relaxed after Miranda had effectively taken charge. She still vividly remembered when a dozen or so humans had seen her tell off the Alabaster snake in public… and their looks of utter horror for what was about to happen—because, yes, the snake girl’s usual response to dissent was just to kill whoever disagreed.

People were dumbfounded when they saw that the snake girl just nodded enthusiastically and asked what she was then supposed to do. From that point on, they were all incredibly friendly whenever Miranda was around, and the fact that the snakes no longer killed people who messed up was a huge improvement. The young snake still needed to learn that simply attacking people wasn’t in any way constructive.

Miranda sighed as she saw that the snake girl was a tad down after being told what she was doing wrong for the umpteenth time that day. It was probably time to "reward" her.

"We can continue this tomorrow, okay?" Miranda said in a soothing tone. "Also… I have a surprise for you."

The snake girl just looked up and tilted her head to the side.

"A surprise from the Chosen," Miranda clarified.

The eyes of the girl instantly lit up as she jumped to her feet. "What!? What is it!?"

Miranda smiled at the nervous and excited girl. "A name."

Jake and Miranda had agreed that this time around, Miranda would help him decide, and she quickly realized that Jake was obsessed with using the physical appearance or attributes of creatures to name them. It made her question whether, if Jake ever had a kid, he would name him or her Humany or something else dumb like that… Alas, at least Miranda was there this time around to shoot down any downright horrible name ideas. Because Jake had a lot of dumb ideas.

After a bit of time, they narrowed the names down to a few. All of them were still real names, and all of them were even acceptable names for a girl. However, all of them also partly included parts of the Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake’s race name or physical attributes. Miranda personally thought that using parts of the race name for the naming scheme was moronic, as when the beast evolved, the race name could entirely change. So calling the snake Alabastie—an actual suggestion by Jake—would just come off as incredibly dumb-looking if she ever evolved.

She really hoped he had been joking, though, as Jake could not seriously just take the first word of a creature’s race name and slap on an "ie" or "y," right? Yeah, that was too much for even him… even if he had kind of done that with Sylphie. And Mystie… Yeah, okay, he had been absolutely serious.

Good thing Miranda was there. Anyway, the final battle of names came down to Scarlett, after her red eyes, and Allie. Allie because of Alabaster, and because it still fit Jake’s obsession with names ending in "ie" or "y." Both of these were at least real names, and both were short and sweet. Even if the snake ended up changing race later on, the names would not be questionable.

"A name!?" the snake girl gaped. "Me, named by the Chosen? Really?"

She was almost dancing, and Miranda had to admit she looked rather cute. If she hadn’t seen the girl rip the head off a man without flinching, she would even have gone as far as to call her innocent-looking.

"Yes, but he had two suggestions, so you need to choose yourself," Miranda made clear.

Miranda had to admit she was not actually that comfortable just naming another person herself. She wanted them to at least have some choice over the matter. Not that any of the beasts Jake had named complained about their names, no matter how bad they were… Miranda just wasn’t comfortable doing it.

"What are they!?" the snake girl said, practically jumping up and down.

"One of them is Scarlett," Miranda said, the snake girl listening attentively. “It comes from the red color of your eyes, and the color red often symbolizes courage, passion, heat, and force. It is a powerful name. Some also think it a violent name—something that is fitting for your rather fiery personality.

"The second name is Allie. Parts of the name stem from your race and that you are an Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake. The name is considered fair and symbolizes harmony and nobility, and was originally the name of a saint. Moreover, it is often a nickname, so if you wish to have a longer, more formal-sounding name, you can also do that and retain being called Allie by friends and family. If you are not satisfied with either of these naming ideas, do not hesitate to voice it, and we can go back to the drawing board."

"No! No, I love both of them!" the girl instantly said, waving her hands back and forth.

"Alright," Miranda said with a smile. "Just think carefully about it. A name is important and isn’t something one should just choose haphazardly."

Future Scarlett/Allie fell into pondering, seeming to think very deeply about what name she wanted. It was something that Jake should maybe do once in his damn life, as he had a tendency to just jump straight into a dumb decision.

Heck, for all Miranda knew, he was probably doing something reckless and stupid at that very moment.

Fooled. Bamboozled. Entrapped. Completely and utterly let behind the light and taken advantage of. That is the fate that befell Jake after he argued with the Cosmic Genesis Worm. He had fallen for the dumbest thing ever: the good old "then prove it" argument.

Proving that he was not afraid of water, that is.

Jake was not afraid, and even if he knew he was being baited into it, he had gone along with Sandy’s taunts. It wouldn’t be that bad to just dive down under the water for a little bit and maybe fight a few D-grades or something, right? He just had to avoid any C-grades. Heck, he could even practice stealth a little, sneaking his way down there and finding whatever it was he was looking for!

He had so much belief in himself… so how the hell had he ended up in his current situation?

Jake constantly shot arcane blasts behind himself to catapult forward faster as the large shark chased him angrily. He had to continually break through barriers, as the water itself tried to stop him and slow him down long enough to be devoured by the monstrous beast. A beast that was naturally a C-grade.

[Razorstream Shark – lvl ???]

As for where the hell Sandy was? Well, Sandy was busy eating an entire fucking coral reef that the shark protected and seemed to use to create some natural formation. Jake had gone there after being told by Sandy that it looked like a great spot to find valuable things, and since he wasn’t a chicken, he could totally go there and get some herbs, right? There were indeed good herbs there, no way around it, but there was also an angry shark. A shark Jake had made even angrier after he stole some kelp.

Spinning around in the water, Jake took out his bow and charged an Arcane Powershot. The water fought against him as always, but he managed to overpower the natural environment and launch an arrow nevertheless.

It flew forward and hit the side of the twenty-meter-long shark, ripping off a piece of flesh and making it even angrier. Jake rapidly shot again before stepping down with One Step, teleporting to the side just before the maw of the shark snapped shut.

The arrow he had shot had no velocity at all, as Jake had released it with no power. Yet just before the shark shut its mouth around the arrow, it suddenly split into ten, with those ten further splitting into ten each for a hundred total.

Its mouth snapped shut just as all the arrows exploded at once, ruffling the large beast a little. Jake even saw the arcane energy flash up through its gills. Once more, he had done more to annoy it than actually damage it.

Charging again, the shark seemed to be getting a bit serious. The water around it warped as several teeth-shaped projectiles were summoned and shot towards him. Jake avoided and shot another arrow, but the waters around the shark moved as a powerful current began revolving around the beast.

Jake’s arrows were thrown off course with the shark charging again. Having no time to release another ranged attack, Jake decided to face it in melee combat. From within his Soulspace, he felt sim-Jake’s attention. His simulacrum observed attentively.

One would think that a shark had few close-combat options besides simply trying to bite its target to death, and one would be correct if it was a normal shark. But this one was an early-tier C-grade with a healthy repertoire of magic.

The sphere of water around the shark began warping. Teeth-like objects appeared within it, and Jake’s eyes opened wide as he focused. The shark barreled forward, and Jake entered the sphere as he swayed. Several attacks flew by him, but as the current only flowed one way, they all came from the same direction, giving him a chance to dodge. He dodged and used his katars to slightly veer some teeth away from him, but soon enough, the shark was upon him.

Rather than try to bite him, it tackled with its snout, which now had even more damn teeth growing out of it. Jake met it head-on, punching forward with his full power. A mix of dark and arcane energy revolved around the katar as Jake used Descending Dark Arcane Fang for the first time in quite a while. The shark had no doubt willingly decided to trade the blow, as Jake’s hand was hit by several razor-sharp teeth in turn, but rather than cut through his gloves and puncture his hand, the gloves remained undamaged since Jake had already poured mana into the legendary item to strengthen it.

Their clash sent a wave of pain through Jake’s arm, and he was shot backward due to the sheer level of size and momentum the charging shark had. The bones in his arm hurt, a few cracks having formed here and there. Not that the beast came out of it unharmed. It now had a deep wound in its snout that penetrated nearly three meters into its head, as Jake had extended the blade with Descending Dark Arcane Fang.

He felt the faint approval of sim-Jake, but also some criticism over his failure to hit the brain and how he hadn’t properly transferred the impact through the rest of his body to lessen the strain on his arm. Jake took it in, as he decided that if he was going to be forced into underwater combat, he should at least make something out of it.

Neither of them knew how long sim-Jake had left, but to Jake’s surprise, he felt like his simulacrum had recently gotten more personality back. Before, he’d regressed to nothing but a nearly mindless machine improving Shadow Vault.

I guess sim-Jake never got to do any underwater combat… Better get his take on this afterward. No, not afterward. Right now.

Jake smirked as the annoyed shark charged once more, a pulse of dense water affinity washing over him. A few thin cuts appeared on his body as he felt a concept of sharpness within the water itself, only making him smile more.

What human hadn’t dreamt of fighting a shark?

Probably most humans.

The thing is, Jake wasn’t most humans. Never had been.

He dove forward. Human met shark, the two clashing as the water filled with blood and a happy worm ate an entire coral reef in the background.

Chapter 40

Angry Shark, Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo

When fighting a larger foe, one had to always make use of that against them. The shark’s size made it far stronger in direct clashes, but Jake’s smaller size offered him more mobility to maneuver around the shark.

Not that the shark was slow. It did not only use its body but its magic to move in unpredictable ways. Jake had to constantly adapt, as the entire body of the beast was its weapon. Teeth-like scales protruded from its skin, all angled to cut him simply by brushing against the body of the beast. This meant that Jake had to constantly back away and make sure only his weapons touched his opponent. To make matters worse, the Razorstream part of the shark’s name was not a joke. The currents of water around the shark cut him as though they were filled with tiny razorblades, putting a constant strain on his Scales of the Malefic Viper.

The passive barrier from Arcane Awakening also helped—a skill he had been forced to use right off the bat to just put up a fight. Fully activated, too. His body was flushed with power, every attack dealt a little more arcane damage, and the passive shield took off a bit of the power from the razor-like water.

Jake clashed with the beast several times, slowly being forced to retreat, with sim-Jake always at the back of his mind. As if Jake had two minds, they both analyzed their opponent on the fly and adapted their strategy. Fangs of the Malefic Viper made sure every stab included a good dose of poison, and his Hunting Momentum was slowly building up, but the Razorstream made him constantly take damage, and he was hit all the time, as the moment-by-moment fight had him on the back-backfoot.

Fighting in water was just a lot harder, and even if he could use his wings to maneuver better than a human normally would, it was still far worse than what a creature naturally operating underwater could do. All of his attacks were weakened, too, as he always had to fight against the water to do anything. Even so, Jake did not feel any true mortal danger, because he always had one thing he could do to end the fight right there and then: retreat.

Jake could easily get away at any point unless the shark wanted to chase him above water, in which case Jake would happily fight it up there. He was convinced the shark could fight above water if it so desired, and he could make the battle far easier by simply flying up a few kilometers, but he wanted this fight. Sim-Jake wanted this fight.

Jake was forced back by a powerful torrent of cutting water, his scales and arcane barrier both clattering from the thousands of small cuts. His armor was slowly getting torn to shreds, but in return, he managed to land a hit here and there.

Cuts from Jake’s katars quickly proved ineffective; the natural armor offered by the teeth-like skin was highly resistant, meaning only stabbing would work. And katars were really good at stabbing things, so it worked out.

A large, summoned maw of teeth tried to close around Jake’s leg. He barely managed to avoid it and charged towards the shark. It whipped its body around to smash him with its tail and push him away, but Jake had seen that move before. He ducked under the tail and stabilized himself to not get caught up in the resulting wave of pressure from the water. He then rapidly dove forward and stabbed the backside of the shark with Eternal Hunger before it could once more blast him with a wave of water magic.

Jake tried to summon mana strings to bind or restrain the massive C-grade, but the teeth on its skin moved and tore off whatever he used. Moreover, it began to release these teeth out of its skin like projectiles, each of them far more powerful than the magically summoned teeth in the water.

Both of them seemed to realize that finishing the other off quickly was not an option. The shark dedicated its focus to whittling Jake down, while Jake slowly wounded and poisoned the shark. The hemotoxic poison he’d used made the beast bleed even more than it should, coloring the entire area of their fight red with blood. Not that the shark seemed overly bothered, even after hundreds of liters had been drained. Its Vitality was above expectations. However, he also noticed one other important thing.

While Jake was not confident fighting underwater, the shark wasn’t confident fighting someone Jake’s size either. Something that had quickly become clear upon diving beneath the waves was that the scale of most creatures down there exceeded that of the land dwellers. Chances were, the only creatures that were small were weaklings that the shark could simply swat away or eat in a single gulp, making it completely unaccustomed to someone his size.

They both needed to adapt and overcome the holes in their fighting styles, and in this department, there was no competition.

Jake once more dodged a tail-swipe and landed a small stab on the base of the tail. The beast rolled around to try and cut him like a meatgrinder, but Jake had already teleported back and pulled out his bow. A single Arcane Powershot was rapidly charged, blowing off many of the teeth acting as the shark’s armor and leaving a nasty wound. The beast knew it could not allow him to strike uninterrupted and conjured several ranged attacks to stop him.

Shooting off one more arrow, Jake made it split and explode. A cascade of blasts rocked the water and hid Jake from the shark’s sight. He took this chance to land another Arcane Powershot before the beast could locate him.

With speed surpassing anything prior, the shark was upon him, the sphere of cutting current around it expanding and growing in power. Jake responded in kind as Pride of the Malefic Viper flared to life, and Jake infused arcane energy into his surroundings to faintly stabilize it.

Resource-wise, Jake was nearly on par with a C-grade, at least when it came to mana. He directly engaged in a battle of environmental control with the shark as he met it in melee once more. Jake had had a good few exchanges, allowing him to build some Hunting Momentum, but it was not yet time to use it.

The two of them clashed several more times, both taking damage, with Jake being slowly pushed back by the larger foe. While he was building up for something, he knew the shark was, too. However, as things were, he would gladly take advantage of learning some of his foe’s patterns.

An attack he had seen many times before was used. It was one where the shark tried to smash him with the side of its body and then follow up with a quick spin and a tail-swipe, though the spin was actually just a feint. Jake allowed himself to be hit, even if he could have easily avoided it, and used the momentum from the blow to get shot a bit deeper into the water.

Already having committed to the move, the shark was not fast enough to react when Jake used One Step and appeared right beneath its belly. With one hand, he stabbed Eternal Hunger into its body, and with the other, he stabbed once to break the teeth armor. In a fluid motion, Jake dismissed the katar on that hand and punched forward again, penetrating the wound he had just made with his hand.

He felt the muscles of the shark close around it, and his arm got stuck. Jake gritted his teeth as Touch of the Malefic Viper activated, pumping toxic energy directly into the guts of the beast. At the same time, Jake took control of the hemotoxic energy within it and forced it towards its heart. He had already thoroughly scanned his foe, understanding its physiology and where to hit. All of this was simply a setup for the final blow.

Realizing that Jake was doing far more damage than expected, the shark reacted violently. It began spinning around in the water, with the current sphere flowing in the opposite direction of the spin. The teeth on its skin also began shooting out toward Jake, and the shark shook his body in violent ways.

Jake held on as long as he could. However, the arm inside the shark’s body was fully stuck, the shark still not wanting to let him go. The teeth on its skin began growing towards the arm and dug into it. But it didn’t stop there. The teeth began growing into the arm itself, and, more frighteningly, Jake felt an odd sensation in his body… like his very blood was being manipulated.

As blood began pouring from his eyes and nose, Jake made an executive decision. Without any hesitation, he used Eternal Hunger to cut off the still-stuck hand that had been embedded into the shark just below the elbow. The blood manipulation stopped instantly as Jake kicked off the massive body of the shark, swimming away from it.

As he flew back, Jake used his necklace to deposit a healing potion into his mouth, which he naturally consumed instantly. Dense vital energy entered his body, flowing through his bloodstream and into the severed arm as it worked to reconstruct it.

Jake momentarily stopped up. Blood and healing… Fuck, not now.

The shark came for him again, trying to press its advantage. Jake’s plan was slightly thrown off course, but he could correct it. Retreating, Jake bought time for his arm to regrow as he attempted to not get pinned down and eaten. Unable to properly use his bow, Jake switched to mainly using arcane magic and Eternal Hunger. One had to add that the healing from Eternal Hunger was one of those things he usually didn’t notice due to its passive nature, but it was not something to underestimate. Granted, Jake was underutilizing the mythical weapon and was far from able to properly make use of it, but just the lifesteal effect brought his longevity in combat to another level.

He ended up tanking many hits as he protected his left side, where an arm and hand were slowly growing out. Jake spent mana like it was no object trying to keep the shark at bay, shooting off endless barrages of stable arcane bolts. The explosive ones did nothing, but he had found that hyper-sharp stable bolts penetrated the teeth-hide and caused damage.

One Step was also used liberally to take him away and constantly create distance. In the end, it was impossible to avoid taking any damage, and his body was littered with wounds after only a few minutes. But it was good enough.

The shark, drunk on momentum, did not show any caution as it charged. Jake, having regenerated his arm and hand, pulled out his bow. Surprise flashed in the eyes of the C-grade as Jake grinned and charged Arcane Powershot. Having already committed, the shark did not slow down but instead sped up and opened its maw. A dense barrier of water formed, the entire sphere shifting and gathering in front of the shark. It churned and spun, aiming to cut everything apart, including any arrows Jake would shoot at it.

Jake focused to the extreme as Steady Aim activated at its fullest. When the Arcane Powershot was charged to near-full power, he released an explosive arcane arrow. By the time the supercharged arrow hit the barrier and exploded, Jake had already pulled out a second, far larger arrow.

This one looked nearly like a drill. It was entirely white and far longer than the one he’d shot before, with several odd markings on its body. It was an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter, and with the barrier gone, he shot it fast without even using Arcane Powershot.

The shark was ready and prepared to dodge. Jake had been waiting for this moment. Through the arcane energy filling the water, Jake laid eyes upon the large shark and used Gaze of the Apex Hunter for the first time in the fight. The C-grade froze, unable to dodge the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter… but this attack was not the true finisher.

Jake charged forward after the arrow, pushing both of his wings to the extreme to build up speed. The shark was not ready at all when the arrow entered its mouth. It was even less prepared when a charging human was about to do the same. Just as Jake reached the mouth of the beast, he took out both katars and activated all his Hunting Momentum built up so far.

His entire body filled with the concept, shooting him forward even faster into the mouth of the C-grade shark. The arrow had done plenty of damage, and Jake beelined for his target: the heart. Just as he entered the body of the shark, Gaze wore off. The beast had only been stunned for a second, but in that second, the battle had entirely changed. The momentum had switched.

Upon entering the shark’s mouth, it became clear why it was keen on eating things. Jake had entered a maelstrom of teeth and incredibly fast currents that began cutting his entire body apart. With full power, Jake used the bone katar to punch forward, then released a Descending Dark Arcane Fang to cut through the inner walls of flesh to make his way to the heart.

The Hunting Momentum was all spent, but it allowed him to reach his target. Jake finally saw the heart and stabbed Eternal Hunger into it. The bone dagger disappeared from his other hand as he used Touch of the Malefic Viper with it, controlling and redirecting all the hemotoxic poison in the C-grade’s body to the heart.

Pre-system, Hemotoxins had primarily thinned the blood. Post-system, they had a similar effect, but on vital energy. Blood was a vessel for vital energy and remained thinned, but the vital energy itself was also far thinner and flowed more easily out of the body, along with its decreased efficiency. So what happened when Jake plunged what was effectively a metal straw into his opponent’s container of highly thinned vital energy?

He finally gave Eternal Hunger a good meal.

Razor-sharp teeth still flew all around Jake as he was cut up, but he stood his ground, each wound healing as fast as it came. The vital energies streamed into Jake through Eternal Hunger as the shark thrashed and tried to kill him. Intense pressure, long teeth trying to kill him, and even the flesh walls themselves closed in on Jake, but the shark was fighting a losing battle. Eternal Hunger greedily enjoyed its feast as the shark’s struggles slowed and then stopped.

Jake felt the stream of vital energy halt, and then everything went silent. The teeth around him floated harmlessly as the body of the shark began withering and wrinkling from the inside.

*You have slain [Razorstream Shark – lvl 202] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 194 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 191 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

With ease, Jake cut his way out the top of the shark. With the beast dead, its body was weak and unable to resist even a casual slash. Jake looked at the shark and scanned it for any treasures, only to find… nothing. No, wait. On closer inspection, he found an uncommon-rarity tooth.

He had felt it from the aura of the beast, but this hammered it home… Razorstream Sharks were low-tier beasts. They were firmly on the weaker end of C-grades. Jake just sucked at fighting underwater. This had been the toughest fight since the Phantomshade Panther… and it was an opponent he would have trashed if they had fought in the air.

"Are you finally done?" Sandy asked him, happily swimming over. Well, the worm did not really swim, but seemed to still partly be swimming through space. It was a bit slower, though.

"Yes, I am done…" Jake said with exasperation.

"Would it make you happy if I said I was proud of you for killing the fish?"

"No, not really," Jake said curtly.

"Good, because I am not… You move so weirdly down here. You really gotta work on that at some point.”

Jake shook his head. "Just eat me already; let’s get out of here. And no more underwater adventures.”

"Fine—I don’t really like the stuff down here anyway. Too watery for my taste.”

Jake wanted to smack the worm for convincing him to go down there to begin with.

Sandy ate him up, and once Jake was inside, he deactivated Arcane Awakening and let the weakness flood him. Okay, even if he complained, the fight had actually been good practice, and it had allowed him to test one of the many techniques he had theorized. The entire Touch-controlled Hemotoxin into big slurp by Eternal Hunger had not been made up on the spot, but considered for a while.

He had also gotten a flash of inspiration related to Blood of the Malefic Viper. All in all, it had been a worthwhile fight, but he still wanted to avoid doing that shit again. At least until he had a better way to fight down there.

Jake took a deep breath and got on with things, as he felt a certain someone waiting for him in his Soulspace. Not wanting to make himself wait—because he knew he could be a bit impatient—Jake used Serene Soul Meditation to enter his Soulspace to talk to his other self.

Chapter 41

A Bloody Mystery

"The fighting style itself cannot reasonably include a method to nullify negative environmental effects… We will need something else for that,” sim-Jake said. “There was potential in Pride of the Malefic Viper, but we need a proper method to not find ourselves in a similar situation.”

"Easier said than done, considering these kinds of enemies rely on their environments and will actively try and break down any defenses you have made against them,” Jake argued. “I could likely have made an arcane barrier isolating myself from the water pressure, but the shark would’ve instantly tried to destroy it for its magic to work.”

"I never said it was easy, just that it needs to be done,” sim-Jake said, mulling over the issue. “Maybe figure out how others do it. Though I will admit that it is a major hurdle. Moving in water is simply not optimal with the human body, and it eliminates all footwork and weakens every attack. I can see using the destructive arcane energy as a way to partly eliminate the pressure at all times, especially when striking, but that also creates problems."

"Sustainability." Jake nodded.

"Exactly."

The mana cost from infusing every movement with mana would be too much for him to bear, and they both knew it.

"A solution will have to be found at some point," sim-Jake concluded.

"Naturally," Jake agreed before asking something that had been on his mind. "What happened, by the way? Not to be rude, but you were on your way out the last time we met. Now, you are more you once more. What changed?"

"Honestly," sim-Jake said, “you should know it. I am you, and you are me, and not existing is one of the thoughts that we fear on a very base level. When I did feel myself begin to fade away and become nothing, something triggered in me. A sense of survival, even though I know that remerging with you is still me surviving. I guess you can just say that I don’t wanna die. After meeting Sandy, seeing Earth transformed—and more than just that boring mansion in the Order and the occasional mind-numbing alchemy lesson—I realized that I still want to enjoy at least a few more adventures."

Jake had indeed kind of known this was the case, but he’d wanted to ask anyway, as he wasn’t entirely sure what his other self was thinking. "But this doesn’t mean the merging stopped."

"No, that it does not. But let us just say that I will immortalize myself one way or another. You won’t be rid of me that easily. Luckily, too, because there is more to improve in our fighting style than I originally estimated, and two heads are better than one. Ah, and don’t worry—our new Vault skill will come, even if I know that the Records of that skill keep me alive right now. Keep me… me."

"Just don’t begin to get any fancy ideas about taking over the body and replacing me," Jake said, smirking.

"We both know that won’t happen. I can’t. Your Records trump mine so many times over it isn’t even funny. Being best buds with Villy is just cheating.” Sim-Jake snickered in return. "Now go back to Sandy’s stomach and get to work. I have business to attend to."

Jake shrugged and complied as he exited his Soulspace, leaving sim-Jake behind.

Sim-Jake did not immediately begin practicing; instead, he went towards the chimera of pure curse energy. It looked satisfied after having a feast and didn’t even react as sim-Jake laid a hand on it. Closing his eyes, energy moved between them for a few minutes before he nodded and returned to improving the Vault skill.

Jake, in the outside world, had not seen any of this happen. He was busy getting back the glove he had lost in the body of the shark. Rather than needing to retrieve the physical object, Jake could use the remaining glove to regrow the other one on his formerly severed hand. It would have been cheaper to just retrieve the glove, but he had honestly forgotten about it, as the item had turned inert after he cut off the hand. Sandy had already shot above the water and was flying through the sky, so turning back was not an option either.

Watching it reform on his hand over the next hour was relatively interesting. It was all system fuckery to the extreme, but he was not complaining. Once the glove was back in his hand—and put on his hand—Jake turned his attention to something perhaps even more important.

During the fight with the shark, he’d had a eureka moment. More accurately, as he’d felt his blood flow and carry the vital energies, he had questioned something.

Blood was a damn great vessel for energy. It was what made Blood of the Malefic Viper such a potent skill, and why there were many creatures you could slay to turn their blood into valuable items. Vampires, too, consumed blood due to its richness and purity of vital energy. All in all, blood was essentially a naturally occurring, treasure-tier liquid found within most biological lifeforms.

Its usual effect was carrying vital energy through the body more efficiently. Heck, this was why regenerating dozens of holes in the body was easier than healing a severed hand, even if the pure mass of flesh one had to heal was larger. Regenerating the hand relied mostly on transporting energy through the Soulshape, while holes in the body could be supplied with blood in the nearby area to heal faster. Healing potions also instantly attached themselves to the blood of the body and used that to find where they were most efficiently used. Because the body naturally knew where the vital energy was needed.

Blood was clearly tied to vital energy, and vital energy came from Vitality. Blood of the Malefic Viper even gave Vitality, and it was a fact that someone with more Vitality could produce more blood than someone that had a lower stat. All of those things were true, and yet Blood of the Malefic Viper had nada to do with vital energy at all.

[Blood of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)] – The blood of the Malefic Viper is a toxin more deadly than most poisons. Allows the Prodigious Alchemist of the Malefic Viper to turn their blood poisonous, imitating their Patron. It has been further improved, even carrying traces of the True Blood of the Malefic One within. The blood can be used as an ingredient in alchemy and as a deadly weapon against your foes. The nature of the poison is determined based on the Records of the Alchemist. The blood’s toxicity level is based primarily on Vitality and Wisdom but receives an increase from all physical stats. Passively provides 1 Vitality per level in Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your blood be forever the bane of all that wishes you harm.

The more Jake thought about it, the less it made sense. The skill gave him Vitality, but nothing about the skill seemed to truly indicate it had anything to do with the stat. For all other skills, he saw it make far more sense, but not with this one. Heck, the toxicity of the infused blood scaled with Vitality and Wisdom. They were equal when it came to scaling, but with all other skills, the stat it offered was also the one that empowered the skill the most.

Jake reflected a bit on the skill. He had first gotten it at epic rarity and then upgraded to ancient after the Trial of Myriad Toxins by absorbing the drop of blood from Villy. That had been the catalyst, and what was that drop of blood?

It was a fragment of Records. It was knowledge given physical form, which could also be seen with how it was tied to Sagacity. So the upgrade path Jake had taken back then was making the blood better when used and giving it far more scope. The part about carrying traces of the True Blood of the Malefic One was a buff when it came to alchemy too. All of this made Jake think he had missed something obvious.

He began experimenting right away to try out his theory. Jake could not truly control the blood he infused, and he had always used it as an external tool, either as an ingredient or a weapon. However, last he checked, blood was meant to be inside the body, so would there not be an application there?

Focusing, he infused the blood inside his body as usual. This time, he tried to control it—something usually not needed, as the blood adapted according to his will after being added to a mixture. It was more difficult than Jake expected, and he ended up having to apply some methods from his usual alchemy, effectively turning his body into a cauldron and the blood in his body into the batch. But rather than a poison, Jake wanted to make a health potion.

The result? Him spending the better part of an hour experiencing only failure. The worst part was that Jake knew what he was missing; he just couldn’t fix it. He needed to properly infuse more active vital energy into the blood, but he couldn’t control the process—at least, not satisfactorily. As he wondered what to do, Jake got a brilliant idea.

Taking out Eternal Hunger, Jake proceeded to cut off his hand once more and consume a health potion. Vital energy flooded his body and, as usual, bound itself to his blood. Jake then began the process again, but rather than trying to infuse vital energy from scratch, Jake used the energy from the healing potion as a base and guide. He poisoned the healing potion liquid and tried to make it better. It went okay as he focused on healing the severed hand for the second time that day.

Once it was healed, Jake kept experimenting until the potion cooldown was ready, and he cut it off again. This continued for nearly an entire day, and he slowly began to form a coherent idea as he became more familiar with both his blood and vital energy.

He was still not quite certain about the purpose of what he was trying to achieve, besides making more active vital energy to make his blood better when it came to healing. Jake did feel like he made some progress, but he needed the healing potion every time to properly do it. The highly active energy in healing potions was the apex of vital energy due to the amount of system assistance it got, and Jake knew he could not actually replicate it, but he wanted to at least make some progress…

Or just make his usage of the healing potion better.

Another day passed, and Sandy didn’t ask him to come out a single time, even if the worm did find some stuff to steal here and there. It was understood that Jake did not want any more water combat, and Sandy, quite frankly, also didn’t seem to enjoy being underwater that much either.

This day was spent with Jake cutting off his arm a good forty or so times total, sometimes choosing not to use a healing potion as he healed it. He also tried inflicting injuries on himself in other places. He even took some of the venom from that Emperor Urchin that the whale had given him and consumed it. It was potent enough to deal noticeable damage, even if it was primarily of a neurotoxic nature. He needed it for Palate either way, so why not?

He began to feel like he was touching upon an idea, but he was still missing something. Jake was certain that with another week or so, he would have it down… but he wasn’t that patient when he had other options.

Do you wish to experience the Legacy of the Malefic Viper? Uses remaining: 2

Jake did not know if the charges would carry over to C-grade or if the skill changed, so he should use them all now, right? Also… he kind of liked learning about Villy. It was a bit like stalking your friends on social media for embarrassing photos from their teenage years, and Jake was all for it to get some ammunition to make fun of the god with.

With that in mind, Jake activated the skill and experienced another vision.

"I am once more incredibly impressed with your continued progress," the old man said as he smiled proudly. "To do all this without any dedicated alchemy skill…"

"Saying it is entirely without a skill isn’t correct, Master," the Viper in his human form said. "While it is true they are not dedicated alchemy skills, there are stark similarities."

"True. However, you specialize in poison, as per your heritage. This is the exact opposite of that.” The old man shook his head. "And yet it isn’t. As unsightly as it is, an old man like me does find it enviable to have such heavenly gifts. A body that is an alchemical ingredient in itself."

Jake was confused as he observed the scene playing out in front of him. He saw the Viper sitting with a cauldron inside of a large stone chamber, the old man scrutinizing his work. Moreover, the Viper said a word Jake could have never imagined the Viper would say… He had called the old man Master. He also felt like the Viper was pretty young in this vision, but he wasn’t sure if it was the youngest he had seen him. It had to be close.

"And I wish I had Master’s knowledge of alchemy.” The Viper smiled.

The old man chuckled. "I have no doubt you will surpass this old man in due time. You will learn all I have to teach with the time I have left."

A sense of sadness came over the room as the Viper frowned.

"There is no reason to be sad," the old man soothed the Viper. "Time will claim all, but we enlightened races have our own Path to immortality. As long as our knowledge remains, so shall we remain. The Records of the multiverse are forever. Any who die, have lived, and will ever live are eternal."

"Easy for you to call knowledge eternal… Why not pursue actual immortality?" Villy scoffed.

"Because knowledge can be both a curse and a gift, and your old Master had decided his Path.” The old man shook his head at the would-be Primordial. "Now stop dallying and explain to me the process of what you are attempting to do."

"Fine," the Viper said as he looked down at what he had just brewed. "So, the thought process behind this attempt was to…"

Jake listened but began to zone out, even if he knew he should be listening. He couldn’t stop himself as he stared more at the old man and faintly noticed something. Something that was barely detectable, perhaps due to the nature of the vision… The old man had a Bloodline. That in itself was noteworthy, but what stood out more was that it felt familiar. He had seen it before, which made no sense. Because the one who Jake remembered having the Bloodline was also present in the room.

This old man had the same Bloodline as the Malefic Viper.

Chapter 42

What Even is a Health Potion?

Jake was absolutely certain of one thing: two identical Bloodlines could not exist. Even if someone with a Bloodline had a child, the child would have their own Bloodline with its own unique signature. One would be able to feel the difference between two family members even if the effects of their Bloodlines were identical.

But the old man had the exact same Bloodline as Villy. Jake completely zoned out of their discussion as he tried to figure out how the hell this was possible. It was impossible for the Viper to somehow be the kid of this old man, and one could not give their Bloodlines to others, as the Bloodline resided in the Truesoul. Only the system could give a Bloodline, the Viper had said. So Jake saw only one explanation.

The Viper had gained this old man’s Bloodline sometime after he had died. Assuming the Viper had been truthful when he said he got his Bloodline after reaching godhood, then it had to be a lot of time afterward. However, this also raised some questions. Had the Viper requested this Bloodline? If he had, then it had to be a powerful Bloodline, and if it was a powerful Bloodline, then why was the old man stuck at peak C-grade and talking about his time soon being up? Maybe it was just Jake being biased, but he assumed anyone with a truly powerful Bloodline should at least be able to break through to B-grade.

I will definitely have an interesting talk with Villy after this, Jake confirmed to himself as he began to actually focus on the vision at hand.

It was just the Viper explaining what he was doing, and what he was doing was trying to make a healing poison using his blood. The Viper talked about how it was hard to fully isolate the vital energies in the blood, both before he put it in the cauldron and when it was in there.

Jake listened in attentively and quickly got the gist of it, as he had been struggling with the same thing during the last few days. His issue was that the Blood of the Malefic Viper-infused blood was so tied to him that it was difficult to make it more untied. This was not usually a problem with poison, as it was just a catalyst and got infused into all the other materials, but in this case, he wanted it to be a primary ingredient.

As for why he wanted it? He wanted to make a "better" health potion that acted faster and maybe didn’t even trigger the potion cooldown. One that could help him heal a wound incredibly fast and resonate with his Blood of the Malefic Viper. He also just wanted to see if he could upgrade Blood to allow him to heal faster in general.

The health potion was more a representation of what he wanted—a way to practice isolating and controlling the vital energy in his blood—than the primary objective. The Viper said the same as he explained how he wanted to better control his vital energies and blood in general.

The old man chuckled again. "I find it interesting how you try to create a health potion when that is not truly what you want to make. Controlling your blood better is only one piece of the puzzle, and you will never be able to infuse enough vital energy into the blood to heal fast enough for what you want. If you want that, you need to heal yourself in the ethereal realm—heal your Soulshape—and not your physical body. But we both know the inefficiency in that… so what you truly want is a way for your body to do what you want it to, and for more vital energy to work at once. A healing potion does supercharge you with vital energy, true, but what is the biggest obstacle when trying to infuse your blood to heal you faster?"

"Time," the Viper instantly said. "But a health potion fixes that; I just need it to—"

"Why does it need to be a health potion, and why do you need to infuse your blood every time?" the old man asked pointedly.

"I am not sure I get it," the Viper said. "I need a health potion for it to heal… I have tried making toxins that heal me, but it never works. And I need to infuse my blood every time for the vital energy to be properly carried in it."

"Is that because your blood is bad at carrying energy?"

"Well, it is good at carrying energy, but only toxic energies… But… I think I understand what you are getting at. You want me to attune my blood to better carry vital energy, but won’t that just be a step backward after I improved it to better carry mana?"

"Vital energy, mana, stamina… Why do we have to put a label on everything? Why do we need to define what a poison and a healing potion are anyway? The system shall handle all the definitions we need; we just need to force our own understanding. Who is to say a poison cannot be a healing potion and a healing potion cannot be a poison? Ask yourself, who is it meant to heal? If it only needs to heal one person, why does it matter if it is poison or not? As long as it to you is a healing potion, the system shall respect your will.”

The old man smiled, then opened his palm as an orb of energy appeared. Jake felt the intense vital energy from it as it suddenly changed into mana, and then into stamina, and back into vital energy again. With a swipe of his hand, the vital energy suddenly spread throughout the room and hit the walls, making cracks appear all over them. Another pulse of pure stamina was released that somehow repaired the walls. No, had it not been mana there, right at the end? Jake wasn’t sure…

"Energy is energy; as long as you have one, you have them all,” the old man said. “You think too much about making your blood work with one or the other when you need it to work with all of them. Your body is your temple, and you decide the design. Your blood is a part of your body, just like any other element. If you can control how your hand moves, how fast your heart beats, and know how to smile like you are right now… you can dictate what your blood is. Within reason, of course."

Jake barely considered the words, as he was still stuck on what the actual fuck the old man had done before when he demonstrated the energies. The level of energy control he deployed was… not normal. As in, absolutely bonkers. Jake had no idea how the hell he had done what he did. Jake could also change mana into vital energy and vice versa, but that was a long and arduous process when crafting. Not what the old man had just done, where he morphed the energies effortlessly in seconds. No, less than seconds.

The Viper also stared at the old man as his eyes shone with enlightenment. Jake then felt himself truly merge with the Viper, and he instantly noticed some differences. Jake’s blood was not toxic by default, but infused with heavy doses of vital energy, while the Viper’s blood primarily had poison in it. He naturally healed from Vitality-based poisons in his body, whereas Jake healed from regular vital energy.

It was nearly the opposite of Jake, as Jake had to put effort into making his blood toxic, and Villy had to put effort into making it nontoxic. But what the Viper did now was more or less prime the blood. Make it far more malleable to other energies, using the system’s assistance to make it all possible. This instantly made the level of toxicity in his blood rise, and Jake did not hesitate to join in as he mimicked the Viper—but with the opposite result.

His blood became more filled with vital energy as he repeated the process of what the Viper did. Yet he also felt like all poison made from it would be more potent. When Jake infused Blood of the Malefic Viper with mana and turned it toxic, he was just using the mana as a catalyst to change the vital energy. It was all a process that was now being refined and improved.

One could almost say the blood became thicker. Better at carrying energy than before. It did come with the cost of each drop of blood being more valuable, and hence Jake or the Viper losing more health points upon being wounded and bleeding… but the tradeoff was worth it, and it wasn’t a one-to-one increase either. Because Jake also felt that each health point now counted ever so slightly more.

Moreover, the total capacity of the blood changed, as it was ready to receive energy at any point.

The old man came with a few comments here and there as Jake and the Viper both meditated. About half an hour passed before the Viper opened his eyes, smiling from success. Jake was still not there and about to curse… but then time rewound till just about when the Viper began meditating, skipping the first conversation.

This time around, Jake got it, and as he willed it, the scene rewound the third time to show the entire starting talk. The Viper and old man chatted as Jake just listened in, still feeling the changes in his body. A bit later, the vision ended, and Jake returned to the real world with an upgraded skill and a lot of questions.

Jake appeared within Sandy’s stomach, the worm not even asking where he had gone this time. Without further ado, he checked out the upgrade.

[Blood of the Malefic Viper (Ancient --> Legendary)] – The blood of the Malefic Viper is a toxin more deadly than most poisons and the lifeblood of an immortal being. Allows the Alchemist to infuse their blood with energy to turn their blood poisonous, imitating their Patron and even carrying traces of the True Blood of the Malefic One within. The blood can be used as an ingredient in alchemy or as a deadly weapon against your foes. The nature of the poison is determined based on the Records of the Alchemist. Allows your blood to carry more energy than usual, including vital energy, passively speeding up regeneration. This effect is further amplified when consuming a health potion or other sources of beneficial vital energy. The blood’s toxicity level is based primarily on Vitality and Wisdom but receives an increase from all physical stats. Increase in natural regeneration based on total health pool. Passively provides 3 Vitality per level in Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your blood be forever the bane of all that wishes you harm and that which brings you eternal life.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 189 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 190 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 192 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

It was as expected, for the most part. The two levels were a nice surprise, as Jake had only expected a single one. For the skill itself, a bit of the wording had changed here and there, but the big takeaways were that the blood now carried more energy than before, and that the effect was further amplified when using a healing potion. But it still specified that what Jake did when he infused his blood was turn it poisonous. He could not simply infuse it with more vital energy if he wanted to when he used the skill.

To add on, due to his blood now passively carrying more vital energy, it increased his natural regeneration. He could feel it wasn’t by much, but it was there, and the entire increase in regeneration was based on his total health pool.

Finally, there was also an increase in Vitality for each level. Considering Jake was near the end of D-grade, the instant influx of stats was huge, especially considering Vitality was the stat in which he had the second-best percentage amplifier due to the Bloodline Patriarch title and Blessing of the Malefic Viper both including it.

With a touch of excitement, Jake cut off the hand for the hundredth or so time over the last few days. He instantly felt his vital energy move as it began naturally regenerating. It healed faster than before, no doubt about it, but it wasn’t like it just suddenly popped out. He would estimate it was about twenty-five percent faster, with the vital energy consumption about ten percent higher to achieve the same effect. Health point-wise, he lost about the same.

After he fully healed the hand, he repeated chopping it off again and then drank a potion. This time around, the change was noticeable. Before the upgrade, it had taken Jake a few minutes to heal a hand, but now?

He watched intently as what appeared like blood vessels grew into thin air. Soon, they transformed into bones. Flesh grew on the bones, and his hand reformed. The entire process took only thirty to forty seconds, and Jake nodded, knowing this was not the best it could be.

Taking out his cauldron, he got to work. The vision had not been solely about transforming his blood, but also about how to use it. To make full use of it. One of the objectives had been to make a healing potion, after all.

When Jake usually made a healing potion, he didn’t use any Blood of the Malefic Viper. His blood was inherently a poison; there was no way around it, and even this upgrade did not change that. Jake made healing potions according to the methods he had read in books and followed the recipes to the T since, well, it worked. He had never even considered using his blood over purified water when making a health potion. Not that Jake hadn’t tried to make beneficial things with his blood, as he had mimicked the Viper and tried to make a Vitality-based poison that could help heal him. One that could even circumvent the potion cooldown.

Jake now realized that the entire thought process was flawed. Health potions worked because they were health potions, not because of all the ingredients put into them. When Jake tried to make these poisons of vital energy, he—and the Viper, from the sounds of it—had missed the most essential ingredient of a health potion: a truckload of system fuckery.

Without further ado, Jake began the crafting process of a health potion. The only true change was that Jake poured in his blood as the base rather than water. He knew that he first had to prime the blood and make it focused on vital energy, which was indeed what he started out by doing. Once the liquid was ready, Jake just did as he usually did when making a health potion, following the recipe to the letter.

And as usual, the process was straightforward. Perhaps a bit more challenging than usual, but not by much, and after only failing two brews, Jake succeeded.

*You have successfully crafted [Malefic Health Potion (Common)] – A new kind of creation has been made. Bonus experience earned*

Jake looked at the batch and bottled up some of the liquid. It was red, just like a normal health potion, but he did get a slight reaction from Sense of the Malefic Viper when looking at it, making it clear this was poisonous. Using Identify on the potion, though, he was surprised.

[Malefic Health Potion (Common)] - Restores 22,310 health when consumed. Will cause damage to anyone besides the creator if consumed.

Jake stared at it for a while. Everything was pretty much as expected, and what Jake had made was poison to anyone who was not him. The rarity was common as expected, too. Jake knew that rarity was based solely on the amount of resources a potion restored, and after entering the Academy, he had learned that the minimum for uncommon-rarity potions was a hundred thousand resources restored. Yet the number still stood out.

This was the first health potion Jake had ever made that restored over twenty thousand health, and it had instantly jumped to twenty-two thousand. It was about a twenty-five percent increase from his usual max… About the same as what his natural regeneration had increased by.

After putting all the liquid in bottles, Jake—once again—cut off his hand. With great expectations, he chugged the new health potion. It did not disappoint.

Blood vessels instantly sprang out into thin air, forming a red hand shape where it was supposed to be, and flesh grew on the bones within seconds. The red shape filled out, and skin grew over it all. Finally, with a simple mental command, Jake equipped the glove.

Seven seconds.

From drinking the potion to fully regenerating a hand, it had taken him seven seconds. Jake grinned from ear to ear to himself at the result, as one of his biggest weaknesses—amputation—had been significantly addressed. He was more than happy with the upgrade and also felt that the blood was now overall more potent in every way, which would empower all poisons he made by a little. All in all, great stuff.

With all of that done, Jake moved on to the final thing: his talk with Villy.

Chapter 43

The First Sage

He reached out and instantly felt the connection form. "Hey, Villy, I—"

"Jake, just know that Duskleaf and I are both here for you in your time of need,” Villy said, his voice descending with the fakest tone of concern Jake had ever heard. “You do not need to resort to self-harm like that, okay? We are willing to talk, so you can stop cutting your hand off. It has suffered enough… No, you have suffered enough."

"Ha, ha, very funny," Jake responded. Just because Jake had cut off his hand a hundred times or so over the last few days didn’t mean he was into self-harm.

Well, except if it was productive self-harm, in which case he was all for it.

"Heh, so, got a good upgrade this time around? From a cursory glance, it seems like you finally managed to upgrade Blood. I had quite honestly expected that to be one of the first ones, considering you stole a drop from me.”

"Yep, I got it, as well as a vision…"

"Spill it. What kind of embarrassing moment did it show you now? Oh, I know. Is it this time I filled an entire lake with my blood and turned it into a ‘healing potion’ to help the local wildlife, only to poison them all and end up killing off an entire army, to then just get pushed out of the area by a giant weasel that was immune to my toxins?"

"No, but I am sure there is an interesting story there. This vision was quite a bit more relaxed but far more intriguing. First of all… I didn’t know you once had someone you called Master?" Jake couldn’t help sounding somewhat teasing. "You seemed to respect him a lot, too. Truly a loyal disciple."

A few seconds passed. "I have had several people whom I would call Master throughout my life. But based on me actually showing genuine respect, only one comes to mind. The original owner of my Bloodline."

"That is the one," Jake said. "So, what is the story there? I have so many questions."

In a very out-of-character serious and melancholic tone, Villy said, "You know, Jake… you are the first one besides my wife to ever know about him. Not even the other Primordials are aware he existed.

"I never even learned his name, only knowing his title. He was simply known as the First Sage. For reference, the country he belonged to had sages as their elders, of sorts, and he was naturally the highest-ranked one. He, too, was alive when the system arrived, and was already an accomplished, if troubled man. I took quite a bit longer to progress through the grades than many others and, quite honestly, fell behind. The area of the planet I was from was considered weak and desolate, so by the time I reached C-grade, the world was already full of them. However, on my planet at the time, there was no doubt who the most powerful person was. He was a man who I believed I could fool, and I wanted to take advantage of him to teach me alchemy. The old man saw through my disguise like nothing and instantly knew I was the feared Wyvern of the Desolates. But what did he do? He invited me in for tea."

Villy spoke with far more emotion than Jake was used to, making him just shut up.

"He was intrigued by my skills and wanted to learn more about me,” Villy continued. “Tell me, Jake—from what you saw, did he strike you as a talented alchemist?"

"For sure," Jake said. The old man had been insanely talented and was no doubt—

"He wasn’t one. In fact, he never truly chose to specialize anywhere but always ended up pursuing new things. On top of that, he was not a fighter—not because he couldn’t fight, but because he chose not to. I understood why. There was not a single entity on our planet that stood a sliver of a chance against him."

"I don’t understand… If he was this strong and talented, along with having a Bloodline, why didn’t he evolve into B-grade? Or did he end up evolving?"

"No, he died still in peak C-grade," Villy answered, exasperation clear in his voice. "To this day, it still troubles me. I actually think meeting him was one of the reasons I even managed to become a god. Jake, you are talented, but this man… was something more. Your talents are bizarre but specialized, while he was a universal genius. A jack of all trades, master of all. With no effort, any skill he had would reach legendary rarity and beyond. It was like he didn’t truly exist within the world like the rest of us. As if he stood above it and observed. By the time I was in peak C-grade, I knew I still would not have stood a chance against him. Not that I would have after just evolving to B-grade, either… He was a monster. Far more than I."

"I am just getting more and more confused here," Jake said. "Why not evolve, then? What stopped him?"

"Nothing except his own will. He… chose not to evolve. As I said, to this day, it still troubles and frustrates me. He could have evolved, and truthfully, I do not doubt he would have become a god. But he had no desire to be one. He had barely any desire at all. Like such desires were beneath him, or perhaps just not something he cared about. I partly understood why, for he was also pained. Tortured. He did not wish to keep living, and to him, perhaps immortality would have been a curse."

Jake’s frown only deepened, but he didn’t interrupt without getting asked.

"The First Sage taught me only for about a decade. During this time, I never left his side and took in everything like a sponge. My alchemy reached levels I had never even imagined, but more than that, he helped refine my mindset. If you haven’t noticed, I like to find ways to take advantage of the system. This man was the one who originally instilled those thoughts into me. He was also the first one to teach me what a Transcendent was. He was a premier scholar in all things system, and what he discovered back then is now common knowledge throughout the multiverse. The knowledge that man had was out of this world… and before you ask, yes, he was a Transcendent. Not just one, either… I learned of four Transcendent skills he possessed, but he might have had more I never knew about. Wanna hear the funniest thing? One of them was made with the express purpose of shortening his lifespan.

"If you think that one of the reasons for his blight was his Bloodline, then you would be entirely correct. I have told you it is not one that offers combat power, and that is true. In fact, many would call its effects rather mundane, if not useless. I have never told you what it does, and I guess it is about time I tell you, considering how much I know about yours."

Jake would be lying if he said he wasn’t curious. Especially after hearing so much about the original owner.

"Its name is short and sweet: Bloodline of the Immortal Mind. It gives no stats, no boosts to anything… besides one thing. It gives perfect memory." Villy left a pause, allowing Jake to predictably ask…

"But don’t you get that already with high enough stats?"

"You do, which is why many find the Bloodline useless and unnecessary. I will also admit that I was critical of it, as the First Sage explained, but I have come to believe it was a big contributor to his power. Allow me to explain. As I said, like me, he existed before the system arrived, and yet he had a Bloodline that allowed perfect memory, which makes me question if perhaps this allowed him to know and remember things the system never intended for anyone to be aware of."

"Is that why you wanted it? Wait, how did you even get it?" Jake asked, confused.

"As I said, I got it from a system event after becoming a god. It was a bit like your tutorial, and in the end, you could request a reward. I asked for the Bloodline of the First Sage, and to my surprise, the system gave it. Not cheaply, but cheaper than expected. Once more, I felt like the old man had expected this to someday happen.”

"I see. Why did you leave your first master? I cannot believe you learned everything from him in only a few years."

"I did not," Villy said, hesitant to continue.

"Then why?"

"I told you my first master was peculiar, and it was only at the end I realized his true purpose in making me his student. You see, he was obsessed with Records to a probably unhealthy level and wanted to ensure that even after death, they remained known. To him, they were the truly perfect form of memory. The memory of the world itself. I don’t know how or why, but he clearly believed that I would be able to reach the pinnacle and thus chose me. He wanted to immortalize his existence through me and through the system." Villy sighed, and with sadness in his voice, he continued, "The old man had only ever asked me one favor, and it came in those final days. The only thing he ever asked me was to remember him and absorb his Records once and for all. He asked me to kill him.

"It was also only then that I truly became aware of how much he suffered. You see, usually, memories are controlled. Your brain only pulls something up when you need to remember it, but for the First Sage, it wasn’t like this. He remembered everything all the time. Don’t even begin to think you can comprehend what that is like. He spent ages simply becoming able to function. But what truly made him suffer was remembering all that once was. Every little negative thing, every setback, every period of grief he experienced every day. Do you think negativity bias is bad for normal humans? For him, it was all-consuming. He never showed it, not truly, but after I got the Bloodline myself, I understood. It is said time heals all wounds, and trauma and grief eventually fade… To him, every second of every day was filled with those emotions, as though he’d experienced them mere moments before.”

Jake got an odd feeling from that, as though he was not only talking about his old master, but himse—

"Before you say it… Yes, I experience this negative downside too. However, there is a stark difference between him and me. First of all, I got the Bloodline after becoming a god and can handle all this far better. Second of all, I was not born with it and thus had ways to still separate it from the core of my being. Thirdly, and perhaps most important, his mindset differed from mine. He was more emotional on a base level, and he grieved more than I ever did. Even when I suffer, my first thought is not to grieve, but to try and fix the problem. I comfort myself with pretty lies of being able to find a solution. And I can admit that even if the Bloodline has downsides, the benefits it brings are also exemplary. I wanted it for a reason.”

"Did you… you know?" Jake asked.

"Yes. How could I not fulfill the one request my master ever made of me? I did not want to, but I respected him too much to refuse. However, as I said, I like my pretty little lies. He wanted to be immortal but not alive, and he found his Path through me. Today, he is forever immortalized through the Records of the multiverse, and to him, dying was simply a form of transcending above the mundane world. Transcending through me. I still remember his smile as his life faded, and that is the memory I choose to see over his times of suffering.”

Jake practically saw his sad smile on the other end. He just sat silently, not saying anything. He had never heard Villy speak this highly of anyone before, not even his fellow Primordials. There was always a quip in there, a joke about their shortcomings… but with this First Sage, there was only sad recognition.

Neither of them spoke for a while, even as the telepathic connection remained. Jake did not ask any of his usual questions, like if the Viper thought Jake would be able to match the old man if they were the same level or anything like that. Jake already knew that the answer wouldn’t be one he wanted to hear—not necessarily because it would be a no, but because of how pointless it was.

A minute or so more passed before Villy sighed. "The First Sage is the apex of why motivation and drive are important. He had the talent of a thousand geniuses but the will to claim power of none. There was no passion in anything he did, and he truly never cared to get stronger. There was only a sense of hopelessness, like the Path he once followed was impossible. Or perhaps, in death, he got exactly what he wanted. I truly don’t know, as even now, his mentality and mind are above my level of comprehension. All I know is that he was perhaps someone that was never meant to have existed, but I am glad that he did.”

"Next time we meet," Jake said with a smile, “let’s share a toast for the old man. While it was brief, I also learned some good stuff from him, and you are not the only one grateful he lived."

"Let’s do that," Villy said on the other side with a smile.

No more words were necessary, as the connection was cut off soon after that, leaving Jake alone inside the stomach of Sandy. His mind was still filled with thoughts as he considered everything. While Jake had to recognize the old man had him beaten in energy control… Jake was not aiming to be the best at everything.

He was fine with just being the best at killing things.

Feeling his distance from Sylphie and Haven, Jake triangulated it and concluded he would soon reach his goal. The mountains the Fallen King had made his home were close to the ocean, and they would get there as long as they continued straight ahead.

But before he reached his destination, he had some alchemy to do in preparation.

Villy cut off with the connection with Jake and smiled a bit to himself. Parts of his memory he had sealed away were now unleashed and flooded him as he remembered times he had chosen to forget. There were many things he did not tell Jake this time around, and he truly believed that was for the better.

Knowing of the First Sage was not necessarily a good thing. The comment about him perhaps being someone that never meant to exist was not just an offhand one. It wasn’t that it was bad he’d existed, but that his existence had never been intended.

Because something he had not told Jake was that the day he had killed the old man was not the final time he had seen him. The system took many forms when it appeared in front of people… Jake had described it as a monotone, humanoid figure. Some had described the system as a giant floating orb, others as winged beings, and others still as humanoid forms reminiscent of their own races.

As for Villy? Every time he saw the system appear in any form, he met his first master. If it was truly him, Villy did not know, as it didn’t act differently from any other system entity.

But he liked to think that the old man had achieved his goal. His own form of immortality.

Chapter 44

Annoyingly Complicated

As Jake and Sandy continued their journey over the ocean, Jake worked on the upcoming battle. His talk with Villy about the First Sage had been enlightening, and the upgraded Blood of the Malefic Viper would surely help with what he wanted to do. However, it was far from enough.

Unique Lifeforms were annoying opponents; Jake had no doubt about that. This particular Unique Lifeform he would encounter was one of ash and space magic, as far as he could tell. It did not have a physical body but was more like a living domain. The domain was its Soulshape and seemed to encompass a large area, allowing the Ashen Phantom Devourer to move its body—ash—anywhere within it. The domain itself could also move at a fast speed if it so desired, making it a truly nightmarish being to face.

There was probably more to its abilities, but Jake got enough of an idea of what he was facing just from what he had heard so far. What he was facing would effectively be a giant elemental without many of the usual weaknesses of elementals. It would be a master at fleeing, too, according to the information Miranda had given him, so simply attacking it would not end well, even if Jake and the King somehow got it in an ambush and went all out.

The plan Jake had formed was not to fight Ell’Hakan, but instead to kill the Ashen Phantom Devourer by teaming up with the Fallen King. However, to do this, they needed to make sure they could actually kill the damn thing. Jake did not know how strong Ell’Hakan truly was or if he would even be able to successfully kill him, as he was an annoying bastard who relied on more than just fighting. He had a nagging gut feeling that even if he, the King, and the Sword Saint went after the orange guy together, they would fail in killing him.

This is why Jake would instead try and take out the greatest asset this other Chosen had. No matter what, successfully recruiting a Unique Lifeform into your employ wasn’t easy, and losing it would be a major hit to his fighting power.

Going back to having to actually kill the Ashen Phantom Devourer, there was one major problem: It was a creature specializing in ash and space magic. Jake had seen what Neil could do and now what Sandy was capable of, and he was completely certain he would have no way to chase down a peak D-grade Unique Lifeform using space magic, even if it was injured.

The Fallen King had also mentioned this as the biggest obstacle, as, apparently, the King found himself slightly superior during their fights, primarily due to his home-field advantage. One had to remember that the King was, well, a king. He received benefits from an area he had claimed, which allowed him to come out on top. Far from enough to actually get a victory, though, and they were still nearly evenly matched. A single slipup from one party could break the balance, or if one of them managed a breakthrough of some kind by upgrading a skill, either of them could die … The King was more likely to succumb to this issue due to the Ashen Phantom Devourer’s superior escape skills.

This is where Jake came in. More accurately, his ability to be more than just a simple hunter with an arrow and bow. With his current toolkit, he had no way to kill this Ashen Phantom Devourer, and even teaming up with the King, they had no way to stop it, so Jake would work on this issue.

Like with the big blue mushroom once upon a time, Jake put on his thinking cap and began to theorize a solution. He needed to find a way to slow down the Unique Lifeform, but it couldn’t be something that would instantly make it want to run away.

Sleeping Night Toxin was out of the question. That poison was frankly only good against human-sized or smaller foes, and this Ashen Phantom Devourer was the opposite of small. By sheer volume, considering it was a living domain, the only creature he had met with a larger Soulshape had to be the whale. Probably the giant sand worms too, but he would not know before actually seeing his foe. Which led to another problem.

Jake did not know what he was facing. Not truly. It wasn’t like he could research his opponent either, as Unique Lifeforms had this annoying tendency to be unique. Samples were awesome when trying to make a counter to something, and getting a sample was absolutely impossible.

He had to make a general poison not aimed at any particular enemy yet able to affect all Soulshapes. It had to be able to limit the mobility of this Ashen Phantom Devourer, hopefully making it unable to flee with its giant, domain-like body. If not, then at least slow it down significantly.

To do this, Jake would clearly need very high-level material. He would also need a good quantity of it. As for the type? Well, Hemotoxins would not work. Necrotic Poison was also out of the question, as his opponent was not biological. So he would need it to be an ethtoxin—soul poison—or a neurotoxin. Ethtoxin and neurotoxin often went hand in hand, as ethtoxin was more a classification of many different kinds of soul poison.

Neurotoxin would definitely be good. He had also been researching it quite a lot, so he had some confidence.

As stated many times prior, Jake was not a fan of fate-talk, but… some things were just too much to be a coincidence. Jake needed a good source of natural neurotoxin, and what had he just been handed not long ago? A whole crystal container full of the stuff.

[Lifeblood of the Emperor Urchin (Ancient)] – The Lifeblood of a slain Emperor Urchin, an incredibly poisonous creature only found in areas with extremely dense water affinity. Its very blood is toxic to consume and especially toxic if directly injected. The Lifeblood is of a neurotoxic nature. Has many alchemical uses and is especially potent when combined with other neurotoxins or poisons with the water affinity.

By now, he was beginning to suspect there was some kind of foul play involved. Even if the Viper did not spy, had this Karroch god been watching the situation on Earth? While Jake could feel if people observed him, it was entirely possible the god had just kept an eye on everyone else.

Not that Jake would complain if the weird beastmaster god had decided to help him out. Ell’Hakan had spent a long-ass time preparing and had his god help liberally, so it was only fair Jake also did a bit of cheating. It wasn’t even Jake cheating… just someone else giving him an unexpected hand.

It also wasn’t the case that this neurotoxin would instantly be able to accomplish his goal. The Lifeblood of the Emperor Urchin needed to be injected to work correctly, so if Jake decided to use the poison as-is, he would accomplish nothing. Chances were it would just harmlessly fall through the domain of the Unique Lifeform, and the only losses the Unique Lifeform would face would be whatever ash was hit.

Jake would need to make this Lifeblood into a workable ethtoxin that did not require injection but could be directly applied to an area. One common way to do this was making it into a mist that was passively absorbed along with atmospheric mana, or having it be naturally antagonistic towards anything with a soul in the area. Both options would work in this case, but Jake was not sure making a mist would be wise. First of all, what if the Unique Lifeform, just, you know, moved out of the mist? It would also very obviously telegraph he was using poison. While Jake could try to mask it with the poison mist from Wings, he was not sure it would fool the Ashen Phantom Devourer.

So, he would have to find a subtle way to administer it while still fighting with the Ashen Phantom Devourer. A way to directly apply it to the Soulshape. As long as he administered enough and could control it, it should be adequate, given his upgraded Touch of the Malefic Viper.

Before he began doing anything, Jake consumed a bit more of the poison from the large crystal, making use of the large quantity he had. He knew it would not be a poison made in a day, but luckily he had some time before he reached his target… and even if he was too slow, well, he could just tell Sandy to enjoy eating some more stuff.

Heck… maybe he could even make the worm find some stuff he needed for the concoction.

Caleb leaned back in his office chair and read over the recent reports. Four hundred and twenty-four. That was the number of City Lord or other high-level leaders of cities that the Court of Shadows had eliminated over the last many weeks, only to have them replaced with leaders from the United Cities Alliance. It was… a lot. All of these cities where they had killed people were also fringe members of the Holy Church or independent cities that did not ally with anyone. Needless to say, the influence of the United Cities Alliance was growing rapidly, and they had prepared for this takeover for a long time.

A knock on the door made him look up. He raised his hand and swung it open.

Matteo walked in and handed him a token. "Job’s done."

"Good work as usual," Caleb acknowledged as he took it. The soul remnants in the token confirmed the kill. The way the tokens worked was that they recorded the actual notification of a given kill—something which resonated with the Truesoul of the target. It was a truly foolproof form of authentication that nothing less than a Transcendent skill or Bloodline could circumvent.

"How many more targets?" the most efficient assassin in the Court asked.

"Only seventeen without people already on the contract," Caleb said with a sigh. "Four of which ended with the given assassin dying, so security in those locations will be heightened. Once done, chances are Arthur will just come with more, though."

"Are those four close enough for me to take them all?" Matteo asked.

Caleb shook his head. "No, only two of them are. I will have Nadia take one of the others and send team one to handle the last one once they return.” He considered going himself, but he was frankly too busy these days. At least the levels were good.

Matteo nodded and held out his hand. Caleb took out the given tokens with information on the targets and their locations and handed them to him. The man looked them over but didn’t leave. Instead, he took a seat in another chair and looked at Caleb from across the table.

"What?" Caleb asked.

"Are you really okay with all this?" Matteo asked. "We are indirectly working against your brother, no matter how we spin this. Compromising your personal values like this cannot lead to anything good."

Caleb sighed and leaned back. "What was the state of the last city you went to?"

"It was an utter shithole," the assassin answered without hesitation.

"Yeah, see, that is where all of this gets a bit more annoyingly complicated. The reason why these takeovers from the United Cities Alliance have been successful is that they are taking over from someone worse. Who would have thought that a system of governance decided solely by who was the best at killing stuff would lead to not-so-ideal City Lords?

"If we were further fucking over the people of Earth just trying to survive, I would have less conflicted feelings, but as things are, I cannot say what we’re doing isn’t… good. Say what you want, but the United Cities Alliance cares about the approval of the public. They are also generally growing, and anywhere they go tends to improve for the better. I have even heard some leaders voluntarily reach out to join the United Cities Alliance and allow actual administrators from the Alliance to take over, leading to better-run cities. Who we're killing aren't pillars of the community; it is more that we are removing a few moldy support beams threatening to ruin the stability of the entire structure."

"Doesn’t change the fact you are working against the interest of your family," Matteo said.

"No, it doesn’t… but it does make this entire shitshow a whole lot more complicated. Also, rather than think of it as working against Jake, I would rather see it as doing him a favor, you know?" Caleb gave a slightly cheeky smile.

Matteo frowned. "How is any of this doing him a favor?"

"See, I would agree that usually making life harder for someone is a dick move, but for my brother, he tends to enjoy it. Moreover, when he returns and gets into action, I hope that a better future can come from it. He will not take this lying down."

"What if he does not return in time? What if he does and Arthur still gets voted World Leader?"

Caleb considered that for a while. "I see three scenarios. The least likely is that we will simply remain. My brother leaves, and we all handy-dandy hang out on Earth and use it as a branch, with Arthur being a nice ally. The second one is Arthur winning, and we leave. Even if the Court is against this, I am willing to simply leave the Court altogether and take my family with me. Hopefully the Order of the Malefic Viper will take us, and my gut tells me that the Malefic One would hide our family even if Jake died as a final gift to him. Finally, the most likely thing to happen if Arthur does become World Leader? This planet goes to shit, and Jake hunts him down and kills him, any kind of advantages granted by being World Leader be damned. I don’t see Valhal doing shit about it either, as while I didn’t see the contract, they are not dumb enough to not leave themselves an out and force them into a fight with the Order of the Malefic Viper."

"None of those options appear particularly positive." Matteo shook his head. "What about if the Malefic’s Chosen does return? Earth will not be the same after this, no matter what. Who will become World Leader?"

"That," Caleb said as he tried to sound smart, "I don’t know."

Ell’Hakan stared at the sun slowly descending towards the horizon as he focused. Soon it would be time. Taking out his trident, he made sure it was in top condition. He had made a small house in the middle of the plains outside of Haven and away from anywhere the humans lived. The reason was simple: He needed the Chosen to fight without any distractions.

The sun above bared down on him as he absorbed its light, the surrounding plains faintly glowing gold from the potent energy of the star. Everything was prepared, and he was ready for the fight. The plains were ready, and his domain was set.

Looking out the corner of his eyes, he saw one of the two servants stationed in their area make their way over. They had been placed in Haven to keep an eye on things and make sure everything was going according to plan.

"My Lord," the woman said as she stopped in front of him and kneeled, “the natives are still unable to break through the defenses created by the Verdant Witch and take control of the Pylon. I do not believe our interference is required unless the Malefic’s Chosen takes longer than anticipated to return."

Ell’Hakan nodded. "As long as they do not manage to take control before there is less than a month to the World Congress, there shall be no worries. By then, it will be too late for the humans to claim it in time. Keep up the work and ensure things continue as they are."

"Yes, my Lord. May I know what the intent is if the Malefic’s Chosen does not return according to prediction?"

"Predictions. Plural. Only a feeble plan fails if a few factors are out of place. The framework shall remain, and the objective shall be accomplished. Have no doubt… I believe he will make it back just in time.

"Now go. Sunset approaches."

The servant nodded as she rushed back towards Haven. Ell’Hakan did not look after her but instead stared at the orange glow on the clouds above, the sun slowly descending below the horizon. He sat down and marveled at the beauty of the celestial object.

Faint rays of sunlight licked his skin, and the orange glow intensified. Minutes passed as the sun fully disappeared below the horizon. Staring upwards, he saw the clouds obstruct him. Gripping his trident, he raised it and felt the resonance as a beam of shimmering light descended. The clouds parted as the moon appeared, lighting up the blue tattoos lining his body. Even the plains themselves also took on a slight blue color and glowed.

As power filled him, he smiled and bowed his head towards the moon before turning and bowing towards where the sun had gone down. "Your child thanks you. Mother. Father."

Chapter 45

Sandy's Personal Aquarium

"Ifeel bad for them,” Sandy said. With a judgmental tone, they elaborated, “Imagine just living your happy life in the water, and then, suddenly, this naked monster comes down and forces you to stab them several times as you try to get away in fear. But the monster refuses and just keeps smashing his body into you in a ridiculous display of self-harm. The confusion when he then just leaves with several of your spikes in his chest must only make it worse, too.”

Jake was sitting on a jagged rock sticking out of the deep ocean, completely naked. Well, naked as long you didn’t count the many quills sticking out of many places on his body. He ignored Sandy as he meditated, feeling the venom from the many quills course through his body. He purposefully did not eliminate it right away but slowly integrated it into his body.

He had gotten super lucky, as they had come across an area filled with sea urchins. No C-grades were around, but thousands of D-grades dwelled below, and Jake had jumped into the water with glee once he discovered them. Sense of the Malefic Viper had detected them even from a distance, as they were all highly toxic and had powerful neurotoxins on their quills. From how the venom felt, Jake assumed these were all weaker versions of the C-grade he had gained the Lifeblood of. Probably also weaker variants. However, what mattered was that their venom was similar in nature.

This meant Jake had just stumbled across a living treasure trove of potential ingredients. It was also a great way to feed Palate and allowed him to get more familiar with the Lifeblood of the Sea Urchin Emperor. Consuming the actual liquid was only worth it in small quantities due to the diminishing return of Palate when eating something new. Yet he still wanted to become more familiar with it, so these lesser D-grade variants were perfect.

There was the negative side effect of Sandy being bored of waiting. Jake had spent about a day here with the many sea urchins, and he knew Sandy was getting more and more impatient. It was weird that a C-grade was so much in a rush for no reason, but Jake assumed it was just in Sandy’s nature.

"I told you to find a solution, then," Jake said in return, briefly exiting meditation. "As long as the sea urchins are here, we stay here. At least for a while longer."

"You just wait!" Sandy said with indignation. "I will show you!"

"Do just that," Jake said teasingly. "Back to meditation."

Sandy tried to say more, but Jake blocked the worm out. He opened a single eye and saw Sandy wriggle in anger up in the air, making him smirk as he reentered meditation. The poison still flowed through his body, and he absorbed it all over the next hour or so before diving under the waves again.

The sea urchins were all large, porcupine-like creatures that were pretty much just oversized versions of the pre-system animals. The sea had many parts where it was not as deep, and this was one such place since they were close to a few islands, meaning he could make it to the seafloor only by diving a few hundred meters down.

Jake happily swam down to a big crowd of the animals, and annoyingly enough, they now no longer attacked him on sight but instead just hunkered down and erected their spikes. Not to worry, Jake could make them attack him anyway. He just barrelled into one and got himself impaled. Well, okay, not impaled, more stabbed a bit.

Each sea urchin’s main body was about the size of a small two-person car, with their spikes a tad longer than that. Their sizes did vary a bit, and there were some variants here and here with different forms of venoms. Jake wanted the ones with white tips on their quills and avoided the ones with blackened quills. He did try to get stabbed by them a little, but they just had Necrotic Poison, so it wasn’t that exciting.

Mind you, he hadn’t gotten stabbed on purpose the first time around. These sea urchins hunted as a flock, and the first time he dove down, they had all attacked him. Their tactic was to form a barrier of themselves all around their prey, slowly encircling and then stabbing them to death.

Jake reckoned this was also the cause of their mixed toxins. Neurotoxins would make it harder for the prey to flee, while the Necrotic Poison would slowly whittle down and kill it. It was a good strategy, and Jake could even see C-grades dying when a thousand sea urchins decided to attack. Especially larger C-grades would find themselves injected with ludicrous levels of venom.

However, this strategy of theirs quite frankly sucked against small targets. It was clear that Jake did not fit in the underwater meta, where most powerful creatures were massive and those of small size moved in huge groups. He was a single small person, so only a handful of urchins could prick him at once. If all of them struck him at once, Jake could not come out of it alive due to the sheer physical damage, but as things were, they were simply not a threat.

This time around, Jake spent a few minutes down there before coming up again and integrating the venom. The last time he went down there, he’d killed a few to consume their Lifeblood, but sadly the system was annoying in that regard. He already knew that when a creature died, its remnant Records would be infused into select parts of their bodies. If it was weak enough, sometimes no item at all would be born, but in most cases, something would come out of it. The most common thing was a Beastcore, and so was it with these sea urchins. If they had a Beastcore, the Lifeblood would be useless, and only one of the spikes could get infused, making it into great material for a spear but shit-tier material for Jake. He even had one of them not result in an item at all, indicating these were low-tier creatures. He could kill enough and get some blood, but he didn’t feel comfortable killing hundreds for only one or two to give him Lifeblood.

Hence why Jake continued this process of diving down, getting stabbed, and going up to integrate.

The next day, Jake also began to forcefully extract some venom from some of them for further testing. On the third day, it appeared that Sandy had had enough.

Jake was sitting on his rock and meditating as usual when the worm swept down and pushed him hard, sending him splashing into the water.

"Stop ignoring me!" Sandy yelled, finally getting Jake’s attention.

"What?" Jake said as he stopped ignoring the worm and got out of the water. "Didn’t you say you were fine with waiting a bit longer yesterday?"

"That was yesterday!" Sandy once more yelled madly. "Also! Since you are not killing these things, do you need to stay here?"

"Well, I gotta go where they go," Jake answered with a shrug. He had taunted Sandy for a reason and hoped he had gotten through to the worm.

"Great!" Sandy said, suddenly sounding a bit happier.

Jake got a feeling he had indeed managed to get his point across.

Sandy flew past Jake and down into the water, where he saw the worm suck up seawater like a vacuum. Space distorted and warped as the C-grade went further down until, finally, Sandy reached the seafloor where all the urchins were. The vacuum then got stronger as a whirlpool formed, sucking in hundreds of tons of sand along with several hundred of the sea urchins.

Jake caught on quick and smiled. "I only need the ones with the white-tipped quills."

Sandy kept sucking for a minute or so more, eating close to a thousand of the D-grades, all of them between level 150 and 170. After being done sucking up, the massive worm closed its mouth for a bit and then opened it again, spitting out large sea urchins like they were watermelon seeds. Jake counted them all and saw nearly nine hundred had been tossed out.

The worm then swam up and also chomped down on Jake, sending him back to his usual cave-like stomach. Outside, Jake saw Sandy land and lay down on the large rock Jake had been sitting on earlier.

"So…"

"Ugh…" Sandy groaned. "I think I ate too much. My stomach hurts… Give me a moment."

Jake patiently waited for ten or so minutes. Throughout this time, Sandy sometimes spat out water, some of it containing a few quills here and there. After these ten minutes, Sandy once more rose up and took to the air.

"Better thank me for making a water stomach," Sandy complained.

"No one asked you to," Jake chuckled. He had just heavily implied they should do something like this.

"Coercion through boredom is literally torture, and how is torturing someone not forcing them?"

"Rather than discuss the definition of torture, how about you explain what you did?" Jake asked curiously. In all honesty, even after all his time, he had no idea how Sandy worked.

"Fine, fine," Sandy agreed. "I spent these last few days figuring out how to make a bigger stomach. You see, I thought that since I can eat you and get stuff when you do the alchemy, why can’t I eat other creatures and maybe get something for that? Even if it doesn’t work like this, I can keep them around, and you can stop being so boring."

"So I can go there somehow?" Jake asked, unsure how the setup of Sandy’s stomachs worked. His Sphere of Perception looked outside of Sandy while inside, only revealing the room he was in. He assumed this was linked to him being unable to see inside of people’s bodies, even with his sphere.

"Yeah… two seconds," Sandy said. Two seconds passed before, off to the side, a hole appeared in the floor. It looked like a manhole without the cover, and Jake saw water within.

"Is this a portal?"

"I guess you can say that," Sandy answered shruggingly. "I don’t really know. I am just going by feel, you know?"

Jake did know and decided not to argue further. Jumping into the manhole, Jake felt like he was in the ocean again. His sphere instantly spread out, and Jake was taken aback. The stomach Jake was usually in was about the size of a large room, but this place put any aquarium on pre-system Earth to shame… Shit, it put all of them put together to shame.

Jake’s sphere could fully spread without him being able to see the bottom. Swimming downwards, he soon got a scope of things, and Jake estimated the entire stomach was around a kilometer deep and spherical in shape. The bottom was covered in the eaten sand, with the walls the usual rock-like surface Jake’s stomach had originally been before Sandy turned them transparent.

"This is larger than I thought," Jake said. "How many of these can you make?"

"A few, max," Sandy answered. "It drains quite a lot of energy if I want to keep the environment healthy. I also probably shouldn’t keep those things in there for too long, though they do seem docile enough."

"Probably shouldn’t, no," Jake agreed. It was good that they were a solid two out of ten in the smarts department. The one point was only given due to their teamwork. Jake wouldn’t be sure how to feel if Sandy began abducting more intelligent species.

Jake quickly left the water stomach again and entered his own stomach. The manhole that was there remained to now give him easy access to materials. Sandy, in the outside world, could finally fly forward, albeit a bit slower than before, as the worm got used to having eaten so much stuff.

As he looked at Sandy fly, Jake could only begin to imagine what kinds of things the Cosmic Genesis Worm could do in the future. How large could the worm’s spaces be if they were already this spacious in C-grade? Would an S-grade Cosmic Genesis Worm have entire solar systems within its stomach?

The thought was insane but not out of the question, based on what he had seen so far.

Shaking his head, Jake returned to the task at hand. He was getting better at using neurotoxins with every passing day, but more than that, Jake was now finally forming an idea of what to do. The sea urchins had given him quite the inspiration, leading him to ask himself… what if, instead of trying to subtly inject the neurotoxin into the Ashen Phantom Devourer over a long period of time, he did the exact opposite?

What if he bombarded it with ungodly amounts of neurotoxin all at once in an attack it could not avoid? For him to, metaphorically speaking, attack with a thousand smaller doses all at once?

The Fallen King focused on regenerating his severed leg. Reforming it was far more difficult than for a normal biological lifeform—if he even was one—as the Fallen King did not possess any Vitality. Or vital energies at all, for that matter. His body was not truly flesh and blood, after all.

He had fought this Ashen Phantom Devourer dozens of times by now. Every exchange ended with the other Unique Lifeform fleeing after taking significant damage. Every time, he came out on top. He was winning the battles… but… losing the war.

The Fallen King had yet to fully recover for weeks now. He still had a few golden orbs remaining to restore himself, but those had been running out fast too. His issue lay in the fundamental difference between himself and the Ashen Phantom Devourer.

While he had to heal using time, the Ashen Phantom Devourer healed by being true to its namesake. It devoured other beasts in the surrounding area and dove beneath the earth to consume those who resided in the subterranean world. As a result, the other Unique Lifeform recovered slightly faster every time.

And it knew it, gladly fighting the month-long battle of attrition.

Losing a leg had been the biggest loss so far. The Fallen King had attempted to conserve resources and ended up losing the leg in the process. He knew he should have used his golden claw, but a moment of hesitation had nearly proved fatal.

Neither of them had shown any trump cards either. They simply consumed too much energy, and both knew that they risked leaving an opening. There were also some good things, such as the King now far more easily dealing damage to the Ashen Phantom Devourer and Telekinesis being solely a defensive tool. What truly mattered was striking the soul of his foe.

Despite all this, the King was not overly worried. Alone, he would perhaps lose after a long time. Even that was uncertain, as he still had his most powerful attack remaining, which should give him a high chance of at least ensuring mutual destruction. Again, this also assumed the King would even die if he was killed, considering his peculiar relationship with the Hunter.

Not that the Fallen King wanted these fights to end just yet. Neither of them did. Killing the Ashen Phantom Devourer was one goal, yes, but a more important goal was proving himself superior to the other Unique Lifeform. A goal only slightly surpassing enjoying fighting a foe of equal level able to fight on equal footing with himself.

Sadly, the fight would end in due time, as the King did have one more weapon to deploy. He was a King, after all, and while he was not a subject, the little hunter was certainly someone worth having assist you.

He had spoken to the little witch already, and he was more than prepared. In fact, he was excited to see what the little hunter had cooked up.

Chapter 46

In This Time of Change

The days passed one by one as Earth had finally begun finding some semblance of stability. Settlements and larger cities had survived the many beasts attacking and made adequate defenses in preparation for more attacks. Some cities still fell here and there, but for the most part, there was peace.

Some smaller teleportation networks had even appeared, linking allied cities to one another. The Holy Church had some up and running relatively fast, allowing them to quickly move between their cities to assist in case of attacks. They were working towards something, and none knew exactly what it was, but it did include many high-level members of the Church making their way back to Sanctdomo—likely one of the reasons they had rushed to reestablish a teleportation network. Out of all the factions, the Court of Shadows was perhaps the most effective, primarily with their ability to quickly link not necessarily allied cities, but locations of different networks close to each other, and then just melding in and making use of others’ teleporters to move around fast.

And move fast they did. Because another source of stability was, surprisingly enough, a huge number of assassinations. Anyone who wasn’t blind could see this was done with the United Cities Alliance behind the job, based on how they always had a candidate ready to take control within mere hours of the current City Lord dying. Candidates who had been in the cities for months and slowly gained a following and influence.

To the surprise of many, the alien invaders that the United Cities Alliance worked with did nothing during this time. They were spotted here and there and did, in some rare instances, step in and help protect cities from attacks. Even then, no one knew what their goal was.

The faction with the biggest change was the Noboru Clan, which had been split into three separate internal factions. One of them supported the United Cities Alliance, one surprisingly wanted to join the Holy Church, and a final one wanted to stay fully independent. Some fringe members also remained, including a group who still believed the Patriarch lived.

This split led to them losing many cities to outside forces and even invading each other using nonviolent methods and political scheming. They also dealt with beasts far worse, and the base of the once powerful clan was shaken. Without a single, powerful leader to unite them, it looked as though they were headed towards collapse, or at the very least, being split into smaller factions. So far, at least no significant violence had taken place, and differences were being worked through, but it was a losing battle. Each schism’s goals were simply too different.

The only place that could be said to have been oddly unaffected was Haven. Even with the City Lord gone, things mostly continued as usual. People from the United Cities Alliance had come but had yet to take over the Pylon.

There was also the issue of Miranda having been a very popular City Lord. Surprisingly, the majority of citizens were indifferent to the true owner of the city, as he was never really around. They knew he existed, but that was the end of his involvement. Well, besides that, they did know that Miranda had been appointed by him, meaning he couldn’t be that bad, in their eyes.

All of these and more were reasons why the temporary City Lord was not a member of the United Cities Alliance, but an old leader. Phillip, the former leader of the Fort, had—with reluctance—agreed to take up the mantle. His reluctance was part of the reason the United Cities Alliance had agreed, and he was also generally not considered part of the Malefic’s Chosen’s entourage. Another reason was the understanding that it was only till an actual City Lord was deployed there.

Be it by the rightful one returning or a newcomer taking over.

Besides that, there was the Fort. A place where nothing at all had happened. There was not really a true local leader of the Fort besides Phillip in Haven, but most would look towards Arnold if they had to name one. Look towards him both figuratively and literally, as a large part of the city was a metal dome that housed his personal workshop.

In the section of the world already controlled by the United Cities Alliance, it was also mostly calm. Paradise was a sore spot for many City Leaders, but none dared to challenge them, especially not after Renato made ample use of Sylphie and Carmen both residing there. Even if saying they resided there was somewhat fallacious, considering they had not been there for a long time since leaving for the jungle to hunt.

Finally… there were some people on Earth who didn’t truly know where they belonged, with this conflict only shining a brighter light on that fact.

--

"You need to," the woman said in a comforting tone. "Not for anyone but yourself. You can prepare a thousand more things, but you knew this day would come eventually. You are ready, William. You say the system says you have yet to find your Path… I think this is the final piece you are missing."

William listened to Ms. Kim, his former psychiatrist, but he still felt a shiver run down his spine. He knew she was right, and her telling him that only confirmed it. He felt like she was the only person he could ever be open around, and it had been hard not seeing her for so long due to all the tasks Master had sent him to do.

"But the nightmares still haven’t stopped," William muttered. "The random visions here and there…"

"Because all you have is an idea built up in your mind," Ms. Kim said, further trying to comfort him. “He is nothing more than a concept, a representation of fear. If you confront him, you will see that reality isn’t as scary as the monster your imagination has created.”

With a sigh, William just nodded. Logically, he knew it. The monster was not immortal or unbeatable; the alien had shown that. Even if it was not a decisive victory, he had come out on top. However, that didn’t mean William would stand a chance.

"If you don’t rid yourself of your fear before evolving, you risk internalizing it further, truly making it part of who you are,” Ms. Kim continued. “Is that really what you want? No one says you have to beat anyone, just that you have to confront him. I have met him, and while I do agree he is intimidating, he is, in the end, still human.”

William’s Master had been silent, too, in recent times. In fact, he had not spoken to William since his last conversation about being stuck at D-grade, where he had been told to figure it out himself. This had only added to his anxiety, as he would at least have confidence meeting the monster if that meeting had been planned by Master.

He had done all he was told with the beasts, and they were on their own now. William had never been tasked with fighting anyone or anything during this time, and he had barely leveled his class. Not since returning from Nevermore. In Nevermore, William had killed enough to nearly reach the D-grade cap of his class and made significant progress in his profession. By all accounts, he should be ready after another long period of refining himself. Did he think he was the strongest human on Earth? No, no, he was not, but he was not that far off. The Judge of the Court was about the peak of humanity outside of that monster, and William had confidence about going against him.

"Okay," William finally relented.

Ms. Kim smiled. "Just remember there is no shame in retreat and that you do not go to fight. You go to confront your fears and find your Path."

William nodded again as he sighed. It wouldn’t be that simple, would it?

"Ms. Kim?" William said.

"Yes?" she asked, a bit confused by his tone.

"Thanks for everything.” He knew it wasn’t true to their agreement, but he couldn’t help himself from giving her a hug. "Say hi to little Seo for me, okay? Just in case."

Ms. Kim, to his surprise, returned his hug. "As I said… just retreat if it gets too dangerous, okay?"

She let go of him, and William also backed off.

"You are not the same person you were back then, William. You can overcome this."

William nodded again, not entirely sure about that. Not the first point, but the second one.

Saying his goodbyes, William went towards the nearby teleporter and appeared in a damp cavern. He felt the presence of the C-grade space jellyfish wash over him as it emerged from the water.

"You have come to a decision?" the C-grade asked him.

"Yes," William said. "The moment that he appears, send me there. No matter where or who that monster is facing."

"So it shall be," the C-grade agreed without arguing anything.

William sat down on the ground as he meditated and prepared himself. He did not know how long it would take before the monster made his presence known, but William knew he had to go there. Not because he feared the monster would die, making him lose his chance to face him. No, that sentiment was utterly ludicrous to him.

He would go because… Ms. Kim was probably right. The monster was the reason he could not evolve, and he would have to face his fears if he wanted to prove his Path.

Days had turned to weeks as the pair of human and worm journeyed across the ocean. One had done alchemy, and the other had flown while they talked and discussed whatever sights they came across. Jake had only gotten into a single more fight, and Sandy had mainly digested what had already been eaten earlier on their trip. However… all good things must come to an end.

Sadness was in the air as the shoreline entered their sight. Jake had already been spat out of Sandy and was flying alongside the worm at a leisurely pace.

"It is beginning to hurt a bit," Sandy said as they got closer to the shoreline. "Not actual pain, but more a warning that it will come…"

Jake nodded. They had both kind of known this would happen and had accepted it. Only a dozen kilometers from the shoreline, Jake saw vast mountains rise, and he knew the Fallen King was currently in there. It was at the edge of the ocean… and the edge of what was effectively a safety zone for humanity.

The small territory humanity occupied was not much compared to the rest of the globe. Outside of that territory, there were no limitations on C-grades or anything like that, but inside, there were. Jake and Sandy were approaching this safe zone where Sandy, as a C-grade, could no longer keep going.

Soon, they both stopped, just floating in the air a kilometer from the shoreline.

"Stupid system rules," Sandy complained.

"Yeah," Jake agreed. He really didn’t want to split from Sandy for several reasons, the first of which was that he had no way to find his wormy friend again. Sylphie, he had a bond with, but Sandy was an entirely different sort of animal. A Cosmic Genesis Worm also traveled around a lot due to its nature of consuming natural treasures in insane quantities, making his C-grade pal even harder to pin down and find again.

"You gotta go?" Sandy asked. "Why not just ignore all the stupid human stuff and keep hunting? Does it really matter? Oh! We could even maybe just go somewhere else? Like, there is an entire universe to explore, right? Let’s go there! After you evolve, though…"

Jake could not help but smile. "I need to go. I have been thinking about this situation a lot, and honestly, this entire conflict is partly my fault. It is time I made a decision. But I would be more than up for exploring with you another time, okay?"

Sandy wriggled a bit, clearly not happy. Jake just rubbed the side of the massive worm, not even sure if they could feel it. If not the physical touch, he was sure Sandy could at least feel his intentions. He honestly would like to just fly around and adventure with Sandy, even heading straight up and into space. Shit, even just exploring what was up there in the sky before reaching space would be…

Wait a fucking minute.

"Hey, Sandy… you wanna try something?" Jake asked with a grin.

"What?" Sandy asked, perking up a little.

Jake looked towards the sky. "See if this damn restriction has a vertical limit."

Sandy took a moment to comprehend what he meant before getting it. Jake barely had a chance to react before the massive worm bent its body and chomped down on him. As he didn’t resist, he was thrown into the old room again. Outside, the surroundings were already moving.

The water below was getting further away, the clouds above approaching with alarming speed. It was time to see how far they could go. Jake assumed that a long cylinder of restricted space didn’t just extend endlessly out of Earth, and he had already seen that the restrictions lessened the deeper you went into the ground, so why should it not be the same when heading upwards?

"I will admit it is a creature I have not seen before," the scaled god said with skepticism. "But that does not mean much when they are still in C-grade. For such special beasts, I can see many Paths that only result in death."

"Very insightful," Vilastromoz said with a smirk. "You know, I thought something similar once upon a time when I stumbled across this incredibly stupid lizard with a few too many heads rolling around in a swamp. Turns out that little lizard became a slightly smarter lizard with way too many heads. Oh, and a god or something."

"Master…" Snappy—or the Lord Protector, as some liked to call him—said with exasperation and slight embarrassment. "I am simply saying that it is a gamble I am uncertain I should take. There are risks involved; you know that. You chose to make a bet because the human truly was extraordinary, but this creature is not in the same realm as him."

"I would never force you to do anything like this," the Viper agreed, “but I am saying that I see potential. I have never come across a creature like this before either, and from what it has displayed so far, even you must admit you are impressed. And… getting in on the ground floor, especially before some other god swoops in, is a good idea. The worm is hidden by Jake’s Shroud due to its current proximity to him, but that may very well change. If you act now and your gamble succeeds, the gains will be that much better."

Snappy fell silent for a bit, with Villy just staring at him. He had made the Lord Protector observe all his recorded memories of the worm—perfect photographic memory and the ability to play those memories back was a perk of his Bloodline. That was what his old friend had done over the last few days as he evaluated the worm.

As for why Vilastromoz was having Snappy do it? Because his Path was more closely aligned with the worm than the Viper’s own. The Path of consumption and devouring everything in one’s way was far more like Snappy than the very selective Viper.

"Perhaps," Snappy said, sighing. “Perhaps it has been too long since I had one of my own, and in this time of change, perhaps taking a bit of a risk is only right."

Vilastromoz failed to hold back a smile. He truly did not believe his old friend would regret it.

Chapter 47

All Hail Sandy

They had just made it above the clouds when Jake felt a ping from Villy. "Hey, Jake, can I borrow you for a second?"

"Sure, what’s up?"

"No, I mean in a more literal sense. Can I borrow your body to do something?"

"I guess?" Jake kind of agreed.

"Great!"

Jake felt the Viper descend. It was like Jake’s aura got mixed with something else, and he then felt a third presence enter, confusing him even more. At that moment, was very happy that he had a strong soul, which experienced massive pressure from channeling but a fraction of the Viper’s aura.

Sandy also noticed, stopping in mid-air before saying in a confused tone, "Uhm, I just got some weird pop-up, and I think it might be a scam?"

"What is it?" Jake asked curiously, soldiering through. Had Villy decided to bless Sandy? That would actually be awesome, and he was mentally slapping himself for not having thought of giving the worm one earlier.

"You see, I got this Blessing thing offered like you have, right?" Sandy said with doubt.

"Yeah?" So it was Villy giving a ble—

"And… well, I just feel like if you have to include that something is True in the description, isn’t that kind of red flag that it isn’t? Like, if it is real, why do you need to put so much emphasis on it, you know?"

Wait, what? Jake asked himself, utterly perplexed at what Sandy was asking. Include True? Did it maybe say something about it coming from someone with a True Blessing?

"Can you explain what it says in detail?" Jake asked Sandy.

"Okay, it asks if I want to talk to this god or something about receiving a True Blessing? It is very weird.”

Jake, even more confused, asked, "What is the name of this god?"

"The Boundless Hydra."

Who the fuck is that? Jake asked himself for a moment before a lightbulb went off. Sandy: likes eating stuff. Snappy: likes eating stuff. It all suddenly made sense; they were a match made in heaven.

"Hey, Villy, is Snappy really offering Sandy his True Blessing?" Jake asked the Viper.

"Yes, but an emphasis on offer,” Villy explained. “It will be up to them to reach an agreement if your wormy friend agrees to a conversation on the topic. You will have to function as a conduit during this process, and it will be a bit straining, but you should be fine."

Jake nodded, totally fine with that, before telling Sandy, "Yep, I know who the Boundless Hydra is. The offering is a True Blessing, the same as what I have but from a different god. I would recommend for you to have this talk with the guy, okay?"

"Oh, okay," Sandy agreed. "As long as it isn’t a scam."

Villy’s presence intensified as Jake felt the god channel power through him. He allowed it all to go through with a slight headache. Jake closed his eyes, as Sandy had also completely frozen in the real world while the Hydra and Cosmic Genesis Worm spoke.

--

Snappy had disappeared and returned to his own realm for the conversation. Forever true to tradition and all that. Then again, giving a True Blessing could not be done the usual way. The two souls had to meet, as the transference was more intimate and intense than any other Blessing. Doing it in the divine realm of a god was the easiest for both parties.

Vilastromoz smirked as he wondered what kind of monster he was helping to create.

Worm and Hydra met.

The Lord Protector—also known as the Boundless Hydra—had assumed his true form. A mass of heads too difficult for a mortal mind to comprehend appeared before the insignificantly small Cosmic Genesis Worm. The Hydra soon collected its form to only be a nine-headed hydra.

Two figures simply existed for a few seconds before the worm opened its mouth and began sucking. "This place tastes weird."

"You are within my divine realm, and what you are consuming is my energy," the Hydra spoke. “I am known as the Boundless Hydra, Lord Protector of the Order of the Malefic Viper.”

"Wow!" Sandy said, impressed. "That is such a long name! I am just Sandy. Pleased to meet you, the Boundless Hydra, Lord Protector of the Order of the Malefic Viper."

Silence followed for a period. Sandy just sucked in some more of the atmosphere and looked around, clearly unsure how to act or what to do. The Hydra, on the other hand, just observed.

"Tell me, Sandy… why do you travel with the Chosen of the Malefic Viper?" the Hydra asked the worm after a few minutes.

"What a silly question," Sandy said, scoffing. "We’re friends!"

"That is now. The Chosen of the Malefic One will keep walking a Path of conquest and power. He will grow in power without end, and his true stage is not your small planet, but the multiverse as a whole. Are you willing to follow him that far? Are you willing to do what is necessary to remain someone useful to him even as he soars towards the apex?"

"What do you mean when you say do what is necessary? I am just doing what I do. I eat stuff, grow, and get stronger and better at eating stuff. I am not doing that to be useful to him; that would be super silly, wouldn’t it?"

"Does that mean that you intend to abandon the Malefic’s Chosen if you find it convenient?" the ancient god asked the mortal worm.

"Maybe? Who knows? We are friends, and Jake says that friends don’t owe each other anything. They help because they want to, not because they have to. Also! I remember him once saying never say never, so I am never going to say never. Wait, I did just say never a lot of times… Anyway! Jake is my friend, so that is that. Stop talking about silly stuff like abandoning others. If anything, he was the one about to abandon me just now!" Sandy said all this with much gusto, not a shred of fear within them.

The Hydra fell silent for a few seconds, seeming to contemplate the answer. "Would you give your life for the Malefic’s Chosen?"

"No, I am pretty sure that would kill me, and I wouldn’t like that."

"If you were given the choice of betraying and backstabbing the Malefic’s Chosen for a tremendously powerful treasure, would you do it?"

"That sounds like a dumb thing to do and also super impractical. How do I even stab him when all my teeth are gone? Also! I am pretty sure I wouldn’t be able to stab him in the back even if I had teeth. He is mega good at knowing when something is trying to hit him from behind."

"Do you ever think you will be sated? When will you be satisfied with devouring treasures? Is it truly a Path you want to follow for eternity? A never-ending cycle of consumption?"

"Maybe not?” Sandy once more answered without hesitation. “Sometimes I also like to lay around and digest and stuff. But after that, I will definitely need to head out for a snack. Why would someone not want to keep eating stuff? Eating stuff is the best. Oh! And I can even find different ways of eating things, like making food-making stomachs and stuff by eating living things! That is infinite food right there. Doesn’t sound boring at all.

"Now! Why are you the only one asking me questions? So, why are you called the Boundless Hydra? Did you use to be bound or something?"

"My Path was similar to yours, and in my pursuit of power, I expanded every part of myself and grew. We hydras tend to gain power from having more heads, and my goal was to reach the apex. Turns out the apex is realizing there is no limit, only one’s abilities holding one back.”

"Cool! I am fine with only one head, though.”

"I would assume as much. But we do share the Path of consumption, even if there are differences. Nevertheless, my Records do complement yours. So, finally… would you, Sandy, the Cosmic Genesis Worm, have the honor of becoming my Chosen?"

"Chosen… Oh! Like Jake and his friend Villy!? Yeah, we can totally be friends if you want to! You seem like an okay hydra."

"Friends… Yes, you can view it as that," the Lord Protector said, choosing not to argue. "With it will come responsibility and power. It will allow you to go further, but should you fall, it will, in turn, harm me. It is both a responsibility and a privilege. You will come to possess an Identity that will be recognized in the wider multiverse too. It is truly no decision to make lightly.”

"Sounds like a lot of things just for becoming your friend, but I guess all that stuff is fine. Though, actually, can you explain it all a bit better?” Showing some hint of doubt for the first time, Sandy continued, “Jake did also mention that only idiots don’t properly take their time to understand an agreement before accepting it. That is how you get scammed, and I am not here to get scammed. So! Details, please?"

"Gladly," the Hydra answered in a pleased tone.

Jake felt damn weird; no two ways about it. He’d felt his body flooded with the two presences as Sandy’s body had gone entirely limp. He instinctively knew their soul had been projected elsewhere, probably into the realm of Snappy.

Considering Jake was unable to move or do anything, he just had to ask Villy how things were going.

"So, are those two having a nice chat?" Jake asked the snake god.

"That is between them, and not even I can forcefully listen in,” Villy answered. “Sure, Snappy would just allow me to, but I won’t. But I will share a bit. You are probably wondering why Snappy is suddenly here, talking about giving away a True Blessing. Snappy has not given out his True Blessing for many eras; he has barely given any Blessings out, in fact. Firstly, it is not really part of his Path, and secondly, there is risk and responsibility tied to having blessed ones out there. Snappy has been cooped up in the Order ever since I went into seclusion, and I believe it’s high time he begins to get a bit more out there."

"Doesn’t exactly explain why you want him to give out a True Blessing, and especially not why Sandy would be a good candidate. Like, I kind of see it, but have you not talked repeatedly about how giving a True Blessing is a huge commitment?"

"It is, which is why I am not the one deciding if he chooses to bless the worm, and he may just decide on only giving a lower-level Blessing. What I did suggest to him was that maybe the worm was worth gambling on. So yes, it is a massive gamble, but one I think is worth taking for him. Plus, it will give him a stronger connection to the outside world.”

"I guess," Jake semi-agreed.

He hated to admit it, but… Sandy was not exactly the kind of being Jake thought of when someone mentioned a Chosen. Not that he was, either.

"Think positively—with any Blessing from Snappy, that worm will gain a huge boon," Villy said. "Okay, finally, I will admit that I want to see what exactly a Cosmic Genesis Worm can turn into as it grows in power. It is an interesting beast, and one I think can be useful to you for a long time if it can keep up with you. A True Blessing from someone like Snappy will help with that tremendously. More than that, the guidance of the Boundless Hydra would prove invaluable."

"As long as Sandy also wants it," Jake said.

"Jake, you are the only one I know that cannot renounce a Blessing, and also the only one I know who would not instantly jump at the opportunity of a True Blessing. Anyway, the worm can just choose to throw it away if it turns out to be something they don’t want. The bond between a Chosen and their god is not one of equals, but is closer to that than any other Blessing."

The two of them didn’t get much more time to speak before Jake felt a change. The presence of Snappy intensified to an entirely new level, forcing Jake to metaphorically grit his teeth. It was as if his insides were burning, and the epicenter of this presence was Sandy.

Seconds passed before it subsided, and as Jake felt Villy and Snappy both retract their auras, Villy spoke in a joking tone, "All hail Sandy, Chosen of the Boundless Hydra, the Devourer of Dimensions."

Jake did not pay it any mind but instead focused on Sandy. The first thing he noticed was how the worm’s aura had changed. Grown. Not by a small margin, either; the growth was significant. Jake knew this had to be the titles added by being blessed, along with the bonuses of the Blessing itself.

"So… Sandy, how are you feeling?" Jake asked the worm.

"Huh? Oh, hey there, Jake!” Sandy said with glee. “That was so wild, but also kind of fun. I made a new friend with the super-big Hydra guy, and we agreed that I would get blessed by him and stuff, so now I am a Chosen too! Isn’t that cool?

"Moreover! I am faster and even more durable now! I got boosts in all stats, and my tummy ache is entirely gone after that. Definitely a nice hydra."

Jake felt genuinely happy for his wormy friend but had one burning question in his mind.

"You also got a skill, right?"

"Yep!"

"Great. If you don’t mind me asking, what rarity is it? And could you tell me what it does, at least for me to get an idea?" He knew it was a lot to ask, but he was damn curious. Jake had a strong feeling there existed a rarity beyond mythical but below divine, and he wasn’t sure if Sandy would get a divine skill, as Snappy was no Primordial.

"The skill is divine, and as for what it does…" Sandy said, really dragging it out for dramatic purposes.

"Yes?" Jake asked, prompting the worm.

"It makes it so that…"

Jake felt like smashing something.

"… I cannot tell you what it does!" Sandy said in a loud and cheerful tone.

"What?" Jake asked.

"Yep, my new friend told me not to tell anyone," Sandy said, still annoyingly cheerful. “So, sorry. Your fault for telling me that friends have to keep promises.”

It was not a discussion Jake wanted to take up, as there was no winning. Instead, he would focus on moving forward. Or, well, upwards.

"Well, anyway, that was a nice little intermission to our journey," Jake said, changing the topic entirely. "Are you ready to truly go and explore what resides in the upper layers of our planet’s sky and hopefully allows us to travel together for a bit longer?"

"Yeah, that was definitely a fun time," Sandy agreed. "And also, yeah, let’s go! Oh, but one thing first."

Sandy spat out Jake, who appeared in the real world with confusion. Sandy then seemed to focus before spitting out a small sphere that looked like a mix between stone and metal, giving off odd energy. It was about the size of Jake himself, and he could only stare at it with bewilderment. Especially as it contained Sandy’s presence, meaning it was part of the worm.

"Can you keep that with you?" Sandy asked. “It can go in your spatial storage.”

"What is it?" Jake asked.

"I made a promise not to tell, but I need you to keep it safe, and it will be super useful even when I can’t follow, okay?"

Jake stared at the stone and shook his head, then stored the item that was clearly a product of the newly gained divine-rarity skill.

Chapter 48

Strategizing

Vilastromoz grinned as he waited for Snappy to return. Genuinely, he hadn’t been sure if Snappy would actually give his True Blessing to the worm. He had gone with the tried-and-tested strategy of starting with the most extreme example of a Blessing while only expecting a Divine Blessing. A Greater Blessing also wouldn’t have been that off from his expectations.

He would be lying if he said it didn’t please him. Then again, Snappy was better at judging the abilities of the Cosmic Genesis Worm than the Viper was. As mentioned, then while they both walked Paths where consumption was a big part of it, Snappy walked one where eating things was the primary element. If Villy was a master, then Snappy was a grand master.

As expected, Snappy returned soon after handing out the Blessing, looking a bit worse for wear. Giving out a True Blessing was never easy, and it quite literally ate your Records when you did it. If giving out a normal Blessing—even a Divine one—could be said to consume a limited resource pool, then giving away a True Blessing was giving away a portion of your maximum energy pool with the hope that the one you gave the pool to would improve the maximum. That, or die too early, making you permanently lose a portion of this pool that you would then have to make up for. Losing a single Chosen prematurely was a significant loss, even if it wouldn’t necessarily result in any loss of combat prowess.

What it would do in every case was limit the potential of a god and make it harder for them to progress. In the same way, then, if the Chosen did well, it would also help the god. Records mixed, too, giving other benefits. While Jake enjoyed plenty of the Viper’s Records, Vilastromoz too enjoyed the Records of Jake’s achievements. The exchange was not equal but heavily favored for the Chosen, at least in the lower grades. What an S-grade did simply resulted in more meaningful Records for a god than nearly anything a D or even C-grade could possibly achieve.

This was why most gods waited to A or S-grade to make someone a Chosen. The chance of the person dying then was just lower, and one would nearly always get their investment returned. Especially as many gods hoped for the ultimate bounty of their Chosen reaching godhood, resulting in not only a huge return on investment but a new loyal god joining them in their factions.

However… the gains from someone you blessed even earlier on their Path reaching these levels of power were nothing compared to what the Viper would get from Jake. While the Viper had made Jake his Chosen rather impulsively, it wasn’t as if he had done so without any thought.

"Had an enlightening conversation with the Cosmic Genesis Worm?" Vilastromoz asked Snappy.

"Moreso than expected," Snappy answered. "I must admit, I had not expected the level of presence resistance to be that high. It went above and beyond anything I have seen of any C-grade before. A result of your Chosen, I believe?"

"Yep," Vilastromoz confirmed. "This is that Sylphian Hawk all over again, though slightly less potent, as far as I can tell."

"Sandy was still affected," Snappy agreed, “just able to ignore it far better. Stoic is not the word I would use, but perhaps willfully ignorant is more accurate."

Vilastromoz nodded, having his thoughts reaffirmed. "So, what made you decide to give the True Blessing?"

Snappy was silent for a moment. "No single factor was behind it. However, I had feared that Sandy would have been bound to your Chosen too tightly and not have enough independence. It was good to confirm that is not the case. Moreover, as the Cosmic Genesis Worm was in my realm, I could feel its conceptual level of digestion and analyze how their inner world works."

"And?"

"I found it acceptable to make Sandy my Chosen," Snappy simply said with a smile. "The worm also had an acceptable personality and demeanor."

Vilastromoz also smiled and shook his head. "Keep your secrets, then. Though I must add, I am surprised Sandy could get the divine skill you chose to give. As far as I know, the compatibility requirements are through the roof on that one."

Snappy sighed. "How do you already know?"

Villy just kept smiling as he kept an eye on Jake and the worm. "Happy thoughts. At least you don’t have to be that worried about Sandy dying to any unforeseen circumstances now."

When Jake thought about it, he had never actually gone that far into the sky. The furthest he had gone was with Hawkie while exploring the cloud continent, and that had still been in the lower layers of the world above. He had, for a long time, theorized one could find many powerful things up there, and that theory was soon proven true.

Earth had several layers of clouds, and entering each layer was like entering an entirely new world. Clouds above and below made it look like one was within a cave of clouds in the sky, and as Jake and Sandy entered one of the extremely far-up layers, Sandy suddenly stopped to shudder.

"This place is good," the worm said.

"Really?" Jake asked rhetorically with delight. "That is great! Now see if you can move to the side too. Towards the west, that is."

They still needed to make sure Sandy could actually enter the airspace above where the Fallen King was before they could call this a success.

However, Jake had a strong feeling it would be fine. This feeling primarily stemmed from the many beasts already in the area to the west, and far in the distance, Jake saw something extremely large move. So large it had to be C-grade.

As he had hoped, Sandy encountered no more problems, but they did make it clear that going downward through any of the cloud layers was not an option. Jake asked Sandy to spit him out, and the worm did so.

Standing in the air outside, Jake stared downwards.

They were approximately two hundred kilometers from the surface of the planet. The cloud continent had been around twenty-five kilometers from the surface, so he was now around eight times higher—which made sense, considering the presence of C-grades there.

"I guess we will have to say goodbye too… I can’t follow you down from here," Sandy said with some sadness.

"Wait a bit," Jake said as he kept looking down and focusing.

He squinted his eyes and strained himself. Faint traces of stamina entered his eyes to empower them. In his vision, the layers of clouds thinned, turning into only a faint mist. Focusing more, the mist began dispersing. Layer after layer disappeared, and a mountain valley entered his eyes.

And people laughed at full Perception builds, Jake thought, smiling to himself. Okay, no one had really laughed about his stat build to his face, but plenty of people probably wanted to!

Looking around, Jake soon spotted what he was looking for. A mountain peak with gold on top—the residence of the Fallen King. It was a bit far off to the side, but he had time to get in position. Nothing was going on all the way below, as far as he could see, meaning no fight was happening.

"What are you looking at?" Sandy finally asked.

"The mountains below to figure out the best spot to prepare," Jake answered.

"You can see all the way down there?" Sandy asked with confusion. "That is like, super far, isn’t it? And isn’t all the stuff in the way annoying?"

"It is, but I can handle it. I also think I may have to go a bit lower while I prepare, as I don’t want any C-grades to interrupt me.”

"So it is goodbye…" Sandy said with sadness. "Oh, well. I guess nothing can be done about that."

Jake frowned a little, as the last part sounded far less sad than the first. It took him a moment, but he got it. "You detected something tasty?"

"Maaaybe? The sky is way better than the water; that is for damn sure," Sandy said cheerfully. "But do say hi again when you are done dealing with human stuff, okay? Just take the egg—I mean, rock—thing, I gave you earlier and infuse some energy into it, and I will come if I can."

Jake smiled as he patted his wormy friend. "I will. See you around, Sandy, and happy hunting. Treasure hunting, that is."

"You too! Good luck killing stuff and all that, and I hope that weird stuff you prepared works. Unique Lifeforms sound scary.”

With those words, Sandy left to do wormy adventures of their own. Jake would be lying if he said he wouldn’t miss the giant gluttonous worm, but such was life. At least he now had a method of contact, and even if he didn’t, he could contact his fellow Chosen through Villy.

Yes, it still felt weird that Sandy was now a Chosen of an extremely powerful god and that there was absolutely no change in the worm despite that. Not that he complained, as he preferred it that way. He did wonder what that entire egg business was about, as that wasn’t something Sandy could do before, meaning it definitely came from the skill granted by the True Blessing.

This meant the egg had to come from a divine skill, even if it felt rather mundane. Villy had said that no combat-oriented skills could be given, but that didn’t mean Jake had any idea what the worm had gotten. I guess I will find out at some point. For now, let’s focus on the task at hand.

Jake dove downwards for a good while until reaching around the hundred-kilometer mark. He timed himself and estimated he would be able to reach the ground in around two minutes if he went at full speed. This put his speed somewhere around two to three times the speed of sound, closer to three.

Taking some more notes, Jake scoured the mountain range below, waiting for something to happen. As he did this, he also took out a token and activated it. A minute passed before he felt Miranda make contact.

Miranda had activated the ritual circle to establish a connection with Jake, and it formed effortlessly.

"I am in position around a hundred kilometers above the mountain range now," Jake said, surprising Miranda a bit. Not only due to how fast he had gotten there, but because he was so far up in the sky. “I have visual contact with where the King resides.”

"Is that within feasible striking distance?" Miranda asked with doubt.

"Yes," Jake simply answered.

She did not even try to argue it. Jake knew far better than she did when it came to these kinds of things. "Very well. I will now form the three-way connection. Wait a minute."

Miranda quickly took out a few more items that she placed on the circle. Pouring her mana in and controlling the ritual, a second connection was formed. Focusing, Miranda took these connections and channeled them—first through herself, and then into the circle, connecting them all with herself as the central medium.

"It has been a while since we last spoke, little hunter," a voice spoke to not only Miranda but everyone else part of the ritual. Jake being everyone else in this case.

"That it has," Jake agreed. "I hear you have been struggling with some ash guy or something? Do you mean to tell me that this other Unique Lifeform is superior to you?"

"Superior is a strong word to describe a creature of equal class,” the King said, scoffing. “That neither of us can kill the other is only a testament to the power of Unique Lifeforms.”

"Sure, a testament to their power. I guess to take down such a powerful foe, you need an expert in killing Unique Lifeforms. I guess I can consult, considering my vast experience on the subject?"

"I must disappoint you; I sadly do not have several system-granted items to make this Unique Lifeform weak enough for you to stand a chance."

"Too bad,” Jake said. “Guess we will have to just kill it the old-fashioned way, then, huh? Oh, wait, you also tried that and failed? Damn.”

"Boys, be nice to each other," Miranda finally cut in to mediate the two bickering… eh… peak powerhouses of Earth? The peak of D-grade, at least. Anyway.

"Jake is now in position in the air far above the mountain range,” Miranda said. “Am I correct to assume that both of you are ready to engage the next time the Unique Lifeform shows up?"

"Yes," the King answered.

"I would prefer to wait until the time after that," Jake said without a hint of teasing, surprising Miranda with his patience. She had assumed he wanted to rush in. “You say it comes by often… Make it so that this time is shorter than the others. Make it believe you are truly struggling and soon unable to keep up. You already said you are slowly losing out; make it believe you are at your limit. Then make it retreat, fully heal up, and return for the killing blow.”

"Why the delay?" the King asked, no longer joking around either.

"For me to properly assess the Unique Lifeform and make use of some of my skills. Will it be a problem to do this?" This was no jab, but a genuine inquiry.

"Yes, it should be feasible,” the King answered. “I have been facing mounting pressure recently, and I can play it up.”

"Alright," Miranda agreed. "Allow me to contact and bring in the final member of this little plan."

Miranda had already prepared as the two spoke and activated yet another token. She repeated the process from before, sacrificing quite a sum of energy to facilitate what was essentially a group call. The old man she wanted to bring in had been waiting and nearly instantly reacted.

"Greetings, Ms. Wells, Jake, and… the Fallen King, is it?" the Sword Saint spoke.

"Well met, swordsman," the King greeted.

"Hi, there," Jake put in.

"I am glad you could join us," Miranda finished. Channeling the presences of four people in a ritual like this wasn’t easy, especially considering the distance between some of them and her having to make sure the connection was secure.

"I take it the time is approaching?" the Sword Saint asked.

"Yes, we’ll soon be ready and want to make sure you are in position and able to engage when called upon," Miranda told the Sword Saint.

"You need not worry; I am ready. Simply say when.”

"Great,” Miranda said. “Jake, if you would explain your plan of engagement to the others?"

"Okay, so I thought that—"

Jake went on to explain as Miranda just listened in and focused on the ritual. The King asked a few questions, as he was the only other one directly involved in the fight with the other Unique Lifeform, with the Sword Saint more there to offer advice. Jake also gave the Sword Saint some tips, as they all knew the old man would have potentially the most dangerous job of all:

Keeping Ell’Hakan busy during the takedown of the Ashen Phantom Devourer.

In total, it took about half an hour to go over everything, and by then, Miranda was also plenty tired. They said their goodbyes, and, with relief, she disengaged from the ritual and let it fade. Not having the energy to clean the circle then and there, she went to relax in another room and found a certain snake sitting by the door.

"It went well?" the Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake asked.

"As expected," Miranda answered. "What about you? Have you decided on a name yet?"

"No… it is too hard. But I thought, what if we combine them?"

Miranda was a bit surprised, but after thinking about it, it wasn’t a bad idea. Allie Scarlett or Scarlett Allie. Maybe make it Allison, or—

"How about Scallie to—"

Miranda instantly raised her hand, making the snake shut up. "Back to the drawing board on that one."

Chapter 49

Assessment & Preparation

Jake spent the next day or so refining and making more of the poison that he would use to take down the Unique Lifeform as he waited for it to appear below. It took about twenty-six hours before Jake spotted the Ashen Phantom Devourer move roughly a hundred kilometers below himself.

Its form was truly massive, and to Jake, it looked like the sandstorm he had seen in the desert, but made of ash and not sand. Without knowing better, he would not even have thought it a living creature. Black ash simply swept across the mountains as if a strong wind carried it. As it approached the residence of the Fallen King, the ash began to condense itself into a vaguely humanoid form a bit more than five meters tall.

The figure raised a long, log-like arm, and space seemed to distort. A giant bullet of ash collected and then shot out of the domain towards the residence of the King. The King responded with a barrier, and the Unique Lifeform emerged.

Ash can leave the area, forcing it to generate more, Jake quickly concluded as more ash just seemed to appear within the domain. Focusing, he tried to look deeper and get a feeling for what he was facing. His high Perception had already allowed him to look past the clouds that blocked out his vision, but now he wanted to see something not visible to the naked eye.

The domain of the Unique Lifeform was its Soulshape, which meant it had to leave something there. Some part of itself, at least in the metaphysical realm. Usually, Jake saw the Soulshape of a creature by relying on the poison running through their bodies and using Sense of the Malefic Viper. However, in this case, he could not feasibly poison the Unique Lifeform to do this without it discovering his presence.

According to him, the King could see the full body of the Ashen Phantom Devourer. His sight was not the same as that of a human’s but far more magical in nature, and Sandy could likely also have sensed the body of the Unique Lifeform. The environment it occupied simply had to be different in some way, even if it was not currently within his visible spectrum.

The human eye had limitations, such as not being able to see infrared or ultraviolet light. Overall, it had a relatively narrow spectrum of wavelength visible to it. Probably a good thing, too, as being able to see outside of it would be a miserable experience, considering all the wavelengths in the air at all times stemming from phone signals, radio waves, the internet, and whatnot. Yet humans had found ways to still see these things. Measure them using devices to translate them into something humans could see and understand.

Jake had no such measurement devices, and post-system, they likely wouldn’t even work either. What he did have was a superhuman body and Perception above anything a D-grade human should ever have. He could see mana of different affinities, use tracking to detect things that weren’t truly there, and even adapt and get used to these things, such as when he’d acclimated to dark mana. So why should he not be able to also see outside of the visual spectrum of humans and see the metaphysical? Gaze of the Apex Hunter already allowed him to "see" his opponent’s soul, based on the description, and that skill had permanently modified his eyes to allow this. Shit, at times, he felt like he had seen someone’s soul, such as when he tried to get around Identify protection.

At this point, it was no longer just a theory that he could do it, but a conviction that he simply hadn’t found the proper method.

The battle below continued as the two powerful entities clashed repeatedly. The Fallen King purposefully played it defensively and blocked most attacks with his powerful telekinesis, allowing the weaker blows to merely fizzle out upon encountering his barrier.

Ash formed into different shapes appeared to be the primary method of attack deployed by the Ashen Phantom Devourer, but Jake quickly saw it wasn’t that simple. The ash was not simply compressed but layered in odd ways. A single spear of ash looked like it was made of obsidian, making it far more condensed than what made sense. To add on, the ash could also change shape even when in flight, and rather than fly straight, it often seemed to teleport.

Because it did teleport.

Another thing the King had already mentioned was the ash’s ability to not only do damage but multiply by itself. Jake was not entirely certain what affinities composed ash, but he assumed it had to do with fire of some kind. Now that he observed it in action, he became more and more certain of one thing that also made the Phantom part of the Unique Lifeform’s name make sense.

Dark mana. The ash is heavily infused with dark mana. The dark mana materialized as the ash consumed the mana of the King whenever they clashed, and the ash constantly filled the huge domain due to the Unique Lifeform absorbing energy from outside into its territory at all times.

Every particle of ash also had dark mana within, absorbing some of the King’s simply by passively touching his barrier. This dark mana appeared weaker than its space and ash magic and pretty much only included the assimilation parts of the dark affinity. From Jake’s initial assessment, the King was superior in both power and resources, but the Devourer won out in durability and Endurance.

Not that either of them wasn’t considered a pinnacle creature, even in their weak areas.

The more Jake understood his opponent, the more he knew what he was looking for. Focusing, he began to see an outline. Following that path, the outline turned entirely black. Huge parts of the mountain range suddenly got covered in complete darkness.

It was… massive. Jake knew this was the true body of the Unique Lifeform, and he now also knew he had severely underestimated the size of his foe. It truly was nearly as large as the C-grade whale had been, but he also saw something different. Its size shrank whenever it launched attacks, growing in between attacking or defending.

Size represented by resources remaining, Jake then also concluded.

The entire domain could naturally also move. The King retreated out of it several times, and that was when Jake noted one more crucial aspect. It moved using physical ash. In order to move the domain, the ash had to "push" the perimeter of the domain by flying in the direction the Unique Lifeform wanted to go, meaning that a physical barrier would obstruct it. Jake breathed out a sigh of relief upon realizing this, as that ruled out the Unique Lifeform fleeing below the ground by simply moving its domain downward.

Jake kept refining his vision as the dark blob became more transparent. He then began to see that light also refracted here and there within the domain whenever space magic was deployed, and more ash appeared.

Golden light and waves of pure force met ash as the two Unique Lifeforms fought, leaving the entire area broken and destroyed—even more than it already was. The King’s golden attacks seemed to do significant damage to the Ashen Phantom Devourer whenever ash was destroyed, and sometimes the entire domain seemed to move in order to try and avoid attacks. However, more often, the other Unique Lifeform moved to block. At nearly all times, it also kept a figure condensed somewhere, and Jake also realized the reason for this.

It needs a focal point of energy. Like a catalyst at the center of a ritual circle, condensing a body allows it to focus its energy into a single entity to then further condense and launch attacks.

Another potential weakness. Destroying this condensed body would do more damage than striking anywhere else, as it contained more energy than anywhere else. If the Unique Lifeform had been C-grade, it could likely have made far more of these forms or perhaps not had to at all, but as things were, this was a limitation in its abilities.

The entire battle between the Unique Lifeforms ended up taking around an hour. After an hour, the King began to launch larger and larger attacks, damaging the Devourer more and more. Yet it also left him open, and the Devourer struck and tore off some of his natural bark-like armor, even smashing the King back several times.

Yet just as the King looked like he was about to unleash some final attack, the Ashen Phantom Devourer simply retreated. The domain moved away the same way it had come, and Jake stared after it as he saw it reach a large hole in the ground more than fifty kilometers from the King. When it reached the hole, the entire domain shrank and entered. The domain was only about sixty to seventy percent of its regular size at that point, too, visualizing the damage it had taken. It had clearly gone to absorb more energy again and return at full power, while Jake could see the King had taken far more damage and would need longer to heal.

A good strategy if you are not in a rush and play it safe… Too bad it read the situation wrong.

Jake took out his token again, and as he saw the King retreat to his residence, the connection was formed.

"Hey, Miranda, that was fast. So, how you holding up down there?" Jake asked the King

"As predicted. The Ashen Phantom Devourer should estimate that I am at about half resources now, and by the time it fully recovers, I would barely be able to reach around sixty to sixty-five percent. I also used my boosting skill liberally this time around to appear more desperate. In reality, I can consume a few Soul Marbles, and I should be back to over eighty percent. Before you ask, potions do not help; besides, potions barely work on Unique Lifeforms. My guess is that the Devourer shall return within the next twelve hours in an attempt to finish me off. In fact, I think it wanted this battle to be the last but decided to retreat to fully secure the kill without being harmed too much itself."

Jake nodded. "Twelve hours is plenty. Miranda, be ready to inform the Sword Saint. I will eat my bow if that orange bastard doesn’t have some method of coming to help fast, so we need the old man on his toes."

"Of course," Miranda agreed. "I will leave you to your preparations now. Neil has also prepared, and if everything goes as hoped, we should also be able to return to Haven promptly."

Jake once again nodded. "I have a good feel for what this Ashen Phantom Devourer can do now, and I believe it will be in for quite the surprise. You have confidence in fulfilling your part even with your injuries?"

The last part was naturally asked of the King.

"More than ready," the King responded confidently.

"Very well. See you when the Ashen Phantom Devourer arrives. I will prick your soul when I engage. Jake, over and out."

With that, the conversation ended, and nothing more needed to be said. All that was needed now was execution, and Jake had twelve hours to make sure everything was perfect. Luckily, he had already done most of these preparations by creating the one crucial factor to make their strategy work:

A working neurotoxin.

Due to the lack of time, Jake had not held back when it came to using ingredients. Jake had sought deep and taken out everything he had stored and bought from all around. He had experimented a lot and found one ingredient that mixed incredibly well with the kind of toxin he wanted to make. It was an old gift from his little brother.

[Umbral Lotus Leaf (Ancient)] – The leaf of a legendary-rarity Umbral Lotus. This leaf is incredibly poisonous and releases dark-affinity mana all around it. Consuming it may lead to adverse effects. Many alchemical uses and creations will have neurotoxic and Perception-limiting effects.

Jake had kind of forgotten he even had the lotus leaves. As he didn’t have enough of them to actually experiment, Jake had had one in Palate since the day he began working on the neurotoxin and instead used lesser dark mana poisons. His control of dark mana had proven invaluable during this process and allowed him to get better far faster than expected.

The second ingredient was naturally the Lifeblood.

[Lifeblood of the Emperor Urchin (Ancient)] – The Lifeblood of a slain Emperor Urchin, an incredibly poisonous creature only found in areas with extremely dense water affinity. Its very blood is toxic to consume and especially toxic if directly injected. The Lifeblood is of a neurotoxic nature. Has many alchemical uses and is especially potent when combined with other neurotoxins or poisons with the water affinity.

Then, for a third ingredient, he also pulled out something he hadn’t really ever made use of. A reward from the entrance-exam dungeon of the Academy in the Order.

[Refined Manticore Stinger (Epic)] – The refined stinger of a high-tier D-grade Manticore. The venom within is now more powerful than ever, even compared to when it was alive. This toxin is of the earth affinity and will petrify anything it comes into contact with. Slowly produces more venom when infused with appropriate energy. Has many alchemical uses.

Jake had carried it around with him for a long time, producing plenty of venom passively during this time. He had found that only natural passive mana seemed to work with it, meaning Jake could not infuse it himself… but Sandy could. So, Sandy had been nice enough to dedicate a stomach to storing the stinger and constantly infusing it with energy to pump out more and more venom.

The petrification effect was good at adding a certain rigidity to the neurotoxin. He did not need the petrification effect, but just making it a bit harder to move was more than fine. Just as he’d ended up refining away the water-affinity part of the Lifeblood, so had he removed most of the earth affinity of this one.

Finally, to finish off the concoction, Jake naturally added his blood as well as some good old moss. Moss was always good in these kinds of concoctions.

It had taken many days of experimenting and many failed products. Jake did make several neurotoxins, but every time he made one, he ran into the same issue of how to deliver it properly. Making a poison that had to contact the ash itself was not feasible, based on what the King had told him during his preparation phase, so Jake had gone in a direction where it simply needed to touch the Soulshape.

This meant Jake sacrificed a lot of potency for easier delivery. He also sacrificed a lot of other aspects of the poison. It did not need to deal damage; it did not need to even be particularly potent… It just had to work and be hard to deal with in a short amount of time.

Making a poison like this in only a few weeks was not easy, but Jake luckily had enough good ingredients with him to waste. What he didn’t have enough of, Sandy had helped him find. Finally, three days before they’d arrived at the mountain range, he had made the first batch of poison.

[Soul-Petrifying Shadow Poison (Rare)] – A special poison created by combining several powerful ingredients with the singular goal of creating a potent neurotoxin able to affect the soul. This is a soul poison that will actively attempt to affect any Soulshape it touches due to its nature. Once infected, a target’s Soulshape will become more rigid, severely limiting all mobility. The dark energy makes all movements of energy more difficult for any affected target. This poison is incredibly difficult to cleanse and has a slight ability to self-replicate if not actively challenged, and it will strengthen itself as more poison is injected.

The poison looked good and had a long description, but quite frankly, it was atrocious. It was weak as hell, and Jake would prefer to use common-rarity poison on his arrows over this new neurotoxin. Each dose was just so weak. However… it did its job. Because it had an element of scalability beyond any other poison he had ever made.

More importantly, it was relatively easy to make as long as he had all the ingredients. The rarity was only what it was due to the ingredients used, and the level of difficulty—or lack thereof—was also reflected in him having only gained two levels.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 191 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 192 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 193 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

These levels included all the batches Jake had made. He only had three leaves, but luckily each leaf had enough energy for several batches of poison. This meant Jake had managed to create a total of fourteen batches of the poison, resulting in seventy-one bottles. He had only failed a single concoction, and that had been his third-ever attempt, once more reflecting the easy crafting difficulty.

Compared to his Sleeping Night Toxin, this poison was shameful, and he would gladly forget he had ever made it once done… but for this fight, it should be enough. If he had more time, perhaps he could have made it better, but he didn’t.

One good thing, though. After this fight, he wouldn’t have any more of the poison, because all of it was getting used today.

With twelve hours or so to the fight, Jake began preparing. He would show that while the two Unique Lifeforms could perhaps match or even beat him in a straight-on fight, the game changed when he had preparation time.

The Ashen Phantom Devourer was about to learn why messing with an alchemist—or worse, an alchemist-hunter—was what many would classify as a very bad time.

Chapter 50

Broken Sky

It was a fight that he knew they could not lose. One that could perhaps decide the fate of the planet he had now come to call home.

The King meditated as he healed himself as much as possible. He wished he had the skill to set up a proper formation to help him in his regeneration, but sadly that did not fall within his skillset. Having anyone else make such a magic circle also wouldn’t prove very effective due to the uniqueness of a Unique Lifeform.

The King consumed and slowly absorbed a Soul Marble, feeling his body fill with energy. He would take another one just as the Ashen Phantom Devourer attacked again, but that would also be his final one.

One might ask why the King stayed in a losing war for months. There truly was no logical explanation for this besides an unwillingness to retreat and abandon his claimed territory. He was a King, and an enemy had invaded his domain, so he had a natural urge to defend it. That he knew the benefits he could gain from killing another Unique Lifeform also played a huge factor. Finally, he still had a good chance due to his ultimate move.

Hours passed, and he progressively felt better. He purposefully did not heal his natural armor fully, allowing cracks and missing pieces here and there to look like he had been unable to properly recover. One might also ask if using these underhanded tactics wasn’t above a Unique Lifeform, but the King would find such a question utterly foolish. To purposefully give up an advantage and act with overconfidence was how he had found himself slain once already, and he had no desire to repeat that.

His prediction of twelve hours turned out to be slightly off, as only nine and a half hours later, he felt the other Unique Lifeform approach. The Fallen King could only hope that the little hunter was ready despite the pushed-up timescale, and if not, the King would simply have to hold on a bit longer than expected.

The King teleported out of his residence and saw the incoming mass. A soul of equal power approached, its size and power nearly fully recovered in such a short time span. The giant cloud of ash moved ever closer as the taunting words echoed.

"Yet you remain guarding your pathetic kingdom in your ignorance. Behold the result of your folly: death."

It had almost become a ritual by now for the other Unique Lifeform to start by saying something taunting and slightly annoying. Not that the King had ever been bothered by such childish words. Like before, he simply engaged, but he made sure to hold himself back a bit this time around to appear weaker than he actually was.

The Ashen Phantom Devourer struck with full force right from the beginning. Evidently, the intent was to overwhelm the King so that he would use his trump cards while the Devourer was still close to full power, allowing it to slay him as soon as possible.

Staying defensive was difficult, even if the King knew he was just buying time, and he did launch the occasional attack to not be too suspicious. Luckily, the other Unique Lifeform could easily misunderstand his carefulness as doubt and weakness, making it appear less out of place than it actually was.

Massive waves of ash crashed against the telekinetically formed barriers of the King like the tide of the ocean crashing into a dam. With every second, they grew in power, and the King felt the constant eating away of his energy from the dark affinity of his foe.

Nevertheless, he was far from defenseless. Both his claws glowed golden as he tore the wave apart and unleashed several of his own, breaking apart the body of the Devourer. It rapidly condensed a new one as a mountain of ash formed and crashed down towards the King. Hundreds of tons of ash fell upon his body, smashing him into the ground despite his barrier.

With annoyance, the King raised two fingers and sent out two thin waves of force that he swiftly moved in a circle, cutting a hole in the ash. He barely got through before the hole closed, the King avoiding being crushed. Yet just as he emerged, the King was struck by a blast of ash, sending him tumbling back. Sometimes the Devourer infused the ash with pure space energy, making it look like a transparent flame despite it simply being pure kinetic force infused into ash.

An annoying but highly effective attack.

About five minutes passed as they fought, the King getting forced back more and more. A vague sense of doubt began to enter the King’s regarding whether the little hunter was ready. The King would have to pick up the pace himself and use his boosting skill prematurely if he was not. That could potentially throw off the plan.

Just when that doubt set in, he felt a weak attack on his soul from far above. It was the Hunter’s gaze that had briefly landed upon him and attacked.

Too weak to damage him or even affect him, but just strong enough for him to sense.

It was the agreed-upon signal, and the King did his part.

Activating his boosting skill, the King attacked with massive waves of force, making the Ashen Phantom Devourer defend. While it was still defending, the King spread his presence and focused all his power on restricting the domain.

He hoped that whatever the Hunter had prepared would be enough to—

The King felt a shockwave. Both he and the other Unique Lifeform momentarily stopped as their senses sought the sky.

A sky that looked to have been shattered, falling as crystals in shades of purple.

The shade of the Hunter’s arcane affinity.

Perhaps this clash could be the last, the observer noted with hope. He had been stuck in the mountains for months now at the orders of the Celestial Child, and while he did have some complaints about his station, he did not complain. It was the will of heaven’s child; who was he to argue? Besides, he knew he was the weakest of those who had been brought to this new planet.

He had looked at this battle play out so many times already, and he had noticed the shift. The first time the Ashen Phantom Devourer had lost pretty handily, enough for him to assume that perhaps this Fallen King was superior. However, as time went on, the momentum shifted, and the Devourer slowly began winning out. Once more, he, as a servant, could only admonish himself for questioning the actions of the Celestial Child.

This time around, the fight was indeed much more fierce, as both seemed to go all out. Then, suddenly, the Fallen King seemed to stop. He pulled out immense amounts of power to hold the Ashen Phantom Devourer still. Is this perhaps his trump move?

He got his answer at that very moment. As a servant, his skills were limited in everything but Perception, and yet he had not noticed something had been brewing far up in the sky. When he saw it, he instantly recognized the energy signature.

The Malefic’s Chosen.

The servant quickly took out a token and fulfilled his duty, infusing his message that the Chosen was there before crushing it. He took out another token in preparation to relay what was about to happen, but he suddenly felt a shift in space behind him.

He quickly turned and saw a figure had appeared only a kilometer or so behind him, having been teleported in.

Who!? Wait…

The figure rapidly made its way over as the servant spoke, "What are you doing he—"

The words got stuck in his throat, nothing more than a hiss coming out. He stared with wide eyes as strings wrapped around his neck, but surprisingly they didn’t harm him. Why would they harm him, now that he thought about it? Why was he even…

His thoughts didn’t go further as his mind slowly gave out, and he fell to the ground, unconscious.

--

"It is time," the C-grade jellyfish spoke as William opened his eyes.

"Has he appeared?" William asked with a mix of anticipation and reprehension.

"Yes," the jellyfish answered without explaining further.

William knew that he couldn’t delay, having already spent many days steeling his resolve. "Take me there.”

A magic circle appeared on the platform in the cave. The metal mage promptly flew over and landed on it, and the space magic around him warped everything. The teleportation was truly marvelous, and only a few seconds later, William found himself standing on a small cliff on the side of a mountain.

Instantly, he felt the wave of pure power descending. He did not know who it was initially, but soon he realized.

Yet another thing also caught his eye. A nahoom was hiding not far from him, holding a token and also observing. William did not know why, but his first reaction was to charge the alien. The other party had already seen him, but before he could finish asking why William was there, strings had already wrapped around his neck.

William sent through a powerful pulse of pure karmic energy. He manipulated the man until he fell. Knocked out but still alive. Seeing the token that had fallen on the ground, William just shook his head. He knew he had just helped the monster… but it was necessary. William needed to confront him, and Ell’Hakan showing up would ruin that. Moreover, he would prefer for no one else to know he was there or what he was doing.

As for the fight between the Unique Lifeforms and the monster… William already knew it was not anything he should get involved in. Whatever the hell that monster had done was exactly the kind of thing one could expect, as the entire mountain range was bathed in a hue of purple.

--

Approximately nine hours earlier.

Prep work for any large project was always hard work, but Jake had enjoyed his time doing it. Twelve hours to prepare wasn’t a lot, but to Jake, that was eleven mana potions and a whole lot of mana. After his conversation with the King, he got to work.

Using Avaricious Arcane Hunter’s Arrows, Jake summoned a stable arrow and proceeded to take out a bottle of his sweet neurotoxin. He carefully soaked it in poison and, using stable arcane mana, dripped a bit more poison on the tip before covering it up, leaving a hollow tip with still more poison inside.

After that, he tossed the arrow in his quiver and summoned another, only to repeat the process. Hours passed as Jake kept making arrows and putting them in his quiver, where they would remain effectively frozen in time. He did use his quiver to store poisoned arrows usually, but this was the most extreme case of him ever doing it. Frankly, the quiver was one of those things Jake barely thought about in his daily life, even though it was incredibly valuable to him.

[Quiver of Perriniality (Legendary)] – A quiver created from the leather of a powerful B-grade beast with the ability to create minor subdimensions within its skin, which then stores different natural treasures to use as weapons. Made into a quiver, it now retains those same effects. Allows the wearer to infuse mana into the quiver to conjure arrows. Allows the wearer to store conjured creations classified as arrows within the quiver without experiencing any energy decay for an extended period of time. The inside of the quiver is spatially expanded, allowing the wearer to store arrows of varying sizes. The wearer will have innate control of the inside of the quiver when bound. Enchantments: Perrinial Quiver.

Requirements: Lvl 135+ in any humanoid race.

He was glad that the arrows stayed classified as weapons even after he modified them slightly with a toxic payload. Jake had also made sure that he didn’t break integral parts of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter’s Arrows skill, because he would need a function of that skill later.

A hundred arrows were soon stored. Then two hundred. Three hundred. The bottles of poison emptied one by one, and Jake had to consume a mana potion here and there as he began the second aspect of the project. Inside the quiver, an arrow began to appear as Jake closed his eyes and focused.

It was entirely purple but had green threads running through it. Its size was incomparable to anything Jake had ever made before, and he was happy to see that his Willpower did slightly help him also affect the shape. It was naturally an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter, and the one he was summoning was incredibly thin for its size and close to five meters long. His time observing the Unique Lifeform had been primarily to make this exact arrow.

Once it was fully summoned, Jake began the third part. In the real world, Jake began weaving a net of mana strings and wrapping it up tight in preparation. He could sadly not do it in the quiver, so this had to be enough.

Hours kept ticking by, but Jake was ready after the seventh. He knew there was a chance the Unique Lifeform would come earlier, and his guts told him he wouldn’t have the full twelve hours. He trusted himself as always and went with seven to prepare in order to be safe.

Jake then spent the next hour summoning stable arcane bolts. During this time, Jake had never been topped up with mana. He consumed a mana potion whenever he could, primarily to ensure he was always close to full in case the fighting began.

Soon, Jake spotted the Ashen Phantom Devourer emerge from its underground hunt. Jake did not hesitate for a moment. Arcane Awakening activated at its full 60%, and he unleashed Pride of the Malefic Viper to better control his mana.

He then threw hundreds upon hundreds of arrows out of the quiver. Using Pride, he froze them all and made them levitate as he finally reached the final arrow. The massive Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter emerged, and Jake’s many magic strings instantly sought towards it and wrapped around it. These strings then flew out from the large arrow and wrapped themselves around the hundreds of smaller arrows.

His head was pounding, his body overflowing with mana as he finished his massive tapestry of arrows. In the sky hung a vast spiderweb of interlinked arrows with stable arcane bolts also mixed in here and here. As a final thing, Jake infused stability into all of the strings to make sure they didn’t break.

Taking a deep breath, Jake finally took out his bow and nocked the massive Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter that all of the other arrows were attached to. He began charging Arcane Powershot, and energy flooded the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter without harming any of the strings on it.

Jake had also learned something else about Hunting Momentum that day. While it did build up when he observed a target and stalked it, that charging was usually incredibly slow. But preparing to strike like this? It had been building far more than expected, and while it was far from maxed out, it was an added bonus he would in no way say no to as he infused it all into the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter.

Go.

The strike contained everything he had, and the opponent wasn’t even aware it was coming, making Stealth Attack further amplify the power of the strike. Jake released the string, and an explosion rocked the sky. The clouds parted all around him as the massive arrow began descending, dragging along with it over four hundred other arrows and well over a thousand arcane bolts.

It did not stop there. Jake began flying downwards without hesitation, chasing his arrows.

Nothing could stop the attack, and a few unlucky creatures that got in the way died simply by being too close to the descending strike. Jake kept pushing himself to follow the arrow, which naturally flew far faster, and soon enough, it exited the final layer of clouds just above the Ashen Phantom Devourer’s domain.

Jake gritted his teeth and strained himself more than ever before. Blood began pouring out his nose, and his head felt like it was about to explode. Yet he grinned, as he knew he could do it. He felt the connection to every single arrow—all four hundred and eleven of them—as he used every shred of his Willpower to activate the skill, even using Words of Power.

"Splitting Arrow Rain."

Chapter 51

Unique Trump Cards

One became ten.

Each arrow split ten times, making what would only have been light rain into a storm flood. Each arrow was still purely stable arcane mana as it fell. The Ashen Phantom Devourer reacted quickly by trying to move away, but the King strained himself to contain the Unique Lifeform.

Not that he had to constrain it for long, as the arrows struck less than a second after becoming visible. The Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter hit the domain and instantly disappeared into the Soulshape of the Unique Lifeform. This left the more than four thousand arrows and many stable arcane bolts to just fall into the domain.

Jake, with blood running from his nose and a toothy grin, acted. The connection with the arrows had never been lost, and it took nothing more than a mental command. Every single arrow crackled with instability as, in an instant, they shifted from pure stability to pure destruction.

And then everything exploded.

From up in the air, Jake saw the entire world flash purple. Even with his high Perception, it took him a second to see again, and what was revealed could only be described as a cataclysm. What had once been a mountain range was now still kind of a mountain range, but with a massive crater in the middle.

However, Jake had no time or attention to spare for observing the environment. He had known that even if this attack went above and beyond his expectations, it would not be enough to kill a peak D-grade Unique Lifeform. And he had been right.

All the ash had been destroyed, but the domain remained. The King had managed to shield himself, as he was not the primary target, and did not hesitate to engage as the domain stirred. Ash began appearing as a figure assembled itself.

Jake pulled out his bow while flying down and released another barrage of arrows. A wall of ash appeared and blocked them all, but this left an opening for a golden wave to cut across the domain and destroy the assembled being of ash.

Another one appeared, but there was no time to rest. The domain had shrunk by nearly forty percent from that one opening attack, and as Jake released his second attack, the barrier did not manage to be assembled in time. It was instead conjured just after the arrows passed, allowing arcane explosions to destroy even more of the ash.

The neurotoxin was beginning to really kick in. Jake was also certain that every bit of ash now had an even higher cost to being summoned. The Unique Lifeform had also naturally noticed the poison and begun eliminating it from its soul.

Oh, no, you don’t!

Touch of the Malefic Viper activated as Jake controlled the poison from up in the air. The King also did his part. Explosions rocked the domain, and golden waves constantly ripped apart the creature. Soon, the Unique Lifeform tried to escape, but Jake slowed it down enough for the King to easily keep up.

Jake followed the domain of ash across the vast mountain range, focusing solely on Touch of the Malefic Viper. With every second, the domain shrank by a little, and the King seemed to only increase the fervor with which he attacked.

After a minute or so of this, the Ashen Phantom Devourer seemed to realize it was actually in trouble. Big trouble.

"Pathetic to require the help of a mere human! An utter embarrassment to call yourself a Unique Lifeform! If you truly think this is enough to—"

"Funny," the voice of the King echoed out as it interrupted the Devourer. "You sound like me just before this very same human killed me."

The Unique Lifeform seemed shocked for a moment. Jake even felt it stop fighting his poison for a fraction of a second. Yet it quickly collected itself, an odd calmness overtaking its form. Jake felt the shift instantly, and a sense of danger appeared, telling him to stay the fuck away from the Devourer.

"I see."

That was all the Ashen Phantom Devourer said as it stopped completely. The King kept attacking, but Jake rapidly threw him a look and used a weak Gaze to warn him. Just in time, too.

Everything warped. Space itself shattered and distorted as the domain collapsed in on itself, releasing a massive wave of energy that sent Jake flying upwards and pushed back the King, who had barely managed to get out of the domain.

Then, with the push came a pull. The entire Unique Lifeform was now no more than five meters across and looked like a miniature black sun… No. What could happen to a star after it collapsed.

At that moment, the Ashen Phantom Devourer had become what Jake could only describe as a black hole. And as a black hole, it sought to devour everything.

Space itself bent, light refracted, and the mountains surrounding them began cracking and collapsing in the distance. The ground below rose as Jake felt a pull—not only on the physical realm, but even the metaphysical one.

Mana, affinities—everything was being pulled in. Jake had to resist it as he flew upwards with all his might, and he even felt the poison being rapidly consumed and devoured as the black hole grew. Gritting his teeth, Jake stopped himself in the air and reached out, his hand glowing green.

Black veins spread up his arm as he infused his hand with even more energy, intensifying the glow. His poison gained new life, destabilizing the black hole and lessening its suction. It was still growing, but it had slowed down.

As Jake considered what to do next, he saw the King move. Rather than retreat, the Unique Lifeform flew forward with his glowing golden barrier. Power revolved around him, and Jake realized what he was about to do.

Without a doubt, this was the trump card of the Ashen Phantom Devourer. It was well known that all Unique Lifeforms were innately born with one such unique skill. The Devourer had one… and so did the Fallen King.

The King did not stop as he reached the black hole, and Jake helped by channeling Touch to the extreme. He suddenly heard a crack. A deep scar formed on his mask, followed by many smaller cracks and crevices.

Below, Jake saw the King enter the black hole as the mask slipped off his face, falling towards the ground. Falling, because the very moment the King entered the domain of the Ashen Phantom Devourer, the suction stopped.

The world seemed still. Everything that had been floating in the air stopped, and Jake even sensed that his own poison was unable to move. Unable because what it resided within—the Soulshape of the Devourer—shuddered.

Shattered.

An invisible wave erupted from within the black hole. Jake summoned a barrier of stable arcane energy and, to his surprise, managed to entirely block it out, making him realize this was mere remnants of the actual attack.

Jake stared as everything the Devourer was consuming fell down again. Where the black hole had been, a single figure remained and reached out with an ivory claw. The shattered mask, still falling, reassembled in mid-air and was telekinetically called over to the King, who put it back on. In the other hand, he held a small black orb that promptly disappeared.

The black hole was gone. The domain was gone. And all Jake felt were broken remnants of what had once been a soul floating in the air before dispersing—a bit of it entering Eternal Hunger, as always.

*You have slain [Ashen Phantom Devourer – lvl 199] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 195 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Jake kept staring. The notification was there, but a hint of doubt still remained in his mind. It felt too… easy?

He began flying down as the King also descended to the ground. The Unique Lifeform landed and sat down, and Jake felt the energy fluctuate within the King. He felt weak, far weaker than usual, and looking at the mask on the King and Jake himself, he was indeed damaged on a fundamental level.

"Is it dead?" Jake asked as he landed.

"You unleash an attack capable of destroying an entire region upon a creature that is effectively a living domain, further adding a massive toxic payload to the mayhem you created, and you question its efficiency?" The King scoffed. "The Devourer is dead. The soul was weakened and capable of destruction, so I capitalized on the weakness and went in for the kill."

Jake considered that for a moment before grinning. "Turns out you Unique Lifeforms aren’t all you are hyped up to be."

The King did not even bother responding to that. "I, too, had to use my trump card, and will find myself weakened for a period. I apologize. You will have to deal with the rest of your matters by yourself."

"That was the plan," Jake said with a nod.

And he already knew the first matter to deal with. From up in the air, he had spotted a little nahoom rat keeping an eye on the King and the Devourer fighting.

"How unexpected, but not entirely unpredictable," Ell’Hakan mused to himself the moment he got the message from the servant observing the fight between the two Unique Lifeforms. He had now sent a message stating that it appeared someone else had also joined the fight, with the only likely culprit being the Malefic’s Chosen.

Needless to say, he could not have an important bout between two Unique Lifeforms going on without keeping a constant eye on it. It was sad that he could only get a brief message without any details, but just knowing it was happening was good enough. He did expect a more thorough report from the observer soon, but there was no need to wait for that.

Ell’Hakan had expected the Malefic’s Chosen to prioritize returning to Haven over engaging the Unique Lifeform. That the Ashen Phantom Devourer had yet to defeat this Fallen King was as to be expected, and he didn’t have his servants interfere for a reason. Either Unique Lifeform winning was simply not of particular interest to him—at least, not if one won too fast.

The one winning would have to be the Ashen Phantom Devourer, though. With both the Fallen King and the Malefic’s Chosen there, the Unique Lifeform should be pressured, giving Ell’Hakan quite an opportunity if he said so himself. Keeping a Unique Lifeform loyal was difficult, but if he could get it to feel a sense of debt towards him, that would be more than welcome and extremely exploitable.

Now, as said, he would naturally not allow such a battle to go on without having a method of keeping an eye on it, and in the same vein, he would not allow such a battle to take place without giving him a way to get there.

The house he had constructed was not just for him to reside in while waiting for the Malefic’s Chosen, but also to serve as a small hub for teleportation. Taking out a token, he called for one of the two people stationed in Haven to come over and operate the teleportation circle for him to use. The distance required for the teleportation made it a necessity to have someone on this side.

Ell’Hakan waited and soon saw his servant rushing towards him. Just before he could begin to gather the energy from the sun and moon array, he stopped. Something had suddenly appeared in the plains, looking like a rectangular wall or…

A painting?

Out stepped a figure Ell’Hakan did not immediately recognize, and his servant clearly didn’t either as she continued running. It was only a few seconds later that Ell’Hakan realized who this newcomer was. The Patriarch from the Noboru Clan.

Unexpectedly, a second figure then also appeared out of thin air. A red liquid that Ell’Hakan surmised had to be blood formed a human-looking figure that promptly intercepted the servant. To his surprise, his servant was actually stopped in her tracks when a large wall of blood appeared and pushed her back.

The old man from the Noboru clan didn’t even look back, instead wandering through the plains towards Ell’Hakan. He looked relaxed, far more so than he should, and as their eyes met, Ell’Hakan frowned. He felt the emotions from the man, and they were not as expected.

He felt as if he was staring at a still lake and not a human being. Nevertheless, even if it was so, that didn’t mean much in the grand scheme of things.

Ell’Hakan walked down the steps of his residence towards the old swordsman. Neither had drawn their weapon, and he saw no reason to be the first to do so. His servant dying would be an annoyance, but if push came to shove, the teleporter could still be activated and bring Ell’Hakan to his destination—if he was fine with destroying it in the process and having the servant on the other side suffer the backlash.

However, that would put him far away from Haven, allowing the Malefic’s Chosen to potentially retreat and make his way there before Ell’Hakan could. He still had things he wanted to be done here in Haven, and more importantly, it could only be activated in these plains outside of the small city. Besides, even if he lost this one servant to what he guessed was an unknown blood mage, there was another stationed in Haven he could call upon.

Needless to say, something had to be done before that was an option.

"Patriarch of the Noboru clan," Ell’Hakan spoke, “your presence here intrigues me. Last I heard, you were dead, but I reckoned something was off about that, considering I haven’t heard back from your killers-to-be."

Ell’Hakan estimated the human must have spent the last few months recuperating. After the fight during the Treasure Hunt event Earth had undergone, the Sword Saint, as people called him, had been cooped up and injured for several months. The only thing capable of leaving such harm was severe overuse of a boosting skill or soul damage. He guessed it was the overuse of a boosting skill, and it looked like he’d had to use that boosting skill once more to handle the two servants. If not, why would he not have handled internal matters of his clan?

"I apologize if it inconvenienced you that I killed the two of them," the old man surprisingly apologized. Not that there was a hint of actual regret in his emotional spectrum. Not a single ripple disturbed the lake.

"They went knowing death was a potential outcome,” Ell’Hakan said convincingly. Trying to throw a rock into the lake, he continued, “I do wonder why you have appeared here. Please, do enlighten me? From what I heard, your clan is in shambles and could very much need their Patriarch right now. Some of them have even reached out with interest in an alliance. It is not too late to reconsider.”

"A shameful display, and only proof a cleaning of the old clan is required," the swordsman said with a sigh, for the first time showing a faint hint of disappointment. It disappeared as fast as it had come, but it confirmed the man could not fully control his emotions. No human could. No… no living entity with emotions could fully control them. Not even gods.

Nodding, Ell’Hakan decided he should stop wasting time. "Your attempt at buying time is valiant; however, I must disappoint you. While I would love a conversation, I have other, more pressing matters to attend to. I truly hold no interest in you or your clan, and I will give you the choice of leaving now or accepting the consequences of staying."

"Tell me… Ell’Hakan, was it? What do you think of this planet? Its lands and its residents?"

"Chaotic but malleable," Ell’Hakan answered, humoring him for a moment.

"Chaotic… Yes, to that, I agree.” The man nodded and smiled. "Secondly, you fought Jake Thayne, the Malefic’s Chosen. What was your assessment of him?"

"Chaotic fits him very adequately, too. Powerful, yes, but chaotic. I fail to see the purpose of this line of questioning outside of simply delaying me by piquing my curiosity?"

"I was curious, too," the old human said as he slowly unsheathed a sword. The blade looked simple and unassuming, but Ell’Hakan felt uneasy when he looked at it. "Curious how far I have come. Please allow this old man the honor of your assessment, you who have conquered another world."

Ell’Hakan was about to answer when the lake of emotions rippled and moved. His eyes opened wide as serenity was replaced with pure devotion, and when the old human bent his knees, an aura washed through the plains, the mental image of his emotional state replacing a lake with that of a sword.

More than a distraction, Ell’Hakan realized as he took out his trident and got into a defensive position.

Chapter 52

Sun & Rain

Sword met trident as the clang of metal sent them both back. The blade rose again, the robed nahoom retreating with measured steps. Miyamoto pressed forward as several more blows were exchanged, his opponent backing away with every attack.

The mana in the air began to heat up as the swordsman dodged to avoid a beam of concentrated sunlight descending from far above. Around the alien invader, a ring of golden light formed, the very plains around them seeming to resonate with him. The ring moved in front of Ell’Hakan as the trident stabbed forward, releasing an explosion of golden flames and forcing Miyamoto to leap back.

"This planet keeps perplexing me," Ell’Hakan spoke as he spun his trident, leaving trails of flames behind it. "The information on you was limited. I genuinely expected those two to be capable of killing you, and even if they failed, to at least put you out of commission for a good while. It appears I was way off."

"To reach for true power is to subvert fate and expectations," Miyamoto simply spoke as water droplets formed around him as if it were raining.

Ell’Hakan responded by sending out a wave of golden flames, intensifying the sunlight above. Several golden orbs appeared in the sky, all of them burning with deep flames. The Sword Saint countered with a thin mirror of water to block out the flames entirely.

The nahoom had taken this brief chance to move, turning into golden flames and appearing further back. Rising into the air, a magic circle appeared above him as he pointed towards the Sword Saint.

Miyamoto wanted to move, but he suddenly found space itself acting up. Like he’d been separated from reality itself.

"I must apologize, but I simply do not have the time to be fighting you right now," Ell’Hakan spoke. "Please be so kind as to be gone."

The magic circle above him intensified in energy. Miyamoto had heard of this, and even if it was far weaker than what had been used on Jake, it was still a very potent skill.

"Celestial Alignment of Yore."

Everything spun as the Sword Saint was sent flying. While in the air, he pointed his blade forward and closed his eyes. A plane of water condensed as he inserted his sword into it. Colors began to appear on the plane, and soon it depicted plains with a small, lonely house sitting in the middle. The painting was not made from memory; he had painstakingly painted it only the day before.

Miyamoto willed the plane of water to move as he also stepped into it, appearing standing on the plains only a few hundred meters from where he had been before. A confused Ell’Hakan whipped around to see him standing there.

"I must also apologize," Miyamoto said, not a hint of being sorry in his voice. "My hobby happens to be painting."

"That was not space magic," Ell’Hakan said with a frown.

"No, it was not.”

"Then was it—"

The Sword Saint charged forward without answering, water condensing around his blade. Ell’Hakan frowned even more as he was forced to block and sent backward. Miyamoto did not give him time to rest. The water droplets condensed even more around the tip of his blade as he stabbed forward.

A single droplet was shot forward, drawing the first blood of their battle. A thin cut tore through Ell’Hakan’s robe and left a slit on the side of his arm. Miyamoto moved to attack again, but his opponent’s body language made him reconsider as he stepped down hard and jumped back.

Just in time, too, as a massive beam of sunlight shot down and left a huge scorch mark just where he would have been standing. Opening his eyes wide, the Sword Saint swept his blade upwards and sent out a crescent wave of water that encountered another massive beam.

It was cut in two, leaving him unscathed as the water refracted the light. However, even so, Ell’Hakan was clearly done playing around. A dense aura of heat spread from him as the plains themselves were set ablaze. The sun seemed to almost turn entirely red, the sky above resonating with the burning plains below.

"This time, I genuinely apologize. I shall take you seriously."

The sun above pulsed, and a wave of red light descended upon the plains. Miyamoto opened his eyes wide as the sun suddenly seemed to disappear from the sky above, only to reappear below the horizon far behind Ell’Hakan.

"Sunrise."

A blast of flames forced Miyamoto back. A barrier of water protected him as he smiled. He landed on the ground and shifted his stance, holding the handle of his blade with both hands. His boosting skill activated as he also got serious.

"Rainblade."

Water met fire as their two domains clashed. Ell’Hakan turned into red flames and stormed forward, the Sword Saint responding in kind. They exchanged several blows, the Sword Saint slowly winning out as the nahoom was pushed back.

So far, the only wound given had been that minor cut, but that all changed now. Several small scratches began to appear on Ell’Hakan, but Miyamoto did not relax. The gaze of his foe was calm and collected. He did not panic in the slightest, even as he took a cut on his shoulder, forcing him to retreat.

Swiping his blade, the Sword Saint sent a long crescent wave of water out, making Ell’Hakan vault over it. He pointed his trident forward and shot a condensed beam of light, singing the Sword Saint’s left arm slightly when he failed to dodge in time.

Not feeling deterred, he moved forward again and pointed his blade.

"Ten Thousand Droplets."

As he willed, ten thousand small droplets appeared and shot forward. A vast wall of red flames met them, evaporating most, but some got through. Ell’Hakan was hit and stumbled back with dozens of minor puncture wounds covering his chest.

Yet he seemed relatively unbothered. The trident moved again, the middle of the three forks lighting up. The sun behind him then began ascending as the temperature rose, and the sky itself began burning. An endless inferno descended upon the old man, which he met with the serenity of an undisturbed lake.

Water whirled around his sword, Rainblade making it an instrument of the element itself. He slashed as a wave of water appeared that rapidly multiplied and countered the fire descending towards him. In the same fluid movement, he positioned his blade and blocked the trident of Ell’Hakan, feeling that the alien had gotten even stronger than before.

Physically, the Sword Saint was perhaps superior, but Ell’Hakan did not simply rely on his physical stats. Every attack was infused with a powerful concept. Not that the Sword Saint found himself on the backfoot due to this.

Their weapons flew through the air and clashed multiple times. Miyamoto analyzed his opponent and slowly began to regain the upper hand. With an upwards strike, he made Ell’Hakan attempt to dodge, but the blade pivoted to the side and turned the slash into a sideway sweep.

The alien tried to teleport, but droplets of water had landed upon him to restrict his movements ever so slightly. The blade sank into the side of Ell’Hakan, but he managed to turn to flames, leaving a spray of blood in his wake.

He appeared again a few hundred meters away, his side entirely cut up. His left lumbar was halfway cut through in what would have been a lethal blow pre-system. Miyamoto considered charging again but held himself back.

"The sharpness of that blade… You cut through my bones like they were nothing," Ell’Hakan spoke in a contemplative tone. "I wonder, why is someone like you working for the Malefic’s Chosen? What do you have to gain by doing so?"

The Sword Saint just smirked to himself as he sheathed his blade. "What do you have to gain by invading the planet of another Chosen? Much less one who has nothing to do with you. You are the only one who chose to make an enemy, not him. In my eyes, the questionable decisions in this entire conflict are one-sided. There is an aggressor and a defender, with the natural inclination of man being to side with the defender."

Ell’Hakan looked at the Sword Saint a bit more before shaking his head. "You have no reason beyond personal sentiment? Do you honestly see your clan thriving more under the oppressive rule of the Order of the Malefic Viper than the United Cities Alliance? An alliance that is even protected by Valhal from outside forces? Meanwhile, the Order tends to make the areas they control living hells for those not part of their cult."

"I fail to comprehend the purpose of your words." Miyamoto smiled. "He who stands before you is nothing more than a simple lone swordsman. Order, Alliance, gods. Nothing else matters when two warriors meet. Unless you choose to continue this meeting as non-warriors, cease your needless words. I say this assuming you came here as a warrior to begin with, of course."

The nahoom’s smile faded, and Miyamoto knew something was coming. Underestimating his foe was something he would never do, and he prepared to draw.

Ell’Hakan raised his trident towards the sky. A beam of light descended upon him as Miyamoto saw the air shimmer. His water droplets began to evaporate, and his skin burned as the temperature rose even more than before. Up in the sky, the sun now hung right above his head.

"Scorching Noon."

Miyamoto also exploded with power, fully activating his boosting skill to stave off the constant exposure. Ell’Hakan also clearly did something similar, as his skin began glowing orange. The plains—now entirely free of vegetation—also glowed, and the Sword Saint felt the area itself feed whatever skill the alien was using.

Fighting a foe in their territory is always more complicated.

Taking a stance, the Sword Saint drew his blade once more and, with the draw, released a torrent of water as if he had just opened a floodgate. The nahoom was taken by surprise and sent blasting back, but Miyamoto followed the flow of water and made a downward cut.

His blade encountered the trident, the impact embedding the feet of his foe in the ground. The water covering his body allowed Miyamoto to ignore the sunlight for now, but he felt the draw on his resources.

Ell’Hakan’s trident seemed to explode, sending Miyamoto back a few steps. Refusing to lose momentum, the old man attacked again but was blocked. Blocked and countered. His speed fell behind his foe’s as he took a minor cut on the arm and another minor scratch on his thigh. Both wounds burned with golden flames, forcing him to expend even more energy putting them out.

Yet he attacked again. The flow of water was relentless, and so was he. After dodging an attack, he found an opening and stabbed forward. The blade extended and penetrated his foe, but as it was just a blade of water, it failed to cut through bone.

Ell’Hakan groaned and stumbled back, his eyes burning. He raised the trident and slammed it into the ground with both hands.

"Ember Chains."

The flames all around the old man suddenly condensed and formed chains as they came from all directions. He cut through several, but two managed to wrap around his one leg, tethering him to the ground and burning him.

"Sunwrath."

The entire world seemed to turn golden at that very moment. From above, a massive pillar of pure light and fire descended upon the lone, chained swordsman. He knew it was too late to dodge, so he used one of his rare defensive skills just as the attack hit.

Sunlight seared into the ground as everything around it burned, yet no one was caught within.

Miyamoto landed on the ground a few dozen meters to the left of it while taking a deep, tired breath. He had many nasty burns all over his body, and what little hair he had was already seared off. Where he had landed was where he had been only ten or so seconds ago.

"Time magic," Ell’Hakan recognized out loud. "Who the hell are you really?"

"A swordsman," Miyamoto simply answered.

This did not please his opponent, as another dozen or so, albeit far weaker, sunbeams shot down from the sky aimed at the old man. Not seeing himself be outdone, Miyamoto also began releasing ranged attacks, putting the alien on the defensive and leaving a few cuts here and there on his body.

He felt a hint of tiredness from constantly fighting under the intense sunlight, and he knew his foe was also getting tired. He knew by now he had more than fulfilled his task, and Ms. Wells had already tried to contact him once.

The old man had not answered, but he knew the outcome. One attempt to contact meant victory, two meant it was a draw, and three would have meant failure. Seeing as they had won, there was truly no reason but his own hubris to continue the fight.

But had Jake not said a bit more selfishness was healthy? If so, the old man would relish this opportunity to face a strong foe and show him that he, too, had not stopped growing stronger. A Chosen was a multiversally recognized title only given to supreme talents. Something many also apparently considered him. Miyamoto found it weird to call himself a talent, considering it was usually a title given to juniors, but he still wanted to prove himself.

For the longest time, he had been resistant to having a Patron. Aeon, the Primordial of Time, had convinced him that his stance was, in many ways, nonsensical. A Patron did not need to be someone you worshipped so much as a subtle guiding light. Moreover, the Sword Saint had found that he and his new Patron were more alike than one would perhaps expect.

While he had not taught Miyamoto much, the old man had learned a few things. The concept of time was vast and never-ending, and comprehending the nomological was as much about understanding yourself and your goals as it was understanding the world. In the same way, it also requires one to understand their position within this world.

Miyamoto knew he was a man that arguably should not even be alive. He had seen death more than once, and each time he had overcome it, or it just hadn’t been his time yet. He had been granted one more season. After his fight with Jake, he’d realized that in this changed world, it was no longer about accepting what you had been granted and making the best use of it. It was also about taking from the world.

His realizations had led to enlightenment and Transcendence. A Transcendence was viewed as the pinnacle of what one could achieve, but Miyamoto knew that wasn’t the case. Nothing could ever be truly perfect, and there was nothing that could not be honed. Nothing that could not be trained with and used in different ways.

This was the second thing his Patron had taught him. A Transcendence was far more than a single skill. It was a gateway and a Path. A recognition from the world itself.

Ell’Hakan regarded him as he levitated into the air. Miyamoto knew something big was coming, but he did not hold any fear. He sheathed his blade and bent his knees as he got into position.

"Well, then, swordsman," Ell’Hakan spoke, “please also assess me as I assess you. Shatter my expectations more."

His words were not spoken in a tone of mockery. There was genuine respect in his voice, and his request was not a joke either.

The old man would oblige.

In the sky above, the sun turned entirely red. The sky was bathed orange, and the world was set aflame. The only place untouched in the plains was a small bubble around the Sword Saint as he stood with closed eyes, focusing.

All of the fire and heat then began condensing above the floating figure. A second celestial object slowly formed as a small sun was born. Ell’Hakan’s entire body burned as he stabbed his trident into it, turning it entirely golden.

Lowering the spear, the sun followed and began descending towards the Sword Saint like a giant fireball of certain destruction.

"Sunfall."

The heat was overwhelming, and the soil and sand all around the old swordsman began to change. Small pits of lava appeared, the sand turned to glass, and everything that couldn’t burn melted. Yet as everything was at the zenith… the sky darkened.

A drop of water fell upon the lava that had formed, turning it into black obsidian. Clouds appeared and blotted out the sun as the Sword Saint changed. His wrinkled hand turned smooth, black hair grew from his temples, and for a moment in time, he was in the prime of his youth.

"Glimpse of Spring: Stormcut."

He unsheathed his blade as the heavens shook and the clouds parted.

Chapter 53

Miscalculations & a Third Meeting

The heat dispersed as the sun was severed in two. The world flashed as it exploded, blanketing the entire plains in flames that washed over the old swordsman. His stance held firm, and soon enough, all the fire stopped.

Clouds above were parted as if a giant blade had cut them open. Miyamoto lowered his blade, his body wrinkled again, and his black hair turned gray, with most of it falling off. At least the burned-off eyebrows and what little hair he’d had before getting it burned off had returned.

"A Transcendent…"

The rain had already stopped falling, and the sun above dimmed. The Sword Saint frowned and squinted as the form of Ell’Hakan was revealed. A part of his thigh and his entire left arm had been severed, but his stance remained strong.

Miyamoto had hoped to do more.

Ell’Hakan regarded his injuries as flames licked the wounds. The sun was no longer red, but gentle flames still descended to heal the enemy Chosen. The Sword Saint considered his next move. To have a single Glimpse was something he could do without any significant backlash, but more than that would lead to consequences. To fully use Springtime Advent was also an option, but one he would naturally prefer to do without.

Just as he considered all this, his opponent dismissed his trident and floated down, landing on the ground.

"You called it a glimpse," Ell’Hakan spoke. "Which must mean that, should you truly call upon it…" The alien sighed. "You asked for my assessment. It appears you entirely fell outside of any I could have possibly had before we fought, but now that we have clashed, I believe I understand. You are truly just an old swordsman, in all its purity and all its power. I thank you, but continuing this battle would be detrimental to both of us, wouldn’t it?"

Miyamoto did not disagree. "You, too, asked for my assessment. While you are powerful, you seem to walk different Paths. Writing a story and trying to form a legend is not something one can force, but something that is born from truly monumental events. You can try but never guarantee success. No strategy or plan will ever work perfectly… but I have a feeling you already knew this."

Ell’Hakan smiled. "Several minutes ago, I got the message that the Ashen Phantom Devourer had fallen. If your primary objective was to delay me, then I will wholeheartedly admit defeat. Several miscalculations were made, the biggest of which being the Malefic’s Chosen’s speed at getting back and, perhaps more importantly, your existence. I heard the natives of this world call you the Sword Saint. An earned name."

The old man simply nodded in recognition, seeing no need to speak anymore.

"Considering all this, I must say my goodbyes and bow out," Ell’Hakan said. “Once more, I thank you. This was an enlightening encounter. However, I will leave you with a warning. While you may not see it happening now, the Order of the Malefic Viper is a faction to be wary of. The Malefic’s Chosen may strike you as a person worth trusting, but I felt his instability. He would not make a good leader, and I find it highly probable that other forces will simply make use of him until those with actual power in the Order step up and take over. So decide. Either give this planet to the Order of the Malefic Viper, or find a way to push them off it entirely.”

Miyamoto frowned—not due to the words, but what was lacking. He felt no emotional manipulation at all, and while it was possible he could just not detect it, he didn’t feel that was the case.

"Another miscalculation you have is in regard to Jake Thayne,” the Sword Saint replied. “I do agree he is not a good leader, and I do not see that changing. Leading is simply not his Path, but you view him as solely chaotic. I see more than that. You are not the only one who has clashed with him and made an assessment, and it is my turn to apologize now. I trust my own assessment far more than yours, young man.”

"Fair enough. I hope, for your sake, your choice turns out for the best. If not, then I am sure countless factions in the multiverse will gladly offer you a position. Perhaps my biggest miscalculation was to focus so much on the Malefic’s Chosen and not those who had chosen to gather around him.

"Now, I had more I wanted to do and say, but staying here only puts me further at risk. It would be silly for me to stay, only to figure out the Malefic’s Chosen somehow had a teleportation circle set up or something akin to that, leaving me to face a battle between two monsters. So may we meet again, Sword Saint. It truly was a pleasure.”

The house had been broken during the fight, but it appeared that a teleportation circle had still been protected beneath the rubble. Ell’Hakan turned into flames and appeared atop it, and Miyamoto made no attempt to stop him as he teleported away, the circle exploding in his wake.

A minute or so passed as a figure of blood condensed beside the Sword Saint. Iskar, the former Monarch of Blood, looked at Miyamoto. "He left? I should have figured after that servant woman decided to end herself."

Miyamoto nodded. He took out a token and crushed it as he waited for Ms. Wells to contact him. He reckoned that by the time she did so, Ell’Hakan would already be far gone from Earth.

Perhaps for the better. Because Ell’Hakan was not the only one who had made major miscalculations.

Jake was about to leave towards where he had seen the nahoom when he remembered something even more important.

"Wait, where is the loot?" Jake asked the King.

The King just looked at Jake. "It is mine. I can make far better use of it, and this entire scenario only took place because of you. Killing the Ashen Phantom Devourer means a victory for you against an enemy Chosen, while it does little for me. Therefore, is it not only reasonable that I, at the very least, get the tangible bounty?"

"You could have just said you ninja-looted it," Jake said with quite a bit of snark. “No reason to try and justify yourself. This is why I don’t do group hunting, by the way." He then unfolded his wings and took to the sky towards where he had seen the little observer.

He was still waiting for word from the Sword Saint on how his confrontation with Ell’Hakan had gone. Jake was not afraid of the old man dying in the slightest, but there was the risk of him overextending himself using his Transcendence. Ell’Hakan dying was not even a potential outcome in his mind.

Flying over, Jake detected a presence there. One far more powerful than what he would expect of some nahoom scout or observer. One that also felt oddly familiar, though he could not place where he had felt it before.

As Jake got closer, he saw a surprising sight. A nahoom was lying on the ground, clearly unconscious, while someone in a suit of armor stood by him. On second inspection, the suit of armor was more like that of a golem or something, with no openings anywhere.

That was when Jake recognized him. More accurately, he recognized the armor. He recognized the feelings of smashing that armor into the ground, bending and tearing it apart as the person inside of it was made into a mushy soup of flesh, blood, and bones. Jake Identified him as he flew closer and landed a dozen or so meters away.

[Human – lvl 199]

He had to dig into his memory a little to recall the name. Thinking about it, this was only their third-ever time meeting, and Jake reckoned it would go the same way as every other encounter. Maybe… because he didn’t feel anything from the other party. Not a single shred of hostility or bloodlust. Due to the armor, Jake could not actually see the person himself, so it was hard to really say anything quite yet.

Hence, Jake opened with the most relevant question. "What the hell are you doing here?"

And a relevant question it was. Because what the hell was he doing there? Why had he knocked out the nahoom? Why had he clearly just been standing back and not trying to interfere with the fight? Based on his track record, trying to strike Jake mid-fight would totally be something he would do, so why hadn’t he?

The young man didn’t answer, making Jake consider if he’d maybe read it wrong—perhaps he’d just left the armor there—but his senses told him that there was a human inside of it. Jake then considered if he should just rip it open and see for himself, but the young man finally spoke.

"Confront…" he said in a meek voice that Jake could barely hear, even with his Perception. He did pick up that one word, though.

"To confront me?" Jake asked. "Well, what are you waiting for, then? I am right here. Shit, shouldn’t I be the one confronting you? Did you just come here to get your skull bashed in again, or what? Make some goddamn sense."

He really did consider just attacking, but he held himself back. The situation was just too weird. William was strong. A level 199 human—a talented mage, based on all Jake had heard—and he had briefly faced Caleb and come out on top. Yet, even so, he had done nothing ever since returning to Earth… besides that one time when he’d decided messing with Jake’s family was a good idea. He had missed every single World Congress despite clearly having a Pylon. He hadn’t even taken part in the Treasure Hunt or the Myriad Paths event, which once more made no fucking sense.

Finally, the biggest reason was the psychologist lady that Jake had spoken with at the end of the First World Congress. He still remembered their conversation vividly due to how weird it had been. She had been almost apologetic about what William had done. Back then, she hadn’t outright said he was a changed psycho, but it had been heavily insinuated he was, at the very least, not as bad as before.

Oh, and the fact that she’d explicitly stated that William’s experience in the tutorial had given him PTSD—something Jake honestly had a hard time seeing. To suffer from something like that was far less common due to the system, and it wasn’t like it was just something that naturally happened due to death. Jacob had died once, Bertram had died dozens of times, as far as Jake had heard, and even the King had been killed by Jake once.

Moreover, it was the kind of thing that would usually disappear with time. Sure, there could still be remnants, but this felt way too extreme.

Yet as he saw the mute armor in front of him, it was hard to deny. Also, if he did suffer from PTSD and was afraid of Jake, seeing the fight he’d just had with the Ashen Phantom Devourer probably hadn’t helped the matter.

"I…" William stammered, making Jake shake his head.

"Take off that damn armor already. It didn’t help you last time, and trust me when I say it won’t this time either."

To his surprise, the young man obliged. The armor seemed to turn liquid and reveal a young human, looking very much the same as the first time Jake saw him in the tutorial. Visually, that is. The aura he gave off was far removed from the one he’d had back then. Far more muted and meek.

Jake did not talk, instead just standing there and staring at the kid. William didn’t even look up at him. While Jake had deactivated Arcane Awakening and was currently suffering from a period of weakness, he also knew he could activate it right away if need be.

Not that he thought he needed to. William was currently about as scary as a wet noodle.

"…orry…" Jake once more heard a meek voice say.

"Do you want me to go closer, or do you want to speak up?" Jake asked.

"Sorry," the young man repeated, still staring at the ground.

"Sorry is such an easy word, isn’t it?" Jake scoffed. "What are you sorry for? Come on, say it out loud."

Did Jake know he was being a dick? Yes, yes, he did. Did Jake care that he was being a dick towards William? No, no, he did not.

William had only ever been an annoyance at best to Jake. At worst, he had been the person Jake had perhaps hated the most. Yet, as Jake stood before him like this, he just felt weird about it. If someone had asked him earlier that day what he would do if he met William, Jake would have first asked who William was again and then proceeded to clarify that he would replay their last meeting by curb-stomping him.

"The tutorial…" William began. "Your parents… brother… Reika… Sultan… the Church… Ell’Hakan… City Alliance… everything."

Jake was about to say something after the first three, but he stopped himself. Reika, Sultan, Church? Had he even helped Ell’Hakan somehow? Did he work for the United Cities Alliance now? Rather than just get an apology, Jake felt like he got a bunch of questions.

Realizing things were a bit more complicated, Jake wanted to get to the bottom of it. But before all that, one more question still needed to be answered.

"You never properly answered: Why are you here?” Jake asked. “What are you hoping to accomplish?"

William hesitated but finally answered, "I… am stuck."

"I am going to assume you don’t mean literally stuck, as you seem to be able to move perfectly well, so how are you stuck?" Jake asked sarcastically.

"Evolution quest," William muttered. "Can’t find my Path."

Jake listened and quickly got it. Considering how much he had talked to the Viper and how much he had heard from lessons and others, he did get the general gist of people being stuck and unable to advance. Having a mental block was a very common obstacle to progress. That William had Jake as a mental block he needed to overcome was surprising, but it probably shouldn’t have been.

"And you hoped that confronting me like this would help with that," Jake explained for the kid. "Which begs the question, what do you want from me? To see if you could beat me? See if I would kill you? Well, congratulations—you are wrong on all fronts."

William finally seemed to stir a little as Jake kept going. "Quite frankly, I don’t care about you. The only time your existence has even crossed my mind was when you annoyed me. Today I had to remind myself who you even were. You mean nothing to me and are nothing more than a bad memory at this point. So if you want a clean break or whatever, it is entirely one-sided, as I broke away from you long ago. But now that you have shown up in front of me, you got me curious. Tell me what you have been up to all this time and why the hell you thought it was a good idea to keep fucking with the guy who already killed you once."

Did Jake know by now that William was scared shitless of him? Well, yeah, of course.

Did he actually care and have a desire to help William overcome this fear?

Fuck no.

He just wanted to know how big of a mess the moron had made.

Chapter 54

0/10 Master, Would Not Recommend

What the actual fuck? Jake thought as William finally started stringing together sentences more than a few words long. He began to explain what he had done since returning from the tutorial, and it all just felt so odd to hear.

Right after returning, he had met up with the psychiatrist—not a psychologist, though Jake still kinda didn’t know the difference—as well as her child. They had then set off, and William had leveled, gotten a Pylon, and done all that one would expect someone to do in the early days of the system.

Besides going to the First World Congress, that is. Both because William hadn’t wanted to go, and his master had discouraged it.

From that first mention of his master, Jake began to notice the pattern.

William had then kept doing what he did, and… well, he had done a lot more than Jake knew. He had met with Reika and talked to her while she made her way to Haven. He had met Sultan at some point, too, and even met Jacob several times. As for what he had done with them? Well… asked them questions and talked to them or something like that?

Jake asked why he did what he did, and his answer was consistent: It was what his master had recommended. Not even William knew the purpose of much of what he did; he was effectively just reading a script. As time went on, it also sounded like he started to question Eversmile less and less.

The Treasure Hunt? His master had also told him going to that was a bad idea and that it would be better to head for where Jake and Caleb’s parents lived to learn more about Jake.

Second World Congress? William had considered going, but his master had once more said it would be a waste of time.

William had also aided Ell’Hakan by proxy via helping to awaken memories in beasts. Why he had done this, the young man admitted he didn’t know. He said as much quite clearly, yet one thing lacked. There was no real questioning anymore, just an admittance he didn’t know.

He also mentioned the nightmares. Since the time William had nearly died while killing Richard, he had suffered from nightmares whenever he slept and even sometimes while he meditated. After Jake had killed him for real, the nightmares had only gotten worse, and Jake was apparently the primary topic of these nightmares.

So that explained why the PTSD just kept trucking along and seemed to not get better, even with a professional like Ms. Kim around. Oh, yeah—William talked about Ms. Kim a lot. Enough for Jake to feel weird about it.

The final thing that really put the nail in the coffin was the Myriad Paths event. His master had said that he already knew his Path and didn’t need it. This last one especially made Jake catch on, taking note of the one commonality in all of William’s horrible decisions after the tutorial.

"Holy shit," Jake said after William was done talking. By now, he had taken a seat on a stone, with William having barely moved besides shifting his feet here and there.

One thing was clear from all of this. Clear to Jake, that is, but not William.

Eversmile, William’s master, did not actually give a shit about William or his progress in the slightest. No, that wasn’t even right. It was more than that. Eversmile had been actively handicapping William for some inexplicable reason, and Jake had no idea why.

"Did you never stop to think for yourself for a single second?" Jake asked William. While William was a naïve moron, the young man had not given Jake the impression he was a complete idiot. Was the fact that he was being fucked over not evident enough?

William seemed confused by the question. At this point, Jake’s annoyance at encountering the young man had nearly been entirely replaced with curiosity to figure out what the hell was going on. Almost. He also wasn’t quite at the stage where pity became a thing.

"Eversmile—or Master, as you call him—is clearly the reason why you can’t advance in your Path," Jake easily concluded. "Seriously, what the fuck is wrong with you? He has been cutting off your legs beneath you at every turn to handicap you. Jeez, how blind are you?"

"I… Master is the only reason I even made it as far as I did, and…" William tried to argue, actually showing a bit of spirit.

"Bull-fucking-shit," Jake said, scoffing. "Who the hell can’t evolve to C-grade with the kind of start you got, being blessed by a Primordial and all that? Shit, even without the events, you should have been able to. Think for just a single second here. If your dear master guided you so thoroughly, then why are you still stuck? Why is the Path he has shown you not one that works? I would begin to question my GPS if it made me drive into a wall."

William did not answer but just looked confused. He also looked up for the first time, made eye contact with Jake, and promptly proceeded to look back down. In that brief second of exchanging glances, what Jake saw in William’s eyes surprised him a bit. There was only fear and what Jake could almost describe as hopelessness.

It reminded him a bit of Phillip, the man who used to lead the Fort. He, too, had given up and more or less retired, with no desire to really do anything, and approached everything halfheartedly. Yet he had bounced back. Even now, he was holding down the fort in Haven while keeping all those from the United Cities Alliance in a political chokehold.

Jake just sighed. "Alright, let’s go over things a bit. First of all, why did you go to Nevermore? What did you gain from it? You did not use the power and temporary advantage for anything, as far as I can tell."

"Master said I would need it…" William muttered.

Jake just sighed again. "You know, I asked the Viper if I should maybe head to Nevermore. Wanna hear what he said? That the only reasons one would go to Nevermore in D-grade were if one didn’t think they would make it to C-grade, had no true confidence in their ability to compete as a C-grade, or because they were fanatics part of the Primordial Church that went there for scholarly reasons or whatever. I, of course, asked why, and he explained that Nevermore has a few rules and restrictions. Due to this, then while one can enter at D-grade, it is smarter to wait for C-grade. Also, one can enter some competition or leaderboard or something like that if entering still in early C-grade, but if one went in D-grade, that isn’t possible.”

"That…" William hesitated. "Master never mentioned that. I—"

"If you don’t trust me, then maybe ask yourself why Ell’Hakan hasn’t gone either. Why no one from Earth has gone besides you. The answer is simple: Because it is a bloody dumb idea. You are aware I have been outside of the universe. I spent months at a time away. Why would I not have gone to Nevermore? I am waiting for C-grade—that is why."

William kept quiet as Jake kept going.

"Also, you talk about nightmares. Pretty funny, now that I think about it. I have only had one real nightmare since the system arrived, and you know why that was? Because Eversmile was the one who caused it to mess with me. And now you say you are suffering from nightmares? What a coincidence, eh?" Jake shook his head. "Skipping all of the system events was also moronic. You kept saying your master said they were not needed or a bad idea, which just leads me back to the same question from before: Did you ever stop to fucking think? Why did my Patron recommend going? Why did Valhal, the Court of Shadows, Holy Church, or every single faction with just a fraction of knowledge of the multiverse put such importance on these events? Because they do matter. It isn’t about having found your Path or not; it is about the sheer amount and level of Records offered from these events. They are our advantage as a new universe."

"It… makes no sense," William actually argued. "Why would Master spend so many resources to revive me? Why bless me? Why spend so much time just to harm me? What could he possibly gain from me not taking part in events?"

"Fuck if I know," Jake admitted. "Eversmile is insane. He is a scientist who just does shit to see what happens. But I do know why he wanted you out of events."

It was actually quite simple. Others had already made use of this "feature" of the system events, such as Jacob when he’d warned Casper about the planned attack of the Holy Church on the Risen.

"The system restricts all outside connections during these events, including divine ones,” Jake explained. “While in the World Congress or Treasure Hunt or whatever, you can’t talk to them, and more importantly, you can’t be influenced by them. So that is clearly why he didn’t want you there. Geez, how much did he fuck with your mind, I wonder? Any idea?"

The last part was not spoken to William. The two of them had been there for some time, and that seemed to have attracted the attention of a certain Unique Lifeform. The King had appeared from below the ledge close by and landed on the ground.

"The metal mage," the King simply said. "I remember him. He killed one of the Beast Lords during the tutorial, did he not? Ah, yes. I observed him too for a while, until he met his end at your hands. How does he even live? All I remember was seeing him die, and then I was unable to observe the area for a period."

The King had spoken to both William and Jake despite clearly not caring much about the young metal mage. Jake did not want to explain either but just gave the cliff notes. "Killed by me, resurrected by a Primordial who loves karmic magic, and now it looks like the disciple of the karmic fucker has become the one being fucked with."

"Explains some things," the King merely said.

"Like what?" Jake asked curiously.

"His pathetic state," the King pointed out, his interest in the conversation waning by the second.

Jake considered what the King said and nodded. "True. He does seem like an entirely different person, and not only in a positive way. He is like a damn husk of nothingness."

William did not argue any of this as he just looked to be deep in thought. Jake decided to change the topic a bit by pointing to the knocked-out nahoom on the ground.

"What’s up with him?" Jake asked. "I can see you knocked him out, but why did you do that? I thought you worked with Ell’Hakan."

"I did," William said. "Maybe. I helped guide the Ashen Phantom Devourer towards this mountain range, and I helped bring together some powerful beasts and stuff."

The King finally seemed interested again. "You work with those annoyances? Explains why they came together if a third party was facilitating it."

"Back to the nahoom," Jake said. "Why knock him out?"

"I didn’t want him to know about this," William answered, confused.

"What I was asking was not necessarily why you stopped him from observing, but why you knocked him out.” More curtly, Jake added, “Not to unnecessarily bring up the past, but your go-to tends to be just killing people without any particular reason, doesn’t it?"

"I… try not to kill…" William said. "Ms. Kim said that taking a life needs to be a deeply considered action, not just something you do."

"Now I feel like you are calling me out." Jake shook his head, not sure he should even believe it. "So, the psycho turned all saintly, huh? Then tell me… what are you going to do now? You know, considering you have been fucked over by your so-called master so badly, I could just do you a favor and end you here and now? That is one way to pay for all your sins if you feel bad about everything you’ve done."

William actually looked like he seriously considered it for a moment, but he finally just shook his head. "I promised Ms. Kim…" William said in a meek tone.

"So, what are you doing, then? From the looks of it, you haven’t renounced your Blessing yet. Pretty sure I would feel that, so what is the hold-up?"

"I… Master isn’t answering… but… this doesn’t make any fucking sense!" William finally exploded and looked up. "No fucking sense! Master has helped me so much, spent ages teaching me karmic magic, guided me, given me tips and advice, and you say that was all to fuck with me!?"

"Sounds like it." Jake shrugged.

"Why!? Give me one good reason! Why use the Leaf of Yggrasil, why give me a powerful weapon, why help me find the people I wanted to find after returning to Earth, and why help me awaken my Bloodline!? Why would he do all of this for some sick joke!?"

Jake was about to answer when he bit onto something towards the end of his outburst. "Bloodline?" Jake asked, confused.

"Yes! My Bloodline! You have one, right? So do I! So why are we so different!? Why—"

"The mere fact you ask if I have a Bloodline is evidence enough," Jake said.

"Evidence of what!?"

"You don’t have a fucking Bloodline, you dunce. Was that another damn lie he told you? I guess he didn’t tell you that everyone with a Bloodline can feel others with one. I have met those with Bloodlines, and you sure don’t have one. Oh, Eversmile probably told you some bullshit about this being a lie or something, right? Damn. Hit that right on the nail, huh?" Jake tossed in the last part when he saw William about to protest.

"I have a Bloodline… The system says so," William still argued.

"Do you have a Bloodline Patriarch title?" Jake asked.

"No?" William said after a pause.

"Well, the other guy from Earth with a Bloodline does. I do. Shit, this is getting more personal than I like, but what is your Bloodline about? Just some basic stuff.”

William clamped up at that, but the King came in and said, "At the very least, share the rarity. If you do so, then the Hunter shall share too, will he not?"

Jake was confused about what the hell the King was getting at, considering Bloodline did not really have rarities, but he quickly understood what the King was hinting at. "Yeah, sure, that seems fair enough."

The young man hesitated for a moment. "Mine is ancient rarity…"

"A lie it is. Bloodlines do not truly have rarities," the King answered before Jake could. "They are classified as Bloodline Abilities and not skills, to begin with, even having their own spot in the status screen. Thus, they are not part of your race, class, or profession. The only rarity a Bloodline can have is Unique, and that only appears if you are the only being in existence with your specific Bloodline.”

Jake threw the King a look of surprise at how much he knew about Bloodlines. What he said was entirely correct and aligned with what Jake had learned and experienced.

William now looked even more lost than before as he just stared at the two of them. Several seconds passed before Jake spoke again.

"I really hope we've established by now that Eversmile is a right bastard, and honestly a piece of shit of a Primordial. Oh, and apparently also a horrible teacher."

The young metal mage did not respond, as he had gone back to staring at the ground.

"The young metal caster I saw during the tutorial was a human with drive and goals,” the King said. “One who sought power selfishly and slaughtered anything in his way. I am not saying that version was better, but at least he moved according to his own will and not the will of another. You may think you have changed, but fundamentally I do not believe you humans can truly change that much.”

"Oh, yeah, definitely," Jake agreed. "You were a grade-A asshole, but at least you were a grade-A asshole of your own twisted volition. I totally understand why the system would say you need to find your Path, because you seem to have completely lost all will to actually progress. Why are you even getting stronger? What for? Just to make the master that you now learned is a lying piece of shit happy?"

"I… don’t know," William muttered.

"Well, sounds like something you need to figure the fuck out. You don’t even need a good reason to want to get stronger; it just needs to be your reason. Your Path."

Jake’s words seemed to sink in, as William looked deep in thought. Jake felt proud he was getting through, but he suddenly felt a mental nudge.

The King looked at Jake and sent him a private telepathic idea. "May I know why you decided to help a former enemy overcome this obstacle?"

Jake looked at the King, puzzled. He was about to answer when he stopped himself. "I… kinda just got caught up in the moment?"

Chapter 55

End of Conflict: The Start of Another

The King had indeed asked a very pertinent question. Why the hell was Jake even wasting a second of his time on William? The little psycho was not an ally, friend, or even acquaintance. Shit, he was worse than a stranger, in that he was a former enemy.

However, Jake’s curiosity had won out. Eversmile was someone who had fucked with Jake before, and Jake had assumed that William was his favored little disciple, but now it turned out that he, too, was just another guinea pig to be fucked with and discarded.

Or was he? That was the big question. Was all of this a part of Eversmile’s plan? Maybe the plan was for Jake to kill William and somehow form a karmic connection between himself and Eversmile? Maybe it was for William to try and kill Jake or something?

Maybe Jake had no fucking idea and should probably stop guessing what a Primordial that had lived for trillions of years was thinking? Even Villy said he didn’t truly understand Eversmile and found him perhaps the most unpredictable of all the Primordials.

Now, what would Jake then do? He still had the option of just killing William, but that just seemed too damn meaningless. He did not give Jake the impression he would even fight, meaning he would likely just run away if Jake tried anything. Could Jake catch him? Maybe, but what would he get out of that? Jake didn’t even think it would give a single level.

What the future threat level of William represented was also something to assess. Jake could, for obvious reasons, not accurately predict this, but his gut told him it was low to nonexistent. William was still scared of Jake, and Jake was totally okay with that. He had also not really done anything to harm Jake or those around him since returning to Earth, and the ambiguous things he had done, like messing with Jake’s parents, had not resulted in any harm and been done under the pretense of Eversmile ordering it.

Jake waited around with the King as William seemed to consider what Jake had said about finding his own Path. It took a bit, but Jake didn’t feel like he was in a rush, considering he was still recuperating from using Arcane Awakening. Was meditating a better use of his time? Probably, but it was also infinitely less entertaining.

"I…" William finally began. "I just fuck everything up…"

"Not going to argue with that one," Jake agreed snarkily. “You do have a tendency to fuck things up.”

"Every time I decide what to do, it just ends up fucked," William began muttering. "The tutorial was… horrible."

"To be fair," Jake said, “if not for me, you would have probably succeeded. I heard a bit from the Viper about what would have happened without me, and things would have turned out infinitely better for you. Not better in the sense that you would have killed the final boss like I did, but way better than getting bitch-slapped into ground paste within your tin-can armor.

"Oh, though, I can’t say what would have happened after. No one could besides maybe Eversmile, and who knows if he even has a clue? I don’t wanna try to figure out what he is trying to do. Trying to understand crazy sounds like an excellent way to waste your time." Jake shrugged.

"Everything in the tutorial was me…" William said, having registered but clearly not digested Jake’s words. "I killed people for barely anything…"

"Why does this human take such issue with ending the lives of his own species?" the King asked Jake, though he spoke out loud so both could hear it. "Is it not natural to want to establish dominance over your own kin? To kill them is the ultimate sign of supremacy."

"Eh, humans aren’t as ultra-individualistic as you Unique Lifeforms,” Jake explained. “We are flock animals, and probably due to evolutionary reasons, we are inherently resistant to killing or seeing those of our own species killed. Establishing dominance over others was usually done in ways that did not cause excessive harm. Didn’t want your gatherer to have broken hands or be unable to work and all that. Not that humans don’t also love killing each other, but we usually do it for greater reasons than simply to prove we are better than someone else. Greater reasons that often end up just being bullshit, but if the flock decides it is acceptable, it becomes acceptable. Those who did kill people for what others would view as trivial reasons were very much ostracized, as they posed a danger to the stability of the flock.”

Probably not entirely scientifically accurate, but that was at least how Jake had understood things from his social studies and biology classes.

"From my understanding, William here was what we called a psychopath,” Jake continued. “An inherently broken human without the ability to feel empathy, and thus unable to properly integrate and operate within the flock. He could wear a mask and act like a flock member, but it was all an act. When the tutorial hit, he could finally unleash crazy, and as he didn’t feel anything when killing other humans, he could do so easily. In retrospect, being at least a bit of a psycho is probably an advantage in this new world.”

Again, Jake was not a psychologist or psychiatrist. The fact that he didn’t really know the difference between the two was a dead giveaway of that. The last part was mostly what he’d understood from his talk with that Ms. Kim lady during the World Congress.

"He then evolved, and with evolution got this little imbalance fixed, making him able to feel empathy and emotions and all that again," Jake finished explaining to the King.

The King just scoffed. "The more I learn of you humans, the more I realize how flawed of a species you are.”

"Flawed enough to have kicked your ass," Jake said, smirking.

"You speak as if you are not also a fundamentally broken human, based on your own description. You, too, slaughter your own kin without mercy and dominate them without hesitation. Does that not make you as flawed as he was?"

"Did I ever argue I wasn’t a bit out of the ordinary?" Jake answered, not really caring about the King’s judgmental jab in that area. Was Jake a perfectly stable and healthy person mentally? Fuck no, but he also didn’t see why he should be. If he wanted to reach abnormal levels of power, being a bit abnormal was only to be expected.

Also, there was this minor little detail of his Bloodline being a thing. If Jake becoming more stable and considered "mentally sound" would result in him hampering his true nature, then what the hell was the point of that? He remembered suppressing himself, and it had sucked.

Returning to the topic at hand, Jake regarded William.

"Sure, you used to fuck everything up, so just stop doing that," Jake easily advised. "If you don’t know how to not fuck shit up, then don’t you have some less crazy people around you by now, like that Ms. Kim lady? Use her; she seems interested in helping you, so let her. But cut off that asshole Eversmile like the tumor he is."

"What if… Master must have a reason to—"

"Sure he fucking does, but his reason is entirely selfish and clearly not for your good," Jake said, getting a bit tired of how dense William was. Then again, he had undergone years of indoctrination, so maybe it was only natural.

"I can’t just…" William muttered again.

"Yes, you can. Develop some goddamn agency. Look, how about this? Join the next World Congress, no matter what anyone says or does. See if that changes anything. Or, you can just stop chickening out and get rid of it now. Find your own Path. If your master truly cares, he will reach out when you evolve to C-grade. Shit, shouldn’t he be happy if you figure out how to evolve, even if that evolution comes from cutting him off? Sounds like a win-win."

Alright, that logic was a tad flawed, but Jake didn’t bother trying to come up with something better. Why would he? His stakes in William "getting better" were low as hell. He still wasn’t even sure why he was helping the kid. I blame that damn psychologist… or was she a psychiatrist?

William actually seemed to be considering his words. After thinking a bit, he frowned as if he had detected something. He looked to the side and sighed.

"Ell’Hakan just left the planet," William said.

"How do you even know tha—"

*You have successfully defeated and pushed a higher-leveled enemy Chosen off your planet – A new feat has been accomplished. Bonus experience earned*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 193 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 197 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 194 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

…

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 196 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Jake didn’t continue what he was about to say as he stared at the notifications. What the hell?

Five damn levels had just randomly landed on his lap, and Jake was confused about what had just happened. Okay, the system explained what had happened, but five levels? Really? Jake hadn’t even fought the guy himself.

Shaking his head, Jake knew he would have a conversation with Villy after he was done dealing with a certain former psychopath.

"It appears he has," Jake recognized. "But how do you know?"

"Karma," William just said. "All the subordinates he brought with him are also gone, besides the one lying right here and two that managed to hide shortly after coming to Earth. They may also be gone. I don’t know."

"How sure are you?" Jake asked with a frown.

"Ell’Hakan does not have the ability to obscure himself from karma like you do…" William muttered.

That was when Jake realized something. Had Eversmile fucked William in incredibly many ways? Yes… but he had taught him karmic magic in a genuine fashion. Sensing someone powerful—especially someone with a Bloodline like Ell’Hakan’s—was not easy, but from the sounds of it, William could do so rather effortlessly. Jake also didn’t feel like it was just something William had been deceived into thinking, considering the system had just confirmed the Chosen was indeed gone. Jake knew Karma was in no way simple, either... It was some weird shit.

What is your goal, Eversmile? Jake asked himself once more.

"Well, that is one issue fixed, but it also means I have to get going. The World Congress is in…" Jake trailed off towards the end, as he wasn’t actually sure.

"Twenty-eight days, four hours, and eighteen minutes, soon to be seventeen," the King spoke.

Jake just looked at the King and shook his head. What a nerd.

"Yeah, in a bit under a month,” Jake said. “Go there and see how it feels to not have a god living rent-free in your head. Or better yet, evict that god here and now and renounce your Blessing. I am not going to tell you what to do, but I will give you one warning. I don’t care if Eversmile or the entire fucking collective of Primordials ask you to do it: If you mess with my family or friends again, we will have a repeat of the tutorial. We clear?"

William just nodded meekly, building up the confidence to ask, "What about the nahoom?"

Jake looked at the unconscious alien. "Not like torture has ever worked for shit, and I am not a fan of it anyway. Do with him what you may."

When he turned to leave, William spoke again, as much to himself as Jake. "Is this really it?"

Jake turned his head. "What did you expect? I am not your friend, but I don’t bother seeing you as an enemy, either. Figure your shit out, and if you want to come after me for revenge after that, then you are more than welcome. Just don’t be like that alien fuck and come at me straight."

William did not say anything. He looked up to the sky as Jake summoned his wings again. The King made his intent to follow Jake known as the two of them headed off, leaving William alone with the knocked-out nahoom.

As he flew away, he faintly felt the aura of William change behind him. Jake smiled as he got his second weird notification of the day.

*You have successfully turned a disciple of a Primordial away from their Master, leading them towards the Path of a heretic – A new feat has been accomplished. Bonus experience earned*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 198 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

One more thing also became clear. Jake had really underestimated the weird ways he could level his profession. It turned out that doing stuff one would expect of a Heretic-Chosen actually counted. Who would have thought?

Anyway, Jake had the King follow him as they began flying upwards. Jake had wondered if the King didn’t need to stay, but he said there was no reason to. Soon, word that the Ashen Phantom Devourer was dead would spread, and as long as it was known he lived, nothing else mattered. The beasts that held doubt would be turned towards the King.

The King had also said that sticking around Jake was probably safer during his period of weakness. Which was a good point, as Jake had a feeling that defeating the King here and now would be incredibly easy. His aura was still scary, but it was clearly a front. One that would fool most, but Jake saw right through it.

As for why they were flying upwards? Well, it hadn’t been that long, but Jake needed to get back to Haven, and considering the lack of teleporters available, he went for something nearly equally as good. On second thought, something many would consider superior.

A giant space worm.

Within a house floating through the endless space of an empty part of an unknown universe, a single figure sat and stared out into the nothingness.

Eversmile’s smile grew as he felt the Blessing be denounced, and then the karmic link change. Several more threads in the tapestry also underwent subtle changes as a cascade effect began. Some of these changes were not as he had predicted, but that was the beauty of an experiment like that. The unpredictability of it all.

The Malefic’s Chosen and his dear, now former disciple were sure to bring him many surprises in the future. Seeing as everything was going as it should, he contacted his mortal associate to let them know that they were moving on to the next phase of the experiment.

Back in Haven, the entire situation had turned quite lively. The nahoom stationed there had promptly left, and those from the United Cities Alliance were perplexed. They knew a battle had occurred, but not why it had happened or who was fighting.

So when Miyamoto walked into Haven, they were more than a little taken aback. When only an hour later, a group of people teleported into the plains outside of Haven, things changed even more. This group naturally consisted of Miranda, Neil, Hank, Lillian, and all the others who had gone to the Grand Mangrove River.

That day, it became clear to everyone.

Ell’Hakan had lost, and with that, the United Cities Alliance was about to have a very bad time, as the winds of change were blowing directly against them.

Chapter 56

Towards Haven We Go

Jake and the King didn’t really encounter anything of note as they both flew skyward at a relaxed speed. Both were in weakened states, and while Jake was quickly recovering, the King was not. Hence, the relaxed approach.

On the way up, Jake infused some energy into the rock that was totally not an egg that he had received from Sandy. It had only been a few hours since they parted, and Jake would be lying if he said it wasn’t a bit weird that he was already back again, but it wasn’t his fault that he sucked at predicting his own future plans.

Okay, it probably was his fault, but in Jake’s defense, he had been somewhat mentally occupied with taking down the Ashen Phantom Devourer.

"You mentioned that you made it here with the help of a C-grade entity," the King said as they flew up. “Will this entity be willing to assist both of us?"

About now, it should probably be made clear that Jake had not shared much of how he had traveled across the world, much less talked about Sandy. He’d just said he had made an ally that could help him traverse the world far faster than by himself, and that was why he’d had time to strategize and such even while moving forward.

No actual details about Sandy had been shared for several reasons, the primary one being that Jake just didn’t like sharing information about others without permission. Telling everyone about Sandy and their abilities just didn’t sit right with him, so he kept things simple.

Moreover, Sandy was not the type of worm that one should be told about. Sandy was the kind of worm one just had to experience.

"I am sure it will be fine," Jake said to the King as they soon reached the layer of clouds Sandy could operate in.

Jake and the King stopped, and Jake kept watch to make sure no C-grade decided they looked like prey. Neither was in good condition to have a serious fight, so they preferred to just wait for Sandy to make it there.

Ten or so minutes passed before Jake felt an aura approach. Jake looked up and saw Sandy descend from the layer of clouds above the one they were in. Jake smiled, but his smile quickly froze as he felt more auras. Several more auras.

All of them were far more powerful than Sandy’s, making them at or near mid-tier C-grade.

"EAT BOTH AND GO!?" Sandy yelled into his head from afar.

"Yes!" Jake confirmed.

"Don’t resist the pull," Jake warned the King, and just in time, too.

With great speed, Sandy barreled down and opened their mouth, gobbling up Jake and the King. Sandy then quickly began flying close to the layer of clouds leading to the lower-leveled region below.

Inside the stomach, the King stopped to admire what had happened while Jake stared outside. There, far up in the air, several figures now emerged. There were more than a dozen of them, and as they got closer, Jake got a proper look.

It was a group of griffins. Dense wind magic revolved around them as they tried to chase down Sandy, who was flying away at an equally fast pace.

"Sandy…" Jake said. "Why are they chasing you?"

He kind of already knew, but he just had to ask anyway.

"Greed is indeed a sad thing," Sandy said with a holier-than-thou tone. “I have personally always believed that sharing is caring. That is the true way of the worms.”

"You stole something from them?"

"Permanently borrowed sounds nicer," Sandy said with a bit of cheek before promptly changing the subject. "I barely managed to get in a snack before you came back. What happened, and who is that scary-as-hell thing you also made me eat?"

"I am aware you are speaking about me," the King interrupted, being all scary by picking up on them speaking telepathically. "Incredibly interesting, this place. We appear to be within the Soulshape, and yet at the same time not. Some undefined space, perhaps?"

"Yeah, I was just about to tell Sandy who you are," Jake said. "Oh, by the way, this is Sandy. Sandy is a friend of mine and also happens to be the Chosen of Snappy. Or, well, the Boundless Hydra, Lord Protector of the Order of the Malefic Viper is probably his official title."

"I see," the King said, not putting much stock in such titles.

Jake proceeded to explain to Sandy what the two of them had been up to and where they were headed. Sandy was only semi-distracted as the griffins managed to pour their magic into their strongest member, making the beast shoot forward with incredible speed and catch up to Sandy.

This resulted in claws scratching Sandy’s rock-like skin and a lot of wind magic trying to rip the worm to threads. This kept on for a while, and as Sandy began to take damage, they decided it all got a bit too much and activated some skill akin to Jake’s One Step, thus teleporting them forward tens of kilometers five times in a row.

I am more surprised Sandy couldn’t make a wormhole, Jake joked to himself… fully aware that Sandy potentially could make a wormhole, and even if they couldn’t now, then they would no doubt be able to in the future.

During their talk, Sandy managed to gain enough distance for the griffins to give up, resulting in them once more getting away with a successful robbery. After Jake explained everything, they had some small talk as Jake moved on to the next topic at hand.

Jake had already made Miranda aware the Ashen Phantom Devourer was gone, but he still needed to talk to her and the Sword Saint. He wanted to know what had gone down in Haven and let them know he was coming posthaste.

While the King and Sandy seemed to strike up a conversation, Jake took out a token and infused some energy. He waited for a few minutes, but nothing happened. Jake frowned, wondering what was up. He was not nervous, as he guessed that she was probably busy. She’d also planned on heading straight for Haven once Ell’Hakan was gone.

Instead, he turned his attention towards a certain god he knew had to be waiting for his telepathic phone call.

And he clearly was, based on how fast he responded.

"My Chosen comes out victorious in this first chapter of the story, huh?" Villy said. "Though I am more interested in your little interaction with that metal caster."

"I figured," Jake said, also primarily wanting to talk about that. "So, off the cuff, thoughts on what went down? Should I just have killed him?"

"Maybe, maybe not," Villy said. "What I can say is that no matter what you did, there was no winning if you view your true opponent as Eversmile. Because he is not about winning or losing to begin with. No matter the outcome, it is still a result and thus a data point for him. So, I guess in a sense, you could say he succeeds no matter what, as even no result would still be a result worth noting for him."

"I get that part. Kind of. Eversmile is a maniac, but I don’t think he is stupid… Why waste so much on William? There must have been easier ways to get someone like him than all the mess he went through.”

"The metal caster is unique. His state before the system, where his brain itself deviated from the norm, is not something you will ever see with the system present. It simply can’t be there, so him being in that state before already makes him interesting. You also misunderstand something… Eversmile’s investment is not only due to the caster, but who the caster was killed by. The person who just made his former follower into a heretic. You are as much a subject of his experiment as the caster is. And, if I am perfectly honest, so am I due to our out-of-the-ordinary relationship as Patron and Chosen.”

Jake nodded along, once more reaffirming to himself that trying to understand what Eversmile was truly up to was a waste of time.

"Any comments on what else has been going on?" Jake asked.

"Not much; things seemed to go as you wanted. But one piece of advice: Keep your useful relationships intact. I initially wasn’t sure if it was even something for you, but Nevermore has a dungeon path that is suited for parties, and seeing as you and quite a few of those around you will reach C-grade around the same time, it seems like an obvious thing to participate in. Besides that, I don’t really have much to add. Outside of you potentially understanding why Yip’s Chosen went after you, and why that is not necessarily a bad thing."

"Definitely did get more out of making him leave than expected," Jake agreed. "Do you think he will keep making problems?"

"Oh, Jake… this was just the first arc of your story. I am sure there is far more to come, and the fact that Yip has not made any moves himself either is proof of this.” Somewhat teasingly, Villy added, “Better be prepared to keep dealing with him and others who may want to make trouble for you in the future.”

Jake sighed. "I guess my intentions towards Earth is a good call, then?"

"Depends on what you want out of your home planet, but I would overall say that is the best course of action. One that will also hopefully come with other rewards down the line while also assisting those around you. Anyway, I have some stuff to deal with myself to prepare for what is to come. Keep up the good work. Ah, one final note. It should be possible for you to easily create another teleporter out of your universe if you make use of those snakes in the mangrove. One of them has some talent in space magic, so I would look into that."

"Noted," Jake said. "Good luck with whatever you are up to… Actually, what are you up to?"

He felt Villy’s amusement as the god answered, "Visiting an old friend and looking into some equipment upgrades of my own. You are not the only one who has gear that has fallen behind. I haven’t had a good upgrade in eras, you know?"

Jake was a bit surprised, even if he probably shouldn’t be. It only made sense that gods needed equipment, too, and also that Villy could use equipment even if he had been a beast in his mortal days. Ascending to godhood changed things in ways Jake didn’t yet know and had no desire to find out about. At least, not yet. He would figure it out when he became a god himself, or at least got a little closer to godhood.

The two of them casually chatted a bit longer before cutting the connection.

In the real world—Sandy’s stomach—the King looked absentminded, likely talking to Sandy. About what, Jake had no idea, and he didn’t want to snoop either. Instead, he entered Serene Soul Meditation and dove into his Soulshape to check up on things.

Miranda had not spent a lot of time around the Sword Saint prior to her return to Haven. She had talked to him quite a lot during this entire planning stage, but that had also been their first real interaction. Everything else she knew about him had been hearsay.

She had feared that when she returned to Haven, there would be some issues, but she soon learned that the old swordsman was as domineering as Jake. Within an hour of their return, the people from the United Cities Alliance had been captured and contained, with those fighting back promptly seeing their heads removed from their shoulders.

This allowed Miranda to go to her old office without having to deal with many other things. When she entered the building, all of the former attendants looked at her with relief, the city having been rather tumultuous for the last few hours with an old man cleaning house.

Miranda greeted the attendants as Lillian took charge of the former leaders of the Haven, who had, fortunately, all survived this endeavor. In fact, the people from the United Cities Alliance had not killed a single soul or even caused any real problems besides slowly undermining Phillip, who had been the temporary leader.

Entering her office, Miranda instantly saw the mess of papers. It had clearly been searched through, and no one had bothered to clean it up—not even the man sitting behind the desk.

"Enjoyed being the leader for a little while again?" Miranda asked Phillip, who looked bored out of his mind.

"Thank god you are back," Phillip said, sighing. "I must admit, for a moment, it was nostalgic, but that was only until I remembered how tedious it could get. At least you are back now, and from what I heard, you have already finished cleaning things up. Ah, speaking of cleaning… you should go look at the cellar later."

Miranda smiled, knowing exactly what was in the cellar. "Things are indeed being restored to how they were. I will go down and look later, but for now, I will need to focus on properly getting a handle on things. Having not been here for so long, I have quite a few issues to deal with, and the system has bombarded me with City Lord messages."

"Good luck with it all," Phillip said with some schadenfreude. "How about Lord Thayne? Will he be returning too?"

"He is on his way here," Miranda answered as Phillip finally got up from the seat and stretched.

"Good to hear; that means I can finally leave." Phillip smiled. "One thing… Lord Thayne should probably go check with Arnold once he is back. I heard he had several private talks with that orange fellow, and I don’t know what they talked about, only that even the United Cities Alliance left him alone. Considering the emotion-affecting Bloodline… I don’t like the situation."

"I will let him know," Miranda said, nodding as she frowned. She had a hard time seeing the man choosing to ally with the nahoom… but… it was possible. No one truly understood him, and depending on what he’d been offered, it was possible he had changed alliances. She would leave it up to Jake to find out.

"Well, then, I will be on my way. I haven’t been able to indulge myself for months." Phillip smiled as he waved while heading out of the office. "Say hi to the peacekeepers for me."

Miranda just shook her head as he headed off. He had changed quite a bit after the Myriad Paths event, but he still had the qualifications of a leader. One of the reasons he had been put in charge was because of the peacekeepers of Haven. They were effectively the police force, and most of them were old soldiers from the Fort. Considering the peacekeepers were already respected, she could see how the United Cities Alliance had issues taking control. Though they had made quite some progress.

They’d still struggled with the Pylon, though. Which was a bit funny, considering the Pylon they had tried to claim was not even the real one. Miranda briefly closed her eyes as her vision shifted to the cellar. Several skeletons were lying down in the cavern beneath the office, with all of the altars from Yalsten still humming with power. The defensive spell she had made before leaving still held strong, and the United Cities Alliance had failed to breach it.

Ell’Hakan could have overpowered it, and maybe his servant would also have been able to, but they had clearly not tried to help. Ell’Hakan had made it clear from the beginning that he did not want them to actually take over Haven and wanted her to keep living. It all made little sense.

The entire invasion had been… weird. And it had ended too abruptly. This bizarre situation was exactly what they planned to discuss whenever Jake returned.

That, and the future of their planet.

Chapter 57

Bold Plans

Jake stared at the fight with quite a bit of confusion. Sim-Jake crashed into the chimera and purposefully let himself be flung away. He charged again, but this time attacked while using some odd version of Shadow Vault. His form seemed almost like it distorted for a moment as he was launched backward.

Jake’s other self noticed him when he entered and stopped fighting. That was when the second weird thing happened. When he stopped attacking, the chimera also seemed calmer, and even if it still looked aggressive, it no longer mindlessly ran at him.

At least, not for a few seconds. Soon enough, hunger overtook it, and it tried to eat sim-Jake whole. His other self responded by making strings of mana like the real Jake and wrapping up the cursed beast.

"Came to take a peek?" sim-Jake asked.

"I got curious." Jake shrugged. "Good progress?"

"Really good. Your timing is also great, because I will need you for this next part. At least a good portion of it. No rush, but I think it would be a good idea to practice with me before C-grade for the potential title.”

"Title?" Jake asked.

"We got one for making a legendary skill in E-grade, right?"

"Yeah?" Jake said, but he instantly got it. "You really think you—we—can do that?"

"If my entire Legacy will be a skill, it better be the best fucking one we got.” Sim-Jake grinned. "Mythical is not easy to reach, but it should be possible… If not, then at least a damn good legendary skill. I have been considering it a lot and even tapped into some memories of your talks with the Malefic Viper. I think we can do it."

It had not at all been a goal of Jake’s to make a mythical skill while in D-grade, but it should be possible… shouldn’t it? Making one in C-grade would be far harder, but maybe sim-Jake could do it before they evolved? Yeah, if there was one thing Jake never lacked, it was self-confidence, even if that self-confidence was about another version of himself. He believed he could do it.

As for why it was harder to get it in C-grade… Well, that should become clear when he evolved. Rarities were not created equal, and each rarity was relative to a grade. This meant that upon evolution, every single skill would be reevaluated by the system. Reevaluated, in this case, just meaning that a bunch of his skills would probably see themselves downgraded. Not all skills would be downgraded, and some he was sure would keep their rarities. Malefic Viper ones, for instance, and stuff like Brew Potion never downgraded.

This entire downgrade thing was more or less a requirement, as, well, it just got easier to make skills when you got stronger. Any S-grade could teleport around, and most could even do some fancy time magic, both of which were considered rather mundane skills for them but would be ancient or higher skills for D-grades. As for why this downgrade only happened in C-grade? Well, because F-, E-, and D-grade were all considered the lower grades, and the difference between them was not that massive in sheer power, only relative power.

Not that any of this mattered for now; what happened during the C-grade evolution was something for future Jake to think about.

This naturally also meant that the requirements of a skill to be a certain rarity grew. So if Jake could get the Vault skill upgrade in D-grade, it would be best.

"Do you need me right now?" Jake asked sim-Jake.

"Not right now, no. I still need to finish some minor aspects, but you can begin practicing a few things while you are here anyway. Things that will be required.”

Jake nodded. He had a few hours at least before he would reach the airspace above Haven, so he had the time. "What kind of thing do you need me to do?"

Sim-Jake grinned. "Sharing control."

Jake was about to protest when sim-Jake elaborated. "Not to me, but to yourself… How can I say this…? To your other self. Think about it—how do we, right now, exist as separate entities yet still share some memories, emotions, and whatnot? You are clearly the primary version, with me a secondary, and I am able to be the carrier of pretty much all Records related to Shadow Vault. What if we keep this separation but also entirely remove it through our merging?"

Sim-Jake sat down and continued, "A skill’s rarity is all about power and complexity. Complexity in both the traditional sense and when it comes to concepts. What is the most insane concept we have besides things related to our Bloodline? To me, it is my very existence. I exist as the Origin of an entire simulated universe, and the concepts to make me who I am today are something even a Primordial admits he cannot replicate or fully comprehend. So why not at least make some simplistic use of this?"

"Do you think that could actually stop our merging?" Jake asked with a frown.

"Well, fuck no, that would require us to make a Transcendent or something, and no fucking way that is happening. Nah, we will still merge, but the skill will still allow us to tap into the concepts if my plan works out. So, are you up for it?"

Jake considered it and smiled. "This sounds insane enough to actually work. Clearly, something I would come up with."

With that, Jake and sim-Jake began their unorthodox practice. The hours quickly passed, and soon enough, he found himself mentally poked by a cosmic worm.

"Hello, there," Sandy said, making Jake wake up. “We have reached the destination.”

"Thanks, Sandy. What would I do without you?”

"Probably have been really slow," Sandy teased him. "By the way, will you stay gone longer this time around? I kinda want to know how far I can move away to find stuff to ste—borrow—on unlimited time."

Jake shook his head. "It will be a while, yes. Lots of stuff to deal with. By the way, I will also likely make a way to leave this universe in not that long of a time… Would you want to come along? Back to the Order where your Patron is?"

"Nah," Sandy answered. "I still got plenty of stuff to eat here first. Maybe later. Though I will probably go by myself or through the egg you car—I mean, will figure it out somehow!"

"Your call," Jake said, not paying the egg business too much mind. He turned and looked at the King. "You ready to head down?"

"Let us," the Unique Lifeform simply answered. He still looked as weak as before, with the masks still cracked all over. He hoped it wouldn’t take too long to heal, but he knew it probably would. The King was not overly liberal when it came to sharing exactly how long it would take, but as far as Jake could tell, it didn’t actually impact Jake in any way.

Sandy spat them both out, and Jake waved off the massive worm, who wriggled in goodbye.

"A truly peculiar creature you have helped create," the King said when Sandy was gone.

"Eh, it sounds weird when you put it like that. Sandy has been Sandy even since before the evolution; the only thing that changed is what the worm eats and where they can go." Jake shrugged.

"Your inability to recognize your impact on what is around you astonishes me once again," the King jabbed. "And I have no interest in wasting time on trying to fix that. Your city should be directly below us? In that case, we should stop delaying."

Jake agreed—with the last part, at least—as they both began flying down. He was pretty much back in top form after the rest inside Sandy, even if he did feel a bit mentally drained from the practice during meditation.

The two of them did not encounter anything of note as they exited the last layer of clouds and appeared above the vast forest that contained Haven on its outskirts. Jake looked towards the depths of said forest and how far it stretched. From up in the air, he had already observed and noticed how the forest extended all the way to the ocean in the far distance.

Will have to properly explore that place at some time, Jake noted to himself as he and the King flew down and entered the forest just above where Haven was. The King mentioned a forcefield of sorts in the surroundings, but he got through it without any issues—something he accredited to being close to Jake. Having some kind of defensive barrier that at least made Miranda aware of everything within was not really a surprise to either of them, but seeing that it was active was evidence to Jake that Miranda was in the city.

Jake quickly located Miranda back in her old office after a brief search using his tracking skill as it was truly intended to be used. He and the King got quite the attention as they landed in the middle of the street in front of the office and entered. None of the peacekeepers got in their way, but Jake got quite a few respectful nods. They just stared at the King, however, who was floating above the ground like the showoff he was.

In his sphere, he saw that Miranda had also noticed him and gotten up from her desk. Jake decided to wait for her to come, and soon enough, she came down the stairs from her office on the upper floor to greet him and the King.

"Jake, Fallen King, you made it back faster than expected.” She smiled, but her smile soon turned to a frown. "What is wrong with the mask? Did something happen?"

"A temporary issue that time shall alleviate," the King answered, refusing to elaborate further.

"What he said,” Jake added. “Nothing to worry about long-term. So, where are we headed?"

Miranda coming down was a clear indication that she planned for them to leave the office building.

"Towards your house,” she answered. “The Sword Saint should already be waiting there for us."

Jake nodded, and without further ado, they all headed out and back to his old home. He would be lying if he said he hadn’t missed the place. It had been many months since he had been back, and the old lodge had quite the memories attached to it. Hearing Miranda mention it also let him know that it was still standing, which was a big relief. He could totally see Ell’Hakan or the United Cities Alliance choosing to destroy it just to be dicks. In fact, he had almost expected them to at least wreck his laboratory, but from what Miranda said, that had not happened either, partly because they hadn’t known much about it, and if they did know, why would they have bothered?

Sure, Hank and the builders knew, but it had clearly never been a priority to investigate it, and if they expected Jake to die or at least to leave Earth, why destroy his stuff and not make use of it? Every faction had alchemists, after all.

Walking into the old valley was very nostalgic, but he did see one issue.

"Someone stole all my bananas," Jake commented, annoyed as he saw the time-banana-tree-that-was-not-a-tree still there. All the bananas were gone, even if the magic circle left by Mystie was still intact. As for the time musa itself, it had grown a bit since last time, having settled well in the valley.

It did remind Jake of one thing. One worrying thing.

"How about Rick down in the cave?" Jake asked Miranda.

He really hoped no one had made trouble for the troll and his two children while he was gone.

“They are all fine," Miranda explained with a smile. “Ell’Hakan and his ilk clearly had no interest in making trouble for some garden troll, and the United Cities Alliance quite frankly wouldn’t be able to… Rick is close to C-grade by now and swings a mean club. Plus, it would be a PR nightmare, as the troll is quite popular with all those who do the dungeon due to handing out small gifts to those who enter. Not to mention the small, adorable trolls… Killing them would have led to an uproar.”

Jake nodded with relief. Relief for a moment… until he saw something horrific. Within his cabin, a single figure was already waiting while committing a grave sin.

The Sword Saint chilled at a table, a stack of bananas in front of him and several peels in a bowl beside him. The sense of betrayal Jake felt at that moment was incredible… and he immediately went to confront the old man. Jake surprised the others with a One Step as he reached the steps of the lodge and promptly barged in.

"Lord Thayne, it has—"

"Banana thief," Jake interrupted, pointing when he saw the old man had already eaten four of them.

The old man looked confused for a moment before smiling. "I apologize, but I believed it only proper to help myself. You are the one who told me to be more selfish, were you not? Ah, but I can share if you want."

"Well, no, I want Perception-enhancing things. This is just the principle of the entire thing.”

"A shame; they are very tasty.” The old man smiled. "And rather suitable for me. Very peculiar fruits indeed."

That was when Jake noticed a faint shimmer around the pile of bananas, and he also remembered that they tended to go bad extremely fast after being taken away from the not-a-tree. It appeared that he had made a small barrier of time magic or something to stabilize it.

"I see you have picked up on some time magic?" Jake asked.

"A few bits and pieces here and there, but I do not focus on it," the old man explained with a shrug. “What time magic I do care about, I keep internal, not external. But as you surely know, it is hard to not pick up on some things passively.”

Their conversation did not go further, as two more figures entered the cabin. The King had to lower himself a bit to get through the door, while Miranda, of course, easily entered.

"Good to see no one messed with the place," Miranda noted, Jake also observing that it indeed looked to have been left alone.

"It did look like someone searched the place, but I reckon you have nothing of value stored in the cabin?" the Sword Saint asked.

Jake was about to answer no, but then remembered there kinda was something. You know, just the minor little thing called a Pylon of Civilization hidden in a pillar down in the basement. Not like that was something he wanted to share.

"Not anything worth finding for them, at least," Jake said, shrugging.

The old man nodded as he turned and looked at the King. The two stared at each other for a few moments, likely having a telepathic conversation of their own and exchanging greetings.

That, and a bit more, as the King spoke out loud, "A challenge shall be set forth once I am fully restored.”

"It would be my pleasure to learn from you," the Sword Saint said, bowing in response.

Jake just shook his head. Goddamn battle maniacs. Who wants to duel someone the first time they meet? I would never do that!

Miranda also shook her head, clearly outraged by their behavior. "Alright, boys, be nice now and stop fighting so we can begin."

The two of them listened as the King waved his hand and warped the flooring of the cabin to make a chair for himself. Jake hoped he would put it back in place once they were done, but he chose not to comment on it.

"So, are you still planning on moving forward with the current plan at the next World Congress?" Miranda asked Jake.

Jake nodded seriously. "Yeah, I still plan on becoming World Leader."

Chapter 58

World-Tier Preparation

Jake becoming the World Leader? Where the hell did that come from? Yeah, definitely not something many people would have predicted, but that was the best course of action—not only in the eyes of Jake, but also the Sword Saint and Miranda. Even the King had agreed it would be the best choice, and it was not a decision that had been made halfheartedly.

The problem was that Earth had turned out to be rather special, whether they liked it or not. It was the planet that had likely spawned the most talents of the entire 93rd Universe, instantly making it an object of interest even to powerful beings of the multiverse. Beings who would want to come and study or maybe even seize the planet to try and figure out why.

Special planets were nothing new in the multiverse. Besides Great Planets, which were just so massive they went against any logic, there were planets that were effectively massive natural treasures. Some just had a bigger chance to spawn natural treasures, others had many natural formations on them that led to unique things, and others still simply had some undetectable concept that seemed to make all those who came from there more talented.

One such example was the planet Valdemar originated from. It was only a bit larger than the current Earth but constantly gave rise to new S-grade talents, with no one truly being able to explain why. The leading theory was that it all boiled down to Records. With it being the planet Valdemar originated from, it only made sense that those who also grew up there would get some innate Records just for being from the same place.

If this theory was true, then Earth was already in a similar situation. Jake, the Sword Saint, Sandy, Caleb, Carmen, Eron, Sylphie, Arnold, Jacob, Casper… There were so many notable figures from their planet. That alone would leave echoes and influence the future of their little rock floating through space.

It wasn’t necessarily even that Jake wanted to be World Leader, just that there truly was no other choice. In the short term, sure, it would be fine no matter who was picked, but not in the long term.

That was one place where Arthur had been right. He had recognized that the long term mattered, and Valhal was a good choice of ally due to their track record. What they wanted from Earth was to use it as a recruitment ground, as they no doubt recognized the uniqueness of the planet. The management and all that was something they would gladly offload to someone else, especially a native who just wanted to nurture and grow the population. This was further reinforced by Arthur being human and Valhal being a primarily human-focused faction due to its roots.

Any actual leader in charge would have to be strong enough to contest with Valhal, the Holy Church, the Risen, or any other faction of the multiverse. It had to be someone who could, at the very least, force them to the table or make them hesitate before making a move. Someone with backing capable of doing all this… which left slim pickings.

The Fallen King? He was a Unique Lifeform. He had no Blessing, and his biggest backing was Jake, making it second-hand backing at best.

Miranda? Same deal. The Witches of the Verdant Lagoon were powerful, but not at the level of being able to intimidate other top factions. Her becoming the leader would also effectively force the planet to be part of the Order of the Malefic Viper, which came with its own restrictions and rules she did not have a position capable of breaking.

The Sword Saint? He didn’t want to, and he also lacked the backing. Not in the sense that Aeon Clok, despite his stupid name, wasn’t someone powerful enough, but due to him not having a faction of any kind. And to be honest, he also only had a Divine Blessing, so no one would actually believe that Aeon himself would descend and intervene for a single planet.

Jacob? Yeah, fuck no. The Holy Church was not an organization that Jake would ever be fine with taking charge of Earth.

They had tried time and time again to find someone better, but time and time again, they went back to Jake being the best. As stupid as it sounded, the second-best option would be Sandy due to their True Blessing, but that was a hard sell.

Even if they wanted to elect someone else like the King… it would be hard. Something Miranda made clear right off the bat was that monsters were very unpopular right now after the many beast attacks in recent months. It was only made worse by the lull before the storm that had preceded it, leaving many unprepared and feeling like they had been led behind the light.

They still needed the support of the population, and Jake also still wanted a world where there could be some kind of balance. If someone like Arthur became the leader, it would be one hundred percent human-favored. Jake wanted beasts and monsters to at least have a seat at the table. This led to the second reason why Jake thought him becoming the World Leader was best.

Jake had the ability to tell everyone to fuck off.

Okay, one could argue any leader had this ability, but Jake would be able to do this for one simple reason: He wouldn’t actually need to care about the political issues that could result from that. Why not, one might ask? Because he was the Chosen of the Malefic Viper. Him being the World Leader was not synonymous with him actually leading shit; it was just establishing he was the top dog.

The system had shown a tendency to not force Paths upon others. Jake had been the City Owner of Haven since the day he returned to Earth, and the amount of city leading he had done was just transferring all of the responsibility to Miranda.

Jake would essentially just become the World Owner and outsource any actual leading to Miranda. He would still be there as a backer for following system events… which added the third reason why Jake realized becoming World Leader was potentially a good idea.

System events. Jake liked to have autonomy and decide on things himself, or, at the very least, have some serious power when it came to making decisions. The World Congress so far had led to two important system events, both of which had resulted in titles and a lot of good stuff, and Jake did not want to miss out on that. Villy also thought that becoming World Leader wasn’t that big of an issue and ultimately only beneficial if he wanted to keep Earth as his home.

Again, this wasn’t only Jake’s idea either. Miranda had actually been the first to propose it. Jake’s initial plan had been for her to become World Leader, but she had shut it down and even added some extra things Jake had not even considered.

"My entire Path so far, ever since exiting the tutorial, has revolved around you, Jake,” Miranda explained. “I manage the city for you. I got my Blessing because of you. It would not be an understatement to say that everything I am is due to your existence. If I became World Leader, that would be separate from you, and I am not even sure how well that would work for me. I do not doubt that being World Leader will offer a potential C-grade evolution option—one that would likely be unwise to skip over—and I would not pick that, as it would negatively impact me. However, if you become World Leader, we will build upon what we already have, just scaled up from a city to a planet.” The King and Sword Saint both agreed with her assessment.

Jake had also been curious how him becoming World Leader would work for the King, but that wasn’t a problem either. In all honesty, the system had probably expected people who had no interest in actually leading their world to become World Leaders. Jake wasn’t even sure Ell’Hakan had the profession of a World Leader, based on all he had shown. Maybe some offshoot or variant, but it being the vanilla version seemed unlikely.

As for whether it was actually possible to outsource all this leadership, Miranda had already researched it. She had access to the Verdant Lagoon through her dreaming skill and had managed to discuss with people and find some records. This entire thing with Pylons of Civilization was not new, and people knew what World Leaders were capable of. At least in broad strokes. There were always small differences, but the essence was the same.

What she had learned revealed that, indeed, the World Leader did not necessarily lead the world. As one would imagine, then a system where the strongest made actual administrative decisions probably wasn’t the best form of governance, and in previous eras, each World Leader had been able to appoint up to five Ministers who would effectively function as deputy leaders.

It did not take a genius to figure out their plan from there. Miranda had proposed a council of sorts. Five people were an unequal number, meaning they could handle votes themselves, and then there was, of course, Jake, who would still sit at the top and be able to veto stuff.

Jake would pretty much just expand his current method of governance from Haven to the entire planet.

As for who should be on this council? The three people in the room besides Jake were a given, but that still meant they needed two more. This was primarily what their meeting was for, in addition to planning the prep work they had to put in during the four or so weeks before the Congress.

"For the council, the most essential aspect will be the representation of all interests of value," the King said, getting nods from around the table. "I would not be able to lead humans, as they distrust me, and many beasts only respect me due to my power. I can represent many of the monsters, yes, but we will need someone else in addition. I asked Sandy about this on the way here, and the Cosmic Genesis Worm has no interest, so someone else will have to do."

Jake was a bit surprised the King had even asked Sandy, but considering he hadn’t known the worm for long, who could blame him? As for who else to pick… Jake had no idea. They discussed this, and Jake did get some ideas for the King to maybe look into.

Anyway, to summarize who they wanted on the council: The Fallen King, Sword Saint, Miranda, and some other beast or monster. Finally, there was someone proposed who Jake really did not want to have there. In fact, he had argued many times against it but found himself being shut down at every turn.

"As for the final member, there really is no other option, is there?" Miranda asked, getting a glare from Jake.

"No, it is the best choice," the King agreed.

Jake grumbled and sighed. "I am still not convinced."

Who could this final member be, if not the glorious leader of the United Cities Alliance… Arthur.

Even Primordials could not simply teleport anywhere in the multiverse they wanted. While traveling through the void was faster than anything else, it wasn’t instant, and established teleportation networks simply couldn’t stretch across the distances a god sometimes had to travel. The reason why Vilastromoz had headed out was also simple: He was there to reclaim something that would potentially be useful for what was to come.

He repeatedly teleported, galaxies passing by. He had entered 44th Universe several hours ago and was finally approaching his goal. The closer he got, the more well protected the planets became. The more familiar signatures of prominent factions he felt.

The galaxy closest to his goal was nearly overpopulated. Billions of inhabited planets and factions owning entire clusters had grouped there. The Altmar Empire, Automatons, Endless Empire, Valhal, Court of Shadows… No faction that operated on a multiversal scale was missing. Even enemies such as the Risen and the Holy Church coexisted within a relatively small space. At least, small on a cosmic scale.

As for why all these factions had gathered here? Well, the reason was simple. About fifty billion years ago, a figure had decided to move his Starforge close to there to make use of a natural treasure to power it. A giant star had been born, and the greatest smith of the multiverse had moved to claim it.

The Starseizing Titan, a fellow Primordial.

Vilastromoz saw the figure of his old acquaintance before he even saw this galaxy. He felt the shockwaves of his forge, which sent waves throughout this entire part of the universe. Even the nearby galaxy was far away, as nothing short of a god could even approach the forge when it was in operation. Celestial objects that had once been close were now nothing more than cosmic dust.

One might ask why he saw his old friend before the galaxy, and for that one, the answer was easy… Because he was bigger. Way bigger.

It was well known that one should never disturb the Starseizing Titan, yet these factions had gods stationed in this galaxy with hopes of having the Starseizing Titan assist them. It was similar to how Villy used to be hounded by people wanting him to do alchemy for them before he just started killing them for not going through the proper channels.

This well-known rule of not approaching naturally did not count for everyone, and Vilastromoz took a single step closer.

The towering form of the Starseizing Titan filled his entire field of vision. His body had a bluish hue with countless stars glinting within. Even planets were inside, his body large enough to house entire galaxies. It was a form of such size it was nearly incomprehensible, making his title of being the largest living entity in the multiverse well-earned.

This size was indeed abnormal and the trait he was most known for outside of his smithing talent. One other thing that made the Starseizing special was that he had been a Unique Lifeform before he became a god. His final special trait, though somewhat less known, was not having a divine realm.

He was his divine realm.

As the Viper got closer, the massive form slowly moved, his actions no faster than that of a regular pre-system human. A massive forge containing millions of stars was in front of him, and in his hand he wielded a black hammer, all of it slowly moving as if he was the personification of the cosmos itself.

"Vilas," a voice echoed out through the vast space, the sound alone enough to make nearby planets crumble. "It has been… long."

Vilastromoz smiled and nodded. "That it has. I hope you are doing well. Based on how you seem to have grown a few times in size since the last time I saw you, I reckon you have?"

"The Path is endless," the Titan answered before taking a long pause. "I have been well, yes."

"Glad to hear," the Viper said. "Besides greeting an old friend, I assume you know why I am here?"

The Titan regarded him for a few moments before the Viper felt space warp. The entire universe seemed to collapse for a moment, and soon he found himself standing before a figure only about three meters tall. His entire body still looked the same, and in reality, it was the same.

He has improved, Vilastromoz recognized. What the Starseizing Titan did was not space magic… No, the spatial reaction was simply from him shrinking his form. What the Titan did was far more than that. He condensed his body into a smaller form… losing nothing in the process.

"This is the most delayed a client has ever been," the Starseizing Titan said, his voice far more normal now.

"I was… busy," Vilastromoz excused himself.

"You have nothing to apologize for," the Titan said as he held out his palm. "After I repaired it, every era, I revisited… and improved it. I felt it grow as you did. It is only right it finally returns to its master."

Vilastromoz smiled when it appeared. He felt space slightly shake as it began breaking down, and the Starseizing Titan even took a step back as the staff resonated with its true owner.

"Welcome home, old friend," the Viper spoke as the staff floated over by itself. The staff was simple, looking like a long, black snake stretching out and sleeping, the eyes and mouth both closed.

The eyes of the snake opened when his hand wrapped around the metallic body, and black veins spread throughout the body, emitting a loud hiss that resounded through space.

As a Primordial, was it not only right to have a weapon befitting of one?

A true weapon surpassing even the divine rarity.

Chapter 59

Towards a Better Future

Arthur… Why Arthur? Jake had seen Arthur once in his life after the system, and he didn’t like him. In fact, Jake kind of hated the guy now. Why wouldn’t he? All interactions Jake had ever had with him were negative, even the second-hand ones. Moreover, he had been the one who decided that bringing Ell’Hakan to Earth was a good idea, messing things up even further. It was also clear he hated Jake’s guts.

Additionally, Jake did not get why Miranda wanted to work with him due to one minor detail.

"Didn’t he send a group to assassinate you?" Jake asked Miranda with pursed lips. "Sounds like a great guy to work with, huh?"

"You speak as if that is simply not him showing he understands the rules of the multiverse,” the King said. “He read the rule book and knew that the Court of Shadows would act as long as he provided funds. He also understood Valhal. That means he is not as stuck in his thoughts as you may believe, but can adapt.”

"As weird as it sounds, him not liking us is exactly why he is good,” Miranda explained. “The worst thing for a governing body is to have it be filled with yes-men who just do whatever you want. To have no one ever offer an opposing voice. I am firmly in the camp of the Order, and my job is to represent your views. The King will represent his own views and those of monsters while inadvertently also being tied to you. The Sword Saint is also not likely to oppose you and will not be very involved. Finally, a second monster added has a high chance of being on your side too, and sure won’t be on the side of humans. As things currently are, the common human population does not have a single person representing them, and we need someone actually willing to present them. Someone who has the guts to. Like it or not, Arthur has shown himself capable and willing to do this, and he is annoyingly efficient at what he does.”

"Sounds all nice and dandy until he tries to start a civil war or some shit to take control," Jake mused.

"Arthur has also shown himself to not be an idiot, and he knows that will not be in the best interest of the citizens of Earth," Miranda further added. “Giving him a seat at the council will also send a clear message that we are not taking over the planet as the Order of the Malefic Viper, but as earthlings. It will also communicate that you are not the type of person to just go and kill anyone who disagrees with you or puts themselves in positions contrary to yours. While some may interpret it as a weakness to ‘forgive’ him, it can also be seen as a strength that signals you, a Chosen, never truly cared for his petty games. That you don’t care enough about him to personally act. In some ways, I also think the best punishment will be to have him fix what mistakes he had made while we make full use of his expertise. Moreover, I think much of his hatred stems from ignorance. He views us as representations of concepts, not as humans, just like him. I believe with time, we can find common ground, and he can become an asset.

"The man has shown himself to be resourceful so far. Nobody here could have done what he did to make the United Cities Alliance, especially considering his lack of literal power. He got his position in such a short time—not by being stronger than everyone else, but by sheer competence. The majority of humanity supports him based on what he has done, and even in recent months, he has shown his genuine goal with all of the beast attacks. Rather than try and push for anything due to these attacks, he focused solely on alleviating the issue, making smaller response teams and teleportation networks, and stabilizing areas. I highly doubt he had anything to do with these beast attacks, and based on how fast those stationed in Haven gave up after we returned, he also seems to understand when he is in a losing position."

"And you seriously think this dude will just give up?" Jake asked. This part was the one he believed the least.

"Yes, I do," Miranda said with conviction. “Mark my words: Within a week, he will come to Haven and surrender. If he does not come in surrender before the World Congress, then I will take back everything, but I highly doubt that he won’t. Arthur truly cares about humanity, if his words are to be believed… so giving himself up to try and avoid a downright disaster for the United Cities Alliance would be the wisest choice. He will take the fall for his failure and take responsibility as their leader.”

The King also agreed on this, with the Sword Saint nodding along like it was a given. Jake really felt outnumbered…

He understood why they needed someone from the United Cities Alliance, and also kind of understood why it had to be Arthur. As Miranda had explained it, then the man was now stuck between a rock and a hard place. If he kept fighting, the result was already written on the wall, and soon enough, he would find himself slain. Even if he became World Leader, it would be short-lived… and chances were he wouldn’t, because even if Jake wouldn’t be able to kill Arthur, he sure as hell could go on a rampage of the ages.

Additionally, he knew that death would also lead to problems. For better or worse, Arthur had become the symbol of the United Cities Alliance and the hope of all those who wanted an independent planet that would not become slaves to some insidious higher power. If Jake was to kill him, Arthur would become a martyr and spark a war, or, at the very least, an army of fringe terrorist groups.

The only way for Jake to combat this would be a total dictatorship down the line. He would need to rule like the Order and make Earth into something he didn’t want it to be. Jake was fine with people disagreeing and not liking him, and trying to control everyone would go against who he was. He also feared he would need to kill millions, if not billions to try and root out all hidden enemies… which also sounded like something he really didn’t want to do.

In the beginning, when Miranda had mentioned Arthur, Jake’s gut reaction had been, of course, that the dude was in for an arrow through the temple. Why wouldn’t he? But perhaps this gut reaction was why having people like Miranda was necessary.

One had to remember that Jake’s gut was not about making decisions that were good for anyone but himself. The reason he wanted to kill Arthur was just to make himself feel better, the future be damned.

There was also one thing holding Jake back from going full scorched earth on the United Cities Alliance… One that some people would probably make fun of him for.

What would Mom and Dad think?

He was a hunter, yes. He could live with them not approving of this, but Jake did not want them to view him as a monster, and if he became the next oppressive dictator of Earth, they sure as hell wouldn’t take it well. That thought alone was enough to calm Jake down and make him listen to Miranda.

Again, according to her, Arthur also knew all of these consequences of his death could happen, which was why Miranda believed he would give himself up and officially surrender. He would openly do this, announcing his loss to everyone and making a plea for peace. Knowing full well, especially if he went by the track record of the Order, that what awaited him would be an execution.

So if he actually selflessly came to surrender… Jake could maybe accept him being on the council. Maybe.

"Fine," Jake finally agreed. "If he comes, keep him here. I will be back three days before the Congress to have a talk with him if you are right. I will want to at least talk to him before I give him even the slightest shred of political power."

Miranda smiled and nodded. "That is all I can ask."

"What about the other factions?" he then asked.

"Well, the Court and Valhal are no problem; I already received word from Lillian that both will not interfere in anything going forward and respect you or anyone you choose as the World Leader, even making it clear that should we wish for it, they will leave the planet. The Risen are already gone… which truly leaves only the Holy Church as an obstacle worth mentioning."

"With them, I am not budging," Jake made clear.

"I understand and agree," Miranda said with pursed lips. “From what I have gathered, the Augur is not even planetside anymore, and it would not surprise me if the Holy Church does as they usually do in these kinds of situations.”

This was something that they had also all agreed on from the beginning. No other divine factions. Carmen would not be allowed on the council even if she wanted, nor would Caleb or Casper—if he was still on Earth. The only faction with a claim would be the Order of the Malefic Viper, with Jake as the Chosen telling everyone that it was his home turf.

Having another faction would only complicate that. As for people with independent gods, it wouldn’t matter much. Arnold, the Sword Saint, and many others—none of them would be issues to still have around, and the factions like Valhal and the Court would be allowed to remain but fall under Jake’s rules like everyone else.

As for what the Holy Church was doing… Well, they were doing the usual thing. The Holy Church was a bit unique as a multiversal faction in that they valued numbers a lot—not just to increase the chance of someone with talent appearing, but for their faith. They wanted to retain them more than any other faction, which made their usual tactic when they lost a territorial war the same every time:

Mass exodus.

"From the reports of the Court that your brother so kindly sent over, the Holy Church has made a new vast teleportation network to bring all the faithful back to Sanctdomo,” Miranda said, sighing. “Meanwhile, those who were not an actual part of the faction but just living there were given the harsh choice of joining or getting thrown out the gates. They seemed to have read the writing on the wall that they would not win no matter what. If you won, they would lose, and if Ell’Hakan won, the United Cities Alliance would have also moved to get them out. Their final plan seemed to be, at the very least, making sure the Risen would not be able to get anything from Earth either.”

Jake had to be honest… He was all fine with them leaving. Because if they did not, then they had been entirely correct in their assertion that Jake would kick them to the curb and tell them to get fucked. He still considered Jacob a friend, but it was like that kind of friend who you knew was a nice person but had now gotten himself involved in a nasty cult without being able to see it himself. Well, or a friend caught up in a multilevel marketing scam. All Jake would do was hope he saw sense before he went too far down the rabbit hole.

"Let’s hope they all fuck off by themselves; if not, we shall do some cleanup after we get the World Leader position," Jake said. After that, there was only a bit more small talk before they agreed to end the meeting.

"You all know my plans, but what will all of you be doing before the Congress?" Jake asked.

He first turned and looked at the Sword Saint, who sighed in disappointment before answering, "I shall head home to those pathetic dregs who dare claim the Noboru name. A solid cleanup shall begin, and the purging will leave us stronger and not as worn down by weakness. I realize that the clan perhaps expanded too quickly and was too dependent on me to hold it together. What I leave behind will be a clan able to stand on its own two legs. I will forever be a member of the clan, but I will officially step down as Patriarch and remain only as a protector. I will be back for the meeting three days before the Congress."

Jake looked at Miranda. "Don’t look at me like I don’t have a mountain of work in front of me with a damn mountain range in the distance of even more damn work. In a month, we will literally take over the planet, and I still have the aftermath of your war with another Chosen to figure out. Oh, and then we expect Arthur to come… Yeah, do I need to say more?"

He knew that he had kind of messed up and quickly did the smart thing by looking questioningly at the King.

"We need a final beast. You mentioned this… whale? I shall try and seek it out, or maybe try to locate another worthy candidate. I will naturally return for the meeting at hand, but I may not be there three days ahead, and if I do miss it, we will meet at the Congress. I also need to recover, so I shall take it slow and carefully venture out. In a few days, I should be able to show about eighty percent of my full power again, at which point I will head out."

Jake nodded and smiled. It indeed seemed like everyone had things to deal with. As for Jake? Jake would take this month before the World Congress to do something he should have done a lot earlier and a lot more frequently.

All of this talk of taking over the world and the future of their planet reminded him of his family. Reminded him of the nephew he had only seen for a brief period what was to him years ago. It was only right to visit them, so Jake decided to take a break and ground himself before becoming World Leader and making the subsequent push to C-grade.

After the meeting fully concluded, they all split up and went their own ways.

Jake headed out and first made a visit to Arnold. Miranda had seemed concerned about him due to Ell’Hakan apparently wanting to recruit him or something, but when Jake met him, he noticed nothing awry. He even decided to ask if Arnold had joined Ell’Hakan, and his answer had just been that he hadn’t. So, that was that. Jake found the entire thing a bit dumb to begin with. Arnold didn’t look like he gave a shit about who took over the planet as long as they left him the fuck alone.

After visiting Arnold, Jake went for a trip down to the cavern and said hi to Rick and the small trolls, all of whom were over level 95 and close to evolution. He kind of hoped they would stay small and cute—small, here, being relative for trolls—but he knew that wasn’t likely, considering their large parent.

Rick seemed happy and greeted him, handing him some uncommon-rarity flowers. So that was nice of him. The cavern had also really changed, and was now full of flowers and paths of grass one could walk through. Rick really liked flowers.

With the troll visit done, he headed out of Haven and took to the plains, traveling by himself for the first time in a long while. Maybe he would even visit that massive mountain he’d seen on the last trip there to find out what was on top?

There were also the insect plains, but they would have to wait for now, as Jake didn’t want to go on an underground hunting trip.

The entire visit with the trolls and his own plans had put him in a good mood, and with a smile, he headed Skyggen to spend some quality family time.

Ell’Hakan appeared in the vast library as thousands of books circled around him. He groaned a bit from the severed arm—the concept deployed by the Sword Saint still hurt nearly half an hour later. He realized he had miscalculated… but it had worked out anyway.

"Didn’t think to check for Transcendents," a voice echoed as Ell’Hakan felt the pressure, making him take a knee.

"I greet thee, Yip of Yore," Ell’Hakan spoke to his Patron. "It was indeed out of our expectations."

"Those Transcendent bastards have always been incredibly annoying, but even so, the swordsman should not be an issue moving forward," Yip said with a smile as the many books around him had their pages torn out—only to fly into a new book with a seemingly haphazard mix of pages.

"It should not, no," the nahoom agreed. "Everything else went as planned. The native alliance is broken, the Church is abandoning the planet, the Risen are gone, and all other factions seem to have accepted their fates. The Chosen of the Malefic Viper will become World Leader."

Yip smiled. "Good. The first arc has been written, with the mighty Chosen of the Malefic Viper beating back the would-be liberator of his homeworld. Now, it shall fall into the hands of the cruel Chosen. My Chosen failed to stop him, the same as when I failed to stop the Malefic Viper from destroying and claiming the domain of the Brimstone Hegemon.

"A sad tale indeed, but is it not only to be expected that our heroes fail in the first arc? Only to rise to the occasion and strike back stronger than ever as they slowly build power for that final confrontation? A final confrontation that shall leave the heroes victorious and the villains dead… giving birth to the greatest legend of all. A Primordial Slayer."

Ell’Hakan smirked, feeling the emotions in the air as Yip’s confidence grew. Manipulating the god would be foolishness itself, but he could still at least feel the emotions. Every day, his Patron’s power grew—the linked success of both Chosen and god.

The first arc had had some unexpected issues pop up, and many missed opportunities, but the result had been achieved overall.

Their goal had never been to beat the Malefic’s Chosen. It had never been to kill him. Why would they want to kill him when they were only D-grades, isolated on a single planet… with such a small audience… when they could instead expand their battle to be two Chosen World Leaders battling on a galactic scale? Two champions facing each other in the cosmos, fighting for the fate of their entire galaxy.

Wouldn’t that be a far greater story?

Chapter 60

A Chill Trip

The journey to Skyggen was one Jake had made before, but this time was far faster in every way. Jake’s One Step had upgraded, allowing him to go further than ever before, and he was fast approaching the city. It did help that he also ignored everything in the way… except one thing.

Curiosity had always been one of his strong traits, but the last time he had gone to Skyggen, he had listened to the logical part of his brain. A massive mountain appeared before Jake, reaching far into the sky above the many layers of clouds. It was bonkers how big it was, and Jake faintly felt a powerful aura from the top. A C-grade aura. Jake had not wanted to go the last time he was there, as he hadn’t been quite ready to face a C-grade, but this time it should be fine, right?

Right?

Jake rapidly approached the mountain, which only looked bigger the closer he got. It completely put any mountain on Earth to shame, and based on how massive the base was, Jake estimated its height should be measured not in tens, but hundreds of kilometers.

Kind of makes sense, Jake thought. The C-grade—or C-grades, if there were more than one—had to live far enough up on the mountain due to the system restrictions.

The climb wasn’t fast, but it wasn’t slow either. By climb, Jake meant running vertically with One Step. He teleported up in the air like he had just unlocked infinite teleporting double-jumps. Soon, he made it ten kilometers up. Then thirty. Fifty. A hundred.

For every step, the mountain narrowed a little. When he reached the hundred-kilometer mark, Jake guessed the mountain had to be around three hundred kilometers tall. On his way up, he spotted many caves and creatures living on the mountain. Thousands of birds made it their resting place before heading out into the merciless skies again, some of which found themselves hunted by predators lurking on the mountainsides.

None of them paid him any mind, and Jake didn’t bother them either. It did not take him long to finally reach the layer of cloud that allowed C-grades, and he instantly felt the shift. The air suddenly turned chilly, and white snow covered the mountain. He saw now that the rest of the mountain was covered in white, but more than that, he felt something else there. A presence that seemed to seep into the mana itself.

Curiosity still had hold of him as he went to investigate. He flew closer to the mountain and landed as he saw several tracks. Areas where the snow had been disturbed by what looked like a giant claw print.

He kept going forward until he saw a massive cave that seemed to burrow straight into the middle of the mountain. Icicles covered the sides of it, and Jake felt an intense chill coming from within. Enough for him to use a barrier of arcane mana to defend himself from it.

As he stood there, he also felt something from his boots. As he was earthbound, he could detect natural treasures, and from within that cave, a powerful sensation came. Sense of the Malefic Viper did not react, meaning it was not a toxin, but that did not mean it would be useless to him.

Not that Jake thought he could claim it… for he also felt a powerful aura.

Mid-tier C-grade? No… not quite… but still strong, Jake thought. Whatever creature dwelled within also seemed to become aware of him, as its presence swept out from within. Jake was ready to retreat when two blue wisps of light lit up the unnaturally dark cave.

A rumble sounded, and then he heard the sound of claws scraping stone. Soon, the creature became visible as it slowly walked out of the cavern, the chilly air cooling down as it got closer. Jake knew, upon feeling its presence, that it was a creature of pure mana. One of the natural masters of magic in the multiverse.

Blue scales covered its body, and vapor exited its slightly open mouth. Two claws dragged it forward, each attached to large, leathery wings, with two legs being the primary method of moving when not in the air. For some reason, Jake did not feel any fear. He had only a stupid smile on his lips from finally meeting one in the wild.

[Northpeak Wyvern – lvl ???]

Wyverns were not dragons, true. But they were the second-best. Even a powerful hatchling of a True Dragon often could not match a similarly leveled evolved wyvern. The reason was simple… The requirements for a reptile to evolve into a wyvern were incredibly strict, and they needed to have insane levels of innate magical talent.

"Your smell is familiar," a voice echoed out from the wyvern, “but you are not kin."

Jake smiled. "No, I am not. It is a pleasure to—"

"Then die."

His danger sense exploded when the wyvern opened its mouth. Jake reacted as fast as he could, activating Arcane Awakening and crossing his arms in front of him as several layers of arcane magic appeared. Just in time, too.

A chilly wind hit Jake, followed by blue light. To lessen the impact, Jake tried to redirect some of the force as he was shot backward. The arcane barriers froze and shattered one by one, making him feel like he was in the middle of a blizzard. Within a second, the final barrier shattered, and the cold energy hit Jake directly. His skin froze, his armor cracked, and he had to close his eyes for them not to freeze solid, the already-summoned Scales still managing to absorb most of the force.

Luckily, he was also being pushed away at an alarming pace. He flew back rapidly and summoned a healing potion into his mouth to fight the cold energy that invaded his body and sought to freeze his insides.

Soon, he at least stopped accelerating as the power of the wyvern’s breath dissipated. That just left Jake flying through the air like a comet down toward the ground. The entire front of his body was frozen, and Jake gritted his teeth as he managed to move his frostbitten limbs and brace for impact before he smashed into the ground, creating a large crater.

The cold emanated from his body, freezing even his surroundings. Feeling pretty damn chilly, Jake sat up in the crater, the mountain still visible far in the distance.

"What a rude wyvern," Jake muttered.

At least he had been hurled in the direction of Skyggen, so could this count as a shortcut? Definitely not, but Jake wanted to justify his curiosity somehow.

Still more than a little miffed at the lack of courtesy from the frost wyvern, Jake got up. His entire body was stiff, his skin and scales cracked from the frostbite. It was damn annoying, and even with his vital energy working at high speed, it would take some time to eliminate all the frost energy in his body. The breath of a wyvern was far less potent than that of a True Dragon, but it still held incredible conceptual power nonetheless.

Moving forward at a slower pace, Jake continued his journey. He complained a bit under his breath, swearing that the next time he went to that peak, he would show that damn wyvern what true rudeness looked like.

Caleb looked down at the sleeping toddler and smiled. He and Maja had had many discussions during the pregnancy on how to deal with a newborn, especially with Caleb working early hours and whatnot as a schoolteacher. At least that hadn’t been an issue, considering he no longer needed to sleep at all. Adam did sleep a lot, and according to his mom, relatively normal hours, too. At least compared to Caleb.

As a baby and toddler, Jake had been a weird one. Mom had talked about how he would always wake up when you entered the room, almost as if he could detect you in the room… Something he, in retrospect, clearly had been able to do.

"I still feel a bit jealous," Caleb heard his dad, Robert, say from behind. "Back in my day, we had to get up every two hours to a crying baby and soldier through the day on four hours of sleep."

"In all fairness, I am not even getting four hours a week." Caleb smirked.

His dad ignored him with a huff as he looked at Adam sleeping. "I had feared how everything would be for a newborn… but he seems normal. Part of me had thought that maybe kids would grow up to adulthood within a few months or have superpowers, making toddlers even more menacing than before."

Caleb definitely concurred on that one. All of it. He had feared what kind of life a child could have in a world where battle and killing were so common, and perhaps more, how the system would mess with someone growing up.

The system had definitely led to changes for children, but surprisingly enough, they were generally positive. How exactly the status menu of a toddler looked, he obviously couldn’t know, but one thing was clear: their stats did not match their level. At least, not their effectiveness.

Adam was already level 3, which meant that by pre-system standards, he should have more stats than a regular adult man. Or at least close. At minimum, he should be far stronger than he was. Okay, he was still stronger than a normal kid, but it was not extreme, so even if he could crawl faster and had quite the grip, it was not at a level where he could lift his own dad off the ground. He did not seem to display any particularly supernatural traits besides one aspect: durability.

It was weird, analyzing his own son like that, but he also couldn’t ignore reality. Like with any kid, Adam liked to sometimes do less-than-intelligent things. Things that would usually make a kid cry, such as bumping his head or hitting himself with a toy, he ignored. The few times he managed to scratch himself, the wound would also heal within the hour. He had also not been sick once, and he needed less food than pre-system children.

Caleb was, needless to say, thankful that the system seemed to have made life for both children and parents easier. No longer did you need to be so fearful of anything and everything going wrong. Parents no longer needed to have several children to ensure some made it to adulthood, and even without medical professionals, children would be fine.

"We are lucky," Caleb said, smiling as he looked at Adam sleeping.

He left the room shortly after with his dad, going to the living room. It was only the two of them in the house, and Caleb would have to leave soon, leaving his dad behind to babysit. Yes, even with the system and all that, there was no way he and Maja would leave Adam without a babysitter.

"How is Maja settling in?" Robert asked.

"She is doing well," Caleb said with another smile.

She was spending some time with her own parents these days, and had taken a route similar to many others when it came to figuring out what she wanted to do. Her prior ongoing education in law did not prove the most useful post-system, but she still wanted to at least work somehow tangentially to it, so she had decided that since her husband was a Judge, she should do something to help him do his job. Hence, she’d gone into the business of making contracts. System contracts and general administrative work. It was honestly a good thing, as Caleb felt a lot better having someone he could one hundred percent trust at his back.

The two of them chatted a bit more before Dad suddenly seemed to remember… "Didn’t you say something about Jake coming by?"

"Yep." Caleb nodded. He had to say, Jake was really lucky. Adam being born and everything being so hectic had distracted Mom and Dad enough for them not to get too annoyed at his lack of contact. Not that Caleb blamed him; Jake was busy and had a lot on his plate already.

"About time," Robert still grumbled.

Caleb just shrugged, not really seeing much to say. It was definitely not an argument he was going to try and have again.

"So, when will he come?" Robert followed up.

"Not sure of the exact timeline, but last I heard, he was on his way. I have no idea how fast he is these days or if he has any errands on the way, but it shouldn’t be too long.”

Dad just nodded, not talking about it further. Caleb was halfway looking forward to and halfway dreading the talk they would have when Jake arrived. He wasn’t sure how it would go after all the stuff with Arthur. Would Jake get mad at the Court for having helped Arthur? Would he get mad at Caleb? Or would he do as he usually did and not really care?

At least Arthur was gone. Last Caleb had heard, he was headed toward Haven to try and do some damage control. An understandable move, as Arthur truly believed Jake was an unhinged maniac who was seconds away from genocide at any moment. The leader of the United Cities Alliance genuinely feared that Jake would go on a rampage and ravage cities in retaliation. Thus, he hoped to give himself up and lay down his life to appease the monstrous Malefic’s Chosen.

It was a stupid thought, but… Jake was hard to understand for people who didn’t know him. Everyone seemed to have expectations as to how he was supposed to act, viewing everything he did as something pre-approved by his Patron to advance the goals of the Order of the Malefic Viper.

Let’s hope things work out, Caleb thought, sighing as he walked towards his office to finish up some paperwork. He had no idea what Jake was planning but was sure he would find out soon.

It ended up taking nearly ten hours before Jake was back to full speed after his wyvern encounter, resolving himself not to annoy moody frost lizards anymore. The cold energy had lingered far longer than expected, and with Palate useless against it, it had been a struggle to eliminate it all. However, when he was at full speed, he made rapid progress, and it did not take long before Jake closed in on Skyggen.

Only after he entered the fake Skyggen did he realize that he could likely have made it a lot faster by finding out which teleporters were functional again, then finding a city that could take him there.

Earth was rapidly restoring what had been lost, and it wouldn’t take long before a new teleportation network was up and running. One that would even be better than the one before, as all those responsible for making it had gotten stronger and more skilled in the meantime. Chances were that even areas like the Grand Mangrove River could be passed through by the teleporters with just a bit of tweaking. If not, then it should be possible to make a teleportation checkpoint in the middle.

Jake shook his head, not wanting to waste time thinking about it once he saw the streets of fake Skyggen and noted how they barely differed from before. It was evident the beast tides had not reached the city at all, and all that had happened was them expanding as more sought the safety of larger cities.

Remembering the route, Jake passed through the city and went towards the real Skyggen.

It would be good to finally spend some quality family time… and talk to his parents about his plans of quite literally taking over the world.

Chapter 61

Family Time

Jake was rarely nervous, but on that day, he really was. Logic be damned, he was still a bit afraid his parents wouldn’t be okay with him coming, even if Caleb had only ever said they wanted him to. He had to admit that this was one of the reasons he kept trying to avoid going… Jake was very different from before, and with every day, he truly grew further from Jake, a boring salaryman in finance, and closer to Jake the Hunter. Despite how much he had been assured by Caleb, the nervousness still stayed, making him feel like this was a repeat of their first meeting all over again.

To add on, there was one more element. A person who had looked forward to meeting Jake’s parents even more than Jake himself… or, well, equally as much. It was naturally his other self, sim-Jake.

Sim-Jake had last seen his parents the day they died. To him, it had been decades, even if he had been able to experience the real Jake’s memories. However, as he still maintained an ego, it just wasn’t the same. That was why, when Jake entered the real Skyggen, he instinctively knew sim-Jake had stopped his training and was alert and watching.

Who could blame him for being nervous? Both of them? All of this resulted in Jake slowly making his way toward the large residence where Caleb and his parents lived with his head full of doubt. The guards took out tokens to let him in without stopping him or even speaking a word, and Jake knew they had been informed of him coming. He hadn’t tried to hide this time around, so they all knew he was in Skyggen, meaning there really was no way to back down.

Jake approached the house and saw them within through his sphere. Waiting. He took a deep breath and walked up to the door before knocking. Within the house, Mom instantly shot to her feet and rushed towards the door. He was thinking about what to say or how to act when she hastily opened the door and saw him.

In the next moment, Jake realized how dumb he had been.

Without any hesitation, his mom pulled him into a hug. His anxiety washed away as he just returned the hug. Neither of them spoke as he smiled, a well of emotions also coming from within his Soulspace.

He really should visit more.

"How long did you think you could hide it from me?"

The Augur looked out at the vast, golden city from atop the spire. A deep frown adorned his face as he felt the changes in the tapestry from the faraway planet. The mix of hope and fear from his home planet reached him even in another universe—proof of his increased power after his evolution.

"Until you discovered it yourself," the B-grade Bishop answered with a sigh. "I am not foolish enough to think that I can obscure the truth from an Augur for long."

Jacob’s frown only deepened at the answer. "Why was this necessary? What happened on Earth?"

"Movements and machinations above what we mortals are meant to comprehend. The game of the gods is not ours to interfere with; all we can do is try and make the outcome as acceptable as possible. Yip of Yore, a god recognized as at the pinnacle, challenged the Malefic One, and their battle was extended to also include their Chosen. The Chosen of Yip of Yore invaded your planet with the help of a faction of natives and battled the Malefic’s Chosen. This happened only shortly after you arrived here, and recently concluded with the Chosen of Yip abandoning the planet and the Malefic’s Chosen coming out on top.”

Jacob didn’t sense a single trace of falsehood in his words. "Why would all of this require me to leave Earth and come here?"

"It is not only you. The faithful will all be evacuated from the planet, as the Holy Church has decided to abandon it unilaterally. A decision that should not come as a surprise to you, considering the state it was in and the turmoil it faced.”

Jacob wanted to protest but truly couldn’t. Deep inside, he had known this would be the conclusion for quite a while. The Holy Church was a monolithic faction that either controlled a planet or didn’t. They had rituals and effectively terraformed planets to suit them, natively spawning holy energy that strengthened the power of faith for all who lived there. Sharing with other factions, especially enemy factions like the Risen, was not an option.

"After the second event, it was obvious that taking control of the entire planet would not be feasible," the Bishop continued. "Considerations of placing an embassy of sorts there were brought up but ultimately decided against. As things are looking right now, it looks like the Malefic One’s Chosen will end up victorious—something that I also feel does not come as a surprise.” There was a hint of accusation in that last part.

They both knew Jacob had been asked to distance himself from Jake, and also that he hadn’t followed that advice quite as the Church would have hoped. Jacob also knew that the hope—no, expectation—of Jake was that he would leave the planet altogether. There truly was little reason for him to stay, from the perspective of the Church, so they assumed he would just teleport to the Order. Something he had done. Except he also kept coming back, and based on how he seemed to have made a home on Earth, it looked like he didn’t plan on staying away for good.

"Could you tell me everything that happened in my absence?" Jacob finally asked. While the Bishop had explained the cliff notes, Jacob knew there was more to it. There always was.

The Bishop agreed and told him everything without holding back. Jacob had suspected it, but when it was confirmed that his father had been the leader of this native faction, he could only sigh. His sense of helplessness deepened when he learned that the Church had known about this Ell’Hakan coming well ahead of time and had even been warned, hence sending Jacob away beforehand. They had indeed planned on leaving Earth all along and just wanted the Risen gone, too—something Jacob would have been an obstacle to accomplishing. Which begged the question…

"How exactly do you expect me to respond to all this?" Jacob asked.

"I expect nothing; I am nothing more than an instrument of a greater will,” the Bishop said. “What I will say is that I personally question why you believe you have been slighted. You stand here now at C-grade, a multiverse in front of you, the blessing of the Holy Mother upon your soul and the Church at your back, and you care about a small, insignificant planet. The reach of the Holy Church is boundless, and there are numerous places that can benefit from an Augur of Hope. Numerous places for you to exert your Path. Could you truly guide Earth towards a feasible Path with so many elements on it to lead it astray? Your planet was corrupted beyond saving the moment the Chosen of the Malefic One chose to stay there. All you can do now is look onward.”

"And how do you expect me to do that?" Jacob asked further.

"Explore. You have barely seen anything of the multiverse yet; it is a ripe time to see what it has to offer. Leave Earth behind you. Perhaps the system will still offer you to return for events, but if not, then simply close that chapter of your life. People need help and guidance everywhere. People need hope everywhere. With time, I believe you will come to understand that no one has tried to slight or betray you. They simply guided you as you now guide others. Towards a better future.”

Days passed by as Jake did something he hadn’t done in a long time: absolutely nothing. He just relaxed with his family, played with his little nephew, and went around Skyggen exploring. Okay, Jake did do a bit of light work, but it was only reading, meditating, and helping Caleb out with some minor stuff. During meditation, Jake began working more with sim-Jake, but both of them dedicated most of their attention to their holiday. He had even made it clear to Miranda that he was only to be contacted in the case of an emergency, and Villy seemed to get the idea and didn’t pop into his head a single time throughout this period.

Jake naturally also discussed recent events with Caleb and his parents. Everything with Ell’Hakan and Arthur had made quite the ruckus, and especially Caleb had seemed nervous Jake would get mad at him for the whole assassination thing. Jake didn’t know why… It wasn’t like his little brother had killed anyone Jake knew, and while it did indirectly help an "enemy," Jake couldn’t exactly get mad every time his brother took a job. It would be like if he got mad that his brother went to buy potions from someone else, as that would hurt Jake’s financials.

As for the big subject of Jake’s future plans… it felt like his parents didn’t really understand it. They understood the words when Jake said he would become World Leader, but it didn’t really seem to sink in. It was a bit like how they didn’t entirely get what it meant for him to be the Chosen of the Malefic Viper, or how they didn’t really understand the multiverse and the powerful factions in it.

For the most part, Jake got it. The scale of things had gotten ridiculous. Gods who could crush entire galaxies with ease were mentioned as if normal, and factions with trillions upon trillions of members with countless planets were just things thrown out there. It didn’t really make any sense to most people, as it was too far removed from their everyday lives, so Jake didn’t push it either. They didn’t need to really understand… and in a way, taking control of Earth was a way of ensuring they didn’t have to.

Or maybe they did know and just didn’t want to make a big deal out of it. In either case, it was probably for the best, as it allowed Jake to just be himself. For better or worse. Both he and his brother knew that even if his parents and Maja had reached D-grade, the chances of them reaching C-grade were near nil.

It was another thing Jake didn’t want to think too much about. What he did like to think about was the last member of the little family.

Adam, his nephew, had proved himself to be a big fan of his uncle. Who could blame him? He seemed especially interested in Jake’s mana strings, and while Maja wasn’t keen on it, she allowed Jake to make a swing of pure, stable, arcane mana. The moving parts were a bit tough, but he got it working pretty damn quickly and rapidly expanded—from a swing to a slide to a makeshift rollercoaster to whatever else Jake could get on.

No, this was not practicing; this was playing. Did it also happen to be good practice? Yes, but that was a happy little coincidence.

A month seemed like a long time, but the weeks passed by faster than Jake had expected. Before long, it was the evening before Jake would have to head back to Haven, and they had all met up for a final dinner together. None of them really had to eat—besides Adam—but that didn’t mean one couldn’t enjoy a good family dinner.

With the table set and a homecooked meal steaming, it began. They had tried to avoid certain topics during most of the visit—topics delegated as work topics—but as this was the last night, all topics were valid. So, naturally, the conversation fell on what Jake wanted to do after he left.

"I heard you are planning on leaving and going to that Order again soon," Robert, his dad, stated.

"Probably," Jake said, nodding as his mom began piling food on his plate. "I have something I want to do there before the evolution."

"Oh?" his mom asked. "Is it related to that alchemy of yours?"

"Nah. It’s this dungeon with a hydra in it. I can fight the strongest D-grade version as long as I go there before I evolve. I lost the first time around and want a rematch." Jake smiled.

"You lost?" Caleb said with a cheeky grin. "Damn, I didn’t know you could even do that. What did it do, eat all your arrows or something?"

"That is exactly what it did," Jake answered with a deadpan expression. His mom gave him a look to make him stop teasing Caleb, but Jake doubled down. "What? It did eat everything. Arrows, magic, even my poison."

Caleb turned a bit more serious. "Sounds like quite the beast. A strong variant?"

"Yep," Jake said as he took a bite of the food that his mom had just handed him. "This hydra later became a god, too."

Frowning, Caleb thought for a moment. "Wait, the Lord Protector of the Order? The Boundless Hydra? It has an image saved in a dungeon?"

"Right on," Jake confirmed.

"Boys, enough hydra talk," Maja finally cut in. Jake looked a bit apologetic, with Caleb naturally obliging the words of his wife. It was a tad rude to talk about something only the two of them really knew and cared about.

They stopped discussing anything serious for a while and instead talked about causal topics. Primarily a trip Jake and Caleb had made where Jake "borrowed" some more special alchemical ingredients from the Court of Shadows and, in turn, was made to help teach some alchemists. When Jake said talked, what he actually meant was that Caleb joked about how much Jake sucked at teaching people. Which wasn’t really fair.

It wasn’t Jake’s fault all of the alchemists in the Court were morons who didn’t put enough points into Perception to actually understand what was going on. They went on and on about methodology while Jake just kept telling them to look at what the hell they were doing rather than assuming everything went according to theory. Something it turned out they couldn’t do, because apparently Wisdom and Willpower were more important stats when it came to alchemy.

He could only shake his head at their ignorance, which his family only found amusing.

At least he did manage to teach them a little about poisons. Mainly things he felt were rather basic knowledge, but it seemed like him explaining it made them understand it better than if they read it. Jake wrote that up to his legendary teaching skill. Caleb was happy either way, as they both knew Caleb just wanted to have Jake teach to truly show off that there were no hard feelings between the Order and the Court. And Records. Probably some stuff related to Records, too.

The dinner ended far too soon, and it was time for Jake to go. Everyone insisted on escorting him to the city exit, and it didn’t take them long to get there. Jake said goodbye to Caleb, Maja, and Adam before turning to his parents.

His mom gave him a big hug that went on for a bit too long, followed by his dad giving a rare, brisk one. Mom had tears in her eyes, but she didn’t say anything so as to not make Jake feel bad about leaving. They both knew he had to go.

Jake walked out of the hidden city gate as his dad followed him, with Caleb leading everyone else inside again. The two of them stopped a bit outside the city with no one else around. Robert turned to Jake with a serious look on his face. One Jake had only rarely seen.

"Jake… Debra and I won’t begin to act like we understand everything that is going on with you. I get some of it, but I will admit I have given up trying to fully understand what both you and Caleb are doing and how the world has changed. What I do understand is that you have important things you want and need to do. If there is one thing your mother and I would never want, it is you feeling like you are restraining yourself because of us. So please, just do what you have to do. Just know that no matter what happens, we are proud of you, and you can always come to visit… but you don’t need to. You don’t have to hold yourself back because of us; we will be fine."

They smiled at each other as his dad tapped his shoulder. "Take care out there."

Jake smiled and pulled his dad into a hug that lasted quite a bit longer than the last one. Letting go of him, Jake took a step back. "Thanks, Dad."

His dad just nodded. "Now be off."

Jake nodded again and turned to leave.

"Be safe," Jake muttered under his breath as he took off, his dad staring after him as he left. Jake also felt the gazes of the rest of his family from afar.

Intermission 10 - Arthur

Arthur wondered where it had all gone so wrong, but the answer was obvious, wasn’t it?

It had been the moment he had agreed to the offer of that other Chosen—a choice he still questioned to this day. Why had he believed his lies and the blatant deceit? Missed all the red flags? Well, he knew why… Because he had wanted to trust him.

Like every other human on Earth, Arthur had entered a tutorial—quite a difficult one, as far as he could gather. Survival had been the goal, and after the initial panic, he had calmed down. He had entered with several employees and his youngest son, Peter, so in some ways, he’d had an advantage. They had all put their faith in him, and as always, he had risen to the occasion out of a sense of obligation. There had been a total of two thousand individuals, and with Arthur at the helm, less than a hundred had ended up dying within the first month, the majority on the first day before they gathered them. He had done all he could… but even in the tutorial, outside influence had begun to rear its ugly head.

Invitations during evolutions, dungeons made by those who had designs on their new universe. Some people had been convinced, and even Arthur had been close. The offers of the gods had sounded genuine, and it had seemed like a win-win.

It hadn’t been. There was no equal deal, no give and take… It was as unbalanced a relationship as they came. Nearly all the gods who had blessed people wanted them to convert others. Some gods even were antagonistic towards others, and the leaders of man clearly did not enter the eyes of the gods. The battle for influence had mostly been peaceful, but deadly duels had begun to pop up.

A tutorial that was mostly under control began to turn chaotic. Two gods held especially great hatred for each other and decided to wage war by proxy—something Arthur came to learn was rather common practice. Why wouldn’t it be?

To gods, mortals were nothing more than playthings. They saw no reason to take any risks themselves when they could just have their ignorant followers die in their stead, like chess pieces in a game where neither player truly cared about winning, just spiting their opponent.

That was the first time Arthur learned to crack down and be assertive. The gods had no tangible power in the tutorial, and Arthur still had many followers. The majority also soon adopted his sentiment of distaste towards these religious factions, spurred on by their senseless violence and disruptions of what actually mattered—at least, according to most reasonable people.

The tutorial was about survival, and this manifested in frequent attacks by beasts and elementals. Once the religious factions’ conflicts began to result in casualties among the defenders, it didn’t take long before the majority was on Arthur’s side.

He didn’t like to do it, but some of them had to go. It was better to cut off the tumor before it could spread. They threw them out of their settlements into a wilderness where these "priests" and "preachers" quickly fell to the invaders, their followers not devout enough to follow them to their deaths. Many who had gotten blessed renounced them and denounced their former Patrons.

From there, Arthur ruled with an iron fist. He got a lie detection skill early on, and his Identify evolved to also include if people had a Blessing or not. It did not say who or what they were blessed by, only if they had one. This naturally proved instrumental in weeding out those who tried to hide their loyalties and spread conflict.

It had to be noted that Arthur, even at the height of his hatred of divine influence, had never indiscriminately gone against those with Blessings. Some were blessed but never voiced anything. Never tried to recruit anyone or make trouble. Arthur saw no reason to shun these people and simply acted like nothing was different about them. Even some of his closest allies carried Blessings of gods who didn’t care about spreading their faith and growing a faction. From them, he learned many important things.

Firstly, all gods benefited from faith, but some more than others. Some benefited so little that it didn’t matter at all. These gods, Arthur had no issues with. More than Patron gods, they were just personal sponsors and guides. He would compare them to people who identified as spiritual but didn’t view themselves as part of any organized religion. They also didn’t tend to believe that their religious beliefs mattered more than the beliefs of others.

The second thing he learned was that the gods who did benefit from faith were very aggressive when it came to getting it. While they were clearly not monotheistic, they still believed that all those within a group should act as if they were, only recognizing their Patron as the most important god. It was fine agreeing there were others, but they had to be viewed as lesser.

This was simply a requirement for them. A mechanic of the system itself. How exactly faith worked, he never quite figured out, but it was clear that people who believed in multiple gods were worth far less than those who truly believed in only one. There was a caveat to this, as it appeared that gods in Pantheons did not suffer this penalty, giving birth to large, organized religions.

Thirdly, Arthur learned about the existence of different levels of Blessings. Those blessed were far from equal, and each rank of Blessing offered more benefits and more Records. The cost for the god of giving away higher-leveled Blessings also grew, meaning the higher the level of the Blessing, the more devout the person tended to be. Minor, Lesser, Intermediate, Major, Greater, Divine—these were the Blessings he first heard of, but later it was revealed there were two more.

Baptism was not truly a Blessing, but more a brand of sorts. It did not truly offer anything, and as far as Arthur could determine, it was only used by the mega-religion known as the Holy Church. Finally, there was one more that was also hard to argue was a normal Blessing: the True Blessing.

True Blessings were something truly Unique. First of all, a god could only have one True Blessing given out at a time, and often, a god didn’t even have someone who carried it. The ones with the True Blessing were called Chosen, but others also referred to them as Prophets or Champions. They were effectively the mortal mouthpieces of their gods.

Arthur hadn’t encountered any Chosen before the Chosen of the Malefic Viper and the Chosen of Yip of Yore. But everything he had seen pointed to the same reality: the higher the level of Blessing, the more devout the person. Ell’Hakan struck Arthur as a miniature version of his own Patron, and he shared much of the insight Arthur came to have about what it meant to be a Chosen and what the Order of the Malefic Viper was all about. Insights he now questioned the accuracy of.

Why had he believed Ell’Hakan? Even now, Arthur wasn’t sure. The man had just seemed like someone he could trust, and everything the nahoom had said made sense to Arthur. His logic had been sound, and he’d even had evidence of all his claims. He now doubted all of this, as it was clear that while he’d attempted to use Ell’Hakan to remove a major threat from their planet, Ell’Hakan had also just used him as an instrument to further his own goals.

But… as mentioned… Arthur had believed Ell’Hakan because he wanted to. But in his defense, his biases had been confirmed time and time again.

Everything he had done was, at least in his own mind, for humanity, and every step of the way, he’d been affirmed in his beliefs. Peter had even agreed to infiltrate the Holy Church in order to try and get to Jacob, but during that infiltration, he had found out how truly messed up the so-called holy faction was.

Arthur had even considered joining the Church at one point, especially when he learned his son was leading it. Jacob had always been excellent at everything he put his mind to, and Arthur trusted his judgment… At least, he used to. Now, Arthur wasn’t so sure.

What he’d learned from the Church was everything in the tutorial taken to the extreme. While it was not explicitly stated, the City Lords who tried to negotiate with the Church quickly realized what the goal of the Church was: total domination. They would not allow any other faction to remain on Earth, and were more than willing to commit genocide of both their own people and the locals to achieve this. Did they prefer peaceful methods to preserve as many potential faithful as possible? Perhaps… but that wasn’t the kind of future Arthur wanted for Earth.

It would also result in the death of Earth, at least in the metaphorical sense. They would wipe out the culture of earthlings and replace it with that of the Holy Church. The values humanity had built up throughout history would be forgotten. In a few generations, those who lived on Earth wouldn’t even remember what Earth used to be. The history of their homeland would be lost forever.

Arthur could not allow that to happen. But, as he was trying to figure out a way to battle the Holy Church, he came to find an even worse fate for humanity than what the Church would bring. One caused by a faction far more destructive, cruel, and bereft of empathy:

The Order of the Malefic Viper.

When he first heard about them, he’d found it hard to believe. As mentioned, he had many who worked with him and still had Patrons that had no interest in laying a claim on Earth. They told him what was going on in the wider multiverse, with the two biggest events being the integration of the 93rd Universe and the reemergence of the Malefic Viper—two events he came to learn were connected once he knew of the presence of the Chosen of the Malefic Viper…

The Prophet of the Malefic Viper. His Champion. Mouthpiece. The mortal avatar of a god that had Malefic in its very name. A god known for his cruelty and slaughter of ten percent of an entire universe. An utterly monstrous existence that had now laid its hands on Earth. The Chosen had laid his hands on Earth.

Now, why did Arthur think he had an interest in Earth? Everything pointed to it.

The Order of the Malefic Viper had begun expanding in the First Universe. Their methods of expansion were ones that reflected the cruelty of their Patron: slaughter, enslavement, destruction. No mercy was shown on their path to conquest, and any who dared stand in their way or even try to negotiate were killed unceremoniously, their entire factions implicated.

Horror set in when Arthur began fearing the Chosen of the Malefic Viper had similar plans, but he had one hope: that he wouldn’t care about Earth. Maybe he would simply leave and head off to the Order, leaving behind their small rock in space? That hope quickly died after Arthur learned that the Chosen had not only taken part in the First World Congress, but had even been the one with the highest noble rank, holding significant sway over every vote. It would not be wrong to say he ruled the World Congress already.

The Second World Congress and Auction Event only reaffirmed what Arthur thought. He’d tried to get a feeling for the individual that was known as Jake Thayne but found it impossible. He was too aloof, too carefree about anything political. But that didn’t mean he lacked a presence in the political arena, because he had two individuals at his back.

The first was Miranda Wells.

From all he could gather, she’d been a nobody before the system. Not surprisingly, most people who were now prominent had not been known before the system. He did find a large percentage of City Leaders and faction leaders to also have been leaders in the old world, but Ms. Wells was not such an example. From what he learned, she’d just been a manager or something before the system.

Perhaps there would have been hope with her, but she was clearly also a member of this Order. She was blessed by witches and was a witch herself. Those who got to see her in action during the Treasure Hunt reported that she used brutal tactics and magic to kill her foes. The level of trust the Chosen placed in her was also high, making it only reasonable to assume she was absolutely loyal. Hence, Arthur was certain the City Lord had to go to destroy the supporters behind the Malefic’s Chosen. After his death at the hands of Ell’Hakan, they would shamble, and he saw Ms. Wells as the only person able to hold anything resembling a faction together. At least the humans in the faction. Because there was one entity even more dangerous.

The Fallen King.

Upon seeing the Unique Lifeform in the Second World Congress, Arthur had felt like many of the chess pieces fell into place. A king by birth, a creature created to lead and rule. To Arthur, that was why the Chosen had never bothered to expand his faction. Why would he when he had such a creature at his back to do it all for him?

To make it all worse, this Unique Lifeform could lead even monsters under his banner. This was why Arthur had decided he had to do something. Why he, in his desperation, had listened to the sweet whispers of an enemy Chosen who knew just what to say. He had been approached during the Myriad Paths event, and the offer he’d been given was just too good to refuse. Arthur had, in all honesty, been desperate due to how badly he was outmatched, so when he’d been thrown a lifeline, he’d grasped it with both hands.

Ell’Hakan would take care of the Chosen and the Unique Lifeform, and he’d even presented the potential of allying with Valhal—something his Patron had pre-negotiated for them. Valhal was a force that Arthur had no problems with, as they did not want to control the planet. Moreover, they were a predominately human faction, and the contract he’d negotiated with them was incredibly favorable towards Earth. All contingent on the defeat of the Chosen, of course…

Arthur sighed as he was awoken from his thoughts by one of his old employees. They were riding a magical ship, and he had been made aware that Haven was now within sight. Steeling himself, Arthur prepared to face what was to happen.

A captain had to go down with the ship, and as the leader of the United Cities Alliance, he had to take responsibility for his actions. From the very beginning, he had resolved to follow through or die in the attempt.

It was only four days past the defeat of Ell’Hakan, and Arthur had not been made aware of the Order of the Malefic Viper making any moves yet. He hoped that they wouldn’t before he had a chance to give himself up.

Their approach was naturally spotted, and Arthur sighed as he prepared himself. He had only gone with three of his most loyal attendants, and he hoped that mercy would at least be shown to them, though he wouldn’t get his hopes up. They had also prepared themselves to face death.

As an advance party from Haven moved towards them, Arthur had the ship stop. He saw that the group included the assistant of Ms. Wells, Lillian, and the resident space mage of Haven. The space mage alone was strong enough to beat everyone on the ship.

Lillian landed on the ship and regarded Arthur. She didn’t speak right away, instead taking out a token, nodding, and motioning toward the city. "Welcome to Haven; the City Lord is expecting you in the central office. If you would follow me…"

Arthur nodded, a bit surprised they hadn’t put any magical restrictions or something like that on him quite yet.

"Your followers can wait on the ship in the meantime," Lillian followed up.

He couldn’t really argue with that… It was safer to only bring him and split them up.

"Finally, what do you prefer for the meeting?" Lillian asked. Arthur frowned with confusion until she continued, "We have coffee and tea, but if you prefer something else, we can get that too."

Arthur stared at the woman, still confused. A sneaking suspicion entered his mind… Had he misread the situation?

And if he had… how badly?

Chapter 62

More to the Story

Getting back to Haven was quite a bit easier than going to Skyggen. A month was not a long time, but it was enough for many changes to happen. Earth’s space mages had been working tirelessly, and the teleportation network expanded by the day. All the factions that remained were busy claiming what they could, especially after the Holy Church decided to effectively abandon the planet, resulting in the second-biggest faction suddenly being gone.

The United Cities Alliance had clearly known of this outcome and already had people in place to take control. They did proceed with the plan of the takeover, but their loyalties to the Alliance were now in question, as they were also all made aware of their failed overall plan. Which begged the question: What would happen now?

Jake had talked with Caleb about current events, and he at least had to give these City Lords credit. Their response had simply been to do their jobs as best they could and act as neutral forces. They’d invited everyone to make teleportation circles, and they had prioritized their citizens over petty politics, focusing on rebuilding and ensuring public order after all the beast attacks. That was pretty damn respectable and made Jake feel a bit better about what was to come.

For the final stretch back to Haven from the Fort, Jake still had to run. He decided to be nice and not rush, as they were now aware of his arrival back in Haven and could prepare stuff. A bit to his surprise, something unexpected contacted him on the way.

"Had a nice vacation?" Villy asked after the deity descended with his presence.

"I know you peeked in at me pretty much all the time, so you tell me," Jake said in return.

"In my defense, I wasn’t really paying attention. Think of it more as me having a security camera on you where I can pull up the footage if I actually want to see something. Anyway, you had a good vacation, and now it is back to work, which is why I pulled you into a fast meeting. What are your plans with Valhal?"

"Not thought much about it, but I am a bit pissed at them for making a deal that is pretty much contingent on my death. Arthur, I can excuse for being ignorant and getting fooled by Ell’Hakan or whatever, but Valhal? Nah, fuck that; they did it with full knowledge. So something has to give—that is for sure—be it telling them to get the fuck out or demanding some kind of hefty compensation for being assholes.”

"Okay, allow me to offer an alternative. Don’t. I won’t share much, but I will say that things aren’t quite as they seem. Valhal is a good ally to have and a beneficial force to keep on Earth. The entire thing with Yip’s Chosen is also far more complicated than you know, and again, while I won’t share much, you hit it right on the money when you said they went in with full knowledge. Including the knowledge that the contract would never materialize and become relevant.”

"Explain," Jake simply said, frowning.

"I can’t; that would potentially ruin future plans. Some things are simply best left unsaid. But know that Valhal never actually saw you losing as an option. They are allies, and it would be best to keep them as allies.”

Jake kept frowning with suspicion. "You were involved in them even making the offer, weren’t you? What are you up to?"

"Things. We are playing a long game here, and some things will only make sense in due time. For now, just keep positive. Shit, if you want to excuse your sudden sense of forgiveness, just blame it on the Runemaiden. Wait, maybe you can demand to make her your mistress to—"

"Okay, bye!" Jake severed the connection and cut Villy off, a faint echo of a laugh still left behind as Villy clearly enjoyed teasing him.

He knew it was just a method to make Jake not discuss the topic any longer. Jake honestly had no idea what the hell Villy was doing or what he planned, but his gut told him it wasn’t anything that would impact him negatively. He was aware that things between gods were rarely simple, and that something bigger was brewing than just Yip and the Viper deciding to duke it out in a straight-on fight, so he decided to play along for now and be a good Chosen. While potentially using it as something to hold over Villy’s head. He was still a heretic, right?

With all that done, Jake finally made his way into Haven proper. He had already felt Miranda observing him on his trip—not that he didn’t expect her and everyone else to know about his arrival. As he got closer to the city, he also felt more powerful presences, making it clear he was the last to arrive.

The Sword Saint and Fallen King were already there. He had kind of assumed at least one of them to be late due to all the things they’d had to deal with during this month. Both had territories to stabilize and take control of once more, and while Jake had gotten some updates, he wasn’t entirely clear on how things were looking elsewhere on Earth. Primarily because he didn’t really care much and didn’t wanna ruin his vacation by hearing how the rest of the world was potentially in turmoil.

Jake headed straight for the office, where all the others had already gathered: the King, Miranda, Sword Saint, Lillian, and of course Arthur. Jake saw them through his sphere before he entered the office, and it was quite the sight, especially with how overly stoic Arthur looked. However, it at least looked like the man wasn’t too uncomfortable. Jake would hope not. He had been in Haven for weeks already, so he should have had plenty of time for Miranda to set him straight.

Entering the large meeting room, everyone turned to him.

"You are late in your arrival," the King said with a bit of snark. The Unique Lifeform felt a lot better than a month ago, and the many cracks in both masks were close to healed. Jake’s own mask naturally reflected the healing of the Fallen King in front of him, but he hadn’t really followed the mask regenerating during his break. Most of the time, he hadn’t worn the mask, as that had been unnecessary.

"I didn’t know we agreed to meet at midnight," Jake answered back. "I apologize for assuming we would meet at reasonable hours."

"For the record," Miranda intervened, “the Fallen King is the only one complaining. I am personally surprised you even showed up this early. I would have expected you to come a few minutes before midnight tonight to barely meet the meet-three-days-before-World-Congress deadline."

"Okay, I am starting to feel attacked here," Jake said with a smirk. He met Miranda’s eyes and knew what she was doing. Humanization. She was trying to show that Jake was a normal person in front of Arthur by treating him casually and with friendliness. Jake didn’t think the King was in on it; he was just being a dick, with Miranda then proceeding to make use of his dickishness.

"Who would have thought that previous history would be used as a predictor of future behavior," Miranda said, smiling. "Anyway, good to have you join us, Jake. You aren’t actually that late; Lord Noboru arrived only an hour or so ago."

"The lateness of one does not excuse the tardiness of another," the King once more interjected.

"Or maybe you were just early. This is my meeting, so it begins when I arrive. Not my fault you decided to misread when I would come." Jake didn’t care how unreasonable that sounded. He then finally turned to the guy in the room he was truly there for. Not holding anything back, he said, "I must admit, when I last saw you, I was surprised, but I guess I shouldn’t expect anything less of Jacob’s dad. What I did not expect was for you to effectively try and start a civil war leading to millions of deaths for no good reason.”

To his credit, Arthur didn’t deflect or back down.

"Much has become clearer to me in the last few weeks,” he answered. “Light has been shed on my numerous misunderstandings and misinterpretations, and I now realize my mistakes and can only take full responsibility for my actions. However, I will not apologize for my ultimate reason for doing what I did. What I will apologize for is not realizing that perhaps we want the same thing, making my actions unnecessary and harmful.”

"I am pretty sure you already know that I am quite skeptical of all this,” Jake said. “I assume Miranda has filled you in on her plans?"

"She has made me aware, yes,” Arthur said, his gaze firm. “And I also know the decision is ultimately yours to make. What I will make clear is that I also remain skeptical about her proposed arrangement. In all truthfulness, then before I even try to sell myself to this council, I will have to know it will truly be a council and not just a farce to try and sell the mirage of fairness and representation. That it will be a council that can actually lead to positive change and not just work to advance your personal whims or the wishes of the Order of the Malefic Viper.”

He and Jacob are quite a bit alike, huh? Jake thought. Miranda looked a bit nervous at the standoffish demeanor Arthur had adopted, making it apparent that wasn’t how she had expected things to go. Arthur also seemed to misunderstand something.

"It will be to further my personal whims," Jake answered truthfully. "Why else would I bother becoming World Leader except for purely selfish reasons?"

Arthur frowned, but he didn’t look surprised. "Which begs the question: Why even make a council? Why not just have the Order of the Malefic Viper come and take over? With them in charge, it would be—"

"Didn’t you hear what I just said?" Jake interrupted. "I said it was for my personal whims; what does the Order of the Malefic Viper have to do with anything? This entire council idea can be boiled down to a personal whim. Tell me this: Why do you think I decided to become World Leader?"

The other man looked at Jake, confused by the question. "To take control and rule the planet?"

"Wrong." Jake shook his head. "I don’t give a shit about ruling the planet. What I do give a shit about is making sure no one else is ruling the planet. I don’t want to see the Holy Church or some other bullshit faction take charge and do whatever they want. So I decided to selfishly just claim the planet and tell everyone else to play nice or fuck off. The system clearly wants someone to take control at some point, and if that is the case, it may as well be me. But that doesn’t mean I want to actually rule anything. That is what you are here for."

After talking, Jake threw Miranda a questioning look. He was a bit confused about why the hell Arthur was still so ignorant even after all this time. Shouldn’t she have explained all this already? However, she just gave him a smile in return.

Arthur looked to be considering Jake’s words for a moment before asking, "What is your ultimate goal after gaining control of Earth? What is the goal of the Order of the Malefic Viper, and what, if any, role do they play?"

"I don’t have any goal besides keeping things as they are and keeping things peaceful. As for the details, that isn’t anything I want to deal with. Honestly, I just want a place to return to whenever I want, and for those I care about who remain to be safe. As for the role of the Order? Well, they don’t have any—at least, not from your point of view. Sure, they will function as a deterrent to other factions, and I probably can’t avoid anyone going here in the future. But it will be clear that this is my home turf, and that no one should fuck around. There are certain perks to being the Chosen of a Primordial, and with the Viper at my back, no other faction will try to lay claim to Earth either.”

The man once more fell silent, his frown making his skepticism obvious. "And the Order of the Malefic Viper will simply sit back and allow this? What if your Patron asks for you to do something with the planet?"

"Well, the Order doesn’t really have a choice, and if the Viper asks me to do something with Earth I don’t like, I will tell him to fuck off." Jake shrugged. "You seem to fundamentally misunderstand the relationship I have with the Order and with the Malefic Viper. I don’t serve him for shit, and I am more just a member of the Order by association, shamelessly leeching off them for my own benefit. The Malefic Viper and I are, in the simplest of terms, just good friends. So if he asks me for something, I will listen, but I will listen to him the same as I would listen to Miranda or anyone else here in the room. Well, besides you and the Fallen King."

This time, Arthur really didn’t know what to say, prompting Miranda to insert herself.

"I have been trying to tell you that you severely misinterpreted who you were dealing with and the current situation,” she said harshly. “You moved based on biased and false information with little criticism and few attempts to truly verify anything yourself. Was your interpretation one that would be true in ninety-nine percent of cases? Probably, but you still ultimately messed up.”

The Sword Saint also decided to talk. "I do not wish to see Earth fall, either, and would defend it if necessary. My reason for supporting Jake is that I trust him as a person. I learned about him as a hunter before I learned about him as a Chosen. But let me clarify that I will also take a laidback approach to Earth, similar to him… yet should the planet be threatened, I will be here. No matter who the threat is, even if it is the Chosen of the Malefic Viper."

"Well, there you have it." Jake shrugged. "And, again, if it was up to me, you would not be sitting here. However, I have also become aware that just chopping your head off would lead to even more annoying issues, and while you are wholly ignorant of a lot of things, you seem to at least understand how to manage cities and politics. Your role will be the same as before, just on a council with a few differing opinions."

Arthur seemed to listen, sighing as he looked at the floorboards. "I do understand that my actions were inexcusable, and I trusted people I never should have. Before I met Ms. Wells, I wasn’t even aware of the existence of these Bloodlines, much less that the Chosen of Yip had one. I do realize now it influenced me, but that is no excuse for what I did. Let me also make it clear, Lord Thayne, that I do not fully trust you either, but I also know that trying to oppose you at this point will result in nothing positive." Arthur looked up at Jake. "I shall try and do my utmost on this council to make up for the mistakes I have made, but I will not compromise who I am or my beliefs. My priority remains the wellbeing of humanity and preservation of Earth."

"Great," Jake said. "That is exactly what the job description entails. Well, this was easy. Why did we need to meet three days before the World Congress for this, again?"

Miranda sighed. "Because there is still a lot of work to prepare and contracts to draw up. Also, Jake, you have some personal matters you should attend to in the meantime."

Jake raised an eyebrow. "Such as?"

"I have been informed that the snakes at the Grand Mangrove River require your presence for a teleportation circle that should allow you to travel to the Order of the Malefic Viper again. Also, Arnold would like to see you. Finally, would it be possible for you to ask Carmen to come to Haven? The teleportation network should allow it.”

"Oh, no need to worry about Carmen," Jake said with a smile. "She and Sylphie are already well on their way, though they chose to take the more cloudy and scenic route over the teleportation network. They should be here in a day or two, according to Sylphie."

Miranda nodded, surprisingly unsurprised. "Very well. In that case, maybe head over to Arnold or to the Grand Mangrove River. Ah, a teleporter to the mangrove forest is already finished, and you can teleport there directly from the Fort. We shall reconvene when Carmen gets here."

"Got it." Jake nodded as he headed out to leave all the political nerds alone.

It was time to see what the resident mad scientist had been up to in recent times.